<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:26:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration sucks</title>
      <link>https://newsletter.posthog.com/p/collaboration-sucks</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a helpful amount of collaboration. People want to be helpful. People aren’t specific enough about what feedback they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892394"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://newsletter.posthog.com/p/collaboration-sucks'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 27 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lonesword:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If I don’t like my coworkers, I’m out. I like people who give a shit about the work I do (a.k.a “collaboration”). “Whatever, you own it” is just lazy for “I can’t be bothered to understand what you are working on”.&lt;p&gt;The problem is not the collaboration, it’s the ineffective collaboration. Maybe the author should fix that instead of pitching magic anti-collaboration click-bait pills.&lt;p&gt;Also, the problems you solve must be pretty straightforward and unambiguous (or you have a small codebase) if have the luxury of being able to just make a pull request for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zzzeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;wow add Posthog to Places Id Never Work&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;you asked someone what they thought of your approach? BAD! that&amp;#x27;s not our culture!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wagwang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is so dumb, its how you end up with 37 versions to do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;foobarbecue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think this is good advice for building, programming, or operating spacecraft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CGMthrowaway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt;Prefer to give feedback after something has shipped (but before the next iteration) rather than reviewing it before it ships. Front-loading your feedback can turn it into a quasi-approval process.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This works for software dev. Would be more difficult in anything else, where you&amp;#x27;re not constantly updating an existing product on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neilk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The post is obviously a bit satirical. But if I’m gonna take it more seriously. Here’s the thing. I get irritated when founders berate their employees for doing culture wrong. Whose fault is that, genius? Culture is your job. It’s not the job of random employees who will be fired if they make a wrong move.&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t reducible to mindset. In a situation with a lot of people, they want to know what is approved.&lt;p&gt;If you reward people for shipping then guess what, everyone wants to contribute to a thing that is shipping (and gets paradoxically nitpicky). Also, you’re going to have a lot of attention to shipping new things rather than improving stuff that the users rely on. Thanks for confusing the customers.&lt;p&gt;If your edict is “do the right thing for customers” then great, who is the judge of that?&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what’s happening at PostHog. But it is often the case that employees default to useless collab when they are confused about what they should be doing. No one wants to appear idle, so, “collaborating”.&lt;p&gt;Yes, founders, we appreciate you. You were born with the itch to build things and you didn’t care if it was done right or wrong. You found (or accidentally backwards into) an opportunity where that was rewarded. And you built a company around that. Things aren’t like that now. And the people like you? You would hate it if they were your employees now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwaway7783:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Prefer to give feedback after something has shipped (but before the next iteration) rather than reviewing it before it ships. Front-loading your feedback can turn it into a quasi-approval process.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t confuse this with &amp;quot;Don&amp;#x27;t test and don&amp;#x27;t do code reviews&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tombert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel like collaboration can work great with a group of exactly two people.  It&amp;#x27;s not terribly hard for two people to partition work and actively help each other. With two people working on a project, both people can realistically understand most of the codebase, and can competently review each other&amp;#x27;s pull requests.&lt;p&gt;I feel collaboration suffers from combinatorial complexity though, and I feel any number bigger than two ends up doing more harm than good. Once you have more than two people, the codebase starts becoming more segmented, it becomes really difficult to agree on decisions, and the project becomes a lot harder than it needs to be.&lt;p&gt;If I ever get into management, I think I will try and keep this in mind and try and design projects around two-people teams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;didip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For real. The only collaboration that is super fast is between yourself and Claude Code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;commandersaki:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can see how the lack of collaboration lead to the posthog.com website design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moralestapia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This kills the product manager, though.&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s why it still persists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brendanfalk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the real problem here is &amp;quot;decision making&amp;quot; as opposed to &amp;quot;collaboration&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t think of a single time where having someone else review my work or give me feedback is a meaningfully bad thing. It&amp;#x27;s an opportunity to learn. But getting feedback is different to making the final decision.&lt;p&gt;Instead, the real problem is the either 1) lack of knowing who makes the final decision or 2) requiring everyone must agree to a final decision. You will move a lot faster if you know who the final decision maker is, ideally have fewer (or only one person) making that final decision, and encourage people to make decisions quickly (most decisions are reversible anyway)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onion2k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This sometimes leads to valuable insights, but always slows the driver down.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;In cases where the insight is genuinely useful that&amp;#x27;s better than going fast mostly because you were probably going fast in the wrong direction. Ideally you would optimise collaboration to increase the likelihood of valuable feedback (because that saves more time and money) rather than optimizing for speed.&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;#x27;ve lost track of the number of meetings I&amp;#x27;ve been in so that someone can cover their ass by making something a &amp;#x27;collaborative decision&amp;#x27; instead of taking responsibility, so I can totally see where the author is coming from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leptons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We don&amp;#x27;t collaborate, we iterate. I&amp;#x27;m the lead of my department, so I sst the initial direction of the new feature, discuss it with my team, assign it, and let someone build the basic functionality. Then I&amp;#x27;ll review it, and I will pick up the code and move things around, refine the UX, refine the code, and then maybe pass it back to the developer for more changes, until we arrive at something really good. It doesn&amp;#x27;t make anyone unhappy or slow us down, and we often don&amp;#x27;t know where we&amp;#x27;re going to end up when we start a new feature. Things are fluid, but we have a goal of making things easy to use. Iteration among the team members also ensures more of the team knows how the code works, and we often learn from each other. Maybe this is &amp;quot;collaboration&amp;quot; but we call it &lt;i&gt;iteration&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;upghost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Taking the article&amp;#x27;s analogy of the &amp;quot;collaboration while driving&amp;quot;, the F1 sport is quite insanely collaborative. For example, the drivers literally do have someone in their ear by radio being their coach and spotter for the entire trip. I&amp;#x27;ve never heard of the equivalent in software. Does anyone know of anything like this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;klik99:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s no one size fits all - what they&amp;#x27;re saying would absolutely fail at the company I&amp;#x27;m currently at, but sounds like it works for them. The key thing is to have a process that works well for the people who are there, and hire people who work well under those conditions. The people who do well at our company would not do well at their company, and vice versa. I don&amp;#x27;t like how this article makes a claim about what works well for them is actually a universal truth. It really depends on the people there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iLoveOncall:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Praising people for saying &amp;quot;it&amp;#x27;s your call&amp;quot; and in the same article boasting about &amp;quot;extraordinarily high ownership&amp;quot; is simply laughable.&lt;p&gt;The two are literal polar opposite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jesse__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I don&amp;#x27;t agree with Charles&amp;#x27; (clearly nuts) distaste for sparkling water, I&amp;#x27;m happy to see people finally talking about this issue publicly.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve suffered through this at several companies, down to the level of sometimes spending like 3x the time it took to implement the actual feature on answering and &amp;#x27;fixing&amp;#x27; pedantic stylistic nitpicks during code reviews.  While having a homogenous style is important, I&amp;#x27;m solidly in the camp of &amp;quot;if you want to give me style nitpicks, just change them yourself, tell me, and save us both some time&amp;quot;.  This extends to like 80% of feedback I see in code reviews.&lt;p&gt;Be weird and do stuff. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;shorts&amp;#x2F;DjvVN4Vp_r0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;shorts&amp;#x2F;DjvVN4Vp_r0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;devin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This feels silly. I think this is just &amp;quot;ask for forgiveness, not permission&amp;quot; but made more clickbaity.&lt;p&gt;It also borders on a kind of edgelord attitude that I&amp;#x27;ve seen from people who I wish not to work with again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kristianc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“If you want to go fast, go alone; if you want to go far, go together”&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve often noticed that this is a favourite phrase of those whose preferred motion is narrating other people&amp;#x27;s work rather than doing it themselves. Teams do go further together. But only when everyone is rowing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snackdex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;damn. super cool that posthog is acknowledging the pains of growing even at their scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codegeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Unfortunately for me, not all collaboration can be rooted out, and even I will admit that some collaboration is useful. Ian and Andy edited this newsletter after all.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;So &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; collaboration does work. It is just that the post is talking about things that are not really true collaboration and those should be avoided. Title is click bait but posthog is famous for these.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwaway713:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Every time you see collaboration happening, speak up and destroy it. Say “there are too many people involved. X, you are the driver, you decide.” (This is a great way to make friends btw).&lt;p&gt;Corollary for managers: Do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; say &amp;quot;it&amp;#x27;s your call&amp;quot;, then once the decision has been made (and you skipped all the meetings pertaining to that decision), comment about how you would have done it differently and then retroactively request your report to go back and make changes. This is a great way to lose employees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;john_moscow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you know how to get stuff done yourself, start your own company, get stuff done, and enjoy the profits (or losses, depending on how good you are). It&amp;#x27;s your risk and your reward.&lt;p&gt;If you are working for someone else, the unwritten rule #1 is that a single employee should not amass too much influence within the company to start dictating their own conditions. So, the management culture averages decisions across multiple people, to make sure the loss of one-two team players won&amp;#x27;t be noticed.&lt;p&gt;It can be extremely demotivating if you are smart and capable, but these are the rules of the game. Be nice, get paid, accumulate some savings, make connections with other smart people, learn the market, and eventually start your own game on your own rules. Until then, trying to stand out will get you labelled as a troublemaker, and will hamper your progress in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mcdow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve used both approaches and I can’t disagree more. Writing code first might feel faster but it isn’t. It’s great for surface level issues but just muddies the waters for any consequential feature.&lt;p&gt;Measure(communicate) twice, cut(build) once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bryzaguy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would argue the opposite. If your collaboration sucks IMHO you haven’t done enough. It’s a skill. Imagine you’re playing a team sport and you recommended people play together less to win more games. Now look up Globetrotters vs Lakers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ssalmon74:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Gravitational Pull&amp;quot; is the solution!&lt;p&gt;Instead of the &amp;quot;Collaboration Sucks&amp;quot; approach, we need to apply Gravitational Pull. For every key project, the Driver defines three essential stakeholders (e.g., Tech Lead, Business Owner, Target User) who form the &amp;quot;Quantum Sync Circle.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Everyone else is noise. This prevents endless discussions and focuses accountability right where it belongs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsletter.posthog.com/p/collaboration-sucks</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892394</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A catalog of side effects</title>
      <link>https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/compiler-effects/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;but instead what effects does this opcode have. Different compilers represent and track these effects differently. Different compilers keep track of this information differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891868"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/compiler-effects/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;parpfish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the article title and domain really had me thinking this was going to be about mandela effects&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/compiler-effects/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891868</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A modern 35mm film scanner for home</title>
      <link>https://www.soke.engineering/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Knokke will cost 999€ at launch. Knokke will launch on Kickstarter. Will Knokke support 120 film, panoramic formats, or border scanning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891907"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.soke.engineering/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 22 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fuziontech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m glad this exists but at ~1k EUR I would be interested if it could scan 120 medium format negatives...but the fact that it does not is an absolute deal breaker for me. It seems like they are considering it. I hope they do figure that out sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coreyp_1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I gave up trying to read the article when animations started happening when I scrolled.  It&amp;#x27;s annoying and I have better things to do than waste time waiting for your animations to stutter and finish moving around when I&amp;#x27;m trying to scan the article.  Good luck with whatever you&amp;#x27;re trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rozenmd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the &amp;quot;this is crazy expensive&amp;quot; crowd: this competes with the Pakon F135 - an ancient lab scanner that involves booting up Windows XP, finding old drivers on a CD, etc&lt;p&gt;This sounds excellent to me, personally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ben7799:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still have an expensive Canon dedicated slide&amp;#x2F;film scanner from 20 years ago.&lt;p&gt;IIRC at some point their value started going up as they became rare.&lt;p&gt;Mine did something like 50MP scans of 35mm film&amp;#x2F;slides.  The quality was more than enough.&lt;p&gt;But it was painfully slow.&lt;p&gt;This thing is not 100x faster, so I think it&amp;#x27;s still painfully slow.   If it takes 5 minutes to do a roll of 24 that still means someone with hundreds of rolls needs to have a lot of time on their hands.&lt;p&gt;Not sure I can actually figure out software to get my old one to work FWIW, but I don&amp;#x27;t think I care to deal with it, I have a big enough mess dealing with the ~200k digital photos that are already on disk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ImPleadThe5th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The industrial design is really nice! I like the fun LED display as opposed to an LCD. I am surprised there doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be any physical controls!&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure this will be on every photography youtuber&amp;#x27;s channel shortly, can&amp;#x27;t wait to see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;solatic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Film doesn&amp;#x27;t really make sense anymore outside the realm of luxury-budget art. And if so, why 35mm? Why not medium format &amp;#x2F; Hasselblads, or large format? Why not actually go for the format sizes where there&amp;#x27;s a reasonable argument that film can produce a better end result compared to DSLRs?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeWaka:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t see any infrared sensor. This makes it drastically worse than the competitors on the market, as it&amp;#x27;s an essential sensor for dust and scratch removal.&lt;p&gt;Did they not research the competition?&lt;p&gt;I can buy a brand-new 7200 (virtual) DPI machine with infrared, proper color metering, wide software support, and multi-exposure system for $400, less than half the price of this offering.&lt;p&gt;It also supports slides and single frames, whereas this has a min. of 3 in a strip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wantlotsofcurry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Would&amp;#x27;ve been an auto-buy at $500. Looks cool though I hope they have success&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctkhn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is crazy expensive. I built my own copy stand recently from this post&amp;#x27;s specs and even adding in a digital camera, it&amp;#x27;s still a lot cheaper than 999 euros.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;alexandermatragos.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2023&amp;#x2F;1&amp;#x2F;15&amp;#x2F;building-a-copy-stand-to-scan-film-for-100" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;alexandermatragos.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2023&amp;#x2F;1&amp;#x2F;15&amp;#x2F;building-a-copy...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fusslo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish the fancy scroll nonsense would go away.&lt;p&gt;For example I wanted to look at the first picture in the horizontal gallery that scrolls horizontally when you scroll vertically. However, there is no way for me to view the whole image. Either it is cutoff at the bottom, or it starts horizontally scrolling. Switching from vertical to horizontal scrolling is awkward and I just want to skip the gallery.&lt;p&gt;scrolling on that page feels slow, sluggish, and if you switch to spacebar, you actually miss significant content since it only loads&amp;#x2F;becomes visible halfway into the page.&lt;p&gt;Like others have said, dust is a huge issue. Some film labs cut  film into short strips. some film is just a single image (for example if previously cut to fit into slides).&lt;p&gt;The film is designed to form into a coil. So, if there&amp;#x27;s grit or any hard material you&amp;#x27;ll end up with scratches on the negative itself.&lt;p&gt;--is it only 35mm as well? I don&amp;#x27;t think I see any mention of formats it supports. So I can only assume it&amp;#x27;s just 35mm.--
EDIT: found the 120mm section in the FAQ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stringsandchars:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Disappointed to see that the first reactions on HN are so dismissive.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m both amazed and really pleased to see anyone attempting to launch a totally new scanner in 2025, and genuinely hoping the actual scans are really made at the resolution and color-depth claimed in the text: too many recent scanners are simply upscaled, lower bit-depth devices marketed with exaggerated specs.&lt;p&gt;I also have a Nikon Coolscan 9000, so I&amp;#x27;m not immediately in the market for this. But I don&amp;#x27;t expect the Coolscan to last forever, and the Firewire connections on the machine are already abandoned by Apple, who chose not to support the cables in their latest Operating System - so eventually I won&amp;#x27;t be able to connect it to a new computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anfractuosity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hmm, does seem pretty expensive but sounds interesting.  I&amp;#x27;ve got an old Canon FS4000 for 35mm, which works ok for me.  I&amp;#x27;m curious what people recommend for 4x5 film.&lt;p&gt;Is there such a thing as a cheap drum scanner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mongol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related, not a 35 mm scanner but a super-8 scanner with true hacker ethos: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tscann8.torulf.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tscann8.torulf.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(I have submitted it earlier but no traction)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;turnsout:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When it comes to the light source, it&amp;#x27;s a huge missed opportunity. The next wave of film scanning involves capturing Red, Green and Blue separately (separate narrow-band LEDs) to better isolate C-41 layers and counteract crossover on the image sensor. And yes, it should have an IR pass as well, for dust removal.&lt;p&gt;With that said, I&amp;#x27;m happy to see new film products released in 2025&amp;#x2F;2026. Hopefully this is just the first at-bat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p0w3n3d:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Quite expensive though...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrexroad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I applaud their intent to be repairable, but would really like to see a commitment to open sourcing the software under specific conditions (time, EoL, acquisition, closing down, etc).&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; “Is Knokke open, repairable, and long-term supported?”&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; “Absolutely. We&amp;#x27;re committed to building a scanner that lasts decades.
All schematics and repair manuals will be publicly available, replacement parts can be purchased directly, and the software will remain supported for as long as possible.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brcmthrowaway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why does film attract so much dust?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyframe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d never run film at claimed top speeds unless it was a disposable copy print, but seems exciting. Long way have we come from linear array cameras and telecine to these. Different light sources would be useful for dust and scratches mask. $1k price is also insane. For full mechanical assembly with casters etc it probably comes within five or ten, but still a bargain. I wrote here years ago where I had a side hustle scanning and processing ye olde reels with an absolute beast of a scanner (think room sized) that did 2k in real time with an SGI and Hippi fiber network. Tech almost interesting as films themselves. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sbszllr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone who has a mirrorless scanning setup for my film, and pondered getting a dedicated scanner... the price of this is quite steep given how inflexible of a tool it is.&lt;p&gt;A second hand DSLR setup is going to be roughly the same price or less. I&amp;#x27;m also not sure what kind of workflow improvements it actually offers. If you want fancy and experimental, filmomat has arguably a more interesting but pricier offering.&lt;p&gt;But naysaying aside, I hope they manage to find a niche that allows them to survive as a company, and keep the analog photography revival alive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiagod:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No IR sensor for dust removal?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inamberclad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The biggest pains of film scanning are in the post process color balance and dust removal. Unless this can improve those parts of the workflow, it&amp;#x27;s only going to be a minor improvement. I like the continuous reel movement of this scanner vs a flatbed though, that can improve the physical workflow quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marshferm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Stick to my Nikon scanner until this comes down in $&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.soke.engineering/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891907</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meticulous (YC S21) is hiring to redefine software dev</title>
      <link>https://jobs.ashbyhq.com/meticulous/3197ae3d-bb26-4750-9ed7-b830f640515e</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jobs.ashbyhq.com/meticulous/3197ae3d-bb26-4750-9ed7-b830f640515e</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892773</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adk-go: code-first Go toolkit for building, evaluating, and deploying AI agents</title>
      <link>https://github.com/google/adk-go</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agent Development Kit (ADK) for Go An open-source, code-first Go toolkit for building, evaluating, and deploying sophisticated AI agents with flexibility and control. Agent Development Kit (ADK) is a flexible and modular framework that applies software development principles to AI agent creation. 0 License - see the LICENSE file for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891968"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/google/adk-go'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/google/adk-go</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891968</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xortran - A PDP-11 Neural Network With Backpropagation in Fortran IV</title>
      <link>https://github.com/dbrll/Xortran</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;01) Tanh output The code compiles with the DEC FORTRAN IV compiler (1974). Output The output shows the mean squared loss every 100 epochs, followed by the final predictions from the forward pass. RUN DL1:XORTRN Background This project demonstrates that a minimal FORTRAN IV environment from the 1970s was sufficient to implement a basic neural network with backpropagation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892174"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/dbrll/Xortran'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jacobgorm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When I studied cognitive psychology I remember one of the professors told us about how they had been playing with implementing neurals nets on their PDP11 back in the day. I remember thinking that had to have been be a total waste of time. Silly me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/dbrll/Xortran</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892174</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Terminal of the Future</title>
      <link>https://jyn.dev/the-terminal-of-the-future</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;a first try: Jupyter some problems how does that work. what does a better terminal look like. shell integration There exists today a terminal called Warp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892191"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://jyn.dev/the-terminal-of-the-future'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jyn.dev/the-terminal-of-the-future</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892191</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PBM Drug Pricing Distortion Report</title>
      <link>https://www.46brooklyn.com/research/welcome-to-private-label-park-nuf485-8h5kw-wk8y2</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This drug pricing distortion was supposed to go extinct. PCMA recently claimed that "Drug companies alone set and raise drug prices and can lower the list prices at any time. WAC can inform us about changes brand manufacturers are making to drug list prices (i.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892469"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.46brooklyn.com/research/welcome-to-private-label-park-nuf485-8h5kw-wk8y2'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;toomuchtodo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Original title &amp;quot;This drug pricing distortion was supposed to go extinct. It’s never been more alive.&amp;quot; reworded for context. Mods: please feel free to update to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.46brooklyn.com/research/welcome-to-private-label-park-nuf485-8h5kw-wk8y2</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892469</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Data Formulator – interactive AI agents for data analysis (Microsoft)</title>
      <link>https://data-formulator.ai/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://data-formulator.ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45890394</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Creavi Macropad – Built a wireless macropad with a display</title>
      <link>https://creavi.tech/blog/creavi-macropad-build-log/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning something new, it’s like a mental expedition. Which project should I not start. Create something from nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891319"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://creavi.tech/blog/creavi-macropad-build-log/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stavros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is fantastic. You&amp;#x27;ve detailed a lot of the stuff that ruined my projects, though I never really actually sat down to learn about parasitic inductance and how to combat it. Now I look at the datasheet and make sure I don&amp;#x27;t miss any of the recommended caps and resistors, though I&amp;#x27;m still not at your level of complicated design.&lt;p&gt;The finished product looks great, well done! By the way, why not add two more buttons at those two blank corners? Is it because the labels wouldn&amp;#x27;t fit on the display? You could always replicate the layout onto the display itself and put the labels on that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sulicat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks really nice! It looks real professional!&lt;p&gt;Is there an ESP on there? Are you using lvgl for the display?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://creavi.tech/blog/creavi-macropad-build-log/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891319</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs</title>
      <link>https://thenewstack.io/ffmpeg-to-google-fund-us-or-stop-sending-bugs/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As FFmpeg tweeted later, “FFmpeg is written almost exclusively by volunteers. Earlier, FFmpeg pointed out that it’s far from the only open source project to face such issues. … It’s even more unlikely with Google Project Zero, the best white-hat security researchers money can buy, breathing down the necks of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891016"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thenewstack.io/ffmpeg-to-google-fund-us-or-stop-sending-bugs/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 29 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lamontcg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They should set up a foundation&amp;#x2F;LLC if they don&amp;#x27;t have one already and require a support contract for fixing any bugs in niche codecs.  Target the 95%-98% use cases for &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; work.  If someone gives them a CVE on something ancient, just note it with an issue tracker and that the problem is currently unsponsored.  Have default build flags to omit all the ancient&amp;#x2F;buggy stuff.  If nobody is willing to pay to fix all the ancient crap, then nobody should be using it.  But if someone is willing to pay, then it gets fixed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deepriverfish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;why don&amp;#x27;t they just ignore Goole and work at their own pace?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;egypturnash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The Tragedy of the Bazaar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hmmmmmm. I can understand both points but ...&lt;p&gt;Google is under no obligation to work on FFmpeg.&lt;p&gt;Google leveraging AI to spam ffmpeg devs with bugs that range from real to obscure to wrongly reported may be annoying. But even then I still don&amp;#x27;t think Google is to be held accountable for reporting bugs nor is it required to fix bugs. Note: I do think Google should help pay for costs and what not. If they were a good company they would not only report bugs but also have had developers fix the bugs, but they are selfish and greedy, everyone knows that. Even then they are not responsible for bugs in ffmpeg. And IF the bug report is valid, then I also see no problem.&lt;p&gt;The article also confuses things. For instance:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Many in the FFmpeg community argue, with reason, that it is unreasonable for a trillion-dollar corporation like Google, which heavily relies on FFmpeg in its products, to shift the workload of fixing vulnerabilities to unpaid volunteers&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;How could Google do that? It is not Google&amp;#x27;s decision. That is up to volunteers. If they refuse to fix bug reports reported from Google then this is fine. But it is THEIR decision, not Google.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;With this policy change, GPZ announces that it has reported an issue on a specific project within a week of discovery, and the security standard 90-day disclosure clock then starts, regardless of whether a patch is available or not.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Well, many opinions here. I think ALL bugs and exploits should be INSTANTLY AND WITHOUT ANY DELAY, be made fully transparent and public. I understand the other side of the medal too, bla bla we need time to fix it bla bla. I totally understand it. Even then I believe the only truthful, honest way to deal with this, is 100% transparency at all times. This includes when there are negative side effects too, such as open holes. I believe in transparency, not in secrecy. There can not be any compromise here IMO.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Many volunteer open source program maintainers and developers feel this is massively unfair to put them under such pressure when Google has billions to address the problem.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;So what? Google reports issues. You can either fix that or not. Either way is a strategy. It is not Google&amp;#x27;s fault when software can be exploited, unless they wrote the code. Conversely, the bug or flaw would still exist in the code EVEN IF GOOGLE WOULD NOT REPORT IT. So I don&amp;#x27;t understand this part. I totally understand the issue of Google being greedy, but this here is not solely about Google&amp;#x27;s greed. This is also how a project deals with (real) issues (if they are not real then you can ask Google why they send out so much spam).&lt;p&gt;That Google abuses AI to spam down real human beings is evil and shabby. I am all for ending Google on this planet - it does so much evil. But either it is a bug, or not. I don&amp;#x27;t understand the opinion of ffmpeg devs &amp;quot;because it is Google, we want zero bug reports&amp;quot;. That just makes no sense.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The fundamental problem remains that the FFmpeg team lacks the financial and developer resources to address a flood of AI-created CVEs.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Well, that is more an issue in how to handle Google spamming down people. Sue them in court so that they stop spamming. But if it is a legit bug report, why is that a problem? Are ffmpeg devs concerned about the code quality being bad? If it is about money then even though I think all of Google&amp;#x27;s assets should be seized and the CEOs that have done so much evil in the last 20 years be put to court, it really is not their responsibility to fix anything written by others. That&amp;#x27;s just not how software engineering works; it makes no sense. It seems people confuse ethics with responsibilities here. The GPL doesn&amp;#x27;t mandate code fixing to be done; it mandates that if you publish a derivative etc... of the code, that code has to be published under the same licence and made available to people. That&amp;#x27;s about it, give or take. It doesn&amp;#x27;t say corporations or anyone else HAS to fix something.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;On the other hand, security experts are certainly right in thinking that FFmpeg is a critical part of the Internet’s technology framework and that security issues do need to be made public responsibly and addressed.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I am all for that too, but even stricter - all security issues are to be made public instantly, without delay, fully and completely. I went to open source because I got tired of Microsoft. Why would I want to go back to evil? Not being transparent here is no valid excuse IMO.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The reality is, however, that without more support from the trillion-dollar companies that profit from open source, many woefully underfunded, volunteer-driven critical open-source projects will no longer be maintained at all.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Wait - so it is Google&amp;#x27;s fault if projects die due to lack of funding? How does that explanation work?&lt;p&gt;You can choose another licence model. Many choose BSD&amp;#x2F;MIT. Others choose GPL. And so forth.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;For example, Wellnhofer has said he will no longer maintain libxml2 in December. Libxml2 is a critical library in all web browsers, web servers, LibreOffice and numerous Linux packages. We don’t need any more arguments; we need real support for critical open source programs before we have another major security breach.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Yes, that is a problem - the funding part. I completely agree. I still don&amp;#x27;t understand the &amp;quot;logic&amp;quot; of trying to force corporations to have to do so when they are not obliged. If you don&amp;#x27;t want corporations to use your code, specify that in the licence. The GPL does not do that. I am confused about this &amp;quot;debate&amp;quot; because it makes no real sense to me from an objective point of view. The only part that I can understand pisses off real humans is when Google uses AI as a pester-spam attack orgy. Hopefully a court agrees and spits up any company with more than 100 developers into smaller entities the moment they use AI to spam real human beings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skybrian:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s a thread by Google&amp;#x27;s head of security that notes the ways they&amp;#x27;ve contributed to FFmpeg over the years:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;argvee&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1986194852669964528" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;argvee&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1986194852669964528&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zach_moore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Google is evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seattle3503:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; “The position of the FFmpeg X account is that somehow disclosing vulnerabilities is a bad thing. Google provides more assistance to open source software projects than almost any other organization, and these debates are more likely to drive away potential sponsors than to attract them.”&lt;p&gt;This position likely to drive away maintainers. Generally the maintainers need these projects less than the big companies that use them. I&amp;#x27;m not sure what Google&amp;#x27;s endgame is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisMarshallNY:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks like this was a security issue.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t consider a security issue to be a &amp;quot;standard bug.&amp;quot; I need to look at it, and [maybe] fix it, regardless of who reported it.&lt;p&gt;But in my projects, I have gotten requests (sometimes, demands) that I change things like the published API (a general-purpose API), to optimize some niche functionality for one user.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll usually politely decline these, and respond with an explanation as to why, along with suggestions for them to add it, after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vsgherzi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I understand ffmpeg being angry at the workload but this is how it is with large open source projects. Ffmpeg has no obligation to fix any of this. Open source is a gift and is provided as is. If Google demanded a fix I could see this being an issue. As it is right now it just seems like a bad look. If they wanted compensation then they should change the model, there&amp;#x27;s nothing wrong with that. Google found a bug, they reported it. If it&amp;#x27;s a valid bug then it&amp;#x27;s a valid bug end of story. Software owes it to its users to be secure, but again it&amp;#x27;s up to the maintainers if they also believe that. Maybe this pushes Google to make an alternative, which I&amp;#x27;d be excited for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iscoelho:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s a reproducible use-after-free in a codec that ships by default with most desktop and server distributions.&lt;p&gt;The recent iOS zero-day (CVE-2025-43300) targeted the rarely used DNG image format. How long before this FFMPEG vulnerability is exploited to compromise legacy devices in the wild, I wonder?&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of this grandstanding for arguably questionable funding. (I surely would not fund those who believe these issues are slop.) I’d like to think most contributors already understand the severity and genuinely care about keeping FFMPEG secure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ksynwa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the point of Google&amp;#x27;s Project Zero?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not being dismissive. I understand the imperetive of identifying and fixing vulnerabilities. I also understand the detrimental impact that these problems can potentially have on Google.&lt;p&gt;What I don&amp;#x27;t understand is the choice to have a public facing project about this. Can anyone shine a light on this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bhouston:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would suggest that FFmpeg spin up a commercial arm that gets support contracts with Google, Amazon, etc, but with a tight leash so that it does not undermine the open source project.  Would need clean guidance as to what the commercial arm does and does not.&lt;p&gt;Probably could pull in millions per year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bogwog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it time for FFmpeg to relicense as AGPL? That&amp;#x27;d be fun to witness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ironman1478:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Never work for free. It&amp;#x27;s a complete market distortion and leads to bad actors taking advantage of you and your work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dbl000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand the rational for announcing that a vulnerability in project X was discovered before the patch is released. I read the project zero blogspot announcement but it doesn&amp;#x27;t make much sense to me. Google claims this is help downsteam users but that feels like a largely non-issue to me.&lt;p&gt;If you announce a vulnerability (unspecified) is found in a project before the patch is released doesn&amp;#x27;t that just incentivize bad actors to now direct their efforts at finding a vulnerability in that project?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;section_me:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;FFmpeg should just dual license at this point. If you&amp;#x27;re wanting shit fixed. You pay for it (based on usage) or GTFO. Should solve all of the current issues around this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theoldgreybeard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The vulnerability in question is a Use After Free.  Google used AI to find this bug, it would&amp;#x27;ve taken them 3 seconds to fix it.&lt;p&gt;Burning cash to generate spam bug reports to burden volunteer projects when you have the extra cash to burn to just fix the damn issue leaves a very sour taste in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fully on FFmpeg team side, many companies approach to FOSS is only doing so when it sounds good on their marketing karma, leech otherwise.&lt;p&gt;Most of them would just pirate in the old days, and most FOSS licences give them clear conscience to behave as always.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phkahler:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From TFA this was telling:&lt;p&gt;Thus, as Mark Atwood, an open source policy expert, pointed out on Twitter, he had to keep telling Amazon to not do things that would mess up FFmpeg because, he had to keep explaining to his bosses that “They are not a vendor, there is no NDA, we have no leverage, your VP has refused to help fund them, and they could kill three major product lines tomorrow with an email. So, stop, and listen to me … ”&lt;p&gt;I agree with the headline here. If Google can pay someone to find bugs, they can pay someone to fix them. How many time have managers said &amp;quot;Don&amp;#x27;t come to me with problems, come with solutions&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;warmwaffles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just mark CVEs as bugs and get to them when you can. In this case, if Google doesn&amp;#x27;t like it, then so be it. It&amp;#x27;ll get fixed eventually. Don&amp;#x27;t like how long it takes? Pay someone to contribute back. Until then, hurry up and wait.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;justahuman74:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does Google seriously not have a whole team of people who help maintain ffmpeg?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeepYogurt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We&amp;#x27;re well past the point that any serious security team should be able to submit a fix along with a bug report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;benced:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is dumb. Obscurity doesn’t create security. It’s unfortunate if ffmpeg doesn’t have the money to fix reported bugs but that doesn’t mean they should be ignorant of them. I don’t see any entitlement out of Google either - I expected this article would have a GH issue thread with a whiny YouTube engineer yelling at maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prewett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;They could shut down three product lines with an email&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If you (Amazon, in this case) can put it that way, it seems like throwing them 10 or 20 thousand a year would simply be a good insurance policy! Any benefits you might get in goodwill and influence are a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;woodruffw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m an open source maintainer, so I empathize with the sentiment that large companies &lt;i&gt;appear&lt;/i&gt; to produce labor for unpaid maintainers by disclosing security issues. But &lt;i&gt;appearance&lt;/i&gt; is operative: a security issue is something that I (as the maintainer) would need to fix regardless of who reports it, or would otherwise need to accept the reputational hit that comes with not triaging security reports. That’s sometimes perfectly fine (it’s okay for projects to decide that security isn’t a priority!), but you can’t have it both ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;profsummergig:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A bunch of people who make era-defining software for free. A labor of love.&lt;p&gt;Another bunch of people who make era-defining software where they extract everything they can. From customers, transactionally. From the first bunch, pure extraction (slavery, anyone?).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chemotaxis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am fairly confident that this article is largely AI-generated. More generally, the whole site appears to be heavy on AI slop, e.g.: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thenewstack.io&amp;#x2F;how-ai-is-pushing-kubernetes-storage-beyond-its-limits&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thenewstack.io&amp;#x2F;how-ai-is-pushing-kubernetes-storage-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And maybe it&amp;#x27;s fine to have AI-generated articles that summarize Twitter threads for HN, but this is not a good summarization of the discussion that unfolded in the wake of this complaint. For one, it doesn&amp;#x27;t mention a reply from Google security, which you would think should be pretty relevant here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ranger_danger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wouldn&amp;#x27;t they just fork it, fix their own bugs and stop contributing at all?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JamesBarney:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I get the idea of publicly disclosing security issues to large well funded companies that need to be incentivized to fix them. But I think open source has a good argument that in terms of risk reward tradeoff, publicly disclosing these for small resource constrained open source project probably creates a lot more risk than reward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thenewstack.io/ffmpeg-to-google-fund-us-or-stop-sending-bugs/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891016</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Pelican on a Bicycle</title>
      <link>https://www.robert-glaser.de/agentic-pelican-on-a-bicycle/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Models running in a loop using tools. Sometimes they have vision capabilities, too. What if they could see their own output and self-correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891817"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.robert-glaser.de/agentic-pelican-on-a-bicycle/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.robert-glaser.de/agentic-pelican-on-a-bicycle/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891817</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
