<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 01:53:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Britney Spears' Guide to Semiconductor Physics</title>
      <link>https://britneyspears.ac/lasers.htm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a little known fact, that Ms Spears is an expert in semiconductor physics. com Physics is a website for students of physics with sections on: mechanics, optics, electricity and magnetism, thermodynamics, nuclear physics and cosmology. If you are passionate about physics and would like to collaborate in this project, by writing content then please contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949326"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://britneyspears.ac/lasers.htm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chris_wot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There used to be a series of network posts by the &amp;quot;Router God&amp;quot;. They went missing, and someone resurrected a bunch of them. Sadly, the article &amp;quot;7 of 9 on OSPF&amp;quot; has left us for good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leeoniya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;oh, good.&lt;p&gt;no longer will i have to settle for learning Quantum Physics from Kim Kardashian [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;old.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;funny&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;6a5mf7&amp;#x2F;whats_less_believable_that_kim_kardashian_would&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;old.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;funny&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;6a5mf7&amp;#x2F;whats_less_be...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AlbertoGP:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Around the time this website was made, I was building an application for a big company in Spain that was to run as a Java applet and required the code to be signed.&lt;p&gt;They did not yet have their own certificates so I had to make my own CA during testing and sign the code, and I wanted to make sure that they did not forget to switch to their certificates later, so instead of signing the code with my name which some bureaucrat might decide to not bother changing, the code was signed by Britney Spears.&lt;p&gt;They noticed it, got the joke and made sure to switch certificates for the release. Everything went well thanks to Britney.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AdmiralAsshat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile Dolph Lundgren has an actual MA in Chemical Engineering. It&amp;#x27;s a pity we can&amp;#x27;t get him to do something like this in earnest to teach engineering concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSR_FDED:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was crushed when I saw the site needed Flash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;opan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The picture on the front page reminds me of the Why&amp;#x27;s Poignant guide to Ruby, specifically it had a picture of a baby shouting some Ruby code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andy99:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Coincidentally I was just looking for this picture yesterday &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;britneyspears.ac&amp;#x2F;wallpaper&amp;#x2F;bswp005_800x600.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;britneyspears.ac&amp;#x2F;wallpaper&amp;#x2F;bswp005_800x600.htm&lt;/a&gt; (the one absent Britney, but this did cross my mind)&lt;p&gt;I remember this, presumably from slashdot 20,years ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gnabgib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(2000) Popular in:&lt;p&gt;2023 (37 points, 7 comments) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=35763307"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=35763307&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021 (168 points, 112 comments) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=25626532"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=25626532&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016 (94 points, 31 comments) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10872658"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10872658&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;philipwhiuk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Author briefly&amp;#x2F;currently worked in SEO as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t see much connection here between miss BS and semiconductor physics.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s just a physics book that happens to have pictures of the popstar in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://britneyspears.ac/lasers.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949326</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PicoIDE – An open IDE/ATAPI drive emulator</title>
      <link>https://picoide.com/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PicoIDE is a device that emulates IDE/ATAPI devices developed by Ian Scott, creator of PicoGUS. Fully open source firmware and hardware Emulates ATAPI CD-ROM and IDE fixed hard drives. iso image support for CD-ROM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949352"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://picoide.com/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trevithick:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is really cool. I&amp;#x27;m glad people are out there making this stuff even if I&amp;#x27;ll never have a use for it.&lt;p&gt;What are the use cases for this? I&amp;#x27;m guessing retro computing and possibly very old machines tied to very obsolete hardware that can&amp;#x27;t be virtualized (e.g. manufacturing controls).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://picoide.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949352</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Your Brain Creates 'Aha' Moments and Why They Stick</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-your-brain-creates-aha-moments-and-why-they-stick-20251105/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Home How Your Brain Creates ‘Aha’ Moments and Why They Stick Comment Save Article Read Later Share Facebook Copied. Click to reveal To induce moments of insight in the lab, researchers used Mooney images, which have their contrast turned up to obscure the pictured object. Can you identify the object in this Mooney image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948792"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-your-brain-creates-aha-moments-and-why-they-stick-20251105/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;650:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[Spoiler]
Here are three words: pine, crab, sauce. There’s a fourth word that combines with each of the others to create another common word. What is it?&lt;p&gt;YXBwbGU= (Use Base64 Decoding)
[&amp;#x2F;Spoiler]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;corysama:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Hare Brain Tortoise Mind&amp;quot; is a great book that goes into how this works and how to work with&amp;#x2F;against it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=aB_4YU6UtCw" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=aB_4YU6UtCw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;tldr: There is a background, non-verbal process in your brain that has the advantage of a larger working set size than your foreground verbal thinking. It is able to observe and consider more stuff at once and find associations better than your conscious thought process.&lt;p&gt;But, it has several disadvantages. It takes time to do its processing. You can&amp;#x27;t will it into action. It communicates non-verbally with your foreground process. It doesn&amp;#x27;t work under pressure (thus the need for relaxed, unfocused time). The non-verbal understanding is difficult to deconstruct, generalize and reapply. It can lead to you solving a problem, not understanding how and not being able to solve a variant of the same problem.&lt;p&gt;So, the general recommendation is: If you have a complex problem to solve, first absorb as much information about the problem as your brain can hold. But, do not try to solve anything. Then, go take a break. A walk in a natural environment is preferable. Don’t think about the problem. Relax in a low stress environment. Let your background brain have a chance to chew on it and maybe bubble up some suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pureliquidhw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Off topic but of all the Mooney images ever made, why a scary clown?&lt;p&gt;That aside, working with complex systems and constraints there often isn&amp;#x27;t an aha moment, there&amp;#x27;s just a decision to be made. As someone who loves that aha moment, I can get stuck trying to figure out perfect from good enough. Interesting to see there is indeed a positive emotion correlated with that aha moment that keeps people searching for solutions.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if there&amp;#x27;s a correlation between addiction and this aha moment. Like you get drunk and suddenly &amp;quot;aha!&amp;quot; those big unresolvable problems don&amp;#x27;t matter. The next morning they matter again until, aha, beer:30 hits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.quantamagazine.org/how-your-brain-creates-aha-moments-and-why-they-stick-20251105/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 21:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948792</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new chapter begins for EV batteries with the expiry of key LFP patents</title>
      <link>https://www.shoosmiths.com/insights/articles/a-new-chapter-begins-for-ev-batteries-with-the-expiry-of-key-lfp-patents</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Limited) has developed and commercialised cell-to-pack technology with its Quilin battery. Such proprietary engineering technology will still deliver competitive advantage. Share this page Share via:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949655"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.shoosmiths.com/insights/articles/a-new-chapter-begins-for-ev-batteries-with-the-expiry-of-key-lfp-patents'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cyberax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What? Patents have been a non-issue for LFP batteries, and the original LFP patents are almost useless today. All the new advances that made LFPs competitive are still well-protected by patents, for at least another decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.shoosmiths.com/insights/articles/a-new-chapter-begins-for-ev-batteries-with-the-expiry-of-key-lfp-patents</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949655</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goldman Sachs asks in biotech Report: Is curing patients a sustainable business?</title>
      <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/11/goldman-asks-is-curing-patients-a-sustainable-business-model.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;"Is curing patients a sustainable business model. sales for these hepatitis C treatments peaked at $12. sales for these treatments will be less than $4 billion this year, according to a table in the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949247"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/11/goldman-asks-is-curing-patients-a-sustainable-business-model.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 19 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shruubi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The problem with investors these days is that too many of them seem so focused on short-term gains and showing their numbers increase quarter-over-quarter that we seem to be incapable of looking at an investment over a longer period of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;missedthecue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Of course it&amp;#x27;s sustainable. Gilead Sciences is a $155B company originally built on a single drug (Sovaldi) that literally cures Hepatitis C. Now they are more diversified and have a stacked pipeline. The business model just changes to one like oil or mining exploration where you find a deposit with a limited lifespan and you have to keep the treadmill going to find new ones before the mother lode that funds your firm is all tapped out and you go bust.&lt;p&gt;But while it makes for amazing ragebait and threads full of grievances aired against the healthcare system in general, I think the question isn&amp;#x27;t very relevant because in Biotech, this is dynamic already essentially forced, cure or not, because of *patent life*. A perfect example of this is Lipitor and Pfizer. Lipitor was not a cure. Statins do not cure you. But it was the most profitable drug of all time. But it eventually went off-patent and now the average price on GoodRX for a 30 day supply is only $6. Pfizer stock has never recovered from that success, though they certainly have a sustainable business.&lt;p&gt;The modern-day Pfizer is Merck. Merck has probably the most profitable drug in world history (Keytruda) which is far more profitable than Lipitor, and which has massively increased remission rates for a wide range of cancers, so it&amp;#x27;s somewhat of a cure as well. But that patent life is about to expire, and 46% of Mercks revenue will disappear with it. Of course, new people are diagnosed with cancer every day, and Keytruda will continue to be prescribed in the millions, but Teva and others will sell the generic version and Merck will lose out on the revenue. So the race is on to get more things through their pipeline, acquire some promising assets, and keep the treadmill going. There are 100+ year old mining and oil companies. None are mining the same asset they had one day one, but this doesn&amp;#x27;t make the industry unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trashface:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakub_g:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Previously:&lt;p&gt;2018: 448 points, 370 comments &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=16827248"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=16827248&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021: 104 points, 100 comments &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=27184116"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=27184116&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tptacek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We get threads about this on HN a couple times a year, and I feel like people have never thought this through. The company that cures T1D or MS will make approximately eleventy jillion dollars. The mustache-twirlers engineering MS into a chronic manageable disease rather than curing it would simply be outcompeted and put out of business by the straight-mustached cure owners. If you believe the mustache-twirlers are capable of &lt;i&gt;suppressing knowledge of a viable cure&lt;/i&gt;, I&amp;#x27;m going to have fun selling you on a lot of more-plausible conspiracy theories; for instance, the faked moon landing, which would have required less collusion and been less impactful to the world.&lt;p&gt;In a strict sense, curing a single disease isn&amp;#x27;t a &lt;i&gt;long term&lt;/i&gt; &amp;quot;sustainable business&amp;quot;, because you&amp;#x27;ll eventually push the population of affected patients below a threshold of profitability. The premise of a major pharma company is that they keep finding other treatments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;garyfirestorm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe the insurance should pay substantial amount for drugs&amp;#x2F;treatment AFTER the patient is cured completely&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Of course it&amp;#x27;s sustainable. It is just not a very good businessmodel compared to some other (cynical) options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spankibalt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Is curing patients a sustainable business?&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The question is: If a capitalist (or agent in a capitalist system) has a choice between a) investing to produce&amp;#x2F;producing a cure, or b) investing to produce&amp;#x2F;producing a more-or-less working symptomatic relief, how many agents&amp;#x2F;capitalists (in decision-making positions) go for choice B, which essentially turns them into legal drug pushers with a money-printing license?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stego-tech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel kinda bad for the writer, because it&amp;#x27;s a good question: no, curing patients is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a good business model, just like public transit is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a good business model.&lt;p&gt;What a lot of folks neglect are N+1-order effects, because those are harder to quantify and fail to reach the predetermined decision some executive or board or shareholder has already made.  Is curing patients a bad business model? Sure, for the biotech company it is, but those cured patients are far more likely to go on living longer, healthier lives, and in turn contribute additional value to society - which will impact others in ways that may also create additional value.  That doesn&amp;#x27;t even get into the jobs and value created through the R&amp;amp;D process, testing, manufacturing, logistics of delivery, ongoing monitoring, etc.  As long as the value created is more than the cost of the treatment, then it&amp;#x27;s a net-gain for the economy even if it&amp;#x27;s a net loss for that singular business.&lt;p&gt;If all you&amp;#x27;re judging is the first-order impacts on a single business, you&amp;#x27;re missing the forest for the trees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwup238:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That questions belies a misunderstanding of how the pharmaceutical industry works and I&amp;#x27;m having a hard time figuring out if the journalist made a mistake or the report was written by someone with little experience in the industry (I haven&amp;#x27;t read it).&lt;p&gt;Since we&amp;#x27;ve mostly run out of small molecule drugs, the (vast?) majority of drugs are developed outside the pharmaceutical industry by biotechs funded by VCs and public investors. It&amp;#x27;s a well understood pipeline now that takes IP from university tech transfer to VC biotech to pre-revenue* IPO with the final exit being an acquisition by a pharmaceutical company, which comes in with the manufacturing infrastructure to take the drug from phase III trials or approval to the mass market. Once a drug is approved (or the phase III is very promising like Sofosbuvir), pharmaceutical companies trip over each other trying to buy the IP. The industry has offloaded most of the scientific risk to VCs and the public while sharing the rewards with those investors.&lt;p&gt;As long as the number of pharmaceutical companies doesn&amp;#x27;t drop to oligopoly&amp;#x2F;cartel levels and capture the regulators completely, the incentives are strong for one pharmaceutical company to buy a cure and take it to market to undercut a competitor&amp;#x27;s treatment. Even if an oligopoly develops, since there&amp;#x27;s no &amp;quot;product market fit&amp;quot; risk and zero scientific risk once a drug is approved, financing the purchase is trivial and starting a new pharmaceutical company to compete with the oligopoly is relatively easy. The manufacturing bit is no joke but the amount of money involved even with a single drug makes starting up a new pharmaceutical competitor totally worth it, since the manufacturing and quality control is a well understood engineering problem.&lt;p&gt;On top of that, it&amp;#x27;s practically impossible for every pharmaceutical company to have a drug that treats the same thing without a ton of consolidation in the market. Drug approvals often use active-comparators and standard of care controls that raise the bar for each new drug on the market that treats the same thing. A cure on the other hand is essentially just competing against a single golden standard (there are many exceptions but it&amp;#x27;s a good rule of thumb).&lt;p&gt;Another factor is pricing. Treatments are generally priced based on how they impact quality of life because that decides how much insurers are willing to pay, especially the big state healthcare providers that have to do hard cost benefit calculations. If a treatment is making bank, the ceiling for what you can charge for a cure is a significant fraction of the lifetime cost of the treatment, and not just based on the QOL impact. It creates a strong incentive for both investors and insurers to get the cure to market.&lt;p&gt;* If you think unprofitable tech IPOs are bad, most biotechs that IPO do so with &lt;i&gt;zero&lt;/i&gt; revenue, let alone profit. Usually to fund clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unyttigfjelltol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The analyst is stuck in the past. Genomic solutions are &lt;i&gt;personalized&lt;/i&gt; medicine. As long as there are new people, and new combinations of genes, there will be problems to solve.&lt;p&gt;Grow up Goldman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mensetmanusman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is for startups that can absorb billions then close their doors.&lt;p&gt;It’s not sustainable for businesses who rely on sickness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jjmarr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The suggestions on making sustainable cures:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    “Solution 1: Address large markets: Hemophilia is a $9-10bn WW market (hemophilia A, B), growing at ~6-7% annually.”

    “Solution 2: Address disorders with high incidence: Spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) affects the cells (neurons) in the spinal cord, impacting the ability to walk, eat, or breathe.”

    “Solution 3: Constant innovation and portfolio expansion: There are hundreds of inherited retinal diseases (genetics forms of blindness) … Pace of innovation will also play a role as future programs can offset the declining revenue trajectory of prior assets.”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
It&amp;#x27;s easy to handwave &amp;quot;capitalism makes curing patients unsustainable&amp;quot; but here we have three strategies for sustainable cures that have a positive impact on society.&lt;p&gt;e.g. Curing blind children is profitable, since there&amp;#x27;s so many genetic reasons a child would be blind that you can keep introducing new cures reapplying the same technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;puppycodes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;socialized healthcare please and thank you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snowwrestler:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It doesn’t matter if it is a sustainable business. People will do what they can to maximize their income now. If 10 companies are withholding a cure to milk the patients, any one of them can break from that strategy at any time, with near-instant financial reward and competitive advantage. It is not a stable equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;egypturnash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile over in the world where the government sinks a lot of money and energy into its citizen&amp;#x27;s healthcare, government-funded labs are exploring permanent cures for all &lt;i&gt;kinds&lt;/i&gt; of problems via genetic therapy.&lt;p&gt;But not here. Someone&amp;#x27;s gotta make &lt;i&gt;mad bank&lt;/i&gt; off of every aspect of this shit here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A_D_E_P_T:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The report-writer must have been from Goldman Sachs&amp;#x27; B-team.  It takes five minutes to turn up ample evidence which demonstrates that curing patients can be extremely profitable.&lt;p&gt;Take, for instance, Harvoni -- a drug introduced in late 2014 which cures Hepatitis C following a single course of treatment.  It has done something like $100B in revenue for Gilead Biosciences, and, minimally, earned them $7-10B in profit.  (Possibly much more than that.)  Its pricing was scandalous, but that&amp;#x27;s not the issue here; the point is that it was unequivocally one of the most profitable drug launches in history.&lt;p&gt;Sure, the eradication of Hep C might make it &amp;quot;unsustainable&amp;quot; -- but it&amp;#x27;s not as though there&amp;#x27;s a lack of other diseases or maladies to contend with.  Take the profits and plant new seeds, buy new technologies, develop new drugs.  Besides, the research and development of new drugs has never been a stable business model, and never truly sustainable off one discovery, on account of patent expiry terms, generic competition, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;doublerabbit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No not really. Just allow euthanasia and be done with it. Yes. there are moral grounds to it. You don&amp;#x27;t want to live life, why can&amp;#x27;t you just do it peacefully?&lt;p&gt;I barely want to live another day of life at the age of 36 :&amp;#x2F;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moelf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(2018)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/11/goldman-asks-is-curing-patients-a-sustainable-business-model.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949247</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why your mock breaks later</title>
      <link>https://nedbatchelder.com/blog/202511/why_your_mock_breaks_later.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;mock import patch@patch("builtins. When that happens, coverage. py that could trip over this mock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949102"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://nedbatchelder.com/blog/202511/why_your_mock_breaks_later.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dherls:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This blog post talks as if mocking the `open` function is a good thing that people should be told how to do. If you are mocking anything in the standard library your code is probably structured poorly.&lt;p&gt;In the example the author walks through, a cleaner way would be to have the second function take the Options as a parameter and decouple those two functions. You can then test both in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lelandbatey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel like the #1 reason mocks break looks nothing like this and instead looks like: you change the internal behaviors of a function&amp;#x2F;method and now the mocks interact differently with the underlying code, forcing you to change the mocks. Which highlights how awful mocking as a concept is; it is of truly limited usefulness for anything but the most brittle of tests.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t test the wrong things; if you care about some precondition, that should be an input. If you need to measure a side effect, that should be an output. Don&amp;#x27;t tweak global state to do your testing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kaashif:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why even mock anything in this example? You need to read the source code to work out what to mock, reaching deep inside the code to name some method to mock.&lt;p&gt;But what if you just passed in the contents of the file or something?&lt;p&gt;Edit: oh wait actually this is what the very last line in the blog post says! But I think it should be emphasized more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Izkata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In Why your mock doesn’t work I explained this rule of mocking:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Mock where the object is used, not where it’s defined.&lt;p&gt;For anyone looking for generic advice, this is a quirk of python due to how imports work in that language (details in the linked post) and shouldn&amp;#x27;t be considered universal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;esafak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is worth pointing out that you can often use containerized services as an alternative to mocking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gsnedders:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Arguably this is a problem in when the patch is unapplied.&lt;p&gt;Presumably in the coverage case it’s being called by a trace function, which inevitably runs during test execution — and while we want the trace function to be called during the test function, we really want it without any patches the test function is using. But this arguably requires both an ability for the trace function to opt-out of patches and for the patcher to provide a way to temporarily disable all of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nedbatchelder.com/blog/202511/why_your_mock_breaks_later.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 22:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949102</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
