<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Marko – A declarative, HTML‑based language that makes building web apps fun</title>
      <link>https://markojs.com/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marko streams content to your users as soon as it's ready. Marko compiles your templates to perform their best with optimized, environment-specific output. One seamless language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858905"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://markojs.com/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;promiseofbeans:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is actually quite cool - JS inside HTML, rather than the more React-y HTML inside JS.&lt;p&gt;As I understand it, Ryan Carniato was a major part of this project, and later went on to lead SolidJS, which goes back to the React style HTML in JS. Has he spoken at all about why he went back to that templating style?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nielsbot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe off topic, but I’d kill for a HAML for TSX or Svelte!&lt;p&gt;Working with HAML really did make building web app fun IMO. I can’t be the only one!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AbstractH24:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There’s some joke here about how that’s in contrast to Marketo…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hyperhello:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The problem when taking several languages and mixing them together this way is that the result is supposed to have brevity, but it’s actually unreadable. You need slash to mean something grammatical, colon has to say something, you can speak “open brace” in a way that anticipates; @ means “at”. This code looks more like a compression scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;croisillon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;previously:&lt;p&gt;January 2023, 125 comments - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=34591625"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=34591625&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 2017, 150 comments - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=15057371"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=15057371&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;February 2015, 10 comments - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=9065447"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=9065447&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Today is ${new Date().toDateString()}&amp;lt;&amp;#x2F;p&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Random number: ${Math.floor(Math.random() * 100)}&amp;lt;&amp;#x2F;p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Sorry, I don&amp;#x27;t like it. I already disliked that immensely in PHP. Not going back to that spaghetti mesh-up.&lt;p&gt;The intro is also incorrect in my opinion. It writes a &amp;quot;HTML-based language&amp;quot;, but this is more a hybrid of HTML and JavaScript. Why is JavaScript not mentioned in the intro?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://markojs.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858905</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WriterdeckOS</title>
      <link>https://writerdeckos.com</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installation will proceed automatically. Restart laptop and it will boot directly into Tilde word processor. To restart Tilde from the Command Line: Type tilde and press enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858945"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://writerdeckos.com'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aplc0r:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I don&amp;#x27;t have a use for this, I do like the idea of purposeful modes in computing. Obviously there is a lot you can do with shortcuts and preferences, but its nice to have a limited to base to start with.&lt;p&gt;I think this is even more important with a mobile platform since for one, battery and processing power is at a premium, and two anything with notifications could take you out of your desired &amp;quot;mode&amp;quot; if you don&amp;#x27;t wrangle them properly.&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;#x27;ve always wanted in a smartphone is to be able to boot into a &amp;quot;camera only&amp;quot; mode. There have been many times where all I need my phone for is as a camera, and I don&amp;#x27;t want it wasting resources&amp;#x2F;battery doing anything else. If this mode were light enough, it could boot up in the same amount of time as a normal digital camera, allowing your the phone to be truly off while you&amp;#x27;re not taking pictures. I do often take a digital camera with me, but sometimes I don&amp;#x27;t want the bulk or maybe I didn&amp;#x27;t initially plan to take a lot of pictures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kosolam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice idea, however, here is a satire piece about writing and writers which I find relevant in this context: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;medium.com&amp;#x2F;@Justwritet&amp;#x2F;you-are-not-a-real-writer-if-5eaa1ff9ca62" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;medium.com&amp;#x2F;@Justwritet&amp;#x2F;you-are-not-a-real-writer-if-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sebastianconcpt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No autosaving. That&amp;#x27;s the wrong way to try to be minimalist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pmarreck:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some of these options would have been way cooler than Tilde; perhaps it could provide alternate options too?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;terminaltrove.com&amp;#x2F;categories&amp;#x2F;text-editors&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;terminaltrove.com&amp;#x2F;categories&amp;#x2F;text-editors&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cosmic_cheese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The idea of a low-distraction laptop OS is a good one, but I&amp;#x27;m not sure that this is necessarily the best approach.&lt;p&gt;If I mentally model such a thing myself, I end up with something that looks a lot like Classic (pre-OS-X) Mac OS. It&amp;#x27;s simplified and has just enough presence to properly host graphical applications. No taskbar, no notifications (or associated drawer), no self-populated launcher menu. File manager is spatial so it doesn&amp;#x27;t need a sidebar or navigation chrome. Multitasking is technically possible, but high-friction since the only way to switch between running apps is the little app switcher menu in the top right corner and becomes more cumbersome the more apps&amp;#x2F;windows you open. Included browser does not support tabs, only windows. Shortcuts to frequently used apps must be added intentionally (to your desktop as aliases&amp;#x2F;shortcuts or to the launcher menu).&lt;p&gt;This design strongly encourages singular focus without forcing it. If you want to have music playing in the background or need to open a browser window for research you can, but gravity is constantly pulling you back towards your task since the machine isn&amp;#x27;t pleasant to use for goofing off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had a good laugh. Why does anyone want this? Put Linux on your laptop and nuke the network stack. Done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teddyh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For those who prefer Emacs over tilde:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  startx emacs --maximized --funcall=darkroom-mode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jchw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is my first time hearing of the &amp;quot;WriterDeck&amp;quot; concept, so it&amp;#x27;s very possible that I am missing some context, but... While booting to text requires less work and less packages, it seems like it has a lot of caveats. Firstly, it will likely be unreadable on any laptop that has a high resolution screen, and frankly even some old cheap laptops have one at this point, at least 1.5x~ish-scale DPI. Secondly, obviously better typography can be done in a graphical user interface, which seems like something you&amp;#x27;d want if you&amp;#x27;re going to be writing on something. Thirdly, while the utter lack of distractions is admirable, this will also lack even the most crucial features and information. For example, I don&amp;#x27;t think you will even realize if your battery is about to die, which seems like it is a good way to accidentally lose a bunch of work. Battery state is probably the only thing that I really think it &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; show you.&lt;p&gt;It would definitely take a bit more work but a tiny dedicated graphical environment that functions as a basic text editor seems like it could go further. No particular need for Wayland or X11 here, either; you could get away with a simple Qt application directly on KMS&amp;#x2F;DRM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;digilypse:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Closing your laptop can also provide a clean, portable writing platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TeaVMFan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like the idea of a distraction-free writing environment.&lt;p&gt;However, when I&amp;#x27;m writing, I find I sometimes need to do research.  I suppose for the best writing flow I should block time for research and time for pure writing.  However, if I discover I need to look something up, a hard block on internet access would be a problem.  Of course it&amp;#x27;s a slippery slope from researching something on Wikipedia to navigating to related articles.  Timed access per hour?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dingnuts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;a single fucking screenshot would go a long way to convincing me this is real. considering I lost an hour yesterday trying to use an open source library that turned out to be vibe coded non-functional slop, I have to ask for evidence that the project is real and functional be presented front and center&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://writerdeckos.com</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858945</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avería: The Average Font (2011)</title>
      <link>http://iotic.com/averia/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I later realised that each font has a ‘baseline’ defined, and an origin on that baseline which each glyph is drawn relative to. I was quite pleased with the results. Perhaps there was a simpler idea that was evading me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859243"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://iotic.com/averia/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;peter-m80:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Btw, &amp;quot;Avería&amp;quot; means &amp;quot;failure&amp;quot; in spanish&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JoshTriplett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an experiment from 2011 in which the author produced a font by averaging all the fonts on their system.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m reposting it here because I noticed that this looks a lot like the uncanny valley produced when an image AI tries to make text, which makes perfect sense: it&amp;#x27;s a statistical average of fonts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iotic.com/averia/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859243</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook enables gender discrimination in job ads, European human rights rules</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/28/tech/facebook-gender-discrimination-europe-ruling-asequals-intl</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Netherlands Institute for Human Rights has ruled that Meta engaged in gender-based discrimination via its algorithm that promoted job advertisements. The Netherlands Institute for Human Rights said in its February ruling that Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd. The Institute’s ruling added that “Meta Ireland has acknowledged that the gender data point can be part of the algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859160"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/28/tech/facebook-gender-discrimination-europe-ruling-asequals-intl'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jl6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Are these ads in the sense of unsolicited adverts, or is this some kind of job search engine where people are actively asking Facebook to find a job for them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JuniperMesos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The Netherlands Institute for Human Rights said in a February 18 decision that Facebook’s algorithm reinforced gender stereotypes by mainly showing “typically female professions” to female Facebook users in the Netherlands and that Meta (META), the social platform’s owner, should have monitored and adjusted its algorithm to prevent that.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; For example, ads for mechanic positions were predominantly shown to men, while those for preschool teacher roles were primarily directed to women. Global Witness said its experiments in the Netherlands, France, India, Ireland, the United Kingdom and South Africa demonstrated that the algorithm perpetuated similar biases around the world. The non-profit’s investigation led to four complaints from the Dutch human rights group Bureau Clara Wichmann and the French organization Fondation des Femmes.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think any of this should be illegal. I don&amp;#x27;t think anyone is meaningfully harmed by being algorithmically shown job ads stereotypical of one gender rather than another, and I have no problem with any organization at all that does this, whether it&amp;#x27;s Meta or anyone else. I do not agree with the position of any of these European human rights organizations, and I&amp;#x27;d probably be in favor of reforming French anti-discrimination law to explicitly legalize what Meta is doing here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Title is incorrect: human rights body&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/02/28/tech/facebook-gender-discrimination-europe-ruling-asequals-intl</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859160</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Near mid-air collision at LAX between American Airlines and ITA [video]</title>
      <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-j76cp7bETw</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-j76cp7bETw</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859216</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humans have remote touch 'seventh sense' like sandpipers</title>
      <link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-humans-remote-seventh-sandpipers.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Credit: Queen Mary University of London A study by researchers at Queen Mary University of London and University College London has found that humans have a form of remote touch, or the ability to sense objects without direct contact, a sense that some animals have. Do humans or robots perform better on remote touch. These findings confirm that people can genuinely sense an object before physical contact, a surprising capacity for a sense that is usually concerned with objects that enter in direct contact with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859928"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-humans-remote-seventh-sandpipers.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://techxplore.com/news/2025-11-humans-remote-seventh-sandpipers.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859928</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Forcing LLM Features</title>
      <link>https://equk.co.uk/2025/10/28/firefox-forcing-llm-features/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;enable", false); user_pref("browser. enabled", false); user_pref("browser. page", false); user_pref("browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858959"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://equk.co.uk/2025/10/28/firefox-forcing-llm-features/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dathinab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;sure the smart tab group features are kind useless (but tab groups are grate)&lt;p&gt;but I don&amp;#x27;t understand why people make such a deal about it&lt;p&gt;it looks a loot like &amp;quot;I don&amp;#x27;t like this so it mustn&amp;#x27;t even exist even if some people like it&amp;quot; mentality&lt;p&gt;like&lt;p&gt;- all of this features are opt in, they don&amp;#x27;t just randomly send your data somewhere or randomly eat your CPI resources (without you having enabled them)&lt;p&gt;- the smart tab group features(1) are the only very visible and kind dump&amp;#x2F;useless one, and you can disable them without tweaking internal configs unser &amp;quot;Addons &amp;gt; On-device AI&amp;quot; (but it won&amp;#x27;t disable the button in the group tabs menu which is used to enable that feature in the first place)&lt;p&gt;- for many users side translations is an important must have feature, it&amp;#x27;s one of the AI features, and having a local on-device no data send to servers translation is very desirable (to be fair US users probably don&amp;#x27;t care nor realize it matters, but it really matters) (To be fair the OP didn&amp;#x27;t disable this either)&lt;p&gt;- for increasingly many users integration with chat bots (e.g. ChatGPT) is a must have browser feature(2). The integration is also only visible in a context menu(3) and hidden in the a selector for the side bar and needs to be explicitly setup before it does anything. So a feature some people want and treat as must have and now can have and for everyone else it&amp;#x27;s pretty much out of the way and not pushed onto you at all. So why insists that it&amp;#x27;s not okay to have it even in a selector hardly any power users will ever use (because the other options there are bookmarks, and history, both with well known widely used keyboard shortcuts)&lt;p&gt;- the preview was a &amp;quot;Labs&amp;quot; (i.e. experimental preview) feature you have to explicitly enable and then use the right hot key to use, and it&amp;#x27;s one of this &amp;quot;some people expect this feature in 2025&amp;quot; features (but not sure what happened to it, it&amp;#x27;s neither in Labs nor enabled in any FF browser I have, so maybe they discontinued it)&lt;p&gt;(1): They IMHO are pretty dump and seem more like a way to setup the whole infrastructure around them with a trivial to implement feature then a in depth feature mozilla cares about. I guess.&lt;p&gt;(2): On HN it often seems like only enthusiasts and not many non-tech people use ChatGPT and co. _That is not true at all_. When it comes to &amp;quot;simple&amp;quot; ChatGPT usage far more non technical users use it then technical one. Like for dump stuff like shopping list, holiday check lists, etc. The problem OpenAI has isn&amp;#x27;t that they don&amp;#x27;t have a lot of users, it&amp;#x27;s that they need a absurd amount of high paying users. But the tasks most non-tech people use generic ChatGPT for aren&amp;#x27;t worth a lot. Like even the Plus plan is a &amp;quot;only if you are wealthy enough to burn 20 bucks every month without caring&amp;quot; option in such a context and the Pro plan just absurd.&lt;p&gt;(3): Is anyone except non technical users still using browsers context menus in a way where a &amp;quot;Ask AI Chat-Bot&amp;quot; entry matters???? Like copy, past, undo, redo, select all have trivial short cuts. Language&amp;#x2F;spell check is rarely touched and inspect has a short cut where you press Q after right clicking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;metalman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;deleated from most recent linux install on a new to me desktop.
vile
I just want to work(create stuff), there is nothing that any &amp;quot;service&amp;quot; can do for me.
the relentles attempts to get in the way of sending and recieving information is mindbogling, and I am going to be getting an analog telephone adapter, so that I can start useing fax, over cellular data, and making paper plans ,taking pictures, and converting to pdf&amp;#x27;s to avoid the wasted time and cost of software solutions
the surreal part is that the LLM&amp;#x27;s have found me, and are recomending me to people looking for custom metal, so much for a low profile there, and somehow my number got out on indeed, and I got a wave of people calling, applying for &amp;quot;the job&amp;quot; but bitterly complaining that the app they downloaded as part of that, wasn&amp;#x27;t working right.
fine, ok, whatever.&lt;p&gt;but not on my machine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;evolving-silica:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure if I ever used any LLM features from Firefox besides exploring, but so far it seems great they&amp;#x27;re trying local approach instead of sending it to some &amp;quot;partner&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;In the comment section here I see lot of people complaining about the fact it&amp;#x27;s enabled by default as well as some concerns about resource usage. Could someone experienced in desktop app architecture explain if disabling them functionalities makes Firefox that much faster or using less resouces? I&amp;#x27;d assume that those functionalities are kind of loaded on demand?&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; became such a keyword that seem to instantly give either positive or negative response, it&amp;#x27;s also an advertised feature of every second app with many of them just forcing AI into you just because of hype. This doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be a case in Firefox - so I highly disagree with the title - the features are there but they don&amp;#x27;t go into your way if you don&amp;#x27;t want them, therefore it&amp;#x27;s easy to just use it, only when needed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;marginalia_nu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mozilla seems to be an organization that is metrics driven to a degree that would make Robert MacNamarra blush.&lt;p&gt;I think this is why they keep shoving new features at users whether they want them or not, making them incredibly difficult to disable, rather than presenting an option try something new, or even making opting out of features easy and intuitive.&lt;p&gt;The latter two would lead to fewer users of the feature, which means it risks being removed for not being used by most users.  Not to mention having an easy opt-out functionality means its usage can be tracked, which could generate unwanted statistics and make a stakeholder lose face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pessimizer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s important to remember that if people think of Firefox as a way to escape LLMs being pushed on them in Chrome, they might accidentally attract users from Chrome. It&amp;#x27;s the only possible reason why this wouldn&amp;#x27;t be a plugin. Why else would a user-focused browser consciously come up with strategies that attack user preferences?&lt;p&gt;You just don&amp;#x27;t understand the eleven-dimensional chess that you have to play to get from 30% marketshare to 2% marketshare. They have to think they have a winning strategy, judging by the way they talk to everybody who criticizes their decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bitsig:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For people using NixOS, you can wrap these configs in extraPrefs in wrapFirefox firefox-unwrapped:&lt;p&gt;Example:
Put this expression(using lockPref to hardcode the config values) in environment.systemPackages(assuming &amp;quot;with pkgs&amp;quot;):&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  (wrapFirefox firefox-unwrapped {

        extraPrefs =
        (
          &amp;#x27;&amp;#x27;
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.enable&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.enabled&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.hideFromLabs&amp;quot;, true);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.hideLabsShortcuts&amp;quot;, true);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.page&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.page.footerBadge&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.page.menuBadge&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.chat.menu&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.linkPreview.enabled&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.ml.pageAssist.enabled&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.tabs.groups.smart.enabled&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;browser.tabs.groups.smart.userEnable&amp;quot;, false);
          lockPref(&amp;quot;extensions.ml.enabled&amp;quot;, false);
          &amp;#x27;&amp;#x27;
        );

      })&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qwertox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is this all about? Where would I find any of these LLM features? What do they even do?&lt;p&gt;When I go to about:config and enter &amp;quot;browser.lm&amp;quot;, there&amp;#x27;s nothing displayed. That&amp;#x27;s on the latest 144.0.2 release.&lt;p&gt;Is any of it somehow related to this? &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.heise.de&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;One-API-for-all-Mozilla-ends-LLM-chaos-11069204.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.heise.de&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;One-API-for-all-Mozilla-ends-LL...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delduca:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Firefox for Windows now have a button “Talk to OpenAI”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;threeducks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think that (optional) AI features are fine, but the model selection only shows the big providers by default. You can enable local LLM support under about:config -&amp;gt; browser.ml.chat.hideLocalhost (set to false). It will check localhost:8080, which is not a great choice for a fixed port. I&amp;#x27;d prefer if I could just point it at any OpenAI-compatible endpoint. Either way, seems to work well when serving a local model with llama.cpp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wondering how these chatbot links in the sidebar are any different from bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve found the &amp;quot;Copy text from image&amp;quot; menu command to be useful from time to time, and the features I&amp;#x27;m not interested in seemed easy to turn off&amp;#x2F;dismiss&amp;#x2F;ignore?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eahm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sharing my configs, hopefully they&amp;#x27;ll be helpful to someone. I don&amp;#x27;t even use Firefox but I keep the settings updated (prefs.js can be modified by Mozilla&amp;#x2F;Firefox, user.js does not change).&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Some settings might block too much, edit and use as you please.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rentry.co&amp;#x2F;browserconfigs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rentry.co&amp;#x2F;browserconfigs&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rentry.org&amp;#x2F;browserconfigs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rentry.org&amp;#x2F;browserconfigs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nerevarthelame:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Honestly, I haven&amp;#x27;t even noticed LLM features in the desktop version. But I found it really annoying in the mobile (iOS) app. There&amp;#x27;s a &amp;quot;Summarize Page&amp;quot; feature that&amp;#x27;s adjacent to &amp;quot;Find in Page.&amp;quot; It&amp;#x27;s easy to mis-tap when you&amp;#x27;re just trying to search for a term on the page. It&amp;#x27;s also activated by the shake gesture, which can happen accidentally.&lt;p&gt;Three dots -&amp;gt; Settings -&amp;gt; Page Summaries to disable that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;f33d5173:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;I would think most non technical users would just use a different browser.&lt;p&gt;I would think most users would ignore the features they don&amp;#x27;t like? Idgi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;impossiblefork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As long as it&amp;#x27;s local I think it&amp;#x27;s okay.&lt;p&gt;I also think that we in the long run will probably let machines do most tedious browsing for us-- digesting ad-ridden websites, digesting interfaces. The LLM navigates the actual web, presented to maximize revenue and maximize user engagement, time spent on the website etc., but we only see actual content, carefully arranged to be as comprehensible as possible, and if we want to communicate with somebody through a website controlled by others we formulate the message and the LLM submits it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lerc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This should not be considered an LLM issue. It&amp;#x27;s a user experience issue.&lt;p&gt;Mozilla has made changes that happened by default before.  Often I have had to find the setting to put it back to how I wanted.  I remember when it moved the URL bar to the bottom.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think it is always an easy call to make.  Tabs were a significant user experience improvement, but hiding it behind an opt-in would have limited it to people who knew about it.&lt;p&gt;I use Firefox as main on desktop and mobile.  I have noticed messages on upgrade pointing to LLM features. I haven&amp;#x27;t engaged with them an from thereon haven&amp;#x27;t noticed any change because of them.&lt;p&gt;Saying there are reports of excessive memory or CPU use isn&amp;#x27;t terribly useful without references to those reports.  One such report posted on HN was shown to have been unrelated to the LLM.&lt;p&gt;Are there any reports actually showing degradation because of LLMs rather than post hoc ergo propter hoc?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;web3-is-a-scam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They’re opt-out and can be disabled in the settings or fully disabled in about:config.  Definitely annoying but not enough to make me switch to a Chromium based browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;briga:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a checkbox on whether you want to use it or not in the settings page, does this not change these settings?&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t feel opposed to them changing the browser in principle--certainly there have been many improvements to web browsers over the years. Is privacy the concern here?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asciimov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is your favorite Firefox alternative?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;superkuh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The built in LLM translation is great. I&amp;#x27;m leaving that enabled. It&amp;#x27;s useful and it&amp;#x27;s a perfect application for local LLM to be better than the equivalent corporate services.&lt;p&gt;I disable a ton in default FF and even run the unbranded versions so that it&amp;#x27;s not trialware (FF branded builds all expire when their baked in add-ons CA TLS certs expire). But the LLM translation? That&amp;#x27;s finally a good feature.&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;#x27;t clear what browser.ml.chat and browser.ml.pageAssist are associated with in terms of features. Does anyone know? I tried disabling all shown in the write-up and local LLM translation still seems to work so I assume it&amp;#x27;s something else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That&amp;#x27;s disappointing. If they can do EME-free builds, they can do LLM-free builds. This isn&amp;#x27;t a &amp;#x27;tricky issue&amp;#x27;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hacks.mozilla.org&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;reconciling-mozillas-mission-and-w3c-eme&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hacks.mozilla.org&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;reconciling-mozillas-missi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MrAlex94:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I understand why Mozilla have started implementing these features, it seems to have more mass market appeal than not - look at how popular “AI” powered browsers have become.&lt;p&gt;But boy does it not add extra effort removing these features every time there’s a new roll-out and it’s not done the best way IMO.
I feel as if these features would go down better if Mozilla actually notified the user that they’re available and then offered whether to enable them or not (could have them enabled by default for new users). That way you’re still giving a choice, but in a more respectful manner.&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested I’ve gutted all the more obscene stuff out of Waterfox and have instead left the useful ones such a ML translation, which is opt-in.&lt;p&gt;Related: I feel like onboarding is a lost art, more software should bring back software wizards and UI tours. Feels like you somehow have to intuitively know how something works (unlikely) or do a web search on how to use everything instead of having it shown to you nicely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lemoncookiechip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They&amp;#x27;re all easily disabled in the GUI itself. The article is exaggerating, the closest argument is that it enables itself by default when it first updated which is fair, but they&amp;#x27;re easy to disable within the menu itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nrclark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mozilla sure is going out of their way to alienate their remaining users. This is going to be Pocket 2.0.&lt;p&gt;Who asked for this? Who wants it? Certainly not the Linux &amp;#x2F; open-source crowd, and they&amp;#x27;re just about the only ones who are keeping Firefox alive.&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;#x27;s anybody from Mozilla or the Firefox dev team in this thread, I&amp;#x27;d be interested to hear the thinking behind this addition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BolexNOLA:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;Alternatives #
There are a few projects that are forks of firefox with these features removed.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;I would think most non technical users would just use a different browser.&lt;p&gt;I would think they would list one or two of them under the “alternatives” section…?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;empiko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Where can I find these LLM features in Firefox?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://equk.co.uk/2025/10/28/firefox-forcing-llm-features/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858959</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
