<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - Korean</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to Korean</description>
    <language>ko</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:49:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-ko.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>오랫동안 Mozilla를 지원해온 일본 커뮤니티가 AI 번역 사용으로 인해 폐쇄되었습니다</title>
      <link>https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;귀하의 브라우저에서 클라이언트 챌린지 JavaScript가 비활성화되어 있습니다. 계속하려면 JavaScript를 활성화하십시오. 이는 브라우저 확장, 네트워크 문제 또는 브라우저 설정 때문일 수 있습니다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original:&lt;/strong&gt; Longtime Mozilla Support Japanese Community Shuts Down over AI Translation Usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830770"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shusaku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s a shame because “improve an off the shelf llm ti translate in line with this large dataset we prepared” is precisely the kind of project people love to work on. It could have been a chance to immortalize the hard work they did up until now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getnormality:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sorry for how you feel about us kicking you in the balls.&lt;p&gt;Would you like to hop on a quick call to chat about this further?&lt;p&gt;Just a quick lil call.&lt;p&gt;Quick lil ol&amp;#x27; callerino.&lt;p&gt;We can hoppity hip hop right on there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thwarted:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the logic behind adding machine translation for content that already had a seemingly robust, enthusiastic, and motivated (volunteer?) community maintaining the translations?  The &amp;quot;saves money&amp;quot; rationale to deploy LLM&amp;#x2F;MT automation doesn&amp;#x27;t make sense when its volunteers are contributing because they want to.  This is kind of community and participation destruction wrought by the introduction of LLMs&amp;#x2F;MT has a serious impact because it undermines the people who are actually willing to do the work. It was presumably costing nothing (or very little) to have the community maintain this content, but the change has cost a significant amount of goodwill.  If the Japanese SUMO community wanted to use MT, it should be their sole decision, baring any issues with their stewardship in general.  This is someone else saying &amp;quot;look, with this great new automation, you don&amp;#x27;t need to spend time anymore doing «thing you &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to do»&amp;quot;. Huh? How does that make any sense to force on anyone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gyomu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a multilingual&amp;#x2F;multicultural human it’s been pretty weird witnessing what AI translation has been doing to regional languages &amp;amp; cultures on the internet in the last few years.&lt;p&gt;Sure we had machine translation before, but it was still a little off. Now the latest language models get us 99.9% there, so they are judged good enough to deploy at scale. What results is a weird twilight zone where everything is in your language, except it feels kind of wrong and doesn’t really communicate in ways specific to the culture from which the language is.&lt;p&gt;You’re in France, you search for something, a thread pops up with everyone interacting in French - seems reasonable enough, but it just reads kind of weird? Then a message is entirely out of place, and you realize that you’re reading an English language thread translated to French.&lt;p&gt;Or your mom sends you a screenshot of a Facebook thread in her native language that has her worked up - and reading it, you realize it’s an LLM translation of something that should have no bearing on her.&lt;p&gt;Same with various support pages on websites - it all reads mostly fine until you hit a weird sentence where the LLM messed up and then you’re transported back to the reality that what you’re reading was not authored by anyone who can actually operate in that language&amp;#x2F;culture.&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of nuance in language beyond the words - how you express disagreement in English is not how you express disagreement in Japanese, how you address the reader in French is not the same as in Korean, etc. Machine translation flattens all modes of expression into a weird culturally en-US biased soup (because that’s where the companies are headquartered and where the language models are trained).&lt;p&gt;I have no illusions that this trend will reverse - high quality translation work is skill and time consuming, and thanks to LLMs anyone on Earth can now localize anything they want in any language they want for ~free in ~0 time.&lt;p&gt;The weirdest part is seeing this bubble up to the real world. I’ve been hearing young people use turns of phrases&amp;#x2F;expressions that I recognize as distinctly American, except not in English.&lt;p&gt;The classic linguist response to this, which I subscribe to, is “no language is fixed, language is ever evolving in response to various external cultural pressures“. Which is true. But it doesn’t make our post-LLM language landscape any less weird.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kaveh_h:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some people do these type of contribution or charity work not just to do some good but also to feel some autonomy and mastery in a world were much of the regular top down driven  drudgery work does not provide much of that feeling. 
 These people are canaries in the coal mine. I expect more people feel a loss of purpose and rise of anxiety and depression in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jahsome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not really able to understand the finer details but I think I picked up enough to get the broad strokes.&lt;p&gt;Really though, all I needed to see was the phrase &amp;quot;jump on a quick call&amp;quot; to form an irrationally strong opinion. That phrase instantly warms my entire body with rage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ants_everywhere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I prohibit to use all my translation as learning data for SUMO bot and AIs.
&amp;gt; I request to remove all my translation from learned data of SUMO AIs.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s Mozilla&amp;#x27;s data...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; explicit violation to the Mozilla mission&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure what this is referring to. I don&amp;#x27;t see any explicit violation of Mozilla.org&amp;#x27;s mission. If anything it seems consistent with that mission to provide universal translation with quick turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adeptima:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10+ years in Japan. The message here is much deeper from my perspective. “Let’s jump on the call” is not the solution. The guy was stripped off of his face. I love Japan for being human. Small business bar or restaurant with 3 tables. Not everything should be streamlined for a quick call solution… the process was pushed on his head. Google nemawashi decision making process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ares623:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is rich&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; We want to make sure we trully understand what you&amp;#x27;re struggling with.&lt;p&gt;The post literally starts with a list of grievances. Maybe ask the AI for an executive summary and the key points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;barbazoo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; They are all happened on the product server, not on staging server. I understand that this is mass destruction of our work and explicit violation to the Mozilla mission, allowed officially.&lt;p&gt;Could this have been a mistake rather than a malicious act?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830770</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAA, 정부 폐쇄로 인해 40개 주요 공항에서 항공편 10% 감축</title>
      <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;요점교통부 장관 Sean Duffy는 수요일 오후 40개 주요 공항에서 항공편 수용 능력을 10% 줄이겠다고 발표했습니다. Sean P. 교통 장관은 "이것은 적극적입니다"라고 Duffy는 기자 회견에서 말했습니다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original:&lt;/strong&gt; FAA to cut flights by 10% at 40 major airports due to government shutdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830797"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mmaunder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Watching officials describe how the NTSB is working hard to investigate the recent air disaster, knowing that many at NTSB aren&amp;#x27;t getting paid...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;runako:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Has anybody modeled what this does to the overall system?&lt;p&gt;My impression is the system doesn&amp;#x27;t have all that much slack to begin with. And then to reduce all the major airports at the same time? And with the (current) expectation that next week will be worse?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;komali2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Even if flights aren&amp;#x27;t cut, TSA and related staff are. I&amp;#x27;ve heard rumors of 4 hour security lines at IAH.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NewsGotHacked:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone figure out yet which 40 airports these are?!? All articles I have seen say 40 airports but don&amp;#x27;t mention which ones&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wnevets:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this the greatness I&amp;#x27;ve been promised?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;defrost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Earlier: &lt;i&gt;US may cut air traffic 10% by Friday without shutdown deal, sources say&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;(reuters.com) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45828203"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45828203&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;istillwritecode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No doubt flights between blue cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CursedSilicon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Kind of glad I picked Amtrak to go down and visit family for Thanksgiving&lt;p&gt;Gonna be rough if the shutdown lasts to the end of November. Shame the usual suspects didn&amp;#x27;t get the memo about how badly their party was just decimated across the country. Should&amp;#x27;ve been a canary in the coal mine moment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JKCalhoun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wild times. I guess I&amp;#x27;m just at a loss for words—what&amp;#x27;s going on in this country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:44:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830797</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rust의 TUI 혁명</title>
      <link>https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;"하단"이라는 제목의 하단 섹션 터미널용 사용자 정의 가능한 크로스 플랫폼 그래픽 프로세스/시스템 모니터 "십자말풀이"라는 제목의 크로스워드 섹션 터미널에서 크로스워드 퍼즐을 재생합니다. joshuto"joshuto"라는 제목의 섹션 Rust로 작성된 레인저와 유사한 터미널 파일 관리자 Material"material"이라는 제목의 섹션 터미널의 머티리얼 디자인 색상 팔레트입니다. 터미널에서 OpenAPI 문서를 확인하세요.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original:&lt;/strong&gt; Rust's TUI Revolution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830829"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dkdcio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the title of this post is odd? it’s a showcase of TUI applications built with this Rust crate — which I am hearing about for the first time, and am interested in. I was expecting a blog post on why Rust is experiencing a TUI revolution or something&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830829</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
