<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:27:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Ventoy: Create Bootable USB Drive for ISO/WIM/IMG/VHD(x)/EFI Files</title>
      <link>https://github.com/ventoy/Ventoy</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;net Tested OS Windows Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8. 1, Windows 10, Windows 11, Windows Server 2012, Windows Server 2012 R2, Windows Server 2016, Windows Server 2019, Windows Server 2022, Windows Server 2025, WinPE Linux Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS(6/7/8/9), RHEL(6/7/8/9), Deepin, Fedora, Rocky Linux, AlmaLinux, EuroLinux(6/7/8/9), openEuler, OpenAnolis, SLES, openSUSE, MX Linux, Manjaro, Linux Mint, Endless OS, Elementary OS, Solus, Linx, Zorin, antiX, PClinuxOS, Arch, ArcoLinux, ArchLabs, BlackArch, Obarun, Artix Linux, Puppy Linux, Tails, Slax, Kali, Mageia, Slackware, Q4OS, Archman, Gentoo, Pentoo, NixOS, Kylin, openKylin, Ubuntu Kylin, KylinSec, Lubuntu, Xubuntu, Kubuntu, Ubuntu MATE, Ubuntu Budgie, Ubuntu Studio, Bluestar, OpenMandriva, ExTiX, Netrunner, ALT Linux, Nitrux, Peppermint, KDE neon, Linux Lite, Parrot OS, Qubes, Pop OS, ROSA, Void Linux, Star Linux, EndeavourOS, MakuluLinux, Voyager, Feren, ArchBang, LXLE, Knoppix, Calculate Linux, Clear Linux, Pure OS, Oracle Linux, Trident, Septor, Porteus, Devuan, GoboLinux, 4MLinux, Simplicity Linux, Zeroshell, Android-x86, netboot. xyz, Slitaz, SuperGrub2Disk, Proxmox VE, Kaspersky Rescue, SystemRescueCD, MemTest86, MemTest86+, MiniTool Partition Wizard, Parted Magic, veket, Sabayon, Scientific, alpine, ClearOS, CloneZilla, Berry Linux, Trisquel, Ataraxia Linux, Minimal Linux Live, BackBox Linux, Emmabuntüs, ESET SysRescue Live,Nova Linux, AV Linux, RoboLinux, NuTyX, IPFire, SELKS, ZStack, Enso Linux, Security Onion, Network Security Toolkit, Absolute Linux, TinyCore, Springdale Linux, Frost Linux, Shark Linux, LinuxFX, Snail Linux, Astra Linux, Namib Linux, Resilient Linux, Virage Linux, Blackweb Security OS, R-DriveImage, O-O.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/ventoy/Ventoy'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/ventoy/Ventoy</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760340</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Perceived 'Claustrophobia' of New York City's Streets (2024)</title>
      <link>http://mfranchi.net/posts/claustrophobic-streets/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Methodology - Bringing in Clutter For this computational analysis, ‘clutter’ is anything that takes up space on the sidewalk. We assign points to different clutters with spatial joins. Since some clutters have non-uniform sizes (for example, there are several different configurations of bus stops, each with a different size), and size data was unavailable for some clutter types, we stick with the naive approach for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mfranchi.net/posts/claustrophobic-streets/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mfranchi.net/posts/claustrophobic-streets/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45759649</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US declines to join more than 70 countries in signing UN cybercrime treaty</title>
      <link>https://therecord.media/us-declines-signing-cybercrime-treaty</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waly said the convention would be a “vital tool” that will ensure “a safer digital world for all. Human rights groups warned on Friday that it effectively forces member states to create a broad electronic surveillance dragnet that would include crimes that have nothing to do with technology. Countries have only recently begun to share digital evidence across borders but the convention would increase that practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://therecord.media/us-declines-signing-cybercrime-treaty'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therecord.media/us-declines-signing-cybercrime-treaty</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760328</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replacing EBS and Rethinking Postgres Storage from First Principles</title>
      <link>https://www.tigerdata.com/blog/fluid-storage-forkable-ephemeral-durable-infrastructure-age-of-agents</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s storage that looks like a local disk but scales like a cloud service. Storage that behaves more like software than hardware. Traditional storage can’t keep up with that pace or economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.tigerdata.com/blog/fluid-storage-forkable-ephemeral-durable-infrastructure-age-of-agents'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tigerdata.com/blog/fluid-storage-forkable-ephemeral-durable-infrastructure-age-of-agents</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45748484</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D solar tower increases capacity factor 50%, triples solar surface area</title>
      <link>https://www.pv-magazine.com/2025/10/27/3d-solar-tower-increases-capacity-factor-50-triples-solar-surface-area/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3D solar tower increases capacity factor 50%, triples solar surface area Janta Power closed $5. The company said its solar tower has a capacity factor 50% greater than traditional solar installations. While typical flat installations have a capacity factor of about 22%, Janta Power said its typical installations achieve a capacity factor of about 32%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.pv-magazine.com/2025/10/27/3d-solar-tower-increases-capacity-factor-50-triples-solar-surface-area/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pv-magazine.com/2025/10/27/3d-solar-tower-increases-capacity-factor-50-triples-solar-surface-area/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45759922</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The International Criminal Court wants to become independent of USA technology</title>
      <link>https://www.heise.de/en/news/International-Criminal-Court-Kicks-Out-Microsoft-10964189.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The International Criminal Court (ICC) wants to become independent of technology from the USA – for fear of reprisals from Donald Trump, Handelsblatt has learned. Furthermore, the US government in Washington is examining further measures against the International Criminal Court, Handelsblatt further reports. However, Handelsblatt sees this as an indication that geopolitics is increasingly revolving around technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.heise.de/en/news/International-Criminal-Court-Kicks-Out-Microsoft-10964189.html'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.heise.de/en/news/International-Criminal-Court-Kicks-Out-Microsoft-10964189.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 13:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45759891</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
