<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:49:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>California DMV approves map increase in Waymo driverless operations</title>
      <link>https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/vehicle-industry-services/autonomous-vehicles/autonomous-vehicle-testing-permit-holders/waymo-approved-areas-of-operation-for-driverless-testing-and-deployment/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waymo Approved Areas of Operation for Driverless Testing and Deployment Approved autonomous vehicle platforms to conduct driverless testing and deployment operations in all approved operational design domains (ODD) in California. MakeModel YearsMakeJaguar I-PaceModel Years2021 and 2024MakeZeekr RTModel Years2022 and 2025 Hours of Operation: All times of day and night ODD Characteristics: All rain, fog, and other conditions All Speeds Approved ODD Maps: Approved Cities and Counties CityCountyCityLivermoreCountyAlameda CountyCityAlamedaCountyAlameda CountyCityAlbanyCountyAlameda CountyCityBerkeleyCountyAlameda CountyCityDublinCountyAlameda CountyCityEmeryvilleCountyAlameda CountyCityFremontCountyAlameda CountyCityHaywardCountyAlameda CountyCityNewarkCountyAlameda CountyCityOaklandCountyAlameda CountyCityPiedmontCountyAlameda CountyCityPleasantonCountyAlameda CountyCitySan LeandroCountyAlameda CountyCityUnion CityCountyAlameda CountyCityAntiochCountyContra Costa CountyCityBrentwoodCountyContra Costa CountyCityClaytonCountyContra Costa CountyCityConcordCountyContra Costa CountyCityDanvilleCountyContra Costa CountyCityEl CerritoCountyContra Costa CountyCityHerculesCountyContra Costa CountyCityLafayetteCountyContra Costa CountyCityMartinezCountyContra Costa CountyCityMoragaCountyContra Costa CountyCityOakleyCountyContra Costa CountyCityOrindaCountyContra Costa CountyCityPinoleCountyContra Costa CountyCityPittsburgCountyContra Costa CountyCityPleasant HillCountyContra Costa CountyCityRichmondCountyContra Costa CountyCitySan PabloCountyContra Costa CountyCitySan RamonCountyContra Costa CountyCityWalnut CreekCountyContra Costa CountyCityAgoura HillsCounty Los Angeles CountyCityArcadiaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityArtesiaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityAzusaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBaldwin ParkCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBellflowerCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBradburyCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBurbankCounty Los Angeles CountyCityCalabasasCounty Los Angeles CountyCityCerritosCounty Los Angeles CountyCityClaremontCounty Los Angeles CountyCityCovinaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityDiamond BarCounty Los Angeles CountyCityDuarteCounty Los Angeles CountyCityEl MonteCounty Los Angeles CountyCityGlendoraCounty Los Angeles CountyCityHawaiian GardensCounty Los Angeles CountyCityHidden HillsCounty Los Angeles CountyCityIndustryCounty Los Angeles CountyCityIrwindaleCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLa Cañada FlintridgeCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLa Habra HeightsCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLa MiradaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLa PuenteCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLa VerneCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLakewoodCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLomitaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityMalibuCounty Los Angeles CountyCityMonroviaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityMontebelloCounty Los Angeles CountyCityNorwalkCounty Los Angeles CountyCityPalos Verdes EstatesCounty Los Angeles CountyCityPasadenaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityPico RiveraCounty Los Angeles CountyCityPomonaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityRancho Palos VerdesCounty Los Angeles CountyCityRolling HillsCounty Los Angeles CountyCityRolling Hills EstatesCounty Los Angeles CountyCityRosemeadCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySan DimasCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySan FernandoCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySan GabrielCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySan MarinoCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySanta ClaritaCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySanta Fe SpringsCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySierra MadreCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySignal HillCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySouth El MonteCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySouth PasadenaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityTemple CityCounty Los Angeles CountyCityWalnutCounty Los Angeles CountyCityWest CovinaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityWestlake VillageCounty Los Angeles CountyCityWhittierCounty Los Angeles CountyCityAlhambraCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBellCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBell GardensCounty Los Angeles CountyCityCarsonCounty Los Angeles CountyCityCommerceCounty Los Angeles CountyCityComptonCounty Los Angeles CountyCityDowneyCounty Los Angeles CountyCityEl SegundoCounty Los Angeles CountyCityGardenaCounty Los Angeles CountyCityGlendaleCounty Los Angeles CountyCityHermosa BeachCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLong BeachCounty Los Angeles CountyCityLos AngelesCounty Los Angeles CountyCityManhattan BeachCounty Los Angeles CountyCityMonterey ParkCounty Los Angeles CountyCityParamountCounty Los Angeles CountyCityRedondo BeachCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySanta MonicaCounty Los Angeles CountyCitySouth GateCounty Los Angeles CountyCityTorranceCounty Los Angeles CountyCityBelvedereCountyMarin CountyCityCorte MaderaCountyMarin CountyCityFairfaxCountyMarin CountyCityLarkspurCountyMarin CountyCityMill ValleyCountyMarin CountyCityNovatoCountyMarin CountyCityRossCountyMarin CountyCitySan AnselmoCountyMarin CountyCitySan RafaelCountyMarin CountyCitySausalitoCountyMarin CountyCityTiburonCountyMarin CountyCityAmerican CanyonCountyNapa CountyCityCalistogaCountyNapa CountyCityNapaCountyNapa CountyCitySt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009994"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/vehicle-industry-services/autonomous-vehicles/autonomous-vehicle-testing-permit-holders/waymo-approved-areas-of-operation-for-driverless-testing-and-deployment/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;visioninmyblood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This means longer driving in highways. Not sure if this is safe. have been developing this tech for a long time and highway speeds are dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;redwood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No santa cruz eh?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tonypapousek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Personally, I can’t wait to be killed by a cold, uncaring robot. Let’s goooo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tcdent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The map area for the Southern California service area is absolutely massive.&lt;p&gt;Without traffic, at highway speeds, it would take you almost four hours to travel from the North end to the South end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;janalsncm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I believe that in 20 years there will be cities (probably not in America) where all cars are autonomous. There will be no red lights, no parking lots, less congestion, fewer accidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;51Cards:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I rode in one of these in Phoenix in June, loved the experience!  Had to go to a pharmacy so purposely picked one a half hour across the city so I could just watch the car perform.  Felt like the future (though it did glitch once).  Made a sudden turn off the road into a parking lot, did a lap of the outside of the parking lot, and exited back onto the same road to continue on.  Must have thought something was blocking the road and made a detour around it?  Other than that it seemed pretty flawless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__grob:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is so cool to see. Saw tons of Waymo in LA&amp;#x2F;Santa Monica area when I was there in October. Very excited to see them expand basically all through SoCal!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bix6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Was curious on the Zeekr RT. Interesting to see it’s owned by Geely.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.motortrend.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;waymo-zeekr-rt-autonomous-ev-robotaxi-windshield-wipers" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.motortrend.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;waymo-zeekr-rt-autonomous-ev...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eduction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“Map increase?” Is that hackernewsish for “larger area”?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmspring:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;First used Waymo in Phoenix.  It was a decent experience.  The funny thing was watching it handle parallel parking.  I mentioned it to the wife - self driving with parkinsons.&lt;p&gt;This last weekend, we were in the city (San Francisco) and literally drove by a Waymo trying to park and the wife started laughing - &amp;quot;you are right&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;int0x29:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My general experience with Waymos and safety is that while they are generally quite safe and communicative drivers (They have a pedestrian yeild indicator that should be required by law) they tend to create safety issues because people drive stupidly around them.  A lot of SF drivers seem to see them, think I know better, and then proceed to do something dumb.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not really sure how to fix this problem.&lt;p&gt;Also if any Waymo engineers are reading this please make the pedestrian yeild indicator icon visible on the front of the LIDAR.  In narrow streets the front is much more visible to pedestrians than the sides as the LIDAR is pretty far back on the car.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ElijahLynn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the dark spot on the maps? Was that the current and then the less dark is the expansion?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;siliconc0w:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do the driving tests cover what you&amp;#x27;re supposed to do if you hit a Waymo or one hits you?  I assume the cops are instructed just to ignore them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tade0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This gives me hope that once I&amp;#x27;m too old to drive, this tech will reach my, very distant from the US west coast, corner of the world.&lt;p&gt;And if not Waymo and its car, then perhaps autonomous buses. There&amp;#x27;s already a shortage of bus drivers in my city and it&amp;#x27;s not getting any smaller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OGEnthusiast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Waymo has so far been awesome, can&amp;#x27;t imagine choosing an Uber&amp;#x2F;Lyft over a Waymo when both are available options. I wonder how much they are bottlenecked by vehicle production though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kfarr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is super awesome but to set expectations it appears that Waymo is quite limited by fleet capacity in all of its current operating zones, so as a practical matter it may be months or years before it operates in all these areas.&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re interested in this stuff I highly recommend this podcast, not affiliated with it I genuinely think it&amp;#x27;s a great source to hear about the behind the scenes of fleet operations to meet demand:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.roadtoautonomy.com&amp;#x2F;autonomy-markets&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.roadtoautonomy.com&amp;#x2F;autonomy-markets&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Edit) I prefer using the apple podcast app, here&amp;#x27;s a direct link: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;autonomy-markets&amp;#x2F;id1770549800" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;autonomy-markets&amp;#x2F;id177...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;willio58:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I didn’t think I’d be so pro Waymo but anecdotally I had a fantastic experience with one recently.&lt;p&gt;I was at a music show very late ~1-2am in SF and walked out to grab an uber to the airbnb I was staying at. I kept getting assigned an uber, then I’d wait 10 minutes, then they’d cancel. Rinse and repeat for 30 minutes, mind you I even resorted to calling Lyfts at the same time and nothing bit. Then I say screw it and download Waymo. 1 minute and it’s accepted my ride, and I know it’s not going to cancel because it’s a robot. 3 minutes and it picks me up. The car is clean, quiet, I can play my own music in it via Spotify, and it’s driving honestly more safely than some uber drivers I’ve had in SF. It’s one of the few things where the end result actually lives up to the promise from a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;epicureanideal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m looking forward to the day when the cost of taking one of these falls to somewhere 20% above the cost of fuel and wear and tear on the vehicle, making it incredibly cheap to take a ride anywhere you’d reasonably want to be driven to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arjie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The effectiveness with which AVs have been able to test and spread despite local municipalities being fairly luddite about them &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; provide positive evidence for the idea that states are the right level of government for many of these decisions. If this had been entirely up to Bay Area municipalities it would have been infeasible, and this outcome and the lives consequently saved will be due to state-level decision-makers being able to make better decisions than local municipal decision-makers.&lt;p&gt;If the urban sprawl of the Bay Area were (correctly, in my opinion) represented as a single fused city-county like Tokyo, I think we would have better governance, but highly fragmented municipalities means we have a lot of free-rider vetos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HPMOR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So when will they be available for commercial rides? Can&amp;#x27;t wait to waymo from SF to Berkeley!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pfooti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looking forward to the highway expansion next. I had to get from mountain view to san francisco yesterday, and waymo was _able_ to do this trip, it was going to take several hours and get routed up el camino real the whole way. Luckily I was standing very close to a caltrain station when I needed the ride, so i just caltrained, and then waymo&amp;#x27;d from the SF station to where i needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kylehotchkiss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m so excited how much of Southern California is opened - Waymo LAX to SD after midnight (there&amp;#x27;s no trains or buses from 12 to 6)!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alooPotato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;why is there an approved map? like i get having a pilot somewhere but once that goes well (and we&amp;#x27;re way past that point), why isn&amp;#x27;t it just blanket approval everywhere. Why would one county be allowed waymos but not another.&lt;p&gt;I get that they might not be approved in the high sierras but just make that a deny list not allow list. Or even just deny the specific conditions you&amp;#x27;re worried about (snow).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwaway48476:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s disappointing that where I live is politically difficult and waymo won&amp;#x27;t come anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JumpCrisscross:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Whoah, Waymo would be able to take one from Mountain View to Napa. (I get why Cupertino is excluded. But. Oof. Come on.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fricken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s been a long time coming, but Waymo is doing it. Waymo is scaleable and on the march! They&amp;#x27;ve been announcing plans to roll out in new cities every month or 2 all year, and by the end of 2026 they&amp;#x27;ll be testing or offering the public rides over 30 metropolitan areas.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m most curious to see how they do in the winter city of Minneapolis over the next several months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/vehicle-industry-services/autonomous-vehicles/autonomous-vehicle-testing-permit-holders/waymo-approved-areas-of-operation-for-driverless-testing-and-deployment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009994</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal blogs are back, should niche blogs be next?</title>
      <link>https://disassociated.com/personal-blogs-back-niche-blogs-next/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal blogs are back, should niche blogs be next. Some people considered this niche principle to be a core tenet of blogging. But with the revival of personal blogs well underway, I think it’s time to bring niche blogs back into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009894"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://disassociated.com/personal-blogs-back-niche-blogs-next/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kazinator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[delayed]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arjie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Are personal blogs back? My personal blog ten years ago (even twenty years ago) received a lot of direct traffic on all sorts of things from the primary search engines and so on. Nowadays, the only search engine that delivers any traffic to my site is Kagi! Looking back, I haven&amp;#x27;t changed my style of writing very much, so I suspect the reality is that I&amp;#x27;ve just fallen behind in a comparative sense. There are much better things nowadays to access.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s probably similar to the street-side musician. In old times, he may have been the only musician around you might hear. Nowadays, he&amp;#x27;s got to compete with a perfect recording of Hotel California by the Eagles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;loktarogar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AI scrapes niche blogs, Google deranks or spam drowns them out. It&amp;#x27;s really not a good time to be starting niche blogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emschwartz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you’re looking to put one up, try &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bearblog.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt; (no connection, just appreciate Herman’s work).&lt;p&gt;It’s got just the features you need, is built by a solo dev, and it’s got a very fair split between free and paid features. I used it to put up my personal site and have been very happy with the experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AndrewKemendo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I didn’t know they ever went out&lt;p&gt;I’ve maintained my own domain since 2010 and know plenty of others that still do as well&lt;p&gt;My page is one of my favorite places on the internet cause it’s in my opinion the original purpose of the internet which is to share your personal research and places to document and share personal ideas with infinite distribution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tinkelenberg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Every blog is a niche blog because blogging is a niche. It never was and never will be mainstream. Social media began as an attempt to make the spirit of blogging a low lift for the noobs.&lt;p&gt;Today, you’re talking to an audience that is online, willing to venture outside social media, and opting to actively read content rather than passively listen or watch. That’s far from everyone and that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;awesome_dude:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t there a cycle - blogs, aggregators, email lists, back to blogs...?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codazoda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you want to setup a super minimal blog checkout Neat CSS.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;neat.joeldare.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;neat.joeldare.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peacefulz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I want to start one myself. More of a public journal, but all the same. I keep having fits and starts and things distract me from the habit. That, and I&amp;#x27;m never satisfied with my implementation in the end and I always want to try new or different things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rmoriz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While there are ~ millions of blog engines out there, what is the current state of commenting and trackbacks?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blakesterz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was wondering what the definition of &amp;quot;niche&amp;quot; was going to be:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   Kottke is one of the better known blogs that does not have a specific speciality. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I think that&amp;#x27;s a good one to highlight as NOT niche, and niche is much more specific. Like I&amp;#x27;ve had a librarian blog since 1999. Pretty much niche.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venn1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Two years ago I started a niche blog and tech site focused on hardware and software guides for Linux creatives. Even set up a forum because I was fed up with digging through scattered mailing lists and Discord servers for information. I like to think it has helped some people and it gives me a chance to practice writing human-readable documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cagrimmett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t call it a comeback. We&amp;#x27;ve been here for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;julianlam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Niche forums. Federated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ilamont:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have been blogging for decades, personal and work. I look at traffic patterns and see all the comments coming through.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think personal blogs are back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ricardobeat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; But with the revival of personal blogs well underway&lt;p&gt;Is it? I haven&amp;#x27;t seen anyone in my circle return to blogging, nor kids of this generation.&lt;p&gt;Discoverability is going to be a massive problem, since search engines are dead. Maybe word-of-mouth through social media is enough?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://disassociated.com/personal-blogs-back-niche-blogs-next/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009894</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I learned Vulkan and wrote a small game engine with it</title>
      <link>https://edw.is/learning-vulkan/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this article will help make some things about Vulkan clearer to you. It’s easy to fall into this trap when doing graphics programming (especially when doing Vulkan since you need to make many choices when implementing an engine with it). Don’t try to make a general purpose game engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010329"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://edw.is/learning-vulkan/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tombert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My opinions of Vulkan have not changed significantly since this was posted a year ago &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=40601605"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=40601605&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure Vulkan is fun and wonderful for people who really want low level control of the graphic stack, but I found it completely miserable to use. I still haven&amp;#x27;t really found a graphics API that works at the level I want that I enjoyed using; I would like to get more into graphics programming since I do think it would be fun to build a game engine, but I will admit that even getting started with the low level Vulkan stuff is still scary to me.&lt;p&gt;I think what I want is something like how SDL does 2D graphics, but for 3D.  My understanding is that for 3D in SDL you just drop into OpenGL or something, which isn&amp;#x27;t quite what I want.&lt;p&gt;Maybe WebGPU would be something I could have fun working on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gnabgib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(2024) At the time (625 points, 260 comments) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=40595741"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=40595741&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakogut:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note that I have retained the original title of the post, but I am not the author.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://edw.is/learning-vulkan/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010329</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pixar: The Early Days A never-before-seen 1996 interview</title>
      <link>https://stevejobsarchive.com/stories/pixar-early-days</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To mark Toy Story’s 30th anniversary, we’re sharing a never-before-seen interview with Steve from November 22, 1996—exactly one year after the film debuted in theaters. An instant hit with audiences and critics, it also transformed Pixar, which went public the week after its premiere. In this footage, Steve reveals the long game behind Pixar’s seeming overnight success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008769"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://stevejobsarchive.com/stories/pixar-early-days'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;djmips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As Steve Jobs muses that Snow white was enjoyed 60 years after it&amp;#x27;s release but computers go to the sedimentary layer. While it&amp;#x27;s true that you can&amp;#x27;t re-release the 1984 Mac debut to fanfare and profit 40 years later - a small group of dedicated enthusiasts are still running their original Macs and others in emulation - so they arent&amp;#x27; completely fossilized!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;disillusioned:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Steve&amp;#x27;s comments around merging the culture of creatives and technologists, and how hard it is to attract and _retain_ the kind of world-changing talent that was necessary to invent a new category are interesting: &amp;quot;the very best creative people will only go to work at a few places, Disney, Pixar, Dreamworks,&amp;quot;... &amp;quot;in the same sense, the very best computer scientists and computer graphics people will only go work in a few places, and Pixar is one of those...&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I think Pixar is the only place in the world that can hire the best from both of these areas.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It feels like there are some obvious parallels to what we&amp;#x27;re seeing in AI hiring, where you have a firm like Anthropic that openly acknowledges that they&amp;#x27;re not going to try to compete on comp but on culture, compared to Meta which is basically saying &amp;quot;we&amp;#x27;ll give you more money than god if you join our efforts to throw things at the wall and be part of this,&amp;quot; and watching as people churn out even though the opportunity cost on the surface may be unfathomable.&lt;p&gt;Put another way: Steve truly understood the virtue and value of that cultural component to not just attract but _retain_ that kind of world-class talent, and _that&amp;#x27;s_ what he attributes Pixar&amp;#x27;s success to. He goes on to talk about how getting those disparate talent worlds to stick together for a decade, and how valuable that is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://stevejobsarchive.com/stories/pixar-early-days</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008769</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuxedo Computers Cancels Snapdragon X1 Linux Laptop</title>
      <link>https://www.tuxedocomputers.com/en/Discontinuation-of-ARM-notebooks-with-Snapdragon-X-Elite-SoC.tuxedo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your understanding. Find out more Technical Service Our competent technicians are also happy to help with service requests. But also outside these times, you can contact our team with your request by e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008156"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.tuxedocomputers.com/en/Discontinuation-of-ARM-notebooks-with-Snapdragon-X-Elite-SoC.tuxedo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aidenn0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m disappointed, but not surprised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exabrial:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I mean I feel like once one of the ARM chipmakers can lend a hand on the software side it should be a landslide.&lt;p&gt;Google and Samsung managed to make very successful Chromebooks together, but IIRC there was a bunch of back and forth to make the whole thing boot quickly and sip battery power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IshKebab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does anyone know &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; Linux laptop battery life is so bad? Is it a case of devices needing to be turned off that aren&amp;#x27;t? Poor CPU scheduling?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ndiddy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a shame that this didn&amp;#x27;t end up going anywhere. When Qualcomm was doing their press stuff prior to the Snapdragon X launch, they said that they&amp;#x27;d be putting equal effort into supporting both Windows and Linux. If anyone here is running Linux on a Snapdragon X laptop, I&amp;#x27;d be curious to know what the experience is like today.&lt;p&gt;I will say that Intel has kind of made the original X Elite chips irrelevant with their Lunar Lake chips. They have similar performance&amp;#x2F;battery life, and run cool (so you can use the laptop on your lap or in bed without it overheating), but have full Linux support today and you don&amp;#x27;t have to deal with x86 emulation. If anyone needs a thin &amp;amp; light Linux laptop today, they&amp;#x27;re probably your best option. Personally, I get 10-14 hours of real usage (not manufacturer &amp;quot;offline video playback with the brightness turned all the way down&amp;quot; numbers) on my Vivobook S14 running Fedora KDE. In the future, it&amp;#x27;ll be interesting to see how Intel&amp;#x27;s upcoming Panther Lake chips compare to Snapdragon X2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrewaylett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I almost certainly wouldn&amp;#x27;t have done more than wished for one, it&amp;#x27;s a shame they&amp;#x27;re not getting any return for their effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tuxedocomputers.com/en/Discontinuation-of-ARM-notebooks-with-Snapdragon-X-Elite-SoC.tuxedo</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008156</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Matrix Multiplication Ugly?</title>
      <link>https://mathenchant.wordpress.com/2025/11/21/is-matrix-multiplication-ugly/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another example is the operation g that that takes an image in the plane and reflects it across a diagonal line that goes from lower left to upper right. The key thing to notice here is that the effect of f followed by g is different from the effect of g followed by f. But if instead, starting from that original R, you were to apply g followed by f, you’d get the original R rotated by 90 degrees counterclockwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009660"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://mathenchant.wordpress.com/2025/11/21/is-matrix-multiplication-ugly/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gweinberg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The commutation problem has nothing to do with matrices. Rotations in space do not commute, and that will be the case whether you represent them as matrices or in some other way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fracus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think it is just a matter of perspective.  You can both be right.  I don&amp;#x27;t think there is an objective answer to this question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sfpotter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think this sentence:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; But matrix multiplication, to which our civilization is now devoting so many of its marginal resources, has all the elegance of a man hammering a nail into a board.&lt;p&gt;is the most interesting one.&lt;p&gt;A man hammering a nail into a board can be both beautiful and elegant! If you&amp;#x27;ve ever seen someone effortlessly hammer nail after nail into wood without having to think hardly at all about what they&amp;#x27;re doing, you&amp;#x27;ve seen a master craftsman at work. Speaking as a numerical analyst, I&amp;#x27;d say a well multiplied matrix is much the same. There is much that goes into how deftly a matrix might be multiplied. And just as someone can hammer a nail poorly, so too can a matrix be multiplied poorly. I would say the matrices being multiplied in service of training LLMs are &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a particularly beautiful example of what matrix multiplication has to offer. The fast Fourier transform viewed as a sparse matrix factorization of the DFT and its concomitant properties of numerical stability might be a better candidate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jamespropp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do you disagree with my take or think I’m missing Witt’s point? I’d be happy to hear from people who disagree with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mathenchant.wordpress.com/2025/11/21/is-matrix-multiplication-ugly/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009660</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Untold History of Arduino (2016)</title>
      <link>https://arduinohistory.github.io/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why Did You Create Wiring. The Language Have you ever wondered where those commands come from. Here are some key moments in the hardware design for Wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009209"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arduinohistory.github.io/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lproven:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Previously...&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29252121"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29252121&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(4Y ago, 6 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=26261237"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=26261237&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(5Y, 1C)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=19414275"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=19414275&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(7Y, 33C)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=11212021"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=11212021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(10Y, 73C)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NaOH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Previous discussions:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Untold History of Arduino&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29252121"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29252121&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 2021 (6 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Untold History of Arduino&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=26261237"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=26261237&lt;/a&gt; - Feb 2021 (1 comment)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Untold History of Arduino (2016)&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=19414275"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=19414275&lt;/a&gt; - March 2019 (35 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Untold History of Arduino&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=11212021"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=11212021&lt;/a&gt; - March 2016 (73 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;doug_life:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note this is from 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rramadass:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A thesis supervisor stealing from his own student and making a business&amp;#x2F;money out of it is lowest of the low. I don&amp;#x27;t understand these kind of people. What harm is there in crediting somebody for their work&amp;#x2F;contributions (especially when they are the main protagonist) even if you make money out of it through your &amp;quot;business acumen&amp;quot;? Where does this sort of mean mentality come from?&lt;p&gt;Speaking personally, i have great regard and respect for the folks who started the Open Source Software movement (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Open-source_software_movement" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Open-source_software_movement&lt;/a&gt;) and its progenitor Free Software Movement (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Free_software_movement" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Free_software_movement&lt;/a&gt;). They urged&amp;#x2F;convinced others to join them with the result that Computing&amp;#x2F;Software became accessible to all (particularly in the developing world); &amp;quot;Software ate the World&amp;quot; because of their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arduinohistory.github.io/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009209</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D printing with unconventional vase mode</title>
      <link>https://vorpal.se/posts/2025/jun/23/3d-printing-with-unconventional-vase-mode/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This potentially means weaker parts. This will make vase mode useful for more than just simple vases. 3 Otherwise, none of this will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010173"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://vorpal.se/posts/2025/jun/23/3d-printing-with-unconventional-vase-mode/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ortusdux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are some great vase mode designs for gridfinity boxes that minimize filament usage and maximize print speed.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.printables.com&amp;#x2F;model&amp;#x2F;324102-vase-mode-parametric-gridfinity&amp;#x2F;files" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.printables.com&amp;#x2F;model&amp;#x2F;324102-vase-mode-parametric...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;addaon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A lot of these tricks are used to print UAV &amp;#x2F; RC wings with internal structure, often out of foaming filaments to reduce weight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://vorpal.se/posts/2025/jun/23/3d-printing-with-unconventional-vase-mode/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010173</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boom, bubble, bust, boom. Why should AI be different?</title>
      <link>https://crazystupidtech.com/2025/11/21/boom-bubble-bust-boom-why-should-ai-be-different/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Think about that for a moment. The internet bubble took 4. But does that make the AI bubble less scary than the internet bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008628"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://crazystupidtech.com/2025/11/21/boom-bubble-bust-boom-why-should-ai-be-different/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Havoc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It being a general purpose tech is what gives me pause&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ghm2180:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have a noob question. How can developed economies where populations levels have plateaued continue to be expected to post positive GDPs (and therefore add net new goods and services) yoy?&lt;p&gt;Homes as assets should pass on, higher cost services of today would be replaced by lower cost which only temporarily would increase units sold(but should eventually plateau because #units&amp;#x2F;person is not going to change). No component of the GDP will move.&lt;p&gt;If the fertility rate of developed economies is less than 2.1 then there should be wealth and asset accumulation among the younger people over time. The demand for newer goods and services from the people who get richer is inelastic: most goods and service&amp;#x27;s prices dont matter to the rich they buy them any ways, and it continues to keep becoming more inelastic.&lt;p&gt;So within like a several years the demand should just collapse as wealth accumulates a lot and people work less and become more price insensitive. Immigration is set to remain low to developed nations for the next 3-5 years.&lt;p&gt;This seems to be quite evident in Japan and EU already(though in the EU if you adjust the productivity for work hours the GDP becomes same as America&amp;#x27;s).&lt;p&gt;So why do people assume developed countries would even buy this much more new stuff. 1.5 trillion$ worth of new things over the next 5 years?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pinkmuffinere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; And Coreweave, the former crypto miner turned data center service provider, unveiled in its IPO documents earlier this year that it has borrowed so much money that its debt payments represent 25 percent of its revenues.&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a sentence. It starts out bad and just gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ManuelKiessling:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know this is semantics pedantry, but there has never been an „Internet bubble“, only an „Internet-related stock market bubble“.&lt;p&gt;It’s not as if there were ten million people using and&amp;#x2F;or building on the Internet, and then this bubble popped and for some years there were only ten thousand people on the Internet.&lt;p&gt;And I think the same is true for „AI usage&amp;#x2F;adoption“.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;toephu2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The fact that I&amp;#x27;m getting rate-limited every day even though my company has enterprise-level subscriptions to gemini, chatgpt, etc. tells me this bubble is far from popping. I predict within a year 80%+ of devs will be using LLMs to write most of their code for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hnburnsy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pets.com→Chewy&lt;p&gt;Webvan → Instacart, DoorDash, Amazon Fresh&lt;p&gt;Kozmo.com → Postmates, Uber Eats, Gopuff&lt;p&gt;Boo.com (fashion) → Farfetch, Net-a-Porter, ASOS&lt;p&gt;Broadcast.com → YouTube, Netflix, Twitch&lt;p&gt;The dot-com bubble didn’t prove the internet was a fad — it proved the internet was inevitable, but the valuations assumed adoption would happen in 2 years instead of 15–20. To me it feels like the AI inevitability will be much quicker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;molave:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From what I remember, in past bubbles that burst, everyone thought stocks will go up forever.&lt;p&gt;So, if people are wondering out loud (with widespread traction) if there&amp;#x27;s a bubble, there&amp;#x27;s probably not one. It may be self-fulfilling. The awareness of a potential bubble influences us to be more cautious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kittikitti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is another doomer article about AI. The author openly admits to using AI for the article and the irony isn&amp;#x27;t lost on me. How long will we be hearing about the AI bubble?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pedalpete:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder if we need a new term rather than bubble for these types of short-term over-invested sectors.&lt;p&gt;The Tulip mania (if it existed) was a bubble. It popped, it&amp;#x27;s never coming back. 
BeanieBabies was a bubble for the same reason. NFT art remains to be seen, but I think it was likely a bubble.&lt;p&gt;The internet was over-invested and decreased significantly when looking on a timeline of 5-7 years.&lt;p&gt;But outside of that, if you were to take the valuation of internet companies, it is greater than during the period we call the bubble.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;ll see the same with AI. There will most likely be a drop in valuations when looking at a medium term timescale, but long-term, I expect AI companies will be worth far more than they are today.&lt;p&gt;When the markets drop on a monthly scale, but then rebound, we don&amp;#x27;t call that a bubble, so why do we call this sub-decade decline a bubble?&lt;p&gt;Do you think we should have another term for this?&lt;p&gt;Same with the housing bubble, yes, it popped and lots of people got hurt, but those who were able to hang-on, I think, ended up ok, and on a moderately decent timeline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shigawire:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think I&amp;#x27;m asking for the impossible here... But is anyone trying to hedge risk in their personal finances?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not a real &amp;quot;investor&amp;quot; (index funds only) but I am feeling more willing to forgo gains to be more risk averse just based on my own neuroses.&lt;p&gt;Maybe I cash out and buy T-bills? Gold? Bullets? What&amp;#x27;s the non-crazy person equivalent?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hmm. The comparison makes sense in some ways, but the thing is - as much as I dislike AI, I think AI will stay, whereas the internet bubble seemed to subside without that much left from it, more or less. While I hate most of AI, it does have some use cases - the current hype will eventually subside or collapse, but I think the core use cases will most likely remain.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;All but Alphabet have seen big share declines in the past month. Microsoft is down 12 percent, Amazon is down 14 percent, Meta is down 22 percent, Oracle is down 24 percent&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;That fluctuates anyway and profits are made by some - nothing new here.&lt;p&gt;I think the world needs to detach from the stock markets though. That may not seem realistic right now, but if you look at the current US president and the ties to superrich, we really have a huge problem now. A few parasitize on the masses. That can not be sustained. It is not ethical.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It will spark a generation of innovations that we can’t yet even imagine.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I am not so sure. So far I successfully avoided AI, including becoming dependent on AI - I am not. So that is good.&lt;p&gt;I can not really see what &amp;quot;innovation&amp;quot; would make me want to embrace AI. Perhaps I can be forced into it, but right now I am happy avoiding it.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Because we humans are pretty good at predicting the impact of technology revolutions beyond seven to ten years.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;No, we really are not.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Not only does the AI bubble in 2025 feel like the internet bubble in 1999&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It is still not the same.&lt;p&gt;I feel the article is falling apart there. It tries too much to compare to the 1999, but it is not the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mattmaroon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One difference is most of the companies listed are old, long standing, well-performing businesses. Pets.com had potential, Apple, Amazon, and Google had large amounts of revenue even 3 years ago.&lt;p&gt;The bubble may deflate but every company mentioned will still be standing, whereas in 1999 many of them were basically Ponzi schemes relying on further investor dollars to subsidize losses. All this AI spending will hurt some investors if the bubble pops but just make for a few bad quarters for the big tech cos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fundamentally they seem different. The web looked like it had the potential to make lots of money but no one knew exactly how.&lt;p&gt;AI literally does people&amp;#x27;s jobs for them. There&amp;#x27;s not much imagination required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vjvjvjvjghv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What’s really scary is the money that’s being invested vs the .COM bubble. In the end 90s 100 million was a huge investment. Now it seems every AI company immediately a billion dollar and more valuation. There was a time when this was called “unicorn”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zahirbmirza:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am very grateful how the title of the actual article linked saved 40 minutes reading the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baxtr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No, it doesn’t. Go and actually read the crazy story about startups like Global Crossing.&lt;p&gt;Crazy amount of funding, little to no revenue, no competitive moat, no demand.&lt;p&gt;Compare that to today, and you see only the crazy amount of funding part is the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mancerayder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I grew up in the 90&amp;#x27;s and remember being a computer nerd BEFORE the .com bubble, and starting my career precisely after it burst.  Let me tell you one difference I personally am experiencing that differentiates the two.  Note, this is a pro-&amp;#x27;we&amp;#x27;re in a bubble&amp;#x27; stance:&lt;p&gt;In the late 90&amp;#x27;s and early 2000&amp;#x27;s, businesses were SALIVATING to get online, individuals were finding new ways to benefit and profit from it, and massive investment was being made to facilitate what was inevitable:  an interconnected network of everything.  Do you remember faxing things ?  Paper mail?  People half in the know were pushing the Boomers and older Gen-X types to get on with it and modernize.&lt;p&gt;Now?  Not only are people not CLAMORING for more AI, it&amp;#x27;s that The Powers that Be are forcing it down our throats.  At work, we have mandatory AI training, we have people getting promoted for promoting extremely dubious AI solutions both internally and on our product.  I log into ANY web site now, whether I&amp;#x27;m shopping for a vacuum cleaner or logging into a vendor website, and I get AI shoved in my face, from from &amp;quot;assistant&amp;quot; I have to interact with before typing &amp;quot;agent&amp;quot;  to new features I don&amp;#x27;t care about.&lt;p&gt;Is there some truth, some merit?  Absolutely. But my red flag I&amp;#x27;m trying to raise is this:  never did it feel FORCED in the 90&amp;#x27;s, there was a salivation from individuals to get more online, and a reluctance from institutions like elementary and high schools to get with the program.&lt;p&gt;Now?  Corporations large and small are shoving it down our throats.  Why?  Well, to justify the crazy spending.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m no prophet and the world (and economy) are fundamentally unpredictable.  But I&amp;#x27;ll say this.  I&amp;#x27;m putting my money where my mouth is, and I&amp;#x27;ve put in an order to buy a 5 digit dollar amount of puts on a big &amp;#x27;AI&amp;#x27; type ETF, that&amp;#x27;ll expire in the Spring.  It&amp;#x27;s already wobbling and if you can&amp;#x27;t beat them, profit off of them when they stumble.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s absolutely something wrong in the current moment, even if AI &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; somehow the future. For one thing, the U.S. economy would probably be in a recession right now if it weren&amp;#x27;t for this insane AI spending.  It&amp;#x27;s wobbled with the recent Nvidia earnings release, and I think it is going to dip (not crash, but start dipping) soon.&lt;p&gt;The author wrote:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;None of these companies has proven yet that AI is a good enough business to justify all this spending. But the first four are now each spending $70 billion to $100 billion a year to fund data centers and other capital intensive AI expenses. Oracle is spending roughly $20 billion a year. &amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;In my opinion it&amp;#x27;s a theoretical arms race &amp;#x27;just because my competitor might win&amp;#x27;, and not based on anything certain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smrtinsert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe guard your investments, but the big question back then was &amp;quot;is the internet really that good, will it stick around&amp;quot; and the reality is it won argument hands down.  The same thing will prove true about AI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rafaelero:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Idk, we seem to be the at the cusp of autonomous driving. Transportation is like ~8% of world&amp;#x27;s GDP. Payroll is, what, 30% of that? It seems like we can already have the return on all AI investment by just conquering this one application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more_corn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ok, so if that prediction is true what actions did you take?&lt;p&gt;Identify the therefore part of the prediction and enumerate the three highest priority steps.&lt;p&gt;Have you determined that the stock market will crash and bought positions accordingly? Have you sold all your nvidia stock?
What are the implications in the broader economy and what steps have you taken?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wewewedxfgdf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yeah except I pay hard cash for multiple AI services and use them all day long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chasing0entropy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The internet was monumental and valuable, offering instant conveyance of media and data. AI is monumental, allowing instant access to near infinite data; but whether instant access is as valuable as instant conveyance yet alone five times the value, appears to be the question&lt;p&gt;Honestly anyone who thinks AI has intrinsic value to rival the GDP of nations is a bagholder in denial and I&amp;#x27;ll be happy to buy your puts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;biff1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There’s a bubble bubble and it will pop in 26.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skeeter2020:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This sort of reactionary post is a tiring as the motivating situation. Here&amp;#x27;s a big difference: aside from all the circular investments the companies at the root of AI have huge earnings and did so before the boom as well.It&amp;#x27;s convenient to say &amp;quot;Look at all these declines in the past month! The end is nigh!&amp;quot; - maybe expand your chart to 12 months or even 5 years. You can argue against Nvidia but if you do they&amp;#x27;ve made you look foolish 3 pivots in a row. Are companies very expensive right now? Absolutely. Are there a lot of frothy valuations and looming failures? Probably - I think so. Is this just like the Internet bubble? Beyond the generic basics, no.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bdangubic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;writing a “bubble” post is new monad tutorial - gotta write one to get some street cred&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mmooss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To say whether it&amp;#x27;s a bubble, we need to know the value of the technology.&lt;p&gt;The value of modern AI seems very high. That nobody knows how high, that they still haven&amp;#x27;t figured out applications, and that the technology and its tools are still far from refined, is normal for any new technology.&lt;p&gt;If you add the value of the potential political power gained by controlling AI, then the value to the owners and investors is astronomical. Many of the investors have demonstrated a strong motivation to sacrifice money for political power, for example by supporting nationalism that undermines a global economy that they benefit enormously from. Somewhere, I read someone explaining their investment by saying &amp;#x27;it&amp;#x27;s the greatest transfer of power in (modern) history&amp;#x27;. Also see: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45983700"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45983700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://crazystupidtech.com/2025/11/21/boom-bubble-bust-boom-why-should-ai-be-different/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008628</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
