<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:36:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Itiner-e: the Google Maps of Roman Roads</title>
      <link>https://itiner-e.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Itiner-e – The Digital Atlas of Ancient Roads Itiner-e aims to host the most detailed open digital dataset of roads in the entire Roman Empire. The data creation is a collaborative ongoing project edited by a scholarly community. Itiner-e allows you to view, query and download roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864341"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://itiner-e.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://itiner-e.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 09:46:04</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864341</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source has a growing problem with LLM generated issues</title>
      <link>https://github.com/opencontainers/runc/issues/4990</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My personal opinion is we shouldn't accept anything LLM-generated, but this is probably not the common position of most @opencontainers/runc-maintainers, so we should probably consider LLM-generated code and issues separately. IMHO, we should close all LLM-generated issues as spam, because even if they are describing real issues the entire issue description contains so much unneeded (and probably incorrect) information that it'd be better if they just provided their LLM prompt as an issue instead. , they understand what their patch does and was able to write the code themselves).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871531"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/opencontainers/runc/issues/4990'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CGamesPlay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I make a lot of drive-by contributions, and I use AI coding tools. I submitted my first PR that is a cross between those two recently. It&amp;#x27;s somewhere between &amp;quot;vibe-coded&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;vibe-engineered&amp;quot;, where I definitely read the resulting code, had the agent make multiple revisions, and deployed the result on my own infrastructure before submitting a PR. In the PR I clearly stated that it was done by a coding agent.&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t imagine that any policy against LLM code would allow this sort of thing, but I also imagine that if I don&amp;#x27;t say &amp;quot;this was made by a coding agent&amp;quot;, that no one would ever know. So, should I just stop contributing, or start lying?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vineyardmike:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve seen an uptick in LLM generated bug reports &lt;i&gt;from coworkers&lt;/i&gt;. A employee of my company (but not someone I work with regularly) used one of the CLI LLMs to search through logs for errors, and then automatically cut (hundreds!) of bugs to (sometimes) the correct teams. Turns out it was the result of some manager&amp;#x27;s mandate to &amp;quot;try integrating AI into our workflow&amp;quot;. The resulting email was probably the least professional communication I&amp;#x27;ve ever sent, but the message was received.&lt;p&gt;The only solution I can see is a hard-no policy. If I think this bug is AI, either by content or by reputation, I close without any investigation. If you want it re-opened, you&amp;#x27;ll need to  IRL prove its genuine in an educated, good-faith approach that involves independent efforts to debug.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;If you put your name on AI slop once, I&amp;#x27;ll assume anything with your name on it is (ignorable) slop, so consider if that is professionally advantageous&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lofties:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sidenote, but I love that in a GitHub issue discussing banning the use of LLMs, the GitHub interface asks if there&amp;#x27;s anything I&amp;#x27;d like to fix with CoPilot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SoftTalker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think everything has a growing problem with LLM&amp;#x2F;AI generated content. Emails, blog posts, news articles, research papers, grant applications, business proposals, music, art, pretty much everything you can think of.&lt;p&gt;There’s already more human produced content in the world than anyone could ever hope to consume, we don’t need more from AI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dropbox_miner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Curious to know if others are seeing a similar uptick in AI slop in issues or PRs for projects they are maintaining. If yes, how are you dealing with this?&lt;p&gt;Some of the software that I maintain is critical to container ecosystem and I&amp;#x27;m an extremely paranoid developer who starts investigating any github issue within a few minutes of it opening. Now, some of these AI slop github issues have a way to &amp;quot;gaslight&amp;quot; me into thinking that some code paths are problematic when they actually are not. And lately AI slop in issues and PRs have been taking up a lot of my time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dropbox_miner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There seems to be a bot that routinely creates huge LLM generated Issues on runc github:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;containerd&amp;#x2F;containerd&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;12496" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;containerd&amp;#x2F;containerd&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;12496&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And honestly, its becoming annoying&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/opencontainers/runc/issues/4990</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 02:10:59</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871531</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Trilogy Studio, open-source browser-based SQL editor and visualizer</title>
      <link>https://trilogydata.dev/trilogy-studio-core/#screen=dashboard-import&amp;import=https%3A%2F%2Ftrilogy-data.github.io%2Ftrilogy-public-models%2Fstudio%2Fdemo-model.json&amp;dashboard=demo_dashboard&amp;modelName=demo-model&amp;connection=duckdb</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://trilogydata.dev/trilogy-studio-core/#screen=dashboard-import&amp;import=https%3A%2F%2Ftrilogy-data.github.io%2Ftrilogy-public-models%2Fstudio%2Fdemo-model.json&amp;dashboard=demo_dashboard&amp;modelName=demo-model&amp;connection=duckdb</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 23:26:48</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870334</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sued by Nintendo</title>
      <link>https://www.suedbynintendo.com/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.suedbynintendo.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 00:13:11</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870675</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to maintain good vision amidst the myopia epidemic</title>
      <link>https://ssathe.substack.com/p/vision-in-the-digital-age</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ssathe.substack.com/p/vision-in-the-digital-age</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 01:20:18</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871107</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If You're Not Active, You're Sick – You Just Don't Know It Yet</title>
      <link>https://howardluksmd.substack.com/p/if-youre-not-active-youre-sick-you</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://howardluksmd.substack.com/p/if-youre-not-active-youre-sick-you</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 21:56:29</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869587</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: DroidDock – A sleek macOS app for browsing Android device files via ADB</title>
      <link>https://rajivm1991.github.io/DroidDock/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DroidDock Browse Android files on macOS with style A beautiful, native macOS application for browsing and managing your Android device files via ADB. Fast, intuitive, and powerful. 📦 Download for macOS ⭐ View on GitHub Version 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870925"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://rajivm1991.github.io/DroidDock/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rajivm1991.github.io/DroidDock/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 00:51:33</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870925</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the UK Lost Its Shipbuilding Industry</title>
      <link>https://www.construction-physics.com/p/how-the-uk-lost-its-shipbuilding</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a time, this system had allowed UK shipbuilders to produce ships more cheaply and efficiently than almost anywhere else. Dutch shipbuilding was “technologically the most advanced in Europe,” and Dutch shipbuilders could build ships 40-50% cheaper than English ones. Structure of UK shipbuildingThe structure of the UK’s shipbuilding industry reflected the conditions it operated under.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871141"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.construction-physics.com/p/how-the-uk-lost-its-shipbuilding'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.construction-physics.com/p/how-the-uk-lost-its-shipbuilding</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 01:23:58</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871141</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Git history was a mess of 'update' and 'fix' – so I made AI clean it up</title>
      <link>https://github.com/f/git-rewrite-commits</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;$ npx git-rewrite-commits AI-powered git commit message rewriter using GPT Automatically rewrite your entire git commit history with better, conventional commit messages using AI. git/hooks/post-commit to automatically improve your last commit message: #. /bin/sh # Clean up the last 5 commits before pushing echo "🔧 Improving commit messages before push.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871084"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/f/git-rewrite-commits'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;greazy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve never seen a single character github username. I thought there was always a minimum number of characters!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pton_xd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think this is the beginning of the end of Github. Who has time to read through all these new vibe-coded projects and tools? The READMEs alone are basically essays. You can always get a chuckle or two if you read long enough though, so there&amp;#x27;s that...&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;p&gt;- OpenAI for providing the GPT API&lt;p&gt;- The conventional commits specification&lt;p&gt;- The git community for powerful version control tools&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The future of sharing code is probably dead. Everything is write-only now. Vibe it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cube00:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Perfect for [...] improving repository maintainability.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This misses the whole point of using commit messages to record intent.&lt;p&gt;At least with a bunch of &amp;quot;fixed it&amp;quot; commits I know what I&amp;#x27;m in for. This only fools yourself and others into thinking the repository was well maintained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/f/git-rewrite-commits</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 01:17:53</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871084</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work after work: Notes from an unemployed new grad watching the job market break</title>
      <link>https://urlahmed.com/2025/11/05/work-after-work-notes-from-an-unemployed-new-grad-watching-the-job-market-break/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I followed the right people. That slow pressure matters. The OECD data shows that occupations with more routine, codifiable tasks have grown less and paid worse than occupations that rely more on social skill or physical presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870863"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://urlahmed.com/2025/11/05/work-after-work-notes-from-an-unemployed-new-grad-watching-the-job-market-break/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 23 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anonymous_343:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Where I work we desperately need two new graduates for embedded controls jobs on-site in the US. We&amp;#x27;re very picky, looking for aptitude rather than specific skills. But over the next year we definitely need two and our preference is new graduates.&lt;p&gt;Just my 2 cents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pizlonator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What we cannot know is: which of these are we seeing:&lt;p&gt;- Just another recession, nothing to do with AI or automation. It&amp;#x27;ll pass and things will be back to normal.&lt;p&gt;- A massive move of well-paid jobs away from western countries.&lt;p&gt;- A massive move of well-paid jobs to automation and AI.&lt;p&gt;What an &amp;quot;exciting&amp;quot; time to be alive&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mproud:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m not saying people should get jobs they are way overqualified for, but I believe there are many in these situations who choose to be unemployed rather than work in jobs that they could do in their industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trentnix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Warning, rant ahead. Not sure if it’s the wisdom of a few decades of experience or if I’m just jaded in the latter half of my career. It’s probably some of both.&lt;p&gt;My heart breaks for new grads. With AI tools, new grads are better equipped to be productive and provide value early in their career than they ever have been. It has genuinely enabled all workers to be productive in areas where learning curves and complexity would have been insurmountable.&lt;p&gt;You should see companies putting the accelerator down on building and trying new things and new markets. But no, it’s layoffs and reductions and reorganizations. Everyone is reading from the same script.&lt;p&gt;Few in the C-suite wax philosophically anymore about how their people are the lifeblood of their companies. Instead, it’s en vogue to plot how to get rid of people. They think making aoftware is just an assembly line. They treat software professionals like bodies to throw at generic problems.&lt;p&gt;Every business plan is some sort of hand-waiving of “AI” or a strategy that treats customers like blood bags, harvesting value via dark patterns and addiction.&lt;p&gt;The result is that most software is anti-user garbage. Product teams emphasis strategies to ensure “lock-in”, not delivery of value. American business software  culture is woefully broken, and I struggle to make sense of how we got here.&lt;p&gt;I want to build software for people. I want to use software built for people. That used to be the recipe for success and employment opportunity. Now, employment as a software professional feels more like a game of musical chairs than a competition that values capability and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;windowshopping:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Two initial thoughts:&lt;p&gt;1. This author&amp;#x27;s writing is extremely, uncommonly good. Good enough to write a book and have it sell. &amp;quot;Competing with the past of the economy,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;residual behaviour of a world that treated labour as sacred,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;immigration without immigrants&amp;quot; -- there are many elegant turns of phrase here. This is a very skilled writer.&lt;p&gt;2. His resume is designed poorly. Have a look. I&amp;#x27;m not surprised his job search has been unsuccessful when his resume looks like an essay. OP, you gotta cut that text down by like 70% and put more highlights. This is the world of tiktok and instagram reels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;etothepii:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; For most of the industrial era, you could assume that any large physical operation, like a warehouse, would need a certain number of human bodies to move boxes and drive forklifts.&lt;p&gt;Were there forklifts for most of the industrial era? Given they were invented in 1917 (according to ChatGPT), No.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I don&amp;#x27;t think it is &amp;quot;playing by the rules&amp;quot; to get a career specific education.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lvl155:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Came out right after dotcom bust. It was really disappointing when I learned that corporate America simply moves on to the next graduating class. All the recruiting mechanisms in place means you’re going to get burned pretty bad if you miss that hiring wave. Some of my classmates took years to find something long term. You’re so much better off taking a year off from school to reset. As most things in life, timing is everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mike_hearn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great article, well written. I&amp;#x27;d certainly consider interviewing this guy - if I was hiring. Based on the other comments it&amp;#x27;s worth noting a few things:&lt;p&gt;1. Ahmed seems to be in the UK, not the USA. H1Bs don&amp;#x27;t affect him. This isn&amp;#x27;t obvious because he talks about the USA. However, the mass immigration into the UK might have impacted him by saturating the low skill markets such that everyone else has to fight over the remaining high skill jobs.&lt;p&gt;2. His internships and projects have all been ML&amp;#x2F;AI, with his most recent at DeepMind. It&amp;#x27;s not obvious from the article that he&amp;#x27;s been one of the people working on automating everyone else out of a job; an ironic twist given his predicament (I&amp;#x27;m sympathetic but to some extent, those of us who live by the sword...)&lt;p&gt;3. The British economy is in the toilet at the moment. This is the most likely reason he can&amp;#x27;t find a job but it doesn&amp;#x27;t get a mention at all, which is curious. It doesn&amp;#x27;t make much economic sense to grow a corporate presence in the UK currently given that Labour is raising taxes, attacking the private sector, imposing heavy regulation on the tech industry and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alyxya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To the people at the top, the job market is a statistic. They can&amp;#x27;t feel empathy on an issue they&amp;#x27;re so disconnected from, so they just think it&amp;#x27;s not their problem, or there isn&amp;#x27;t much they can do about it. Technological innovation is supposed to mean society can produce more with less work, so in theory everyone&amp;#x27;s lives could end up better off over time where we could all work less and get more, but in practice, I see more meaningless work created and wealth continues to consolidate at the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joshdavham:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Depressing article but it really captures the zeitgeist among recent tech grads.&lt;p&gt;I’m more of a mid-level dev, but I was recently unemployed for about 6 months and it felt brutal - and this is despite having a couple years of work experience. I can’t imagine how hard it would be for junior data scientists where there’s an even worse supply to demand ratio of applicants (and almost always with graduate degrees).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lifeisstillgood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Imagine you are an Alien playing Sims 17.0 - Earth Edition.  You’ve got the Industrial Revolution part mostly done, solar is going to hit big in Africa and Apac, the climate warning light came on but the manual says you can push that out a bit.&lt;p&gt;The problem is the economic transmission thing. Money was a great invention, but you are &lt;i&gt;close&lt;/i&gt; to enough energy production for every Sim to be fed and housed sustainably. Then you get some time for the upgrade pack but you can’t stop the oil thing right now and darn it they keep trying to do the work and dribble out wealth that way. What’s wrong with the plan? Industrial Revolution, silicon and robots level, everyone relaxes and we can do the moonbase&lt;p&gt;The problem is they keep thinking they need to create more instead of level off - sharing it more and entering maintenance mode&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bradlys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;It&amp;#x27;s the economy, stupid.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know why we need to be so dramatic about AI and automation. The reason you&amp;#x27;re not getting hired is because there&amp;#x27;s not enough positions and we have a huge amount of people in the industry. Tech is not exploding like it was in the 2000s and 2010s. It is a mature industry. That comes with mature industry issues like when the economy sucks, it doesn&amp;#x27;t grow anymore.&lt;p&gt;Have you noticed how we&amp;#x27;re still in a trade war? What about the government shutdown? The high interest rates? All time highs for cost of living? Wages not keeping up with costs at all for practically &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; profession? Dang, it&amp;#x27;s almost like if all the money going to AI stonkz wasn&amp;#x27;t happening... we&amp;#x27;d be in a recession... hmmmm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lacker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What jumped out at me is that the author had three internships. Those are essentially &amp;quot;entry-level positions&amp;quot;. If you do well at an internship, you typically get a job offer. If you don&amp;#x27;t do well, usually you can at least get some useful feedback.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not saying that everything is perfectly fine in the job market right now, it&amp;#x27;s just a lot more productive to focus on &amp;quot;what skill do I need to work on, that would have let me convert those internships into full time jobs&amp;quot;, rather than &amp;quot;man the job market is bad&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yesimahuman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really feel horrible for people who bet on CS and are hitting this job market right now. It&amp;#x27;s interesting, back when I was in elementary school in the 90&amp;#x27;s, parents of friends knew I had an interest in computers and would tell me becoming a programmer or IT person was a terrible job and I should avoid it. That was maybe true until it wasn&amp;#x27;t, and it ended up being highly lucrative. I can&amp;#x27;t tell if this is the same thing all over again or something completely different. What I think will be fascinating to watch is how the market for talented engineers changes as the bottom drops out and the pipeline of new grads dries up, or maybe it will balance out again? Or will these companies reap what they sow as they stop hiring and then cannot hire again because no one is entering the field anymore?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;themanmaran:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Honestly I think &amp;quot;applying for jobs&amp;quot; is becoming a thing of the past.&lt;p&gt;From the employer side, it&amp;#x27;s becoming incredibly difficult to find qualified inbound candidates. The main issues is AI + non-US spam. Every job listing we post attracts ~200 applicants, and maybe 5 US based humans.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a full time job to wade through the spam to find the actual people, especially when a lot of people are lying about location &amp;#x2F; experience on the resumes. The result is we&amp;#x27;ve just stopped taking incoming applications and only go outbound to find candidates.&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;#x27;re a small startup. I imagine any midsized+ company has 100x this problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aresant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Teleoperation makes this even stranger. . . There are people in one country sitting at desks, driving forklifts in another country . . . It feels like immigration without immigrants.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This is a fascinating point - if Neo &amp;#x2F; Tesla deliver a teleoperated hybrid at their &amp;lt;$30k price point the low-skill US labor force is going to be significantly disrupted on a shorter timeline than I would have previously estimated.&lt;p&gt;These are being pitched as &amp;quot;home robots&amp;quot; but clearly corporations will go all in - 24&amp;#x2F;7 operation (with multiple remote operators), no labor law &amp;#x2F; healthcare &amp;#x2F; pensions, spin up &amp;#x2F; down at will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;silisili:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not understanding the &amp;#x27;I did everything right and look what happened&amp;#x27; intro, though certainly not a unique feeling.  Tech hiring slowed at the tail end of 21 and the mass layoffs started in 22, 4 and 3 years ago respectively.  Studying to go into a market in an obvious downswing has predictable results.  Not that you should give up, but it&amp;#x27;s going to be switch majors or ride out the downturn. And that&amp;#x27;s not unique to now or even computer science(remember the MBA glut from the early 2000s?).&lt;p&gt;That said, I don&amp;#x27;t mean to be dismissive or condescending of the article as a whole, because I think this is a well written article that raises a lot of good points that are worth reading and thinking about.  I find myself with similar thoughts and it&amp;#x27;s a bit scary&amp;#x2F;depressing at times, even as someone nearly twice their age(in part because of my own offspring).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;struct:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;First, I&amp;#x27;m sorry you&amp;#x27;re having problems finding a job -- that sucks.&lt;p&gt;Second: consider that sometimes, the cost-benefit of automation depends on perspective. An example that I like to give is Ocado&amp;#x27;s automated grocery warehouses in the UK: impressive technology, very efficient, but during the COVID-19 pandemic - when everybody wanted online groceries - Ocado had to stop accepting new customers. They didn&amp;#x27;t have the capacity, and adding a new warehouse took years. The regular supermarkets hired people and bought vans, they were able to scale up.&lt;p&gt;Automation is great, but it can&amp;#x27;t help businesses adapt to novel situations. Corporate life is about cycles: the pendulum swings one way, then the other - we&amp;#x27;ve just swung hard over to the automation side for now. The best strategy: know the limits of AI tools, prove your agility and ability to do the things the tools cannot do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lmpdev:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(Australian not an American here)&lt;p&gt;You’d very quickly rise to the top of the public sector&lt;p&gt;My brother in law is only in his mid 20s and is in charge of half a dozen engineers&lt;p&gt;No nepotism (we honestly know no one) just leaping from the right firm to the public sector at the right time&lt;p&gt;Look for government consultant jobs or even better straight engineering roles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;margorczynski:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The most baffling thing is that even now the H1Bs, etc. are still pouring in. How can you say there is a shortage of IT talent and you need to import them where most grads can&amp;#x27;t find any work?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ipnon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is easier to start your own business than to get a job for a certain class of people in our industry. There is just not enough supply of jobs for people who “did everything right.” It’s a painful economic signal that US economy has run out of cushy Big Tech jobs and now needs an influx of innovative firms. This is difficult to explain to your relatives over Thanksgiving turkey but it is nonetheless the truth in my experience. If I could go back in time I would have gone to an Ivy League, gotten the proper internships, moved straight to the Bay during ZIRP, but alas I don’t have a Time Machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nine_zeros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The twentieth century spent a lot of intellectual and moral effort glorifying labour because economies needed people to show up every day. The twenty-first century is starting to build machines and systems that do not need quite as many of us.&lt;p&gt;And herein lies the real, consitent, and real anxiety among the youth - leading to lower birth rates. I myself feel the same.&lt;p&gt;And then I look at the elected corrupt pedophiles, and there is just no hope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GianFabien:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When you look beyond office jobs, you see many real opportunities.&lt;p&gt;For example, there is a housing crisis. Not enough trades persons, building supplies, capital to solve that problem.&lt;p&gt;The unemployment statistics aren&amp;#x27;t detailed enough to show IBM, MS, Facebook, Amazon, etc laying off tens of thousands of employees a year, each. Last I read, over 500,000 staff have been laid off in the past couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://urlahmed.com/2025/11/05/work-after-work-notes-from-an-unemployed-new-grad-watching-the-job-market-break/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 00:43:59</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870863</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iran faces unprecedented drought as water crisis hits Tehran</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4p2yzmem0o</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Officials are pleading with citizens to conserve water as the crisis deepens. "Some nights we might decrease the water flow to zero," he said. "A crisis long foreseen Iran's water crisis has been decades in the making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871043"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4p2yzmem0o'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arubis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I cannot imagine the logistical nightmare of evacuating a metro area with 16 million people. Where do they go? Where has sufficient water to slake the thirst of that many?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rayiner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I find Iran to be a truly baffling civilization. Iranians are so educated and orderly, but the country punches so below its weight class in terms of prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;toomuchtodo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Tehran_water_shortage" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Tehran_water_shortage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4p2yzmem0o</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 01:11:52</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871043</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask HN: What Are You Working On? (Nov 2025)</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869146</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;com/anthropics/claude-code/issues/712 https://github. I currently have several hundred daily players and growing. I just launched a ”community puzzle” feature to let players help build new puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869146"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869146'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;justhw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve working on an AI Thumbnail Generator for making YouTube thumbnails and social media images the last few months. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thumbnail.ai&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thumbnail.ai&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;echoes-byte:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m building Culink — a platform for curated link collections.&lt;p&gt;Not random bookmarks, but organized, verified, and shareable link sets.
Think “Notion meets Pinterest, but for the web itself.”&lt;p&gt;Still early (27 collections so far), but people have already started creating their own.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.culink.io" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.culink.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ramoz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;After creating the feature request for Claude Code hooks[1] a few months back, Cupcake is nearly ready for release.&lt;p&gt;Cupcake is a governance&amp;#x2F;policy-enforcement layer for agents. Its innovation is binding OPA&amp;#x2F;rego to agent runtimes (via hooks).&lt;p&gt;I do not believe we will every strictly rely on &amp;quot;better&amp;quot; models in the wild without deterministic guarantees or ways for enterprises to factor in their own alignment - system prompts dont cut it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;eqtylab&amp;#x2F;cupcake" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;eqtylab&amp;#x2F;cupcake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the formal release here in a couple of weeks.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;anthropics&amp;#x2F;claude-code&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;712" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;anthropics&amp;#x2F;claude-code&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;712&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;primaprashant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Building a docs website [1] for my speech-to-text CLI tool, hns. I use it 5-10 times daily to transcribe my voice, and a few developer friends I&amp;#x27;ve shared it with have also adopted it for daily use. They like that it runs in the terminal and keeps all data local. So, felt like I should write down guides for new users to get started quickly and to highlight key use cases.&lt;p&gt;Building this documentation website using Docusaurus. This is my first time using Docusaurus, and it feels like a very nice tool for quickly developing a documentation website.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hns-cli.dev&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hns-cli.dev&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;czhu12:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve been working on &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canine.sh" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canine.sh&lt;/a&gt; which is a free, open source Heroku alternative for 2 years now.&lt;p&gt;It’s exactly the product I wish I had when I started my previous company. Running on PaaS is incredible for devex but the pricing is bonkers, and the vendor lock in makes it really hard to deal with annual price increases. We spent close to 400k &amp;#x2F; year for just 128GB combined fleet in our last startup on Heroku.&lt;p&gt;Canine tries to get the best of both worlds: developer friendly PaaS with no lockin or price gouging.&lt;p&gt;Just added build packs as a build option recently.&lt;p&gt;Also got a sponsorship from the portainer folks which lets me work on this close to full time&lt;p&gt;Hoping this saves someone the headache I had two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;absoluteunit1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Building &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typequicker.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typequicker.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted a typing application that’s both more than typing random words and is data-focused so I built this.&lt;p&gt;The more you type, the more the analytics system learns about your typing patterns and generates natural text to target those weakpoints (SmartPractice mode).&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of variety as well; you can practice typing code in any programming language, or type text of various topics, use custom text, etc).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;omustardo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A multiplayer game prototype, written in Rust, using Bevy + egui for graphics. Think of it as a bare bones implementation of a game like Runescape, mostly to test out current LLM capability.&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#x27;t found much value in LLMs for coding beyond very self contained tasks, but some people speak highly of it, and I want to be sure that I&amp;#x27;m not missing out. So from time to time I give new tools a try. This time is &amp;quot;Claude Code on the web&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve put in an estimated 50 hours so far. It has a client and an authoritative server. The client displays 3D graphics with some placeholder models. From the client, you can click on tiles and move to them, or click on enemies to pathfind and attack them. You can right-click on tiles or monsters to open a menu with options (attack, trade, move). There are some unit tests and a few integration tests.&lt;p&gt;Right now the issues that Claude has been unable to resolve after a few attempts are:
* Attack animations. I&amp;#x27;m trying to get it to raise and then lower a rectangular block to simulate a sword attack. It really doesn&amp;#x27;t get it, and it&amp;#x27;s harder to write tests for compared to movement and server-client networking.
* &amp;quot;Entity interpolation&amp;quot;. Rather walking entities instantly moving from tile to tile, movement should flow smoothly.&lt;p&gt;I have Claude Pro ($20&amp;#x2F;mo) which let me make a few commits per day. After a few days of that, Anthropic offered $250 in credits to promote &amp;quot;Claude Code on the web&amp;quot;. The credits expire after two weeks. I&amp;#x27;m now five days into that period and have gone through $50 in credits. It is heavily rate limited and frequently locks me out for multiple hours after only a few interactions, but it&amp;#x27;s free credits so I can&amp;#x27;t really complain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sakopov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Every time I talk acquaintances, friends and family members about finances I&amp;#x27;m always shocked at how little people know about basic things like tax brackets, 401Ks, IRAs, ETFs, compounding interest, debt management and etc. So I decided to write a financial literacy&amp;#x2F;education book with a bit of humor and easily comprehensible language to distill some of these topics. I&amp;#x27;m about 1 month into it and try to write a chapter a week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kraddypatties:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We&amp;#x27;ve been tinkering with building realtime talking head models (avatar models, etc.) for a while now, and finally have something that works (well enough)! Operates at ~2x realtime on a 4090, significantly faster than that on enterprise grade GPUs.&lt;p&gt;You can try it yourself at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;playground.keyframelabs.com&amp;#x2F;playground&amp;#x2F;persona-1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;playground.keyframelabs.com&amp;#x2F;playground&amp;#x2F;persona-1&lt;/a&gt; and there&amp;#x27;s a (semi)technical blog post at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.keyframelabs.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;persona-1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.keyframelabs.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;persona-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main use case we designed for was language learning, particularly having a conversational partner -- generally we&amp;#x27;ve found that adding a face to the voice really helps trigger the fight or flight response, which we&amp;#x27;ve found to be the hardest part of speaking a new language with confidence.&lt;p&gt;But in building out the system around the model to enable that use case (tool use on a canvas for speaking prompts and images, memory to make conversations less stale, etc.), we think there&amp;#x27;s potential for other use cases too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rriley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m building &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;unrav.io" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;unrav.io&lt;/a&gt; : A tool to fight information overload.&lt;p&gt;It lets you turn any article, YouTube video, or PDF into summaries, mindmaps, podcasts, chat conversations or infographics that match how you learn with just one click.&lt;p&gt;We just launched this week the Chrome extension so you can do all this in one click on any page, no login needed (with generous freemium usage).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;unrav.io" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;unrav.io&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chromewebstore.google.com&amp;#x2F;detail&amp;#x2F;unravio&amp;#x2F;mbnapibcjcfednnnohpabfgihdcbjoci" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chromewebstore.google.com&amp;#x2F;detail&amp;#x2F;unravio&amp;#x2F;mbnapibcjcf...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would love feedback from fellow builders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;omgbear:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m making a game finally! Merge-three + village sim.&lt;p&gt;Hoping to actually take this one to something polished as opposed to the many half-finished prototypes littering my git repo over the years. I&amp;#x27;ve discovered (always knew?) that heavily cutting scope is the best way, and been successful thus far.&lt;p&gt;It gets pretty boring&amp;#x2F;unbalanced by ~150 turns, but I have some ideas on how to fix. I&amp;#x27;m still playing with ways to help de-clutter the board and make use of the economy aspects.&lt;p&gt;After some false starts with ai-gen art, I had fun learning to color the pixels myself. The process wasn&amp;#x27;t as scary as I&amp;#x27;d thought and the results are better than I hoped.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tower3.dreamofninjas.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tower3.dreamofninjas.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by TripleTown from the wonderful studio Spry Fox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sbinnee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am finally making my own blog. I have been only planning for ages. I found that I had a lot to say for the past years working on AI, and I want to record them somewhere. I do not expect a lot of visitors or at all in fact. The blog is going to be just for me to remember stuffs and to keep track of them.&lt;p&gt;I am using hugo to build suckless static pages. LLM helped me so that I don&amp;#x27;t need to read all their docs. I haven&amp;#x27;t finished it yet nor posted a single blog. But there will be one soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hewwwww:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I continue to work on My Financé, my personal finance tool.&lt;p&gt;I’ve been struggling to find substantive traction, so I’m trying to niche down to make the tool really helpful for people who want to quit their jobs.&lt;p&gt;I built a rudimentary planning and forecasting engine, and am trying to run paid ads to see if the signals resonate with people.  I don’t love ads, but maybe trying to understand them will further inform my opinion on them.&lt;p&gt;One thing I would love to come up with is a way to make the app fully local first, while continuing the ability to sync accounts via plaid. It would be great to not be able to see people’s data at all. Im trying to figure out if there is a good user experience I could provide while minimizing the amount of data I actually have access too. Maybe this feature won’t matter to my primary customers though, I’m not really sure.&lt;p&gt;I still have a ton of fun working on it, and if it never really makes any money I consider it a great success for my personal learning.&lt;p&gt;Link for the curious:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;myfinancereport.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;myfinancereport.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;acarabott:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m working on a book about using WebViews for cross-platform music software GUIs. It has a particular focus on performance, which I gave a talk about at the Audio Developer Conference last year:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.arthurcarabott.com&amp;#x2F;adc-2024&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.arthurcarabott.com&amp;#x2F;adc-2024&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of it I am building a code generator to generate shared type definitions in C++ and TypeScript (plus serialization, comparison and cloning).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jesse__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been working on a 3D voxel-based game engine for like 10 years in my spare time.  At this point it&amp;#x27;s getting pretty close to being shadertoy for voxels.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;bonsai" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;bonsai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently ported the terrain generators to the GPU, and increased the visible volume to 1 billion voxels cubed.  I did a short YouTube video about it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=bLfgjWsM1PI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=bLfgjWsM1PI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a metaprogramming language which generates a lot of the editor UI for the engine. It&amp;#x27;s a bespoke C parser that supports a small subset of C++, which is exposed to the user through a &amp;#x27;scripting-like&amp;#x27; language you embed directly in your source files. I wrote it as a replacement for C++ templates and in my completely unbiased opinion it is WAY better.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;poof" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;poof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;orblivion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Running OpenStreetMap off the grid (self-hosted to say the least) on a Raspberry Pi 500 (and to some extent a Pi Zero 2W) for Internet In a Box:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.linkedin.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;danielkrol_openstreetmap-activity-7380654210146648064-c2Mc&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.linkedin.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;danielkrol_openstreetmap-acti...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the street and satellite tiles are thanks to maps.black. The search uses Nominatim&amp;#x27;s sqlite3 mode. I was told that it&amp;#x27;s experimental only because it hasn&amp;#x27;t been tried in production yet, so I&amp;#x27;m sort of testing it in the process. So far I&amp;#x27;m only doing administrative boundaries and natural features, but so far so good! I&amp;#x27;m going to slowly add a few more types of POIs, I just don&amp;#x27;t want the database file to get too big.&lt;p&gt;Note that Internet in a Box has an OSM offering already, but the data is five years old and the tech makes it harder to update. As of today, there are much easier options on the table, and we get cool stuff like 3d buildings. Also, the search was much more limited.&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;internet-in-a-box.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;internet-in-a-box.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;maps.black&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;maps.black&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;nominatim.org&amp;#x2F;release-docs&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;customize&amp;#x2F;SQLite&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;nominatim.org&amp;#x2F;release-docs&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;customize&amp;#x2F;SQLite&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eru:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I recreated a little tool to simultaneously mount all the commits in a git repository as directories at the same time (but re-use the same inodes for the same content).&lt;p&gt;The code is at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;matthiasgoergens&amp;#x2F;git-snap-fs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;matthiasgoergens&amp;#x2F;git-snap-fs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original was in Python and actually had a decent excuse for existing for a very specific problem at work a few years ago.  The new version is in Rust and exists just for fun.&lt;p&gt;This was also a small experiment in coding with OpenAI&amp;#x27;s codex.  I wrote the Python original by hand---like a caveman.  Codex was mostly ok at the actual code, especially once I told it to make `cargo clippy` happy, but it needed lots of help with the design.  It kept insisting on extra complications and state.&lt;p&gt;But perhaps I&amp;#x27;m a bit unfair here, because I only figured out the nice and simple design after reflecting on the connection between Linux&amp;#x27;s fuse and git&amp;#x27;s design for a while when writing the original.  So it&amp;#x27;s only fair that the computer would also need some help to see how to match them up nicely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jclarkcom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been enjoying the breadth of projects made possible with AI, I&amp;#x27;ve cataloged over 200 of them created in 2025 here:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jonathanclark.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;ai-coding-million-lines-2025.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jonathanclark.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;ai-coding-million-lines-2025...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few of my recent favorites:
- swim lap counter in html&amp;#x2F;JS that uses the camera to watch you swim and count laps&amp;#x2F;timing
- video recorder that records your window&amp;#x2F;desktop and uploads a file to S3
- video conferencing app that allows a 2 year to click on a family member face and initiates a video conference using webRTC, STUN, and browser audio&amp;#x2F;video capture with automatic bandwidth adjustments (works on all platforms with pure HTML&amp;#x2F;JS).
- CUDA based ray tracer with HTML UI that can trace over 2m rays per second on my laptop for scientific study, allowing real-time display of optical parts.
- chat front-end for image models like gemini-pro and openai that take other images and text as references and generate a big library of options to chose from in seconds, I&amp;#x27;ve been using photoshop for decades but I tend to use this more now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;msyea:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m working a Garmin watch app to query all the rich data on the watch (health, physical, environmental, location sensors) from the watch + general AI assistant. Privacy focused using your own keys and Gemini. API calls direct from watch - no backend. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;untether.watch" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;untether.watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paulhebert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I recently launched a daily word puzzle!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tiledwords.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tiledwords.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s inspired by tile placement board games like Patchwork and crosswords. You rotate and move tiles to rebuild a broken crossword.&lt;p&gt;It’s free, web based, and responsive.&lt;p&gt;I currently have several hundred daily players and growing. My wife and I create the puzzles and I’m continuing to fix bugs and add new features.&lt;p&gt;I just launched a ”community puzzle” feature to let players help build new puzzles.&lt;p&gt;I’d love to know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chrivers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Raptor - a new (Free software) way to build things like:&lt;p&gt;* Disk images&lt;p&gt;* Liveboot isos&lt;p&gt;* Container images (docker&amp;#x2F;podman)&lt;p&gt;Many build products are supported, with more on the way:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chrivers.github.io&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;builders&amp;#x2F;index.html#compatibility" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chrivers.github.io&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;builders&amp;#x2F;index.html#compat...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It uses a syntax that is inspired by Docker, but significantly enhanced.&lt;p&gt;Take a look at:&lt;p&gt;* The project: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;chrivers&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;chrivers&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* The book: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chrivers.github.io&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;chrivers.github.io&amp;#x2F;raptor&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seanwilson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A tool for creating custom Tailwind-style color palettes for web and UI design that pass WCAG contrast requirements:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.inclusivecolors.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.inclusivecolors.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The interface is optimized to let you quickly explore and tweak multiple tints&amp;#x2F;shades at once so you can customize all colors exactly how you want e.g. try dragging vertically through the saturation curve in one motion to edit all the tints&amp;#x2F;shades at once, or shift whole curves horizontally by dragging between the dots on a curve.&lt;p&gt;It uses the HSLuv color space, where (unlike say HSL) the WCAG contrast stays the same when you change the hue and saturation sliders. This makes it much easier to explore accessible colors choices as you know only changes to the lightness slider will impact the contrast. You can also switch from the WCAG2 contrast checker to using APCA, which is meant to correct for inaccuracies in WCAG2, such as it being too forgiving for dark mode color combos.&lt;p&gt;Note the mobile version is more of a preview and the desktop version has more features.&lt;p&gt;I probably need to add something like a tutorial as there&amp;#x27;s  a lot going on, but I&amp;#x27;ve added more hints and tooltips recently. Open to feedback on what&amp;#x27;s initially confusing and what changes might help!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChristopherDrum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Continuing with my retro productivity software blog, Stone Tools: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stonetools.ghost.io" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stonetools.ghost.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was getting a little bored of retrocomputing discourse being so centered on gaming, so I&amp;#x27;m exploring the productivity software of the 8&amp;#x2F;16-bit era. I put real effort into learning and using the programs, giving my light-hearted but heartfelt assessment of its form and function for both its time and today.&lt;p&gt;Using the software inevitably gets me thinking about other things, and I explore those threads as well. For example, &amp;quot;Superbase on the C64&amp;quot; also discusses the legacy and promise of &amp;quot;the paperless office.&amp;quot; A couple of other posts got some nice traction here on HN, notably &amp;quot;Deluxe Paint on the Amiga&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;VisiCalc on the Apple 2&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m hoping to build a strong monthly readership, so I&amp;#x27;m putting in the work. It&amp;#x27;s been up for two months and five posts now, with a new one coming at the end of this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deepakrb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m working on &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;regularly.co&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;regularly.co&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; - A website made for inquisitive minds to get their daily puzzle fix. Still very much a WIP (mainly working on tuning the difficulty of puzzles to make it enjoyable for most). That being said I really do enjoy the unique combination of puzzles when I do them each day. I’m looking for feedback so if you do take a look please do let me know your thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m building a small rural ISP and web hosting service, as a way to learn about low-level networking stuff. I&amp;#x27;ve got an ASN + IP space, and am working out the details with a colo, local fiber provider, and some upstreams. Right now I&amp;#x27;m configuring the hardware itself (server, router, switch, etc) and learning all the bits and bobs (Proxmox, BGP, OPNsense, IXPs, etc)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BSTRhino:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;easel.games" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;easel.games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m making Easel, a 2D game programming language designed to match how humans, not computers, think about game logic. It also has automatic multiplayer. I&amp;#x27;ve been working on it for 3 years!&lt;p&gt;Easel feels like a declarative programming language even though it is imperative, because lots of useful game-oriented features are first class. Like behaviours - you just say `on Pointer { ... }` and you have a concurrently-executing coroutine that&amp;#x27;s lifetime is managed. But you don&amp;#x27;t think about any of that complexity, you just think of your entity as having a behaviour and go forth and make your game.&lt;p&gt;It also happens to have automatic multiplayer. Normally with multiplayer you have to worry about doing everything in a &amp;quot;multiplayer safe&amp;quot; way (i.e. be deterministic and only modify the things your side has authority over). My idea was to put all the multiplayer stuff in the programming language itself, underneath all your lines of code. This way, anything you write in that programming language can just be made multiplayer, automatically. So you can just pretend all your players are in one shared world, like a singleplayer game, and the engine does all the multiplayer for you. It was really difficult to make but it makes multiplayer so easy for you now.&lt;p&gt;Easel is my idea of how games should be made, or at least as close to the idea as I can achieve with 3 years of work, and I would love for more people to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xandrius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Currently working on a take on Pokémon GO + Pokémon Snap but for birding. The goal is to explore your neighborhood, find birds, take good photos of them all. Next month, I&amp;#x27;ll be doing an event to find a rare bird, excited to see how it goes!&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s still a small closed alpha, if anyone is interested: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;testers.birdlego.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;testers.birdlego.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a rough trailer of it: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=yVpR8aafFjI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=yVpR8aafFjI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;whenever.world&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;whenever.world&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s an explorable database of films, TV shows, books and board games based around their historical setting: where and when the thing is set. It&amp;#x27;s been incredibly complex and interesting getting the (messy) data, making sense of it and trying to design a UI to explore it.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stevebennett.me&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;26&amp;#x2F;whenever-exploring-times-and-places-in-film-and-books&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stevebennett.me&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;26&amp;#x2F;whenever-exploring-times-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bobnarizes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Building &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;floxtop.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;floxtop.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;, a Mac app that organizes your files and images.&lt;p&gt;It looks inside each file to see what it’s about, then moves it to the right folder with a single click.
Everything happens on your Mac, so nothing leaves your computer. No clouds, no servers.&lt;p&gt;It already works with images, Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) PDFs, ePubs, text, Markdown, and many other file types (30+) in English. Next I’m adding multi-language support.&lt;p&gt;If you have messy folders anywhere on your Mac, Floxtop can help.&lt;p&gt;Try it for free - requires macOS 14+ with Apple Silicon:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;taranntell&amp;#x2F;fallinorg&amp;#x2F;releases&amp;#x2F;download&amp;#x2F;1.0.0-demo-official&amp;#x2F;Floxtop-v1.0.0-demo.zip" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;taranntell&amp;#x2F;fallinorg&amp;#x2F;releases&amp;#x2F;download&amp;#x2F;1....&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;askonomm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Discovered in-door bouldering &amp;#x2F; rock climbing and now go 3x a week, am absolutely loving it! Because of that, I haven&amp;#x27;t really worked on any side projects in a while. Perhaps I don&amp;#x27;t need to? My job advances me plenty in my field, but it is a bit of a bitter-sweet feeling in a sense, like maybe I should try to squeeze more out of my free time somehow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869146</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 21:02:33</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869146</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: LLM Onestop – Access ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini, and more in one interface</title>
      <link>https://www.llmonestop.com</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.llmonestop.com</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-10 01:39:38</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871271</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Heart Association says melatonin may be linked to serious heart risks</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Date: November 4, 2025 Source: American Heart Association Summary: Long-term melatonin use for sleep problems may come with unexpected heart dangers. 5 times more likely to be hospitalized for heart failure. Long-Term Melatonin Use Linked to Higher Heart Failure Risk People who regularly take melatonin to improve sleep may face serious health risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867371"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;apatheticonion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d been taking 3mg slow release melatonin daily for years up until a few months ago. To be honest, I&amp;#x27;m not sure it has any significant effect.&lt;p&gt;Regular exercise and a consistent sleep routine (cardio, weight lifting, going to bed early, and waking up early) has been more effective for me.&lt;p&gt;According to my fitbit, my average sleep duration is 6hr 30min over the last 2 years, down from 7hr30. When I wake up, there&amp;#x27;s no going back.&lt;p&gt;The biggest contributor to my reduction in sleep is my job, which in the last few years added stack ranking and by-annual performance reviews which requires daily book keeping of my &amp;quot;company impact&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I also got an echo-cardiogram last week (unrelated) and it came back in top shape (have a calcium score test coming up). Not saying melatonin isn&amp;#x27;t a risk for cardio health, but as a male in his early 30s with a family history of heart disease, nothing seems to indicate an increase in damage in my case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lateforwork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sleep experts say it is not possible to draw conclusions about melatonin from this study&amp;#x27;s findings — it did not prove cause and effect. A more likely explanation of the results is that insomnia itself could be to blame. In that case, melatonin would be an “innocent bystander”.&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;well&amp;#x2F;melatonin-heart-health-study.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;well&amp;#x2F;melatonin-heart-heal...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smileyferret:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an abstract that hasn’t been peer-reviewed… based on prescription data for an over-the-counter medication. This will be horribly inaccurate because it will miss all the folks who just buy the medication on their own and never have it documented.&lt;p&gt;These TriNetX studies are usually garbage because they’re entirely dependent on how accurate&amp;#x2F;up-to-date the medical record is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;almosthere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;probably written by a statin exec. There is no reason to trust anything anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crdrost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;PSA that melatonin use was way out of control before this study was even published.&lt;p&gt;Sleep aid melatonin is shipped in pills containing ridiculous amounts of the stuff—I’ve seen 10, 12, and 20mg myself, Amazon has a 40mg fast dissolve and 60mg gummies.&lt;p&gt;This spikes your blood amount with 100x-1000x of your natural cycle of melatonin. Why? Because melatonin is not, repeat not, the signaling molecule that makes you sleepy. It responds to light levels and triggers the cascade of &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; molecules that make you sleepy, several hours after it peaks. So that&amp;#x27;s why the 100x overdose—you are trying to kick those secondary mechanisms into overdrive, “hey everyone it is black as the abyss of hell I guess we gotta sleep!!”, because Americans taking melatonin want to pop one just before bed and have it knock them out.&lt;p&gt;And it does that for like 2 or 3 days before your body starts down-regulating all of its sensitivities to those melatonin byproducts. Nerve cells like to be tickled, not zapped, when you shock them like this they react angrily.&lt;p&gt;You want to use melatonin to reinforce circadian rhythm and fight jet lag, you do it with amounts in the ~100 &lt;i&gt;micrograms&lt;/i&gt; range, slow release if you can find it, and you take that &lt;i&gt;at sunset&lt;/i&gt; and let it reinforce your normal cycle. If you&amp;#x27;re looking for an acute sleep aid, take a walk, get fresh air, drink water, and if those don&amp;#x27;t help pop a Benadryl&amp;#x2F;Unisom (it&amp;#x27;s the same drug either way). If you have doctor’s orders of course follow those, but if you&amp;#x27;re just trying to self-medicate that’s how you do it.&lt;p&gt;Absolutely unsurprising that punching your sleep apparatus in the gut once every day for five years increases some sort of stress on your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bilsbie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’d guess it’s just correlated with poor sleepers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;michaelcampbell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This whole thing is akin to the &amp;quot;I&amp;#x27;m just asking questions&amp;quot; crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cultofmetatron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;insomnia is also highly correlated with heart attack risk so there&amp;#x27;s that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pogue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I tried to make the title a little less hyperbolic than the article starts out, as it&amp;#x27;s not a published study and it&amp;#x27;s basically a huge meta analysis that has no other information on age range, dosage, other health problems, etc. But the implications are worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 17:40:38</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867371</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Software Foundation gets a donor surge after rejecting federal grant</title>
      <link>https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The support from the Python community in response has been overwhelming,” Seth Larson told me last week. Please read and share their story. Their announcement also received 1,400 upvotes in Reddit’s Python subreddit and another 355 comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867277"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MarsIronPI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the brief reading of the article that I had time for, I couldn&amp;#x27;t find the exact reason why the grant was rejected.  Does anti-DEI automatically mean discrimination?  Call me naive, but as far as I can see, DEI isn&amp;#x27;t necessary for a volunteer project.  Why does it matter how many of a project&amp;#x27;s contributors are transgender?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buckle8017:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The grant simply required that the recipient comply with the equal protection clause of the constitution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;add-sub-mul-div:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It wasn&amp;#x27;t exactly the Streisand effect, but I remember thinking the whole flourishing of trans rights and acceptance between 2017 and 2021 never would have happened if Hillary had won. Is there a name for this phenomenon?&lt;p&gt;Did both parties implicitly understand up until 2017 that going too hard too fast is counterproductive?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 17:28:45</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867277</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups are pushing the boundaries of reproductive genetics</title>
      <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/biotech/genetically-engineered-babies-tech-billionaires-6779efc8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wsj.com/tech/biotech/genetically-engineered-babies-tech-billionaires-6779efc8</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 14:50:29</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865956</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Computer Church – Pennsylvania Computer and Technology Museum</title>
      <link>https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open by Appointment Fall 2025 Staff Sign-in Home of the Computer Museum ISEC250 Stock Market Computer DONNER 3500 Analog Computer RangeKeeper Mark 7 Reeves Electronic Analogue Computer: P-101 EAI Early Logo Hollerith Model 1 Card Punch Donner 3000 Analog Computer EAI TR-48 Analog Computer •O U R C O L L E C T I O N• ANALOG COMPUTERS Our collection of over 50 analog computers is the largest known collection in the world. READ MORE ANALOG SUPERPOWERS But this particular computer is very special for an entirely different reason. 1976 READ MORE Hollerith Tabulating Machine This is Hollerith personal copy of his article about the Tabulating Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868533"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 19:47:49</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868533</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drilling Down on Uncle Sam's Proposed TP-Link Ban</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TP-Link Systems told The Post it has sole ownership of some engineering, design and manufacturing capabilities in China that were once part of China-based TP-Link Technologies, and that it operates them without Chinese government supervision. That price point (and consistently excellent performance ratings) has made TP-Link a favorite among Internet service providers (ISPs) that provide routers to their customers. TP-Link rightly points out that most of its competitors likewise source components from China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867717"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 15 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;burnt-resistor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Per company government acquisition &amp;quot;bans&amp;quot; are stupid for PR and security reasons. Brand-specific banlists are whackamole when the same hardware and software will be immediately duplicated with another cat-walks-on-keyboard brand name that will disappear within a year.&lt;p&gt;Instead, there should be in-depth, enforced audit, compliance, and evaluation standards for gear for particular purposes. If it doesn&amp;#x27;t meet particular standard(s), then it can&amp;#x27;t be purchased or used.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BobbyTables2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Virtually every home router and a whole lot of small business routers should be considered “national security risks”.&lt;p&gt;TP-Link may be sore for getting singled out but they are certainly not unique.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nickpsecurity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;TP-Link Systems told The Post it has sole ownership of some engineering, design and manufacturing capabilities in China that were once part of China-based TP-Link Technologies, and that it operates them without Chinese government supervision.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Is that even possible? Or do you always have to be on good terms with the Chinese government to own engineering, design, and manufacturing capabilities in China?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SilverElfin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t like that TP Link routers regularly force you to accept new terms of service within their app. If you don’t, then you can’t access much of their configuration options. Basically you get locked out of your own device. I feel like these dark patterns should be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abridgett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll just leave this little NSA intercepting Cisco products reminder here:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arstechnica.com&amp;#x2F;tech-policy&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;photos-of-an-nsa-upgrade-factory-show-cisco-router-getting-implant&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arstechnica.com&amp;#x2F;tech-policy&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;photos-of-an-nsa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ComplexSystems:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t get what to make of this. Is it all just security theater? The idea of having consumer networking hardware that isn&amp;#x27;t riddled with security vulnerabilities seems to be a ship that sailed long ago. I doubt this move will prevent major nation states from hacking into whatever they want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imagetic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have TP-Link Deco&amp;#x27;s for our WiFi, sitting behind a Firewalla Gold. This has been by far the nicest, simplest at home setup I&amp;#x27;ve ever deployed. Do I love that I chose TP-Link? No. But price to purpose it was the best product available to me at the time.&lt;p&gt;If TP-Link gets banned, my concern is what that means for the massive market share in the US. Warranty? Software updates? Or maybe that action is what turns them into an agent of the state. Or do you horde all the hardware until its valuable like DJI parts are today?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chatmasta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TP-Link makes really solid products, and if you don’t want to use their firmware then almost all of them can easily flash OpenWRT. In fact most of their routers are built from OpenWRT anyway.&lt;p&gt;I installed their mesh Wi-Fi system for my parents recently and was really impressed how seamless the process was. It did involve making a cloud account which I wasn’t thrilled about, however.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bethekidyouwant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t get the end game here D-link isn’t any better. Are we heading for isp enforced hardware in our homes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cflewis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been really happy with the TP-Link smart plugs. I keep upgrading them as The Latest Standard That&amp;#x27;s Definitely The Real One This Time Trust Us Bro comes out, and the Matter ones are excellent. Getting an instant response from them is really nice. I see no reason to buy others.&lt;p&gt;I would buy only Hue but that&amp;#x27;s because I have more money than sense, and they don&amp;#x27;t actually make smart plugs last time I looked, they make plugs but label them all as lights in the app, which is more annoying than it sounds.&lt;p&gt;The real problem to solve ditching TP-Link _routers_ is that all routers are uniformly fucking awful, and all you are doing is choosing your particular poison. This is especially true after Apple exited the game so long ago. I use Google Wifi because it mostly works most of the time, but that&amp;#x27;s not glowing praise. But the world has become trained that rebooting a router once a week and praying that it works when it comes back is a perfectly normal state of affairs and we couldn&amp;#x27;t possibly do this any better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WheatMillington:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So much freedom in America lately. TP-Link, DJI, BYD, must be great to never have these options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;riskable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The real lesson here: If you&amp;#x27;re successful, &lt;i&gt;don&amp;#x27;t skimp&lt;/i&gt; on security&amp;#x2F;software! Also, don&amp;#x27;t abandon software&amp;#x2F;firmware security support for your products so quickly.&lt;p&gt;If I was in charge over at TP-Link, getting news that tens of thousands of MY company&amp;#x27;s routers were compromised would have me furious! I&amp;#x27;d be freaking out, making sure that we take immediate steps to improve software&amp;#x2F;firmware quality and to make sure we&amp;#x27;re in a constant state of trying to compromise our own hardware... To ensure no one else finds vulnerabilities before we do.&lt;p&gt;Instead, TP-Link seems to have just laughed and focused &lt;i&gt;strictly&lt;/i&gt; on profit margins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeroConcerns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t have any particular opinion on TP-Link (never used their products), but the idea that a low-cost vendor targeting home and SMB users is somehow a state-level agent trying to compromise those users... needs evidence.&lt;p&gt;I mean, in the case of actors like Huawei, you can at least credibly make the argument that the continued access of their support staff to internal provider networks is a significant risk, but that vector is &lt;i&gt;entirely&lt;/i&gt; absent here.&lt;p&gt;Sure, embedded firmware has been, is, and will continue to be a tire fire prone to embarrassing compromises, but containing those is mostly about notification and containment by government agencies (which the current US administration is doing their utmost best to kneecap) and&amp;#x2F;or large ISPs (which in the US have traditionally never cared).&lt;p&gt;Forcing &amp;quot;foreign&amp;quot; products off the market in favor of &amp;quot;domestic&amp;quot; replacements with the exact same, if not worse, flaws won&amp;#x27;t fix a thing, unless you put some pretty significant controls into place that nobody is willing to enforce or even outline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vjvjvjvjghv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If only there were US manufacturers that could produce things at a decent price and  didn&amp;#x27;t actively hate their customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ddtaylor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The company says it researches, designs, develops and manufactures everything except its chipsets in-house.&lt;p&gt;So, the plastic bits?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 18:17:44</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867717</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sega Master System</title>
      <link>https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only real candidate for this is an SG-1000 in different packaging that came out along the way. The Famicom doubled that to 2KB, and the Master System jumped it up to 8. The only addition on this side is that its palette information is stored in an independent “Color RAM” that only holds 32 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868259"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aledalgrande:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Was just a few days ago in a shop in Den Den town in Osaka, where they still sell original Master System, NES and PS1 games, so many memories!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 19:15:21</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868259</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Consciousness from AI</title>
      <link>https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On social media, people are using LLMs to generate posts just for impressions, instead of going through the process of finding sources and creating authentic content themselves. I want to bring back authentic forum posts, where people can share their ideas and thoughts, with less algorithmic influence than platforms like X. LLMs can be prompted into agreeing with you, which is less likely than with a licensed therapist - it's important to have human to human feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868271"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tyleo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve found the hesitation to shovel text into AI weird given the _lack_ of hesitation to shovel text into search engines.&lt;p&gt;Either case is weird in absolute terms but in relative terms, it all goes to the same place. The human-like nature of AI seems to make people realize this more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chance-Device:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was expecting something about &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; to protect your consciousness from (or during) AI use, but I got a short 200 word note rehashing common sentiments about AI. I guess it’s not wrong, it’s just not very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrloba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is everywhere. Even on birthday invites for my kids there&amp;#x27;s nonsense from an LLM. At work I review PRs with code that doesn&amp;#x27;t even run. Doing research is harder than ever as more and more references are completely made up.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re too lazy and too obsessed with getting ahead to use this technology responsibly in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tmaly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am perfectly okay with offloading low value mental work to an LLM just to recoup time to spend with my family.  The modern world has way too many demands that just suck up time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bukhmanizer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Culturally we are going through a phase where thought is getting massively devalued.  It’s all well and good to say “I’m using AI responsibly”, but it won’t matter if at the end of the day no one values your opinion over whatever ChatGPT spewed out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;satisfice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I always thought hacker culture was independent and skeptical. Somehow AI has turned a lot of them into drooling fanboys.&lt;p&gt;It’s embarrassing. Don’t rely on AI, guys. Have pride in yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thundergolfer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t a new problem at all. If you only started noticing it as a problem with &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot;, as the author apparently did, then you were blind to how our mediums and tools have always shaped us, alienated us from the world and each other, and made us dependent on mechanism. This has happened hugely already with television.&lt;p&gt;You can go back and read McLuhan, he&amp;#x27;s great, but a recent and more approachable book on this is _God, Human, Animal, Machine: Technology, Metaphor, and the Search for Meaning_.&lt;p&gt;Way back in 1969 the utopian vision of technology put humans at the centre. The Whole Earth Catalogue&amp;#x27;s slogan was “access to tools.” Just _tools_. That same year, technology put a man on the moon.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, if you realize the extent and the history of the problem, you see we&amp;#x27;re so far gone, miles away from getting a grip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delichon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This creates a sea of noise and misinformation that people unknowingly consume at scale.&lt;p&gt;The same objections apply to the written word. A culture that succeeded in not succumbing to writing and reading may indeed have been better off in the short term, depending on the quality of the memes. But it would have been at a competitive disadvantage to cultures that were permissive with knowledge transfer.&lt;p&gt;The main advantage of AI so far has been as a distiller of the knowledge embedded in the written word. It&amp;#x27;s another  leap in knowledge transfer. That&amp;#x27;s still a competitive advantage to any culture that doesn&amp;#x27;t abjure it. This particular consciousness intends to leverage the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nvllsvm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In the professional world, I see software developers blindly copying and pasting code suggestions from LLM providers without testing it, or understanding it.&lt;p&gt;When you see that, call them out on it. Not understanding copy+pasted code is one thing, but not testing it is a whole other level of garbage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noir_lord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m far too lazy to be able to responsibly use a machine that can give me semi-sensible answers.&lt;p&gt;I saw the danger of it as a form of learned helplessness down the line and swore off using LLM&amp;#x27;s for that reason, that and I feel no need to delegate my thinking to a machine that can&amp;#x27;t think and I &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; thinking.&lt;p&gt;Same reason snacks are upstairs in the kitchen and not in my office on the ground floor - I&amp;#x27;m too lazy and if they are easily available I&amp;#x27;ll eat them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 19:16:45</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868271</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lisbon Airport is turning away private jets inbound for the Web Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/the-lisbon-airport-is-turning-away-private-jets-inbound-for-the-web-summit-222136161.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lisbon Airport has been forced to turn some private jets away, sending flights to seek runway space at airports as far away as Badajoz, a Spanish city two hours away from Lisbon. That poses a problem for the Lisbon Airport. "Please be advised that there is currently a shortage of private jet slots during Web Summit at Lisbon Airport (LIS) and surrounding smaller airports," Web Summit organizers reportedly told attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867084"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/the-lisbon-airport-is-turning-away-private-jets-inbound-for-the-web-summit-222136161.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slater:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Some flights have had to land up to two hours away from the Portuguese capital.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;How embarrassing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/the-lisbon-airport-is-turning-away-private-jets-inbound-for-the-web-summit-222136161.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 17:09:53</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867084</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask HN: How do you get over the fear of sharing code?</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867176</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my repos are private just because I worry about other students being lazy and just ripping my hard work and claiming it as their own. That really pisses me off when I hear some horror stories like that. It's obviously easier for viewers to just see public code repos and browse without ever requesting access so I know I'm losing some traffic (from my portfolio site)I was thinking the alternative would be just linking my demo on my portfolio site as a proof of concept that yes I made it, yes it works, and if you're curious , here's a link to the code u can request independently of github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867176"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867176'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neilv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the thieves you worry about are actually going steal your code through LLM laundering, without even knowing who it was stolen from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kissgyorgy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Scott Hanselman have a good blog post about this suggesting you should detach yourself from your code:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.hanselman.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;you-are-not-your-code" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.hanselman.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;you-are-not-your-code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Especially true when working as an employee where you don&amp;#x27;t own your code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;siva7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You&amp;#x27;re severely overthinking. The Code isn&amp;#x27;t important. It&amp;#x27;s what you build with it that people care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snayan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People have already given you practical reasons why you&amp;#x27;re better off keeping it public. To answer your question as to how to get over your fear, you need to ask yourself what you&amp;#x27;re afraid of. You&amp;#x27;ve mentioned you&amp;#x27;re worried about someone ripping off your hard work and claiming it as their own. If you can understand the root of why the idea of that pisses you off, you will probably find it&amp;#x27;s an artificial construct of ego. Understand the root and the fear will loosen it&amp;#x27;s grip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;softwaredoug:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I worry about other students being lazy and just ripping my hard work and claiming it as their own. That really pisses me off when I hear some horror stories like that.&lt;p&gt;Make the code part of your professional marketing. It’s not code for code sake but to enable you to blog, speak, etc about something interesting. Then there’s little chance some theoretical thief is also communicating those ideas. And if you’re good at evangelizing yourself it SHOULD happen that someone steals your code. If anyone looks up the ideas, they’ll be inundated by content you created. The code is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bluedino:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wait until every line you write has to be code reviewed when you get a job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drbojingle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If it&amp;#x27;s not open source then don&amp;#x27;t make it public but if you want to lose your fear, just do it. It&amp;#x27;s not like it matters that much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delaminator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Truth: no-one really cares about your code&lt;p&gt;We publish code &lt;i&gt;so others can see it&lt;/i&gt;, the lazy and the productive.&lt;p&gt;Lazy people do not prosper, so don&amp;#x27;t waste your energy thinking about them.&lt;p&gt;Why do you want to publish yours, just as a portfolio? Then make a portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;latexr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve had several people steal my open-source code for different projects before. I’m talking copying (not cloning) the whole thing, changing the credit to their name, making no other modifications, and then republishing on their account.&lt;p&gt;Fortunately they never gained much traction. The ones I know about I blocked on GitHub with a note. No idea if they ever found out or if they tried workarounds, but I figured there’s not a lot more I could do about it and it’s not worth the headache.&lt;p&gt;I continue to share openly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;benoau:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reminds of the thought experiment, &amp;quot;if a tree falls in a forest and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound?&amp;quot;...&lt;p&gt;People you never heard of are open-sourcing projects you&amp;#x27;ll never find every day, there are hundreds of millions of repositories on GitHub and very few of them will ever be seen by humans who didn&amp;#x27;t write them, let alone humans looking to pretend they did.&lt;p&gt;Presumably someone looking at your portfolio will be reviewing CVs to hire?  I think throwing up a barrier on them evaluating your code will hurt you much more than the rest of the world not being able to see it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noir_lord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One of the things you learn as you get older is other people don&amp;#x27;t think about you (or at all) as much you think they do&amp;#x2F;will.&lt;p&gt;We are often our own worst critics - put your stuff out there, there is little to lose and some upside, if someone likes your demo and clicks through to see the code and can see it then that&amp;#x27;s a low friction path, by having to request access most people won&amp;#x27;t or will - but forget all about it etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867176</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 17:17:20</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867176</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bull markets make you feel smarter than you are</title>
      <link>https://awealthofcommonsense.com/2025/11/ben-graham-bull-market-brains/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a wonderful thing. This cycle will not last forever. Making money won’t always be this easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866688"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://awealthofcommonsense.com/2025/11/ben-graham-bull-market-brains/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rvnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like all the crypto geniuses, who are actually lucky guys, but could have been considered the dumbest idiots if cryptos had followed their natural course (being worthless).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pendenthistory:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Unfortunately a lesson I had to learn for myself. Hopefully I can pass it on to the next generation, but I fear they&amp;#x27;ll have to learn it for themselves too. Don&amp;#x27;t pick individual stocks people, buy broad index funds at most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FergusArgyll:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bear markets make michael burry feel smarter than he is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://awealthofcommonsense.com/2025/11/ben-graham-bull-market-brains/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 16:25:05</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866688</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bumble Berry Pi – A Cheap DIY Raspberry Pi Handheld Cyberdeck</title>
      <link>https://github.com/samcervantes/bumble-berry-pi</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3” Touch Screen Display Nice sized QWERTY keypad 37 Watt-hour battery (all day battery life with Raspberry Pi 3b+) Only 2 3D-Printed Parts Minimal assembly required All parts available on Amazon Cost: ~$60 worth of Amazon parts, not including the raspberry pi Parts List Part QTY Cost Buy Link Notes Raspberry Pi 1 $50 Amazon Pick your favorite. 3” Touch Screen Display 1 $38 Amazon Mini Bluetooth keyboard 1 $23 Amazon 37 Watt-Hr USB Power Bank 1 $19 Amazon Comes with short USB-C cable USB-C to Micro-USB U-Shaped Adapter 1 $10 Amazon USB-C Right Angle Adapter 1 $9 Amazon M3x10mm Countersunk Head Bolt 6 Amazon M2. 5x8mm Socket Head Bolt 4 Amazon M3 Threaded Inserts 6 Amazon 2" Kapton Tape 1 ft Amazon You could use another type of double-sided tape bumble-berry-pi-enclosure-A-v3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866772"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/samcervantes/bumble-berry-pi'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;poisonborz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I wanted something small enough to fit into a pants pocket&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to know what kind of pants people wear who say that to this device size (see also Nintendo DS &amp;amp; co)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/samcervantes/bumble-berry-pi</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 16:34:44</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866772</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samsung Family Hub fridges will start showing adds to "Elevate" Home Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-family-hub-2025-update-elevates-smart-home-ecosystem/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.samsung.com/us/samsung-family-hub-2025-update-elevates-smart-home-ecosystem/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 15:18:23</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866165</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI isn't replacing jobs. AI spending is</title>
      <link>https://www.fastcompany.com/91435192/chatgpt-llm-openai-jobs-amazon</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fastcompany.com/91435192/chatgpt-llm-openai-jobs-amazon</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 15:30:23</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866243</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21890</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866572"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21890'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dvrp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;hn question: how is this not a dupe of my days old submission (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45743810"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45743810&lt;/a&gt;) ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JustFinishedBSG:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;CTRL-F: &amp;quot;Fokker-Planck&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; 97 matches&lt;p&gt;Ok I&amp;#x27;ll read it :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21890</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 16:10:23</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866572</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marble Fountain</title>
      <link>https://willmorrison.net/posts/marble-fountain/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TracksMy initial system came together quickly. My first draft was just subtracting a tube from the solid support structure which worked but was super limited. Each support:Pulls towards other supports, weighted by distance and similarity in sizeRepels away from other supportsPulls to stay in the bounding boxPulls towards a fixed radius from the center of the structureSupports also have inertia, which is where the arcs in the structure of the support columns come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866697"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://willmorrison.net/posts/marble-fountain/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dbacar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;ramble about marbles&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;nice one!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;matthewfcarlson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is absolutely brilliant&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://willmorrison.net/posts/marble-fountain/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 16:26:09</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866697</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Manuscripts of Edsger W. Dijkstra</title>
      <link>https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They have been inaccessible to many potential readers, and those who have received copies have been unable to cite them in their own work. A few of the manuscripts written in Dutch have been translated into English, and one —EWD1036— has been translated into Spanish. EWD28 has been translated from English into Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866224"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seeing book sections or chapters starting with zero, always confuses me. I know that this convention is probably inspired by the fact that the addresses of memory locations start with zero. But that case was due to that fact one of the combination of the voltages can be all zeros. So, it&amp;#x27;s actually the count of combinations, and I don&amp;#x27;t think it can be used for ordinal enumeration of worldly things such as book chapters, or while talking about the spans in space and time (decades, centuries, miles etc). There is no zeroth century, there is no zeroth mile and there is no zeroth chapter. In case the chapter numbers are not meant be ordinal, then I think it would be odd to call Chapter 3 as fourth chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the mathematically inclined, EWD717 and EWD765 have two really cool problems.&lt;p&gt;A while back someone posed EWD765 for an alternate solution, I don&amp;#x27;t recall if any other solution was found. That was my introduction to these.&lt;p&gt;[717]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd07xx&amp;#x2F;EWD717.PDF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd07xx&amp;#x2F;EWD717.PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[765]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd07xx&amp;#x2F;EWD765.PDF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd07xx&amp;#x2F;EWD765.PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OakNinja:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love the timeless ”Threats to computer science” &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD898.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD898...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also the burn in the beginning of EWD899 (not transcribed) is noteworthy:&lt;p&gt;A review of a paper in AI.
I read &amp;quot;Default Reasoning as Likelihood Reasoning&amp;quot; by Elaine Rich. (My copy did not reveal where it had been published; the format suggests some conference proceedings. If that impression is correct, I am glad I did not attend the conference in question.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD899.PDF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD899.PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4b11b4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really enjoyed the this one:&lt;p&gt;Some meditations on Advanced Programming&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD00xx&amp;#x2F;EWD32.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD00xx&amp;#x2F;EWD32....&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;#x27;m currently in a Functional Programming course in Haskell... This resonated.&lt;p&gt;I know that we&amp;#x27;ll always need to write programs which directly interface with memory.&lt;p&gt;However, when we don&amp;#x27;t need to do that... Maybe we shouldn&amp;#x27;t write programs in this style (i.e. imperative). Maybe we shouldn&amp;#x27;t even use an imperative language (I know, that&amp;#x27;s a stretch, many languages have incorporated functional aspects and we can utilize them instead of trying to avoid the language entirely).&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Dijkstra ends EWB 32 with:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Smoothly we have arrived at the third component of our tool, viz. the language: also the language should be a reliable one. In other words it should assist the programmer as much as possible in the most difficult aspect of his task, viz. to convince himself —and those others who are really interested— that the program he has written down defines indeed the process he wanted to define.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;As my very last remark I should like to stress that the tool as a whole should have still another quality. It is a much more subtle one; whether we appreciate it or not depends much more on our personal taste and education and I shall not even try to define it. The tool should be charming, it should be elegant, it should be worthy of our love. This is no joke, I am terribly serious about this. In this respect the programmer does not differ from any other craftsman: unless he loves his tools it is highly improbable that he will ever create something of superior quality.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;At the same time these considerations tell us the greatest virtues a program can show: Elegance and Beauty.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Functional languages... help us achieve these aims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulRobinson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I once had one of his quote on the back of my business card when I was doing a lot of software dev consultancy: &amp;quot;Computer Science is no more about computers than astronomy is about telescopes&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I keep meaning to sit down with this site and make my way through it all. Might make more progress if I grab them into an eReader-friendly format and then peruse them more easily when travelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teddyh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Something which I occasionally link to, is this: &amp;lt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;users&amp;#x2F;EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD831.PDF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;users&amp;#x2F;EWD&amp;#x2F;ewd08xx&amp;#x2F;EWD831.PDF&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;.  It not only shows why computer languages should start their indexes at 0 (instead of 1), but also shows why intervals should be specified as lower-inclusive and upper-exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quantum_state:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Truly a treasure trove … unfortunately, much of the wisdom from people like Dijkstra seems to have been forgotten or ignored by the software engineering industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bobsh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a treasure (it’s been around quite a while). For those youngers out there: still completely relevant. Still ahead of the game, imho.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;peterkelly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The most important one in the context of 2025 is this one:&lt;p&gt;On the foolishness of &amp;quot;natural language programming&amp;quot;. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD06xx&amp;#x2F;EWD667.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cs.utexas.edu&amp;#x2F;~EWD&amp;#x2F;transcriptions&amp;#x2F;EWD06xx&amp;#x2F;EWD667...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 15:27:42</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866224</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About KeePassXC's Code Quality Control</title>
      <link>https://keepassxc.org/blog/2025-11-09-about-keepassxcs-code-quality-control/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Code contributions are generally posted to GitHub as a pull request. For creating pull requests that solve simple and focused issues, add boilerplate code and test cases. We do not vibe code, and no unreviewed AI code makes it into the code base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865921"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://keepassxc.org/blog/2025-11-09-about-keepassxcs-code-quality-control/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://keepassxc.org/blog/2025-11-09-about-keepassxcs-code-quality-control/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-09 14:44:06</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865921</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
