<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting notes between Forgejo and the Dutch government via Git commits</title>
      <link>https://codeberg.org/forgejo/sustainability/pulls/137/files</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please note that Anubis requires the use of modern JavaScript features that plugins like JShelter will disable. Please disable JShelter or other such plugins for this domain. This website is running Anubis version 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929247"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://codeberg.org/forgejo/sustainability/pulls/137/files'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kouunji:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is brilliant, especially if this kind of approach was adopted in policy development. Chunks of vetted “code” that is transparently shared and can be used by other governments facing similar challenges…imagine…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bwblabs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very positive to have a governmental hosted git&amp;#x2F;code platform, although I would still advise Gitea (it&amp;#x27;s not documented that pick is explored).&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m a self hosting GoGogs &amp;#x2F; Gitea user for almost 10 years, I did follow the Gitea fork. However regarding the Forgejo fork: the main contributors stayed with Gitea. The ideologically forked Forgejo made some license changes and hard fork decisions that increased the maintenance burden even more, resulting in missing upstream features and decreased security. Forgejo is more busy managing ideals, than creating software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mac-attack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If, like me, you are part of the 99% unfamiliar w&amp;#x2F; OSPO et al:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;interoperable-europe.ec.europa.eu&amp;#x2F;collection&amp;#x2F;open-source-observatory-osor&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;dutch-digitalisation-minister-announces-ospo-creation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;interoperable-europe.ec.europa.eu&amp;#x2F;collection&amp;#x2F;open-so...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good to see forgejo making inroads as someone who also self-hosts it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moelf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the note is written in Typst!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://codeberg.org/forgejo/sustainability/pulls/137/files</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929247</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Uncovered a Race Condition in Aurora RDS</title>
      <link>https://hightouch.com/blog/uncovering-a-race-condition-in-aurora-rds</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Aurora RDS The central datastore for real-time streaming and warehouse delivery of customer events uses Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL. An Aurora cluster consists of: One primary writer instance that handles all write operationsMultiple read replica instances that handle read-only queriesA shared storage layer that all instances access, automatically replicated across multiple availability zones This architecture enables fast failovers and efficient read scaling, but as we'd discover, it also introduces unique failure modes. How Hightouch Events uses Aurora The Plan This was our upgrade plan: Add another read replica (instance #3) to maintain read capacity during the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929921"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://hightouch.com/blog/uncovering-a-race-condition-in-aurora-rds'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hightouch.com/blog/uncovering-a-race-condition-in-aurora-rds</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929921</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving Back to a Tiling WM – XMonad</title>
      <link>https://wssite.vercel.app/blog/moving-back-to-a-tiling-wm-xmonad</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was my first experience with any window manager. This adds a title bar with formatted colors. This looks nicer that having a border surrounding the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928873"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://wssite.vercel.app/blog/moving-back-to-a-tiling-wm-xmonad'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symmetry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The reason I switched to XMonad over a decade ago was actually so that I could have a tiling window manager but still have all the normal desktop environment conveniences.&lt;p&gt;Obligatory dotfiles: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;aclough&amp;#x2F;dotfiles" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;aclough&amp;#x2F;dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;But right now I feel like I should be thinking of moving over to some new Wayland system.  Maybe Niri and XFCE?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NoboruWataya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have been a happy user of AwesomeWM for years. I don&amp;#x27;t actually use the tiling layout all that much (I definitely do use it occasionally and find it useful, but usually I&amp;#x27;m in floating or &amp;quot;monocle&amp;quot; mode). But in additional to tiling support, it is minimalist, keyboard-driven and infinitely configurable through Lua scripts which I really like. I think a lot of other tiling WMs are probably popular for similar reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smallerfish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think Claude Code makes TilingWMs doable. I&amp;#x27;ve always given up in the past because there have been reams of configs necessary to get to a fairly usable state, and I don&amp;#x27;t love reading manuals for desktop environments - but now it&amp;#x27;s all pretty easy to crank out.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been on HyprLand for a week now and haven&amp;#x27;t hit any blockers yet that&amp;#x27;d force me to go back to KDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theoldgreybeard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Switched to Hyprland about a month ago.  Wasn&amp;#x27;t feeling it at first but after a few weeks I don&amp;#x27;t think I can go back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philpax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Configuring your WM in Haskell seems fun, but I suspect &amp;quot;fun&amp;quot; is the primary motivator, not any kind of practical reason.&lt;p&gt;Type-checking keybindings is cute, but you&amp;#x27;re going to discover that the keybinding doesn&amp;#x27;t work when you go to use it, so how much time are you really saving? That&amp;#x27;s not helped by the fact that many WMs&amp;#x2F;compositors have validators for their configs, so you&amp;#x27;re getting much of the same benefit with much less trouble.&lt;p&gt;For reference, Niri&amp;#x27;s config is very approachable: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;YaLTeR&amp;#x2F;niri&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;resources&amp;#x2F;default-config.kdl" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;YaLTeR&amp;#x2F;niri&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;resources&amp;#x2F;default-c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Der_Einzige:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The only reason I used manjaro and thus arch was that it had really nice I3, bspwm, and xmonad distributions.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s very fun to rice a setup and make something worthy of posting on r&amp;#x2F;linuxporn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WD-42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tiling WMs are dead. Long live tiling WMs. Scrolling WMs like Niri&amp;#x2F;Paperwm are where it’s at now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSDude:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used Xmonad for a while, then switched to awesomewm used it for years. It was good on a 1366x768 screen to use space efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bryanlarsen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Recent versions of KDE have pretty good tiling support, so it&amp;#x27;s possible to have a rich DE and good tiling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wssite.vercel.app/blog/moving-back-to-a-tiling-wm-xmonad</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928873</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese is Lyme disease's double-edge sword</title>
      <link>https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2025/11/manganese-is-lyme-diseases-double-edge-sword</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;burgdorferi, they also kill beneficial gut bacteria,” Daly said. Too little manganese and the bacteria lose their defense mechanisms. This discovery holds potential for new Lyme disease therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928709"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2025/11/manganese-is-lyme-diseases-double-edge-sword'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.northwestern.edu/stories/2025/11/manganese-is-lyme-diseases-double-edge-sword</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928709</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Norway's Wealth Tax Unchains a Capital Exodus</title>
      <link>https://citizenx.com/insights/norway-wealth-exodus/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Taxes spreading across Europe: France to join Italy France just announced they will include Bitcoin as a taxable asset under the wealth tax, which means that French residents will pay taxes on the unrealized capital gains of their Bitcoin. Alex Recouso Oct 5 ·News.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929304"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://citizenx.com/insights/norway-wealth-exodus/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kazinator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[delayed]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wronex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The problem isn’t Norway. The problem is everywhere else allowing the amassing of incredible wealth with suspiciously low taxation. But we can’t even agree on a common minimum corporate tax. So yeah. Go Norway. Shame on everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yohannparis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an interesting outcome.&lt;p&gt;Now you know which ones weren&amp;#x27;t really in Norway for the opportunities and the country lifestyle and values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chrsw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People don&amp;#x27;t want to contribute to the country that made them rich. I expect that in a place like the USA, where your taxed money can go to helping people who don&amp;#x27;t look like you or don&amp;#x27;t have your same values. But I assumed Norwegians don&amp;#x27;t mind helping Norway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rdtsc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The recent wealth tax increase in Norway was expected to bring in an additional $146M in yearly tax revenue.&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;#x27;s interesting to see who was expecting it. The country&amp;#x27;s tax authorities, the economists, regular folks? This would seem like something a freshman in econ 101 would be able to predict.&lt;p&gt;The whole &amp;quot;just raise taxes from 10% to 15%&amp;quot; works well in an isolated environment with no other places to go. If there are places with 12% taxes, it should be obvious that&amp;#x27;s where people will move their wealth to.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Cities like Lucerne actively court Norwegian expatriates, creating communities of former Nordic residents who share similar tax-driven motivations for relocation.&lt;p&gt;Exactly. This happens for companies here in US as well. A city was raising taxes on a company headquartered there and were also asking them to donate for parks and other such nice things. Another state got wind of that, and invited the company to move the headquarters there instead, with all kinds of tax breaks and credits and such. So it&amp;#x27;s not only a passive move, but other locations actively trying to recruit entities to move there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://citizenx.com/insights/norway-wealth-exodus/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929304</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You misunderstand what it means to be poor</title>
      <link>https://blog.ctms.me/posts/2025-11-14-being-poor-or-being-broke/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is this mindset from folks that poor people must not be smart. Should I never have any personal time. Folks who say things like this have only ever experienced being broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928912"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.ctms.me/posts/2025-11-14-being-poor-or-being-broke/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jandrewrogers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most Americans don&amp;#x27;t understand real poverty. It exists outside their reality. They&amp;#x27;ve never seen it, let alone experienced it.&lt;p&gt;To the article&amp;#x27;s point, it is about being in a situation where there is no viable path to not being broke. You are stuck in an intrinsic local minima financially due to a total lack of leverage and optionality that a merely broke person has and takes for granted. If you end up not being broke it is because you worked very hard and&amp;#x2F;or were very lucky. Climbing the hill to get out of that minima can be extremely difficult.&lt;p&gt;It is pretty rare in the US for an otherwise functional person to end up there, most people are born into it. You usually have to make a lot of bad choices and&amp;#x2F;or have serious behavioral issues to find yourself in this situation if you weren&amp;#x27;t born into it, which isn&amp;#x27;t the same thing. People who are homeless drug addicts aren&amp;#x27;t &amp;quot;poor&amp;quot; in the sense of the article; if they weren&amp;#x27;t drug addicts they&amp;#x27;d merely be broke in most cases.&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#x27;t see many of the cases of the truly economically poor who get out of poverty ending back there again. These cases are routinely conflated with people who aren&amp;#x27;t poor for structural economic reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bradlys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The semantics here really suck.&lt;p&gt;I grew up lower middle class because for most of my life my parents both had full-time jobs. (By the definition, you are not &amp;quot;poor&amp;quot; in the US if you have a full-time job) However, we grew up what I would call educationally poor. My parents struggled with financial woes constantly. In my mind, we were broke due to their ineptness but they were poor as far as this writer is concerned. That said, I grew up around much more poverty than most in the US can imagine. I went to (public) school four days a week because the local district couldn&amp;#x27;t afford the fifth day. My parents had no thoughts about college or me getting ahead. There was no planning for my future. I had to entirely self-drive everything. There&amp;#x27;s obviously a lot more dark parts of this that come with being educationally poor as well but no need to elaborate.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my point about all that is that I think it&amp;#x27;s really a mindset more than anything else. I don&amp;#x27;t think &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt; can do what I did but I came from such a bad background with no hope at all and I still managed to be early eng for an IPO, FAANG, competitive university, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eulgro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have trouble understanding how someone really can be poor.&lt;p&gt;I spend about 30% of what one makes earning minimum wage full time. I live a frugal lifestyle, but I still feel like most people would consider my lifestyle normal and comfortable enough.&lt;p&gt;If I really needed to, I could probably get by on 10-15% of the minimum wage. In other words, earning the minimum wage, I could make 6-10 persons live on my salary.&lt;p&gt;This is possible because we live in an era of abundance. This wasn&amp;#x27;t possible for most of history.&lt;p&gt;So to me, being poor, for those without major health issues and with the ability to work full time, is either a skills issue, or a mindset issue.&lt;p&gt;This guy has a car. I don&amp;#x27;t think we need to look further than that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0xbadcafebee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[delayed]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;duxup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The advice section distantly reminds me of financial advice I see online.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been lucky and accordingly I am able to take advantage of a number of financially advantageous situations.  But the vast majority of those situations &amp;#x2F; tax benefits are for ... people who already have money.&lt;p&gt;I see people spit out what are one off &amp;quot;true&amp;quot; bits of financial advice at folks who straight up can&amp;#x27;t use it.  The guy with $20 to his name is not saving for his kids college, opening a IRA, etc.&lt;p&gt;The amount of programs and incentives for the poor are numerous, but they get them to the next day, they often don&amp;#x27;t do much beyond that.&lt;p&gt;My only personal example is long ago I remember working my way though a fairly affordable college that I got to attend due to some benefits I qualified for, I&amp;#x27;d get home from two jobs and I was just tired, just broken down.   Sure I got to go to college, but I was dead at the end of every day.   Not a way to go to college.  If I had a family?  People who depended on me then?  Forget about it, no chance.   For me being poor was being tired all the time.  All the bootstrap advice means nothing when you&amp;#x27;re beat down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gnarlouse:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Another point the author doesn&amp;#x27;t make but probably should is the home economics of DIY: A solo person gets 24h a day, just like everybody else. Ideally 8 are spent asleep. Another 8 (minimum) are probably spent working. That leaves a person 8 hours to do their whole life. It eats away at personal time, it bleeds into work and sleep, often by interrupting or occluding the ability to do either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kylehotchkiss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; There is this mindset from folks that poor people must not be smart.&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was a child, that idea has been shoved down my throat. &amp;quot;The American Dream&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;they&amp;#x27;re lazy&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;they should work harder&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Spending some serious time in developing countries fixed that mentality up real quick. Being able to escape the circumstances you&amp;#x27;re born into is a rare privilege in any culture. And that aspect of life in USA seemed to end in the late 90s&amp;#x2F;early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;maerF0x0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; A lot of poor folks are having to stand in line for hours and hours to get food at a food bank due to [government] ineptitude&lt;p&gt;This is an element of the argument for dismantling the nanny bureaucracy and instead going to UBI &amp;#x2F; cash payments.&lt;p&gt;1. It doesn&amp;#x27;t waste time, both of the gov&amp;#x27;t employee, but also of the recipient.&lt;p&gt;2. The author could buy better food, or car parts, or a bus pass, or ... with what otherwise might have been a more or less forced purchase in a single category. The flexibility returns agency and self-help behavior into the hands of the recipient.&lt;p&gt;All this needs to be tempered against the progress[1] we are making against poverty. I know it&amp;#x27;s a lot to ask the poor to be patient, but I do think there&amp;#x27;s an element of knowing that a lot of good people are trying really hard to alleviate the situation can help with the mostly mental elements of the article&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; No matter how fast you run or how high you jump you can never see the finish line. No matter how tired you are the ground keeps moving.&lt;p&gt;eg: this statement is not actually a fact, it&amp;#x27;s a mindset&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a big big testament to the overall worldview that I think is missing, just how impactful choices actually are. Some of these kinds of stories start generations ago, some of them start with the individual themselves having spent excess in the past that could have taken them through the low times (kind of &amp;quot;a waste not, want not&amp;quot; scenario). Some folks had opportunity and squandered it. Some flipped tails (failing scenario) 20 times in a row... People don&amp;#x27;t really want to help the former, but definitely the latter.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;BillGates&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1086662632587907072&amp;#x2F;photo&amp;#x2F;1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;BillGates&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1086662632587907072&amp;#x2F;photo&amp;#x2F;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vaidhy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I do not remember where I read this, but it has struck with me for the last 35+ years - &amp;quot;Poverty is a crime, but the poor are not guilty of it&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I have seen abject poverty growing up in India.. It is right in your face most of the times. I have friends from the other side of the street and pretty much, you live in very different realities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hartator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; never see my wife? My kids?&lt;p&gt;It seems you have what matters man.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qaq:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This sounds more than legit for many places outside of US and maybe some places in US, but in general US does give you an opportunity to move up. So unless it&amp;#x27;s health issue or family issue it really is in one&amp;#x27;s own hands here. I know a ton of people who came here with no $&amp;#x2F;legal status&amp;#x2F;english and are doing really well. If you are a US citizen you already have a huge asset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dijit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Even this does a poor job of explaining being poor.&lt;p&gt;The constant open loop on everything you own, terrified to discard anything even if its broken because there are components that might be useful to fix something else; the constant churn of second-hand (and cheap&amp;#x2F;disposable) things that are already close to death before they come into your possession and- crucially: the crushing weight of knowing that any financial roadbump is existential.&lt;p&gt;As the author mentions, a £50 fine might as well be £50,000- its unpayable, and leads to a sort of doom-spiral of lending to avoid worse consequences. Easily you can end up in unmanageable debt, in rare cases prison, its not uncommon to have the few worthwhile items you own being seized by bailifs to recoup debts, treasured heirlooms that cannot be regained and have little monetary value so they do no impact to your debt.&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to convey this, and what it does to your mentality- I am now built mentally to think quite fiscally conservative and do not take debts or put savings into investments like my peers. I am well off but a fraction of what I could have been had I not has this mentality.&lt;p&gt;You have to live it to understand it, but I wouldn’t wish it on anyone, its a tarpit and getting out of it without someone handing you a branch (and if you no longer have the strength to pull yourself out) then you’ll be stuck in it forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sgarland:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a child, I went from firmly middle-class (dad was a firefighter in San Diego, CA) to pretty damn poor (we moved to the middle of nowhere in Nebraska). I joined the U.S. Navy, and got a B.S. while I was in, then an M.S. in SWE afterwards on the government’s dime thanks to the GI Bill. I did the latter while working nights. I now make more money than I ever thought would be possible.&lt;p&gt;I said all of that to say, I am a poster child for “I crawled my way out of poverty, so you can too,” and &lt;i&gt;I hate that sentiment.&lt;/i&gt; Even though I know that I did in fact work hard to get to where I am, I know plenty of people who work way harder than I ever have, and who have very little. It’s not that they’re blowing their money, it’s that their skill sets don’t pay nearly as lucratively as tech. Very little comes close.&lt;p&gt;If you have never been poor (or at least were raised poor) yourself, you cannot possibly understand what it’s like, and you should probably not be giving advice to those who are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d_silin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Poverty is a funnel with slippery sides and no bottom. You can struggle your entire life just not to slide downwards even further. The post&amp;#x27;s author understands this and so do I.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulHoule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not all poor people are poor in the same way,  that is,  there are different reasons you might be poor.  This is explained pretty well in this classic book:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;The_Other_America" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;The_Other_America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mehulashah:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He right. I’ve seen poverty in India, but I misunderstood it.&lt;p&gt;There was a 12 year old kid who guided our boat down the Narmada after we spread my Dads ashes. He was not in school because he wanted money.&lt;p&gt;I told him I’d pay him double and continue to pay him for his days work, if he’d go back to school during the day and only row boats at night.&lt;p&gt;He said no. Just give me what you owe me.&lt;p&gt;He had no hope that education in the government schools would meaningfully change anything for him. Poverty is not a single static state. It’s a negative feedback loop that requires systemic change to get out of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uzidil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the book &amp;quot;Starling House&amp;quot;, being poor is defined as: you make a list for what you need, another for what you want, and then you throw away the second list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qwertox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; You can’t afford to go to the movies, but will stay home and watch what’s new on Netflix.&lt;p&gt;I never had Netflix nor Spotify and I am not poor. I always thought that having Netflix and Spotify is some kind of luxury. Not a big one, but those services are not cheap, if you&amp;#x27;re on a tight budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tracker1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I get it, I disagree with some of the premise... especially the idea of working two jobs.  My dad has worked multiple jobs at a time when I was growing up... I&amp;#x27;ve worked multiple jobs at a time as recently as this year.  Now, I&amp;#x27;m getting old (50yo) and really couldn&amp;#x27;t handle it as well as I could in my 20s, but I still did it.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not a permanent solution, but it&amp;#x27;s not a bad thing to do when you need to in order to pull ahead.  For that matter, self study and personal advancement.  It&amp;#x27;s hard to get into some jobs as an autodidact... I&amp;#x27;ve been a software developer for going on three decades without a formal education.  There are plenty of times I can&amp;#x27;t get through the HR screening alone.  That doesn&amp;#x27;t mean you don&amp;#x27;t try, or don&amp;#x27;t put in effort to improve your position in life or yourself.&lt;p&gt;I get being broke and poor... I grew up relatively poor.  It sucks.  I also worked very hard to get where I am.  It&amp;#x27;s not always where I want to be, but that&amp;#x27;s life to an extent.  My opinions don&amp;#x27;t always align with everyone else though...  I just don&amp;#x27;t like the idea of giving up, or not putting in extra effort when it&amp;#x27;s an option to pull you ahead.&lt;p&gt;I say this having spent about a year out of the past 3 years without regular income and massively in debt with medical issues I cannot cover, and cannot currently afford insurance (due to debt payments).  It sucks, and I can&amp;#x27;t change the past... I can only put in the effort I need to improve the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jiehong:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I once saw people start their month with 0 on their bank account, and live in the negative monthly credit their bank allows.&lt;p&gt;Them having a job (luckily), means they just about manage to fill that debt back at the end of the month, covering the debt and the small bank interest.&lt;p&gt;They end up paying the bank money bit by bit every month, yet they stay locked in that negative money pit.&lt;p&gt;It’s like being permanently broke, and it all started with one a bad month of extra payments…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JohnMakin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I understand the sentiment. I grew up lower middle class but with financially illiterate and neglectful parents and had a great deal of food scarcity and other things that caused me to leave home at 17. It was really difficult. The first place I managed to get, was a room for $750 a month and I took home $900. I had no car and had to take the bus everywhere. It&amp;#x27;s true - everything just piles up when you are stretched thin.&lt;p&gt;What I ended up doing was finding a cheap place to live in a crappy area with a buttload of roommates, started searching for promotion at my job, got one, which gave me more financial leeway and time (more flexible schedule) to pursue a degree at a community college, which was free because of my income. From there I went to a good state school which was also free due to my income and did well and got a degree in CS and was hired by a professor&amp;#x27;s startup. This whole process took like 15 years of brutally difficult grinding.&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in my spot, that have &amp;quot;made it&amp;quot; (although I still bear the scars all over the place, and I am handicapped in habitual ways, especially financially, that I may never get over without hundreds of thousands of $ of therapy), will look down on people like this author for &amp;quot;not trying hard enough.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#x27;s bullshit. I got extraordinarily lucky and had a streak of nothing too &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; happening (didnt get a crippling illness, car mostly stayed good, grades stayed stable, didnt get laid off), plus innate talents not everyone has. I think it&amp;#x27;s a myth a lot of people tell themselves that they &amp;quot;made it&amp;quot; because they just worked hard enough. The truth a huge amount of the time is you got lucky. Hard work + luck yields opportunity, but not all opportunities pan out. My career may dead end because of AI and I may end up in the same spot again for all I know. All I can do is keep trying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;etchalon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;All of the general guidance to escape being poor is actually advice for getting through being broke.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Paragraph level upvoting needs to be a thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;empiricus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I &amp;quot;like&amp;quot; when ppl talk about UBI and say &amp;quot;but ppl on UBI are not happy and lack purpose&amp;quot;. Compare with being poor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fullshark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s interesting how many comments here are knee jerk annoyance at this blogpost, which in my mind does a good job outlining two different financial situations and how flippant suggested solutions for escaping poverty don&amp;#x27;t make sense.&lt;p&gt;The fact that many of us here have so much compared to others in our community however you define it is disturbing and not helpful information for our day to day lives so we do what we can to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hexator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Understanding poverty starts with empathy. People thinking that &amp;quot;poor is a mindset&amp;quot; are lacking in that. It&amp;#x27;s not that simple! You can&amp;#x27;t just mind your way out of poverty! This isn&amp;#x27;t a math problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lubujackson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Poor&amp;quot; is why razor blades are behind a glass case at Walgreens. Because people steal razor blades, not (just) to use, but to sell at a discount to other poor people.&lt;p&gt;There is also the interesting situation of &amp;quot;newly poor&amp;quot; people getting crushed much faster than people who have been poor a long time. There are community safety nets that bubble up from everyone being cornered all the time. You don&amp;#x27;t go to the mechanic, but ask that guy who charges $100 and can hack something together so you can get to work this week. You know an old lady around the corner who will take your kids in for the night if you don&amp;#x27;t make it home for some reason. These aren&amp;#x27;t solutions, they are patches and stopgaps. But this is also the strength of community that to be more common in the U.S. before suburbs made every family an island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m confused whether the author is poor, has been poor, has never been poor but has deep understanding of what it&amp;#x27;s like for other reasons (friends, family, etc.).  He writes&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I have a van that is falling apart. It needs a lot of work that we cannot afford to do.&lt;p&gt;but I think that should be read as &amp;quot;Imagine that I have ...&amp;quot;, because, from his About page, he seems to have an irrigation and landscaping business and plays around with technology on the weekend.&lt;p&gt;I think the article would have been more effective it had been clearer exactly on what basis the author is writing about the experience of poor people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisMarshallNY:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like this guy’s backstory[0].&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Africa. The poverty I saw, as a child, was foundational in my own personal development.&lt;p&gt;There are some places in the US, that have that kind of poverty, but I have not seen them, with my own eyes.&lt;p&gt;I have family that dedicated most of their life to fighting poverty (with very limited success). They believe that poverty is probably the single biggest problem in the world, today. Almost every major issue we face, can be traced back to poverty.&lt;p&gt;Income inequality is one thing, but hardcore poverty, as described by the author, is a different beast, and creates a level of desperation that is &lt;i&gt;incredibly&lt;/i&gt; dangerous.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.ctms.me&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.ctms.me&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smithkl42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The post does a good job of describing a phenomenological difference between being broke and being poor, and its account seems plausible to me. But what I&amp;#x27;m curious about is the &lt;i&gt;causal&lt;/i&gt; difference between the two. I&amp;#x27;ve known working class folks who seem like they&amp;#x27;re getting by fine, even if they&amp;#x27;re occasionally &amp;quot;broke&amp;quot;, and I&amp;#x27;ve known working class folks who are constantly in financial crisis, and definitely fit in the category of &amp;quot;poor&amp;quot;. I wonder why folks who start with roughly the same skills, intelligence and opportunities (and bank account balance!) can nevertheless end up in very different places?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rsyring:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.ctms.me&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.ctms.me&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would appear from the about page and the article that he has the requisite skills to earn an income that should move him out of the &amp;quot;poor&amp;quot; category:&lt;p&gt;- auto mechanic&lt;p&gt;- digital tech&lt;p&gt;- landscaping&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not trying to dismiss the difficult realities associated with being poor.  But if you have the skills to make more money and bring your family out of the &amp;quot;poor&amp;quot; category, why wouldn&amp;#x27;t you do that?  IMO, basic financial security for your family should trump &amp;quot;I like to work outside.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;He obviously has different priorities, which is fine.  But I&amp;#x27;m not sure the search for sympathy&amp;#x2F;empathy in the blog post is warranted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.ctms.me/posts/2025-11-14-being-poor-or-being-broke/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928912</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RetailReady (YC W24) Is Hiring</title>
      <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/retailready/jobs/kGHAith-support-engineer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re RetailReady (YC W24), an AI-powered supply chain compliance engine shaking up an antiquated (and yes, unsexy) industry. RetailReady is the first AI-powered compliance engine designed for retail supply chains. RetailReady is building an AI-powered supply chain compliance engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928822"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/retailready/jobs/kGHAith-support-engineer'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/retailready/jobs/kGHAith-support-engineer</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928822</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linear Algebra Explains Why Some Words Are Effectively Untranslatable</title>
      <link>https://aethermug.com/posts/linear-algebra-explains-why-some-words-are-effectively-untranslatable</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Call me crazy, but I think that language translation is like a change of basis in linear algebra. 3) Those numbers are the coordinates of the vectors in that basis. Same vectors, different basis: the numbers are different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927210"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://aethermug.com/posts/linear-algebra-explains-why-some-words-are-effectively-untranslatable'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nph278:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just read Wittgenstein (The Blue+Brown Books &amp;#x2F; Philosophical investigations), and this confusion will go away. The difference between translation, definition, and explanation needs to be understood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raincom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There is a better thesis coming from the late philosopher W.V.O Quine: indeterminacy of translation [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;plato.stanford.edu&amp;#x2F;entries&amp;#x2F;quine&amp;#x2F;#IndeTran" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;plato.stanford.edu&amp;#x2F;entries&amp;#x2F;quine&amp;#x2F;#IndeTran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;triclops200:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article assumes that concepts are somehow precise coordinates within a single language; that&amp;#x27;s not the case, at best, speakers of a language mutually approximate a relatively consistent representation, but like, look at a word like yeet or whatever: we decided as a society on its meaning while it was being developed, as it were. Furthermore, it never rigorously defines what it means by translation. It claims 上京 is a single basis meaning moving to Tokyo, for example, but that isn&amp;#x27;t even an accurate translation: the individual components represent superior&amp;#x2F;greater&amp;#x2F;above and Tokyo and as an idiomatic phrase it represents the concept of moving to the capital for a better life. Something like &amp;quot;moving on up&amp;quot; or the like in some vernaculars of English, and idioms translating to idioms is a form of translation. It&amp;#x27;s disingenuous to represent the first concept as a single basis but not the second.
Similarly, it claims mono no aware (物の哀れ) is unable to be translated, but, again, more literally &amp;quot;translated&amp;quot; is saying &amp;quot;the sorrow within things&amp;quot; character by character, and, only as an idiom has the full contextual understanding. It&amp;#x27;s not really a single point even if it&amp;#x27;s rather accurately located in a hypothetical embedding space by Japanese speakers. Imo, an English translation of the concept is &amp;quot;everything is dust in the wind&amp;quot;, only 2 more individual conceptual units than the original Japanese phrase, and 3 of them are mainly just connecting words, but it&amp;#x27;s understood as a similar idiom&amp;#x2F;concept, here.&lt;p&gt;Concepts are only usefully distinguished by context and use.&lt;p&gt;By the author&amp;#x27;s own argumentation: nothing is translatable (or, generally, even communicatable) unless it has a fixed relative configuration to &lt;i&gt;all other concepts that is precisely equivalent&lt;/i&gt;. In practice, we handle the fuzziness as part of communication and its useless to try and define a concept as untranslatable unless you&amp;#x27;re also of the camp that nothing is ever communicated (in which case, this response to the author&amp;#x27;s post is completely useless as nobody could possibly understand it enough internally for it to be useful. If you&amp;#x27;ve read this far, congrats on squaring the circle somehow)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;epistasis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; If the mere sight of the above is like a punch in the face for you, don&amp;#x27;t worry. I&amp;#x27;m not going to math you to death in what follows. I will only remind you of a tiny basic part of it that I think relates to languages.&lt;p&gt;Yes, that mathematical expression is like a punch in my face, but not for the reason you think. I am offended that the rank of the matrix does not match the dimension of the matrix, not that I&amp;#x27;m seeing a matrix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;proteal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think a succinct way to describe my thoughts on linear algebra&amp;#x2F;language is that language has high dimensionality (ie many different basis vectors that may not necessarily be orthogonal) and that individual languages use a unique coordinate system to express thought. Each language is a lossy approximation of all conceivable thought and some languages can more efficiently represent the “all thoughts” vector space because they have basis vectors that point in more uncommon directions (like the go to japan example). So while you can more or less point to any thought in any language, some thoughts are easier to express in certain languages, which the post (and me) agree to be untranslatable words.&lt;p&gt;I tried to find the really interesting article about language and color that describes how some cultures use different naming schemes for colors but couldn’t find it. It talked about how back in the day we don’t know orange as a color, we just thought it was red-yellow and only after the fruit was distributed did the word for the color catch on. Here’s the best article I can find that talks about this phenomena &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;burnaway.org&amp;#x2F;magazine&amp;#x2F;blue-language-visual-perception&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;burnaway.org&amp;#x2F;magazine&amp;#x2F;blue-language-visual-perceptio...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rich_sasha:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a tenuous analogy, but if you along with it, you can take it further.&lt;p&gt;You could consider the &amp;quot;cost&amp;quot; of expressing a word as some kind of metric or norm on the vector. What in one language&amp;#x2F;basis is a simple Kronecker delta, in another is a very complex vector (of course if it were the same vector in two bases, it would have the same length, but we could rather think of translation as an affine transformation, say).&lt;p&gt;And finally, with two bases, they need not span the same vector space. You can have a three-coordinate vector space all you like, if you have only two basis vectors you ain&amp;#x27;t spanning it. At best you can hope for an orthogonal projection from one to the other, and lose some nuance.&lt;p&gt;Eventually, with bilinguality, you learn not to translate words. Concepts live in different languages and describe a reality. Usually you can describe that reality in two different languages, but sometimes not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;behnamoh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tangent: I really like vornoi diagrams and part of me thinks there&amp;#x27;s a hidden, precious concept they represent. I didn&amp;#x27;t get their relation to the article but was wondering if they have applications in engineering&amp;#x2F;sciences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjsg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article seems to think that a word is untranslateable if there is no single word in the target language. If I&amp;#x27;m not misreading the article, then this is completely obvious -- just consider the number of words in English and the number of words in almost any other language, and you will find that there are more English words than the other language. It is now clear that there exist English words that don&amp;#x27;t correspond to a single word in the other language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mannyv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Communication&amp;#x2F;language depends on shared context. The more context you share the shorter the trigger for evoking that thing and that context. And if you share no context communication becomes very difficult.&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;#x27;t aware that that idea was in dispute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d-lisp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Are they multiplying a 3x3 matrix by a 2 component vector ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zvmaz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I hope these rather unorthodox leaps between linguistics and mathematics helped make it almost obvious that some words and ideas are untranslatable in practice. I also hope you don&amp;#x27;t take the analogy too seriously, because it won&amp;#x27;t go much further than this.&lt;p&gt;Phew! Thanks for clarifying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aethermug.com/posts/linear-algebra-explains-why-some-words-are-effectively-untranslatable</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927210</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not even a month passed and Chat Control is back in the EU</title>
      <link>https://reclaimthenet.org/the-disguised-return-of-the-eus-private-message-scanning-plot</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://reclaimthenet.org/the-disguised-return-of-the-eus-private-message-scanning-plot</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929511</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany to Ban Huawei from Future 6G Network in Sovereignty Push</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-13/germany-to-ban-huawei-from-future-6g-network-in-sovereignty-push</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TechnologyFacebookXLinkedInEmailLinkGiftExpandEmployees wait for visitors at the Huawei stand during the IFA Consumer Electronics Show in Berlin. Photographer: Jacobia Dahm/BloombergFacebookXLinkedInEmailLinkGiftGift this articleContact us:Provide news feedback or report an errorConfidential tip. “We have decided within the government that everywhere it’s possible we’ll replace components, for example in the 5G network, with components we have produced ourselves,” Merz told a business conference in Berlin on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929052"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-13/germany-to-ban-huawei-from-future-6g-network-in-sovereignty-push'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kwanbix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice, in 2025, the world is a place where China can not be trusted, Russia can not be trusted, USA can not be trusted, Europe can not be trusted (at least from the point of the others), etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incipient:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t get why Huawei gets specific hate? Shouldn&amp;#x27;t this equally apply to all Chinese vendors? I wouldn&amp;#x27;t expect any are less susceptible to government control?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9cb14c1ec0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is 6G even a thing?  From either a bandwidth demand perspective or a financial perspective?  Every US wireless service just about bankrupted themselves rolling out 5G.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PeterStuer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They are not wrong, but will they also ban Cisco in their &amp;quot;Sovereignty Push&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mannanj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why 6g? who asked for it? I am content with 4g, 5g was a push as it was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tonetegeatinst:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know some open 5G hardware project exists as I read about it about a month ago.&lt;p&gt;However I wonder if that will remain true with 6G, or if it will even be affordable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jiehong:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Which company will design and make 6G telco hardware in Germany?&lt;p&gt;I guess it will be 3&amp;#x2F;4&amp;#x2F;5G for a while, until they can someday cover the country just barely, and then 6G a decade and half later than everyone else (or is it by giving up sovereignty by buying US stuff instead?)&lt;p&gt;Sorry for being hopeless, but Germany has been very good at proving its inability to fix telco issues (or its train issues…).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RobotToaster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And use American Cisco equipment with definitely no NSA backdoors instead?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daneel_w:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good. Don&amp;#x27;t forget their incredibly affordable and attractive smartphones and the fact that they have almost completely captured the market for cellular transceiver chips used in USB mobile modems, both of which are excellent products for espionage and weaponization just like their cellular network equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;avipars:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.li&amp;#x2F;18QJs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.li&amp;#x2F;18QJs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;juliusceasar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Better late than never.&lt;p&gt;China has so many anti-Foreigner laws for doing business in China.&lt;p&gt;West has made China rich and powerful in exchange for cheap labour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jusonce56789:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, people will buy Huawei routers at home anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-13/germany-to-ban-huawei-from-future-6g-network-in-sovereignty-push</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929052</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle hit hard in Wall Street's tech sell-off over its AI bet</title>
      <link>https://www.ft.com/content/583e9391-bdd0-433e-91e0-b1b93038d51e</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complete digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. SelectWhat's included FT Edit: Access on iOS and webStandard Digital$45 per monthEssential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. SelectWhat's included Global news &amp; analysisExpert opinionFT App on Android &amp; iOSFT Edit: Access on iOS and webFirstFT: the day's biggest stories20+ curated newslettersFollow topics &amp; set alerts with myFTFT Videos &amp; Podcasts10 monthly gift articles to sharePremium DigitalComplete coverage$75 per monthComplete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927435"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ft.com/content/583e9391-bdd0-433e-91e0-b1b93038d51e'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theoldgreybeard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can’t wait for the apocalyptic razing that’s coming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;underlipton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s just returning to relative sanity. Go look at a 6-month chart. Of course, it&amp;#x27;s mostly risen with the SP500 tide. The mid-September jump was some sort of mechanical move caused by things deep in the market (and outside it) that you&amp;#x27;re not allowed to know about. Someone needed collateral.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think Oracle&amp;#x27;s stock price has anything to do with AI. That&amp;#x27;s just the public narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This the flipside of jumping up for no good reason on September 10th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lenerdenator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What do you call Larry Ellison losing enough wealth to equal the yearly economic output of a small American metro area?&lt;p&gt;A nice start.&lt;p&gt;EDIT:&lt;p&gt;Downvote it all you want, he&amp;#x27;s not going to increase your pay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lambersley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oracle was late to Cloud and now late to AI.  Maybe it&amp;#x27;s time Larry let someone else take the helm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;francisofascii:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oracle stock down 25% for the past month, but still up 35% for the year and 300% for 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d be skeptical just because it&amp;#x27;s Oracle. Not exactly a sprightly company to bet on for novel technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Previously:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Oracle&amp;#x27;s credit default swaps surge as Barclays downgrades its debt rating&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45910711"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45910711&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;softwaredoug:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe we can avoid an Ellison buyout of Warner Brothers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chollida1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Its worse for some other &amp;quot;ai&amp;quot; related companies.&lt;p&gt;Coreweave for instance, now has its CDS trade around 600bp, which is a 1&amp;#x2F;3 rise in 2 months, which implies that the probability of a default in 5 years is 40% at a 40 cent recovery rate.&lt;p&gt;That makes Coreweave&amp;#x27;s credit rating the equivalent of CCC-, which aint good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zerosizedweasle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I said this earlier but: It&amp;#x27;s interesting to see the market try to do anything to rally. The problem is you guys are rallying on the thought that you&amp;#x27;ve scared the Fed into cutting rates, but actually by rallying you short circuit it. You ensure they won&amp;#x27;t cut. And that&amp;#x27;s how the market&amp;#x27;s lillypad hopping thinking is actually just stupidity. You rallied, so now there are no rate cuts so the crash will be even more brutal.&lt;p&gt;Edit: They&amp;#x27;re trying to do everything they can to stop people from seeing this lol&lt;p&gt;Edit 2: Specifically trying to stop people from seeing this:&lt;p&gt;Yeah for sure but -&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x27;It’s impossible to quantify how much cash flowed from OpenAI to big tech companies. But OpenAI’s loss in the quarter equates to 65% of the rise in underlying earnings—before interest, tax, depreciation and amortization—of Microsoft, Nvidia, Alphabet, Amazon and Meta together. That ignores Anthropic, from which Amazon recorded a profit of $9.5 billion from its holding in the loss making company in the quarter&amp;#x27; - WSJ&lt;p&gt;Their earnings growth is their own money that they gave to OpenAI.&lt;p&gt;You have that waiting in the wings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chasil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;WClqv" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;WClqv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCM9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m bullish on AI as tech but folks are starting to sniff out that the financials of everything going on at the moment aren’t sustainable for much longer.&lt;p&gt;I hope we have more of a “reality correction” than full blown bubble bursting, but the data is increasingly looking like we’re about to have a massive implosion that wipes out a generation of startups and sets the VC ecosystem back a decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmoy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So debt financing (Oracle) vs fund-it-more-on-your-own (other big tech?) vs fund-it-with-equity (startups?)... I guess that makes some kind of sense?  Oracle raises 4x the debt of e.g. Google?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ft.com/content/583e9391-bdd0-433e-91e0-b1b93038d51e</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927435</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'No One Lives Forever' Turns 25 and You Still Can't Buy It Legitimately</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/11/13/no-one-lives-forever-turns-25-you-still-cant-buy-it-legitimately/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“So we went back to Activision and, [after] numerous correspondence going back and forth, they replied that they thought they might have some rights, but that any records predated digital storage. And they confessed, they didn’t have [their] hands on it. And they weren’t sure that they even had any of those rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928492"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.techdirt.com/2025/11/13/no-one-lives-forever-turns-25-you-still-cant-buy-it-legitimately/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 13 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mattfrommars:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;off topic: My goodness, anyone feel the UI&amp;#x2F;UX of the website to be really refreshing? I&amp;#x27;ve lately been digging compact&amp;#x2F;industrialized looking UI vs &amp;#x27;touch&amp;#x27;&amp;#x2F;comfort view that take up way too much real estate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AdmiralAsshat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I struggle to understand why the (potential?) rights-holders are so intransigent about this.&lt;p&gt;If a company came up to me and said &amp;quot;We have interest in reviving an IP of yours. We will take on the development costs, we will take on all the risk, all you have to do is say yes and you will get a fixed percentage of every sale&amp;quot;--that seems like an easy win-win, does it not? The only reasons I would imagine you would say NO were if:&lt;p&gt;1) Concern that the company will do a crappy job and tarnish the brand&amp;#x27;s reputation (which, fair, but Nightreign studios and&amp;#x2F;or GOG  seem to have a pretty solid track record on this)&lt;p&gt;2) Your company&amp;#x27;s bean-counters are both so greedy and risk-averse such that their thinking is, &amp;quot;We only wish to allow something if it will be a guaranteed hit...but if it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a guaranteed hit, we want to do it internally so that we get to keep &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; of the profits!&amp;quot; In which case, the requirements are almost impossible to satisfy, since there is inevitably some level of risk undertaken during the remaster&amp;#x2F;re-release effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RcouF1uZ4gsC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the downside to limiting all movie and software copyrights to 10 years?&lt;p&gt;Source code and materials etc can remain trade secrets if desired?&lt;p&gt;And all IP with a movie as well - including characters. This would stop a studio from forever milking the same piece of IP forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tavavex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No One Sells Forever, eh?&lt;p&gt;But seriously, the way the copyright system prevents people from preserving and re-experiencing works as soon as the &amp;quot;rightful owner&amp;quot; stops caring about them is a travesty. I say that when an IP becomes orphaned, stops being claimed by a new rights-holder, or some time after it stops being sold&amp;#x2F;used, it should be forcibly removed from the grip of copyright and open for everyone to use. Otherwise, we&amp;#x27;re heading to a world where only a slim subset of well-performing properties are being offered, while the rest lie in a gigantic graveyard of things-someone-owns-but-will-never-use instead of being potentially put to use by someone who would actually care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lammy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fuck “buying it legitimately” anyway when it&amp;#x27;s old enough that it would be Public Domain under a sane copyright regime.&lt;p&gt;Relevant: NOLF Revival Edition (same as mentioned in the article and quoted article, but actual link):&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.org&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;no-one-lives-forever-trilogy" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.org&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;no-one-lives-forever-trilogy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=43146581"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=43146581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EvanAnderson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A pertinent prior discussion: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=43146581"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=43146581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LarsDu88:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I remember playing the demos for NOLF and NOLF2 years ago. If I had known it would be impossible to buy 25 years later, I would have bought the game!&lt;p&gt;I also remember reading articles in Game Developer magazine about how sophisticated the AI in NOLF2 was. Wish I could find that article&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;visarga:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Copyright kills works when rights cannot be negotiated, usually because the rights holder is not to be found, but in this case because the situation is just &amp;quot;complicated&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;croes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Everybody is waiting for HL3.
I want NOLF3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lanthade:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I loved NOLF and NOLF2.  I was actually thinking about pulling them off the shelf and loading them up again the other day.  I had no idea that the rights around them was such a mess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skibz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;NOLF is actually source-available [0][1][2], and it has been since not that long after its original release.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s also a community-driven project [3] keeping it playable on modern hardware - however, it hasn&amp;#x27;t seen any activity in several years.&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;#x27;t played or heard of NOLF before, I highly encourage checking it out. It&amp;#x27;s a fantastic title, even after all these years.&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20020217233624&amp;#x2F;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pc.ign.com&amp;#x2F;articles&amp;#x2F;095&amp;#x2F;095995p1.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20020217233624&amp;#x2F;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pc.ign.com...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20010720053220&amp;#x2F;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;noonelivesforever.com:80&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20010720053220&amp;#x2F;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;noonelives...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;osgcc&amp;#x2F;no-one-lives-forever" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;osgcc&amp;#x2F;no-one-lives-forever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;haekb&amp;#x2F;nolf1-modernizer" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;haekb&amp;#x2F;nolf1-modernizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shalmanese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So say someone decides to produce a remaster of NOLF. Does Activision have to produce this piece of paper once they sue to establish standing? If Activision&amp;#x27;s version of this piece of paper was chewed up by rats in the 90s, does their ownership stake vanish in a puff as well?&lt;p&gt;If the potential victory from a lawsuit is $20K and Activision estimates it will cost them $50K to find this piece of paper, is the company relatively safe from a lawsuit?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ferguess_k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;NOLF2 is one of best and interesting FPS I played. I wish they remastered it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.techdirt.com/2025/11/13/no-one-lives-forever-turns-25-you-still-cant-buy-it-legitimately/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928492</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitchat for Gaza – messaging without internet</title>
      <link>https://updates.techforpalestine.org/bitchat-for-gaza-messaging-without-internet/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Next to it you will see an icon with the number of users connected within your network. These work best when connected to the internet. Users within your network can then join it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929358"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://updates.techforpalestine.org/bitchat-for-gaza-messaging-without-internet/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adroitboss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The name choice is unfortunate. I read it incorrectly the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;osobo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I never thought I&amp;#x27;d see FidoNet again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;warkdarrior:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;An &amp;quot;Israel-proof messaging alternative&amp;quot; according to their website. I wonder how well it works in tunnels. Does it require line of sight to route messages?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://updates.techforpalestine.org/bitchat-for-gaza-messaging-without-internet/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929358</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Tech Market Treemap</title>
      <link>https://caplocus.com/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://caplocus.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45928620</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secret Boat Strike Memo Justifies Kills by Claiming Targeting Drugs, Not People</title>
      <link>https://theintercept.com/2025/11/14/boat-strikes-immunity-legality-trump/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It claims that narcotics on the boats are lawful military targets because their cargo generates revenue for cartels whom the Trump administration claims are in armed conflict with the U. Most Read Trump’s Military Occupations of U. “I’m not surprised that civilian and military lawyers raised significant concerns with these strikes, given that they are manifestly unlawful even under the most permissive wartime legal frameworks government lawyers have deployed at any point in the past two decades,” Rebecca Ingber, a former State Department lawyer and law-of-war expert told The Intercept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929863"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://theintercept.com/2025/11/14/boat-strikes-immunity-legality-trump/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gigatexal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here’s hoping Congress wakes up and passes laws that curbs presidential power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://theintercept.com/2025/11/14/boat-strikes-immunity-legality-trump/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929863</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Comes After Science?</title>
      <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec7650</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aec7650</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927042</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
