<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:44:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Iroh-blobs</title>
      <link>https://www.iroh.computer/blog/iroh-blobs-0-95-new-features</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Connection pool There is a new connection pool in util::connection_pool. get_or_connect will try to get an existing connection from the pool. /// The ConnectionRef will be dropped here, and the pool will consider the connection idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.iroh.computer/blog/iroh-blobs-0-95-new-features'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.iroh.computer/blog/iroh-blobs-0-95-new-features</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727557</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are these real CVEs? VulDB entries for dnsmasq rely on replacing config files</title>
      <link>https://seclists.org/oss-sec/2025/q4/79</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;oss-sec mailing list archives By Date By Thread Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq From: Moritz Mühlenhoff &lt;jmm () inutil org&gt; Date: Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:21:54 +0000 On Mon, Oct 27, 2025 at 09:34:03AM -0700, Alan Coopersmith wrote: Among the new CVE's published this weekend were these from the VulDB CNA: For all three bugs, the documented "exploit" requires "Replace the default configuration file (/etc/dnsmasq. conf) with the provided malicious file. Cheers, Moritz By Date By Thread Current thread: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Alan Coopersmith (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Jeremy Stanley (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Andrew Latham (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Sebastian Pipping (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Stuart Henderson (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Sebastian Pipping (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Matthew Fernandez (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Jeffrey Walton (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Moritz Mühlenhoff (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Collin Funk (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Michael Orlitzky (Oct 27) Re: Questionable CVE's reported against dnsmasq Hank Leininger (Oct 27).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://seclists.org/oss-sec/2025/q4/79'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://seclists.org/oss-sec/2025/q4/79</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727137</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI can code, but it can't build software</title>
      <link>https://bytesauna.com/post/coding-vs-software-engineering</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why would these people need me. The fact that I get these requests says something about software engineering. There is old wisdom that says: Coding is easy, software engineering is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bytesauna.com/post/coding-vs-software-engineering'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bytesauna.com/post/coding-vs-software-engineering</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727664</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Dlog – Journaling and AI coach that learns what drives wellbeing (Mac)</title>
      <link>https://dlog.pro/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dlog puts all your productivity tools into one place. Dlog’s coach reveals how your personality, interacts with your character, resources and well-being. Coach has access to your journals and.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://dlog.pro/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dlog.pro/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723646</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
