<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:23:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Why hasn't there been a new major sports league?</title>
      <link>https://humaninvariant.substack.com/p/why-hasnt-there-been-a-new-major</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://humaninvariant.substack.com/p/why-hasnt-there-been-a-new-major</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856563</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI benchmarks are a bad joke – and LLM makers are the ones laughing</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/07/measuring_ai_models_hampered_by/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;6 percent on AIME 2025 without tools), real-world coding (74. 4 percent without tools. are far from the first to question the validity of AI benchmark tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856804"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/07/measuring_ai_models_hampered_by/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mikert89:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AI works, the joke is on everyone in denial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jennyholzer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been getting flagged by high-on-their-own-supply AI boosters for identifying that LLM benchmarks have been obvious bullshit for at least the last year and a half.&lt;p&gt;What changed to make &amp;quot;the inevitable AI bubble&amp;quot; the dominant narrative in last week or so?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;calpaterson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Definitely one of the weaker areas in the current LLM boom.  Comparing models, or even different versions of the same model, is a pseudo-scientific mess.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m still using &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lmarena.ai&amp;#x2F;leaderboard" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lmarena.ai&amp;#x2F;leaderboard&lt;/a&gt;.  Perhaps there is something better and someone will pipe up to tell me about it.  But we use LLMs at work and have unexplainable variations between them.&lt;p&gt;And when we get a prompt working reliably on one model, we often have trouble porting it to another LLM - even straight &amp;quot;version upgrades&amp;quot; such as from GPT-4 to -5.  Your prompt and your model become highly coupled quite easily.&lt;p&gt;I dunno what to do about it and am tending to just pick Gemini as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marshferm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Don’t get high on your own supply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/07/measuring_ai_models_hampered_by/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856804</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sam Altman Is Getting Desperate and It Is Starting to Show</title>
      <link>https://tickerfeed.net/articles/sam-altman-reeks-of-desperation</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is fucking deranged dude. How can a company with $13 billion in revenue make $1. Friar emphasized that the co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856998"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://tickerfeed.net/articles/sam-altman-reeks-of-desperation'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jMyles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He &amp;quot;clarified&amp;quot; on twitter.  I think it&amp;#x27;s very important to presume good intentions, but I have to say, I found these even more troubling than a bailout:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; What we do think might make sense is governments building (and owning) their own AI infrastructure, but then the upside of that should flow to the government as well. We can imagine a world where governments decide to offtake a lot of computing power and get to decide how to use it, and it may make sense to provide lower cost of capital to do so. Building a strategic national reserve of computing power makes a lot of sense. But this should be for the government’s benefit, not the benefit of private companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;softwaredoug:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If the government were to bail out, OpenAI wouldn’t that open up litigation from competitors like Google or anthropic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JKCalhoun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;In the past few months alone, OpenAI has racked up commitments of nearly $1.5 trillion, including:&lt;p&gt;$250 billion with Microsoft - using Azure cloud platform capacity&lt;p&gt;$500 billion with Oracle - for cloud computing capacity…&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;: &amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I assume these companies will eat the loss and write it off for tax purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lagniappe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article seems very wishful, and typed up in an awkward format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timmg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not sure why the government would bother to bail them out.  I would imagine Google could take up most of the slack if OpenAI implodes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prodigycorp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;what is this website? it’s all very confusing. a blog post? a community post? is there an author?&lt;p&gt;I really don’t mean to concern troll or anything but this text is so bizarre, it’s like it landed from space into the middle of some random website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tickerfeed.net/articles/sam-altman-reeks-of-desperation</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856998</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I've Heard Boomers Say That I Agree with 100%</title>
      <link>https://wildingout.substack.com/p/12-things-ive-heard-boomers-say-that</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wildingout.substack.com/p/12-things-ive-heard-boomers-say-that</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856640</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$1T in Tech Stocks Sold Off as Market Grows Skeptical of AI</title>
      <link>https://gizmodo.com/1-trillion-in-tech-stocks-sold-off-as-market-grows-skeptical-of-ai-2000683226</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are also companies like Sweetgreen, the salad company that has tried to position itself as an automation company that serves salads on the side. Bloomberg reported Friday that its stock had slumped 8. 6 percent over eight days, a decline that evaporated some $350 billion in market valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857099"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://gizmodo.com/1-trillion-in-tech-stocks-sold-off-as-market-grows-skeptical-of-ai-2000683226'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gizmodo.com/1-trillion-in-tech-stocks-sold-off-as-market-grows-skeptical-of-ai-2000683226</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857099</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Sam Altman Won't Be on the Hook for OpenAI's Spending Spree</title>
      <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/rashishrivastava/2025/11/07/why-sam-altman-wont-be-on-the-hook-for-openais-massive-spending-spree/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But OpenAI has options. The contracts often have some capital I ifs. “We believe the risk to OpenAI of not having enough computing power is more significant and more likely than the risk of having too much,” he said, adding that the company is also exploring ways to sell compute to other companies directly, much like CoreWeave does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856883"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.forbes.com/sites/rashishrivastava/2025/11/07/why-sam-altman-wont-be-on-the-hook-for-openais-massive-spending-spree/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/rashishrivastava/2025/11/07/why-sam-altman-wont-be-on-the-hook-for-openais-massive-spending-spree/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856883</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple is crossing a Steve Jobs red line</title>
      <link>https://kensegall.com/2025/11/07/apple-is-crossing-a-steve-jobs-red-line/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That was Steve’s red line. What would Steve Jobs do. If Steve were alive today that abortion that Apple calls a music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850430"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://kensegall.com/2025/11/07/apple-is-crossing-a-steve-jobs-red-line/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThouYS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Apple is far gone, macOS has been buggy for a while. At first I thought this was in favor of iOS, but seeing how iOS usability has suffered, and how they are squandering their reasources on pointless redesigns.. I guess they are just another company now.&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;#x27;s a melancholic reality that only certain outstanding individuals can be relied on to produce greatness. Most of us are just not there.&lt;p&gt;Another such example is Python. Python is slowly being bloated by the people in charge, since Guido basically gave up, soon to be as shitty as C++ is.&lt;p&gt;I am afraid Blender and Pytorch will be next, seeing how the original visionaries have left or will leave in the not so distant future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kwertyoowiyop:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The “Guides We Love” feature in Apple Maps is my a great example of this. When I first saw it I was appalled by its complete uselessness. It’s hard to understand how an Apple team could have created and actually shipped such a waste of space.&lt;p&gt;Edit: deleted a couple of company references that weren’t needed to make my point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codingdave:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This is how Steve laid out his plan to us at the ad agency when he returned to a nearly bankrupt Apple in the late 1990s. The customer experience was all-important.&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is a well-known truth that CX drives product success, and if you want to credit Jobs for that, fine.&lt;p&gt;But referencing back to the 90s because Jobs talked to you directly 25 years ago truly dilutes the message. It is really weird, honestly, to claim that a business strategy from decades ago when Apple was in a completely different reality is some sacrosanct policy that shall never be questioned.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; saying the policy is wrong - I agree with it. So do most product managers I know. But all organizations change over time. Society changes. Tech changes. A viewpoint wherein you have &amp;quot;red lines&amp;quot; that cannot be challenged is short-sighted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sidcool:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting read. But I avoid deifying Jobs.  I won&amp;#x27;t be surprised if he went ahead with Ads for revenue.  Who wouldn&amp;#x27;t!  If he were around the iPhone would not be dramatically different than what it&amp;#x27;s now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lvl155:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve been an Apple fan for as long as I can remember. I didn’t worship Jobs but he had complete control of Apple when he returned and molded the company in his vision. The company lacks that vision. Vision Pro is an example of that failure. Luckily for them iPhone and Mac will continue to dominate. They are here for another decade plus and once the AI bubble passes and we settle on clear winners, Apple will pounce on that opportunity. Am I heartbroken that they’re not the trailblazers? Outsiders? Hipsters? Yes. The brand has gone from Ferrari to Toyota. That’s quite literally the most perfect analogy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quantum_state:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Crossing the red line has consequences … though not immediately…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;techscruggs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Remember that Steve Jobs appointed his COO Tim Cook to take over Apple.  Not Ives or Cue or Federighi.  I&amp;#x27;ve always seen this as an acknowledgment that without Jobs the company would not be able to innovate in the same way.&lt;p&gt;Having acknowledged that, Apple shifted to the value extraction phase of its business lifecycle.&lt;p&gt;It sucks.&lt;p&gt;It like when your favorite band starts selling out, but as publicly traded company, I am not sure it is avoidable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;etempleton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;These moves are the dumbest thing Apple can do for the long- term. It is one of the few differentiators they have between Android and Windows.&lt;p&gt;The App Store ads are one thing, it is a store after all, but adding ads to a core OS functionality like Maps is clear degradation of service. When people spend 1 to 2 grand on a premium phone they don’t expect to see ads, ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tedggh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t think Apple fundamental issues are that hard to fix. First, you need to fire whoever is leading the UX on the OS side. Hardware design is still pretty good. Then we can argue about their lack of innovation and missing the AI train, which btw is still not proven to be a bad (lack of) strategy. But until they don’t get the fundamentals right at the OS UX experience nothing else matters. I hate iOS with passion, both on my phone and Apple Watch, it feels like a Beta version most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; What made Steve an effective and visionary leader was that his values were so crystal clear.&lt;p&gt;Steve also underpaid developers - see the court proceedings here.&lt;p&gt;I am not saying Steve was not creative and effective, mind you. He was that. But he also had a criminal side, and I hate this whitewashing of praising Steve without pointing at the criminal side at the same time. See reports such as this one here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.thedrum.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;steve-jobs-named-top-conspirator-judge-throws-out-deal-give-suing-employees-less" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.thedrum.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;steve-jobs-named-top-conspirato...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The media is often not critical of the superrich, even more so when it is owned by them, which is why unaffiliated media must be a LOT more critical in general. The whole article here babbles about how great Steve Jobs is and how bad Tim Cook is. I&amp;#x27;d rather like to think that both are or were humans with failure points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;testfrequency:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most Apple veterans and current will agree and tell you they do not like the direction the company has gone&amp;#x2F;is going.&lt;p&gt;Most are still there as Apple has one of the most stable employment places, ever. I know a lot of old senior Apple folks who all come back to Apple to retire as the benefits are good, pay is ok, and it’s beyond stable.&lt;p&gt;To this end, including the way Apple operates, it’s low noise and low friction to just coast and let the leadership team duke it out over revenue streams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;carefulfungi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How much f&amp;#x27;n money do these massive corporations really need?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lovidico:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Standards sure have dropped. I saw a new iPad mini in store, on display, and it simply couldn’t run the home screen without stuttering and visible frame rate drops! At least in my mind, this seems like a transgression from Apple’s former standards and that’s before the accessibility and visual challenges new iOS has.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wseqyrku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t use my phone much other than you know, for calling and occasional messaging. For me the most annoying is constant asking of password in both phone and mac. It&amp;#x27;s so secure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ebbi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I probably sound like a broken record, but the death of Apple won&amp;#x27;t come from being behind on AI, from losing developer support, from bad products or services. Fundamentally, it&amp;#x27;ll be because it is optimising for being on the stock market and chasing endless revenue growth.&lt;p&gt;All other issues I&amp;#x27;ve outlined is a symptom of that fundamental issue. Apple is losing its soul.&lt;p&gt;The author suggests Steve would have done something based on what Steve did in the past in that particular set of circumstances. But it&amp;#x27;s not fair to suggest what Steve would have done today, given where Apple is now. Would Steve have said &amp;quot;screw it&amp;quot; to the share price and just ran the company with the same ethos? Maybe, he was bold like that. But then he also had a Board to answer to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gigatexal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Who cares? He’s dead. I know that sounds harsh but this obsession and worship of founders has to stop. Companies are people or so says the Supreme Court. So now that the company exists it’s bigger than any one person even the founder.&lt;p&gt;The company he built is now an order of magnitude more valuable and hardware is the best it’s ever been.&lt;p&gt;It’s maturing. No company stays nimble and vibrant and agile forever. It’s paying a dividend for Pete’s sake.&lt;p&gt;All these callbacks to oh no apple under Steve never would have done this … yeah well it’s 2025 and he unfortunately got cancer and died from it. Apple as a company lives on and new leadership should be free to take it in any direction they seem justified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raincole:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s with this uncanny AI Steve Jobs photo? I hope blog writers have red lines too.&lt;p&gt;The sentiment of this article seems to be praising Jobs as a protector of user experience. And the author doesn&amp;#x27;t have the decency to use his real face?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pzo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sadly iPhone sales and revenue saturated like 4 years ago (and the same for Mac, Wearables and iPad [0]). They focus now a lot on growing revenue from services.
Which is kind of sad because they have still much room to grow Mac and iPad:&lt;p&gt;- just make iPad more useful and support MacOS - it&amp;#x27;s not gonna canibalize Mac, they sale each year 2x more iPads than Macs and 12x more iPhones than Macs.&lt;p&gt;- make macbook Pro standard with 32GB RAM &amp;#x2F; 1TB drive (macbook air with 500GB) and cheaper upgrades. It&amp;#x27;s not like those chips are expensive. Better to sell 2x more devices with smaller margin than holding to your margin like virginity.&lt;p&gt;As for services they could go other way:&lt;p&gt;- be AI gateway like OpenRouter and charge user 10% for token credits topup like electricity bill. Devs then don&amp;#x27;t have to setup back-end, protect API key, setup billings, auth etc or charge end user more with subscription.&lt;p&gt;- make powerful Apple TV or cheaper Mac Mini for all users. Create a distributed computing platform that user can opt-in. Now you are competing with CloudFlare. Those devices normally do nothing during night but could generate&amp;#x2F;compute stuff, execute some lambda in sandbox, work as a proxy. Give 30-50% for device upgrades for such users that opted-in for 2 years.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stockanalysis.com&amp;#x2F;stocks&amp;#x2F;aapl&amp;#x2F;metrics&amp;#x2F;revenue-by-segment&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;stockanalysis.com&amp;#x2F;stocks&amp;#x2F;aapl&amp;#x2F;metrics&amp;#x2F;revenue-by-seg...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gwd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; From that point on, Steve would go on to spend lavishly on things that improved the experience, and he would reject—often brutally—any idea that diluted or harmed the experience. ...I’ll go out on a limb and say that uninvited advertising is not normally equated with a better customer experience.&lt;p&gt;YES!!!  SOO much of the Apple user experience has degraded due to this.  I can&amp;#x27;t listen to my own music that I bought on the Music app, without being interrupted asking if I want Apple Music.  I open up the Books app to read Winnie the Pooh to my son, and the opening screen has loads of random trashy romances to try to sell me.  I go to comfort read Ender&amp;#x27;s Game, which I did buy though the store a decade ago, and it helpfully &amp;quot;groups&amp;quot; it with the other four (!?) books in that series which I haven&amp;#x27;t bought, as if to say, &amp;quot;Don&amp;#x27;t you want to buy these too?&amp;quot;  NO!   If I want to buy them, I know where to find them!&lt;p&gt;It is SUCH an unpleasant experience.  EVERY time I open the App Store to update some apps, I&amp;#x27;m angry that I have to wander past advertising assaults to do it.  EVERY time I open the music app to play an old favorite, I&amp;#x27;m angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.  EVERY time I open up the book app, I&amp;#x27;m angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.&lt;p&gt;I very much doubt the execs understand how much they&amp;#x27;re damaging the brand for that little bit of extra revenue.  The see the extra revenue, but they don&amp;#x27;t see the lost brand, or the people that switch away.  Is it really worth it?&lt;p&gt;ETA: I don&amp;#x27;t think it&amp;#x27;s an exaggeration to say:&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don&amp;#x27;t come with a music player.  They come with a music store, that you happen to be able to put your own music into.  But it&amp;#x27;s not structured to help you play your music, it&amp;#x27;s structured to sell you what they want to sell you.&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don&amp;#x27;t come with an e-book app.  They come with a book store that you happen to be able to upload some of your own books into.  But it&amp;#x27;s not structured to help you organize and read your books -- even the ones you&amp;#x27;ve bought; it&amp;#x27;s structured to sell you more books.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wagwang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very ironic but so much of tech ultimately comes down to taste and Tim Cook obviously just doesn&amp;#x27;t have it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;al_borland:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I will never understand why some companies turn away from some of the core principles that got them to their position.&lt;p&gt;If it’s market pressure, it tells me that Cook doesn’t really believe their future roadmap is good enough for growth, so he needs to hedge with other things that make the product worse. Of course those very things will hurt future growth. That’s how an upward spiral turns downward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dilap:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They crossed it definitively, and still unbelievably, to me, when they started showing ads as the first result in App Store search. For a long time searching &amp;quot;ChatGPT&amp;quot; in the AppStore would surface a rip-off clone w&amp;#x2F; a lookalike icon as the first result. How many thousands of users inadvertently downloaded the clone, paid for it, and were, basically, victims of a scam, facilitated by Apple? (Now the first result for ChatGPT, Claude, Grok is at least the correct first party ad, though this almost seems like extortion on the part of Apple.)&lt;p&gt;(Software quality has also fallen off a cliff, though that&amp;#x27;s more a loss of instutional competence, I think, than active anti-user behavior motivated by avarice.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twsted:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am checking this carefully.
The red line is here, for me and I think for many Apple customers.
I choose Apple for being different from other companies, for valuing customer experiences and for rejecting ads and other &amp;quot;insults&amp;quot; for users.
I think that if they cross the line, me and many other customers will leave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chankstein38:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand why car-based things can have ads or updates that popup or things like that.  My car (2024 Subaru) + Android Auto is so restrictive that I can&amp;#x27;t even type a search query into the screen while I&amp;#x27;m parked, I &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to speak to it.  Yet, while I was out grocery shopping the other day the thing popped up multiple times asking me if I wanted to start an update &amp;quot;That would require you to turn your car off for 5-10 minutes&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It popped up a second time as I &lt;i&gt;SLOWED DOWN&lt;/i&gt; at a red light.  I didn&amp;#x27;t even come to a complete stop but apparently that was &amp;quot;stopped&amp;quot; enough for it to pop up.&lt;p&gt;Not to mention while you&amp;#x27;re using Google Maps the whole time it&amp;#x27;s popping up asking &amp;quot;Is that cop still there?  Is there still construction?&amp;quot; and they&amp;#x27;re looking for you to click on a button on the car&amp;#x27;s screen that indicates yes&amp;#x2F;no.  However, when I&amp;#x27;m parked at a rest area trying to look for the nearest cracker barrel it&amp;#x27;ll start navigating me automatically to one that&amp;#x27;s 45min in the wrong direction instead of just letting me pick which one I want to go to.&lt;p&gt;And now, ads will show in Apple Maps?  Ah yeah, when I&amp;#x27;m driving is definitely the best time to distract me for your own greed!&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s asinine.  Obviously the &amp;quot;Safety features&amp;quot; are just performative.  Probably so they can force us to have a mic enabled or something.  It&amp;#x27;s bs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skhameneh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The very first thing I saw from Apple that, IMO, Jobs would have vehemently stopped was the two-toned back on the iPhone 5.&lt;p&gt;That said, the iOS 26 release is abysmal.  The only redeeming thing for me has been the enhancements to Stage Manager, everything else with the UI&amp;#x2F;UX is such a mess that every day it seems like I&amp;#x27;m discovering something new in the realm of awful design.  And this isn&amp;#x27;t limited to minor nitpicks, there are major CTAs that are essentially &amp;quot;black on black&amp;quot; and practically not visible below 50% screen brightness and not acceptably visible at max brightness.  Just last night I noticed the browser tabs will render full color content behind the text.  It&amp;#x27;s so bad I&amp;#x27;ve been considering cataloging screenshots and writing about it, because some of it&amp;#x27;s laughably bad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;metabagel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I ran a reverse image search on the image of Steve Jobs, and couldn&amp;#x27;t come up with anything, so it does appear that it might be AI generated, which I don&amp;#x27;t approve of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kace91:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t care about whatever Jobs thought, but honestly I do care about apple forgetting that the walled garden’s walls are tolerated only because the experience inside is better.&lt;p&gt;Their hardware is still amazing, but I’ve had enough issues with software quality and Cook’s penny pinching philosophy that I’ve bought a second hand laptop to explore moving to Linux.&lt;p&gt;So far, the experience is making me question whether my next main driver will be a MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;roywiggins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is that AI Steve Jobs in the header image? Pretty uncanny and takes away from the article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;matheusmoreira:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They will &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; put ads into everything. Doesn&amp;#x27;t matter what they say, eventually someone&amp;#x27;s gonna show up and notice that money is being left on the table by not advertising to all those users. Paying them just makes your attention even more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;duxup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ads in Maps and how that contrasts with the customer experience is the message here.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll be honest, I&amp;#x27;m tired of the &amp;quot;steve jobs wouldn&amp;#x27;t&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;apple dying&amp;quot; articles, they&amp;#x27;re oh so shrill and tiresome and I think Steve would have changed with the times too ...&lt;p&gt;Steve aside, I find this particular article&amp;#x27;s observation that ads in maps is a bad customer experience something I can agree with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kensegall.com/2025/11/07/apple-is-crossing-a-steve-jobs-red-line/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 20:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850430</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
