<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:29:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Britain's railway privatization was an abject failure</title>
      <link>https://www.rosalux.de/en/news/id/53917/britains-railway-privatization-was-an-abject-failure</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Six freight operating companies were created. Twenty-five train operating units were also established, which from 1996 onwards were franchised out to the train operating companies. Three rolling stock operating companies (ROSCOs) bought — at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914718"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.rosalux.de/en/news/id/53917/britains-railway-privatization-was-an-abject-failure'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 22 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teekert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Our Dutch one is too (privatized in 1995, it&amp;#x27;s one of our biggest employers as well), we have a nice railway system but the car is generally cheaper, even when using it alone. It&amp;#x27;s always about how much money the railway system is loosing, but I don&amp;#x27;t see anybody crying about the money our roads are loosing. Isn&amp;#x27;t it all just transport infrastructure?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmyeet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Two legacies from the 1980s and 1990s that haunt us to this day are:&lt;p&gt;1. The idea of trickle down economics; and&lt;p&gt;2. That public-private partnerships (&amp;quot;PPPs&amp;quot; were a stalwart of Thatcher and Blair) do anything other than simply transfer wealth from the public sector to the private sector. Put another way, PPPs socialize the risk and privatize the profits.&lt;p&gt;For anyone who pays attention and can think critically, this is the least suprising thing that can possibly happen and was evident decades ago.&lt;p&gt;For the railways in particular, railroads (technically, train operating companies or TOCs) in the UK have zero incentive to invest in rolling stock, track, signalling systems or stations because they own none of it. So all they do is engage in cutting costs and gaming politics to raise prices to increase profits. That&amp;#x27;s all that happens.&lt;p&gt;You can say that British Rail needed reform and funding but PPPs were simply not the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fmajid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As opposed to the privatization of water utilities, which was such a resounding success?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jwblackwell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A lot of people in the UK seem to think the trains in Europe are so much better, but that&amp;#x27;s not the case, at least in my experience. We took an interrail trip a couple of years ago and spent half the time sat on the floor and waiting for delayed trains. If anything, the overall experience was much worse than trains in the UK, especially if you factored in the difficulty in procuring the correct tickets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;usrbinbash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All privatizations of public infrastructur and services are failures, simply due to the discrepancy between the interests:&lt;p&gt;The public wants: Cheap, reliable, quality services.&lt;p&gt;A corporation wants: Maximized Revenue.&lt;p&gt;The two inevitably clash. No matter what business, no matter what country. Don&amp;#x27;t believe me? Go and find a single instance of a service that used to be provided completely by the government, that got BETTER FOR USERS (that is: The Public, not investors) after being privatized. I&amp;#x27;ll wait.&lt;p&gt;Public utilitis HAVE TO be run by the public, meaning the government. In pretty much every instance where this isn&amp;#x27;t the case, the provided service is more expensive, and&amp;#x2F;or less effective for the people.&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#x27;s why I am sick and tired of the old trope &amp;quot;bUt pRivAtE sEcToR mOrE effIciEnt!&amp;quot; Sure. That would be the same private sector that caused almost every non-war related major economic crisis, is it not? I think the &amp;quot;efficiency argument&amp;quot; is already a moot point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KaiserPro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The problem with this assement is that it misunderstands the role of the private sector.&lt;p&gt;Yes, those crashes happened, and they were disasters, but they were only partially down to rail track being privatised. They were a result of systemic under investment both pre and post privatisation.&lt;p&gt;THe _other_ key thing that needs to be remembered is that rail is highly regulated. To the point that both price, timetables profit and pay are controlled by the deparment of transport.&lt;p&gt;The bigger issue is that actually the department of transport doesn&amp;#x27;t have the specialists needed to run the railways, they are hired in as consultants.&lt;p&gt;If you compare that to TFL, which operates both private (DLR and some of the overground) and public (most of the tubes, not sure about elizabeth line) and  buseses (which are entirely private)&lt;p&gt;The railways are in the state they are because of poor governance from central government. and poor investment, also from government.&lt;p&gt;IF they had been publicly owned, we&amp;#x27;d be in the same state, because the UK government is not currently able to run services effectively. Unless and until the political classes are willing to pay civl servants competitive rates of pay &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; trust data, then we will continue to be in a mess.&lt;p&gt;Yes, privatization is bad, but the lack of effective governance is the hidden crisis here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tompagenet2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As always this is grossly oversimplifying. As well as the misleading safety stats, as graemep has noted, it ignores that journeys just absolutely exploded under privatisation [&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Privatisation_of_British_Rail" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Privatisation_of_British_Rail&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;endoblast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I miss being able to spontaneously buy a ticket and travel off to see a friend in another town or city. I did quite a lot as a young man with the help of my &amp;#x27;young person&amp;#x27;s railcard&amp;#x27;. The cost would be prohibitive nowadays because only tickets bought well in advance are cheap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ponco:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The privatisation of the commons will endure as our generations&amp;#x27; greatest folly. 
I look at the Australian NBN as a great example of a project that is not economical for a private business to entertain - it requires &amp;quot;The Government&amp;quot; to build. How do we reason with this in the capitalist system?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Depends - some got wealthier. :)&lt;p&gt;Although, even with this in mind, it seems as if the UK really has a notoriously bad railway system. Most countries in the EU of a comparable size have a better railway system as such, even though they also have their own problems. One of the best in Europe is in Switzerland - the swiss really are clever. And also not in the EU.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;epolanski:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Privatization in Europe, otoh, is going okay-ish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildgoose:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I remember that the UK was forced to privatise Rail in the way that it did because of EU competition rules.  I was commuting by Rail at the time and the manner in which it was privatised was considered to be barmy by both myself and fellow passengers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hardlianotion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s really an open question - UK&amp;#x27;s railways were in a poor state &amp;amp; lacking investment when they were handed over.  Rail journeys and infrastructure investment did increase in the intervening period.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not at all clear that railways will have consistent, adequate funding in the public realm, not least because the government is leery of capital expenditure and is always interested in ways to make debt levels look smaller.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FridayoLeary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The central claim of the article makes sense. Tickets are too expensive and that&amp;#x27;s all i care about as a consumer. I don&amp;#x27;t agree with many of the authors arguments and his proposed solutions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; the case
against fragmented and
privatized operations
focuses on three key
arguments. The first is that
railways are complex systems where commercial
boundaries at engineering
interfaces are a threat to
safety and efficiency. The
second is that railway
operations are geographic monopolies where market
conditions are — at best —
contrived. The third is that
railways are a public service
that cannot fail — hence,
introducing private interests into the railways is
merely a way to sequester
income into private hands
while the state shoulders
the financial risk. In other
words, private interests’ role is simply to extract
profit that could otherwise
be reinvested into the
system.&lt;p&gt;That is true of most infrastructure. The closest parallel i can think of is the airline industry. It may never be perfect but these problems are solveable.&lt;p&gt;Next the claim that moving decisions away from Westminster will make things better. That is highly debatable.&lt;p&gt;Finally the main point. The nationalised railway worked well in the 90s so it would work well today. That is such an obviously flawed argument i won&amp;#x27;t even bother discussing it. I think the local government in London has far more direct control of local transport and it is horribly inefficient and expensive. Finally look at the ongoing, slow motion train wreck which is the hs2 rail project. At this stage it&amp;#x27;s just a government employment program for labourers. It&amp;#x27;s way, way too expensive and they should have pulled the plug on it years ago or drastically deregulated idk. As it is we have the worst of both worlds.&lt;p&gt;However, it is interesting that Thatcher didn&amp;#x27;t want to privatise the rails. Does anyone know what her opinion on it was?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arpinum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m undecided if privatisation was a failure. I don&amp;#x27;t know the counterfactual scenario well enough. The article paints a picture that British Rail was doing just fine, making all capital investments necessary, and at low taxpayer cost. I&amp;#x27;m somewhat skeptical that it would continue like that for 30 years. Any better analysis?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abracos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For context: The website is called Rosa-Luxemburg-Stiftung. Rosa Luxemburg was a Polish and naturalised-German Marxist theorist and revolutionary. A very biased source&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dickiedyce:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a Scot who travels on Scottish, English, and Welsh railways, and on Swiss and German railways... Scotrail (now in Public ownership) is pretty good. And I say that as someone in the Highlands, which has had the worst of it in the last 30 years. There&amp;#x27;s been recent investment, and even the re-opening of closed lines and finally new stations where they&amp;#x27;ve been desperately needed (Inverness Airport, Kintore, Laurencekirk). But still plenty more to do.
I visit the south semi-regularly, and worked in London in the 90&amp;#x27;s. Rail around London seems to have really improved over the last few years.
Swiss Rail (SBB) is still the poster child for a decent rail system. Clean, on time, reasonably priced (compared to UK rail), and easy to use. 
What was eye-opening for me was recent travel in Germany (München to Basel in CH)... DB was dreadful and the stations were in an awful state of repair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TriangleEdge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How does the govt pick executives or companies for owning the railways?&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of the three credit bureaus in the US. These companies suck, and offer 0 innovations, but we are stuck them for the foreseeable long term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;graemep:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It implies railways were les safe post privatisation. This is misleading. There were more accidents and deaths, but that was because of a huge increase in miles travelled. Deaths per billion kilometers fell consistently before and after privatisation.&lt;p&gt;A lot of the problems lie in tracks and their maintenance, and the tracks were re-nationalised many years ago. It is not efficiently run (see HS2!).&lt;p&gt;They are expensive, but that is partly because rail workers are well paid. Train drivers can be paid as much as aircraft pilots. Their ability and willingness to strike affects both costs and people&amp;#x27;s willingness to rely on public transport.&lt;p&gt;The big constraint is lack of subsidies. it probably makes little difference whether the system is privately owned but tightly regulated, or publicly owned so much as willingness to subsidise it. This is also shown by the failure of franchises taken back into public ownership to improve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slightwinder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Similar problem with &amp;quot;Deutsche Bahn&amp;quot; in Germany. Probably also the reason why this German political NGO is writing this article. Are there any other countries with similar problems or history in their public transportation-systems?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wtcactus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hear these stories about UK private rail system being terrible for more than a decade now. But, truth is, I go there frequently and the times I had to use it it was quite fine. Lots of trains and they arrived on time (and they were fairly clean).&lt;p&gt;It was much, much better - by any account of imagination - than the public railway we have here in Portugal. And I’m guessing they cost the taxpayers a lot less too (but that part I didn’t check).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wood_spirit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does Britain have any privatisation success stories?  Or any public-private partnership (PPP) success stories?&lt;p&gt;Does any country have any success stories?&lt;p&gt;I can’t think of any.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rosalux.de/en/news/id/53917/britains-railway-privatization-was-an-abject-failure</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914718</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blender Lab</title>
      <link>https://www.blender.org/news/introducing-blender-lab/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lab activity is a project that brings innovation to the Blender project, and contributes to Blender Foundation’s mission. You can make this happen by joining the Blender Development Fund at fund. Francesco SiddiBlender Foundation Support the Future of Blender Donate to Blender by joining the Development Fund to support the Blender Foundation’s work on core development, maintenance, and new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914761"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.blender.org/news/introducing-blender-lab/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DonHopkins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This Blender Lab page &amp;quot;Beyond Mouse and Keyboard&amp;quot; page mentions the &amp;quot;wheel menu&amp;quot;:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;code.blender.org&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;07&amp;#x2F;beyond-mouse-keyboard&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;code.blender.org&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;07&amp;#x2F;beyond-mouse-keyboard&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s an wonderful Blender extension, the Sculpt Wheel, that has concentric rings, and is deeply customizable (this video was posted 15 hours ago so it&amp;#x27;s fresh and current):&lt;p&gt;Blender 4.5 Sculpt Wheel - Glyph+&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=IhO-aU512NE&amp;amp;t=1s" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=IhO-aU512NE&amp;amp;t=1s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lfaw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m quite interested in the academic research aspect, especially since our computational geometry group uses or plans on using Blender. However, I&amp;#x27;m unclear about the details of this announcement. Is it related to funding opportunities or suggesting experimental features?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simgt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If there are contributors to Blender from the industry, who are they? It&amp;#x27;s easy to understand how big tech can be contributing to Linux, data processing pipelines, web frameworks, compilers etc. but it&amp;#x27;s harder to see who has both the skills and incentives for design tools. Maybe some game studios have the necessary slack?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;frustracean:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If anyone else is having trouble loading the CSS for the page, go to &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.blender.org&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;themes&amp;#x2F;bthree&amp;#x2F;style.css?x78892" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.blender.org&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;themes&amp;#x2F;bthree&amp;#x2F;style.css?x...&lt;/a&gt; to be Captcha&amp;#x27;d by Cloudflare - it should load fine after that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raxxorraxor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think there is some problem loading CSS for this site. Could be my current network though...&lt;p&gt;edit: you might need to auth yourself as human to cloudflare on blender.org for the site to display correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.blender.org/news/introducing-blender-lab/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914761</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Partial Outage</title>
      <link>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/1jw8ltnr1qrj</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Resend OTP By subscribing you agree to our Privacy Policy. This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply. This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915731"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/1jw8ltnr1qrj'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gunalx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yep. Was using github for oauth on a petproject of mine. Got the unicorn, and was considering takingthe break, or just etting up something else. Seems to be running again for me now though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rvz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looking forward to the postmortem.&lt;p&gt;Are they using AI agents this time to resolve the outage? Probably not.&lt;p&gt;But this time, there is no CEO of GitHub to contact and good luck contacting Satya to solve the outage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theletterf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was getting crazy thinking that there was something wrong with my SSH keys all of a sudden. Thanks $DEITY it&amp;#x27;s just GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arccy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Your weekly reminder to take a break&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;danfritz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related to the recent announcement they are moving to Azure?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/1jw8ltnr1qrj</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915731</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kratos - Cloud native Auth0 open-source alternative (self-hosted)</title>
      <link>https://github.com/ory/kratos</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents What is Ory Kratos. Ory Kratos is an API first identity and user management system that follows cloud architecture best practices. Self-host Ory Kratos You can run Ory Kratos yourself for full control over infrastructure, deployment, and customization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915114"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/ory/kratos'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bitcrshr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Kratos is awesome, especially alongside Hydra, OathKeeper, and Keto. Super powerful combo, if not a little intimidating at first. There’s a LOT of configuration involved, but that’s to be expected if you want to host your own Auth0 replacement.&lt;p&gt;Their dynamic forms stuff is really cool too, always liked how they chose to go about that. Only complaint I really ever had is that while their docs were overall serviceable, I remember some areas were pretty lacking and I had to dig really far to find answers to some fairly common issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nja:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve used [Keycloak](&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.keycloak.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.keycloak.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) in the past for &amp;quot;open-source Auth0&amp;quot; -- though I&amp;#x27;m not sure it has ever described itself that way.&lt;p&gt;Keycloak ended up being quite extensible and powerful, but the UI and data model both sometimes made things more difficult than they had to be... this could be an interesting project to look at.&lt;p&gt;One bonus (for us) for Keycloak was that it was JVM-based, meaning it was easier to integrate our existing JVM libraries.  Though its use of Hibernate was frustrating at times, heh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;caleblloyd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used Ory Kratos in a Go application a couple years ago by installing it as a dependency.  It worked pretty well but in hindsight I would have hosted it as a separate application because it was a pain to bring along all of its dependencies.&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest complaints was that one of the Account Recovery flows was just an emailed 6-digit code.  So a 1 in 1 million chance that somebody without access to any of your stuff could hack you by just hitting reset and guessing &amp;quot;123456&amp;quot;.  It&amp;#x27;s actually surprising how many other Account Recovery flows across the web I have noticed recently that do the same thing.  Not sure if Ory has added the option for more entropy in this code as of today&amp;#x27;s release though it&amp;#x27;s been a while since I&amp;#x27;ve used it.&lt;p&gt;Otherwise it was a great project to work with that has tons of knobs to customize.  I commend the authors, aeneasr especially.  It must be a ton of work to keep up with all of the auth standards and offer this in an Apache2 licensed package all while building a business around it as well!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/ory/kratos</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915114</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denx (a.k.a. U-Boot) Retires</title>
      <link>https://www.denx.de/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 20 successful years in the embedded world, the DENX holders decided to wind-down operations and retire. Still looking for great support. You will find the same expertise and quality support you experienced in many years in DENX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915069"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.denx.de/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kevin_thibedeau:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;NABLA is one typo away from some unsavory people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.denx.de/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915069</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Competition? That's Usually a Red Flag for Solopreneurs</title>
      <link>https://meysam.io/blog/no-competition-red-flag-solopreneur-validated-market/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All that beautiful infrastructure. They have thousands of customers. customer conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915674"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://meysam.io/blog/no-competition-red-flag-solopreneur-validated-market/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JohnFen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This truth was one of the first things I learned in the School of Hard Knocks. If you&amp;#x27;ve identified a market that nobody else is addressing, the odds are very high that there&amp;#x27;s a solid reason nobody else is addressing it.&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;#x27;t automatically mean that your idea can&amp;#x27;t be successful, but it does mean that you should take a step back and do a hard rethink. Maybe you can identify the reason everyone else is avoiding it and can eliminate or bypass the problem, for instance. But there almost certainly is a problem that you haven&amp;#x27;t spotted. Further, it&amp;#x27;s probably a hard problem to solve, since nobody else has managed it.&lt;p&gt;This kind of thing is one of the several reasons why you don&amp;#x27;t want to be the first to enter a product category (&amp;quot;the pioneers get the arrows&amp;quot;). The sweet spot to aim for is to be second or third. Then the market is already validated, and you can also learn how to make your product better by learning from the mistakes of your competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://meysam.io/blog/no-competition-red-flag-solopreneur-validated-market/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915674</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heartbeats in Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/heartbeats-in-distributed-systems/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is where heartbeat mechanisms come into play. The first component is the heartbeat sender. This component listens for incoming heartbeats and tracks when each heartbeat was received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914815"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/heartbeats-in-distributed-systems/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paulsutter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; When a system uses very short intervals, such as sending heartbeats every 500 milliseconds&lt;p&gt;500 milliseconds is a very long interval, on a CPU timescale. Funny how we all tend to judge intervals based on human timescales&lt;p&gt;Of course the best way to choose heartbeat intervals is based on metrics like transaction failure rate or latency&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arpitbhayani.me/blogs/heartbeats-in-distributed-systems/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914815</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Posts Device Trees for Booting Pixel 10 with Mainline Linux Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-Pixel-10-Google-DTs</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;19 Comments A Chromium engineer at Google posted the initial Device Tree (DT) files for being able to boot their latest-generation Pixel 10, Pixel 10 Pro, and Pixel 10 Pro XL devices with the mainline Linux kernel. Outside the confines of Google's Android, out today is the initial Device Trees for being able to boo the Google Pixel 10 / Pixel 10 Pro / Pixel 10 Pro XL devices with these patches proposed for the mainline Linux kernel. "This series adds barebones device trees for Pixel 10 (frankel), Pixel 10 Pro (blazer), and Pixel 10 Pro XL (mustang).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915380"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-Pixel-10-Google-DTs'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tasn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Still cool, but very much a click bait!&lt;p&gt;You can boot the pixel 10 with mainline Linux Kernel!&lt;p&gt;Oh, but the patches to support that haven&amp;#x27;t landed in the kernel yet.&lt;p&gt;Oh, and you also need a custom bootloader that hasn&amp;#x27;t been released yet.&lt;p&gt;And btw, it doesn&amp;#x27;t boot a fully functional system, just a basic uart interface.&lt;p&gt;Still cool, but not what I expected from the headline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zb3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note these are not the same as the Android &amp;quot;device trees&amp;quot; they stopped publishing with the Android 16 release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.phoronix.com/news/Google-Pixel-10-Google-DTs</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915380</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
