<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:20:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>What If Tariffs?</title>
      <link>https://www.swatch.com/en-en/what-if-tariffs-so34z106/SO34Z106.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The inspiration behind the WHAT IF…TARIFFS. model lies in the current events unfolding in today’s world. The unique details on its dial and battery cover hint at the US tariffs imposed on Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.swatch.com/en-en/what-if-tariffs-so34z106/SO34Z106.html'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.swatch.com/en-en/what-if-tariffs-so34z106/SO34Z106.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710021</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asbestosis</title>
      <link>https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/10/asbestosis.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1913 the Cape Asbestos Company built a huge asbestos factory beside the River Roding in Barking. My grandfather worked for another Cape Asbestos plant on Tolpits Lane in Watford. I don't remember very much about my grandfather because he died when I was 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/10/asbestosis.html'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/10/asbestosis.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710065</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2025: Number of puzzles reduce from 25 to 12 for the first time</title>
      <link>https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I make Advent of Code. Advent of Code uses OAuth to confirm your identity through other services. Then, the service you use tells the Advent of Code servers that you're really you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710006</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitmovin (YC S15) Is Hiring Engineering ICs and Managers in Europe</title>
      <link>https://bitmovin.com/careers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CAREERS AT BITMOVIN Come work with us. Think through the customer lens. Search Location Vienna; Klagenfurt; Berlin Klagenfurt Austria Remote - EMEA Vienna London or Vienna Denver Remote - USA/Denver London Vienna; Klagenfurt Berlin; Vienna; Klagenfurt Berlin; Vienna; Klagenfurt; Remote - EU Germany Spain Positions AI &amp; Beyond Internship Incubator (Summer 2026) Vienna; Klagenfurt; Berlin Business Internship (Praxissemester) Klagenfurt, Austria Customer Success Manager (EMEA) Remote - EMEA Engineering Manager (VOD Encoding) Klagenfurt, Vienna Marketing &amp; PR Executive London or Vienna Product Support Engineer Denver Sales Executive (EMEA) Remote - EMEA Sales Executiv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bitmovin.com/careers'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bitmovin.com/careers</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709698</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clojure Land – Discover open-source Clojure libraries and frameworks</title>
      <link>https://clojure.land/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last updatedNameStarsPavlov38Behavioral Programming for ClojurecljBehavorial programmingECA (Editor Code Assistant) 446Editor Code Assistant (ECA) - AI pair programming capabilities agnostic of editorcljAICode EditorsECA Emacs209Editor Code Assistant (ECA) integration for EmacscljAICode EditorsEmacsclojure2d570Java2D wrapper + creative coding supporting functions (based on Processing and openFrameworks)cljGraphicsJoyride551Making VS Code Hackable like Emacs since 2022cljVSCodeReplicant437A data-driven rendering library for Clojure(Script) that renders hiccup to DOM or to strings. cljVSCodeQClojure37A functional quantum computer programming library for Clojure with backend protocols, simulation backends and visualizations. cljDistributed ProgramminghadoopECA VS Code4Editor Code Assistant (ECA) integration for VscodecljAICode EditorsVSCodePedestal2750An open source tool set for building web applications in ClojurecljAsynchronous HTTPWeb FrameworksWeb Server Abstractiondata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://clojure.land/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clojure.land/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709988</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaserTweezer – Optical Trap</title>
      <link>https://www.gaudi.ch/GaudiLabs/?page_id=578</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LaserTweezer – Optical Trap Optical Tweezers are scientific instruments to manipulate objects of microscopic size. Construction Details Construction Details of “DIY Laser Tweezer” [7]: Conventional DVD drive optical pickups emit a laser beam form a diode that passes through a diffraction grating, a polarizing beam splitter and is then collimated and focused onto a plane. To prevent overexposing of the camera by the laser beam a scatter disk made from black cardboard material with two slits of about 10° is positioned in the optical path just in front of the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.gaudi.ch/GaudiLabs/?page_id=578'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.gaudi.ch/GaudiLabs/?page_id=578</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709922</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a RISC-V Emulator in Rust</title>
      <link>https://book.rvemu.app/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing a RISC-V Emulator in Rust NOTE: This project is actively ongoing. Introduction This is the book for writing a 64-bit RISC-V emulator from scratch in Rust. You'll learn the basic computer architecture such as ISA, previleged architecture, exceptions, interrupts, peripheral devices, and virtual memory system from making an emulator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://book.rvemu.app/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://book.rvemu.app/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709819</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
