<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:50:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Installing and using HP-UX 9</title>
      <link>https://thejpster.org.uk/blog/blog-2025-11-08/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The HP 9000 Model 340 The system specs for this machine are: Motorola 68030 CPU at 16. Yes, that a 68030 machine network booting from a PA-RISC machine. So, how does that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873904"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thejpster.org.uk/blog/blog-2025-11-08/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used the versions 10 and 11.&lt;p&gt;My significant experiences on HP-UX were HP Vault, one the very first approaches of doing containers in UNIX, and going through 32 bit to 64 bit transition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mesrik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;IMHO, HP-UX had hands down best written man pages I&amp;#x27;ve ever seen any UNIX commercial or free. And I&amp;#x27;ve been working quite many with.&lt;p&gt;All man pages were well written, nicely formatted easy to read and almost all came with often valuable examples giving quick enough understanding to check usage most often. That has been absolutely the thing that I&amp;#x27;ve missed other *nix systems since.&lt;p&gt;But there are too many things were done so nicely and made it nice to maintain with HP-UX that it&amp;#x27;s not worth trying to remember and list all. But unfortunately shell environment was not match to convenience GNU tools Linux had from beginning. That is without making effort to install (read: compile from source for quite long time) those HP-UX if that was allowed. With university computing center that no problem, but telco side it was big nono -- not without getting product owner permission first :&amp;#x2F;&lt;p&gt;But just an example Ignite-UX was one of my favourites with HP-UX. The simplicity using a one simple command with few options bootable DAT tape that could then be used to either recover whole running fully functional system or clone that developed system first to staging lab and then up to production with ease was great time saver major upgrades and migrations. None of the Linux bare metal backup systems I&amp;#x27;ve tested have been able to recover exactly same disk layouts, usually LVM part is poorly done. As has been VmWare p2v migration tools also btw.&lt;p&gt;That Linux LVM that Sistina did first before Red Hat bought them, is implemented quite exactly what HP-UX had for some time then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aniou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nowadays NetBSD offers something similar to &amp;quot;context depended filesystem&amp;quot;, i.e. a special form of symbolic links that can points to different locations, according to wide range set of attributes: from &lt;i&gt;domainname&lt;/i&gt; via &lt;i&gt;machine_arch&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;gid&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;For details see &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;man.netbsd.org&amp;#x2F;symlink.7" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;man.netbsd.org&amp;#x2F;symlink.7&lt;/a&gt; - section &lt;i&gt;Magic symlinks&lt;/i&gt; at very end of manual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chkaloon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks for this. Brings back so many memories of the long hours spent in computer rooms with HP 9000s and RS&amp;#x2F;6000s back in the 90s. Seeing that SAM interface made me shiver :)&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s great that there are folks like you preserving this history&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spedione:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The &amp;quot;context dependent filesystem&amp;quot; concept is a bit trippy, but I think it&amp;#x27;s a pretty neat solution to &amp;quot;some systems need a their own version of a file, other files ought to be universal&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TMWNN:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From the author&amp;#x27;s Reddit post &amp;lt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;vintagecomputing&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1ot83o4&amp;#x2F;you_can_boot_68k_hpux_and_parisc_hpux_from_the&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;vintagecomputing&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1ot83o4&amp;#x2F;y...&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;I’ve got my HP 9000 Model 340 booting over the network from an HP 9000 Model 705 in Cluster Server mode and I’ve learned some very unsettling things about HP-UX and its filesystem.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Boot-up video at the end of the blog, where I play a bit of the original version of Columns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thejpster.org.uk/blog/blog-2025-11-08/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873904</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe to decide if 6 GHz is shared between Wi-Fi and cellular networks</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/09/europe_to_decide_if_6/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;"Blocking Wi-Fi access to the upper 6 GHz band would be devastating to the future of Wi-Fi technology in Europe. It claims that Wi-Fi has access to "significantly less spectrum than mobile. " ® Get our Tech Resources Share More about 6G Wi-Fi More like these × More about 6G Wi-Fi Narrower topics 5G Edge Computing Broader topics Cellular network Mobile Network Standards Wi-Fi Alliance More.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874659"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/09/europe_to_decide_if_6/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oytis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the context - what US, UK and China do?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;welder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish govt would put a condition on the mobile carriers to fix SS7 vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hk__2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;EU, not Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mvandermeulen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thank you Europe?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/09/europe_to_decide_if_6/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874659</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft's lack of quality control is out of control</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/08/microsoft_lacks_quality_control/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;" ® Get our Tech Resources Share More about Microsoft Windows Windows 11 More like these × More about Microsoft Windows Windows 11 Narrower topics Active Directory Azure Bing Bitlocker BSoD Excel Exchange Server HoloLens Internet Explorer LinkedIn Microsoft 365 Microsoft Build Microsoft Edge Microsoft Fabric Microsoft Ignite Microsoft Office Microsoft Surface Microsoft Teams. NET Office 365 OS/2 Outlook Patch Tuesday Pluton PowerShell SharePoint Skype SQL Server Visual Studio Visual Studio Code Windows 10 Windows 2000 Windows 7 Windows 8 Windows Server Windows Server 2003 Windows Server 2008 Windows Server 2012 Windows Server 2013 Windows Server 2016 Windows Subsystem for Linux Windows XP WPF Xbox Xbox 360 Broader topics Bill Gates Operating System More about Share 141 COMMENTS More about Microsoft Windows Windows 11 More like these × More about Microsoft Windows Windows 11 Narrower topics Active Directory Azure Bing Bitlocker BSoD Excel Exchange Server HoloLens Internet Explorer LinkedIn Microsoft 365 Microsoft Build Microsoft Edge Microsoft Fabric Microsoft Ignite Microsoft Office Microsoft Surface Microsoft Teams. NET Office 365 OS/2 Outlook Patch Tuesday Pluton PowerShell SharePoint Skype SQL Server Visual Studio Visual Studio Code Windows 10 Windows 2000 Windows 7 Windows 8 Windows Server Windows Server 2003 Windows Server 2008 Windows Server 2012 Windows Server 2013 Windows Server 2016 Windows Subsystem for Linux Windows XP WPF Xbox Xbox 360 Broader topics Bill Gates Operating System TIP US OFF Send us news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873876"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/08/microsoft_lacks_quality_control/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 19 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;karel-3d:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Both Microsoft and Apple software quality has go down recently. What is going on. Is it the AI-produced code? It can&amp;#x27;t be that...&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know how are things in Google land; their apps and websites are just-OK; however GMail seems quite stagnant - yeah they slapped LLM on it, cool; but other than that... they added Chat? few years ago? But at least Google&amp;#x27;s stuff mostly works, even when it&amp;#x27;s boring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_the_inflator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As one MS Director put it out of frustration: &amp;quot;We do test, a lot. Our testers are called endusers. That&amp;#x27;s it.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;More precisely: He said MSlers get paid by results, achieved Business Value. Testers exist and are called &amp;quot;End Users&amp;quot;. Testing is mandatory and part of the core philosophy - they just must do it differently.&lt;p&gt;Reason: Fear of missing out if moving to slow.&lt;p&gt;I reminisce the times, where you put in a CD without internet connection. Actual Office is a mess. Thousands of half finished apps, subject to be cancelled anytime. Windows XP&amp;#x27;s UI was dubbed &amp;quot;glossy&amp;quot; - some of Office&amp;#x27;s apps UIs are LSD trips for kids. This is ridiculous. Nothing to work with and in no way usable for customer presentations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fergie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; At one point, Microsoft&amp;#x27;s QC was legendary&lt;p&gt;I have been Microsoft-adjacent for 30 years, and at no point in that time have I been aware of Microsoft having a reputation for &amp;quot;quality&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fransje26:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; At one point, Microsoft&amp;#x27;s QC was legendary.&lt;p&gt;Is that legendary QC in the room with us right now?&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theregister.com&amp;#x2F;2018&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;20&amp;#x2F;windows_98_comdex_bsod_video&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theregister.com&amp;#x2F;2018&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;20&amp;#x2F;windows_98_comdex_bso...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fortranfiend:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Patches have been a mess the last couple years. Makes me think someone or a group of people either quit, were fired, or got pulled into the ai side of the business. The mistakes being made are that of junior programmers without a proper lead or review and testing team. That plus removal of features and addition of too much telemetry into the os and office products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ethin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hot take but I seriously think both Agile&amp;#x2F;Scrum and &amp;quot;make a single dev do a ton of things that wouldn&amp;#x27;t necessarily count as software development&amp;quot; (like RDB design and management) is the direct cause of all of these problems. It is my opinion that Agile&amp;#x2F;scrum (or, at least, the &amp;quot;agile&amp;quot;&amp;#x2F;&amp;quot;scrum&amp;quot; that corporations understand) institutionalized the &amp;quot;move fast, break things, consolidate everything into as few positions as possible&amp;quot; mindset, in the name of things like &amp;quot;reducing expenditures&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;ship things really fast and damn the consequences&amp;quot;. That includes, oh, I dunno, dumping QA&amp;#x2F;QC and putting all of that on the end-users. Maybe the real Agile might not do this, but I can&amp;#x27;t say because, from what I know, very few, if any, corporations actually use the real Agile at all, and instead repurpose the word to mean a completely different system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bronlund:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Complaining about Microsoft&amp;#x27;s lack of quality control is like complaining the strip club has poor lighting for reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReptileMan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Unfortunately the only thing about MS that doesn&amp;#x27;t suck is their sales prowess. Delivery and quality are optional, but getting companies to use their stack is not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giancarlostoro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not just that, but even their game studios. Take for example Starfield. Lots of hype, massive letdown. I&amp;#x27;m one of many massive Bethesda fans. Starfield absolutely could have had so much more, but HN knows what happens with software projects. Deadlines aren&amp;#x27;t met, marketing &amp;#x2F; business depts start signaling that we need it out the door yesterday, and a bunch of things get cut. I have seen on reddit loads of comments about a ton of content being cut out of Starfield, which is ridiculous, Bethesda games are always content rich.&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is a giant behemoth, it needs to reorg in a way that allows its very distinct pieces to function correctly. I wish Microsoft would let Bethesda have full autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andyish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not just their flagship products. It extends to nearly _everything_ they release.&lt;p&gt;I have a relatively small workforce and office management platform. When MS Places was announced, we thought it was the end. We had a good run, but now one of the big players has entered the market and will wipe out all competition with a single swipe.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it sucks. Potential customers who had waited for months tried to use it and immediately sought alternatives. Existing customers who told us they tried to use it and for one reason or another, gave up.&lt;p&gt;But it seems Microsoft&amp;#x27;s MO has been &amp;#x27;customer driven testing&amp;#x27; for as long as i can remember.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharlin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In 2014, the company decided it could do without many of its testers. Mary Jo Foley reported that &amp;quot;a good chunk&amp;quot; were being laid off. Microsoft didn&amp;#x27;t need to bother with traditional methods of testing code. Waterfall was out. Agile was in.&lt;p&gt;An average software dev today is expected to do the work and have the skillset that used to take a half dozen people or more.&lt;p&gt;There were of course even more roles in the prehistory, but if we think the 2000s, I can count at least: RDB design and management; planning and specification work; interfacing with the customer; testing; merging UI and backend engineering to &amp;quot;full stack&amp;quot;; merging coding, operations and admin to &amp;quot;devops&amp;quot;… I&amp;#x27;m pretty sure that the only reason devs aren&amp;#x27;t yet expected to make their own sales is that the sales department is a profit center and, as such, sacrosanct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recursivedoubts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“slowly, then all at once”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ktzar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Consequences of having early access to ChatGPT and getting AI knowledge debt?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sublimefire:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A pretty thin opinion piece, I was expecting more details. But there are a bunch of comments under that article which is probably juicier than the main text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blueflow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reminder: The UEFI&amp;#x2F;SecureBoot&amp;#x2F;systemd-boot stack is controlled by Microsoft as well. Microsoft signs our bootloaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rochak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Microsoft has gone so deep down the gutter, it is almost unbelievable. I am waiting for the day their profits start taking a hit due to a collective boycott.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;netdevphoenix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article left out the most important question: are there any lasting negative consequences for Microsoft due to all these accidents? The answer is likely no. And that&amp;#x27;s all the the shareholders care about sadly. So this will continue to happen imo. Those Quality Assurance testers won&amp;#x27;t be coming back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gary_0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[deleted]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dude250711:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It will get worse, the combined strike of HTML-based &amp;quot;native&amp;quot; UIs, outsourcing and vibe-coding will be too much for any remaining original devs to defend against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/08/microsoft_lacks_quality_control/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873876</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNS Provider Quad9 Sees Piracy Blocking Orders as "Existential Threat"</title>
      <link>https://torrentfreak.com/dns-provider-quad9-sees-piracy-blocking-orders-as-existential-threat/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That said, for the small Swiss non-profit organization, these proceedings are more than a legal disagreement. In a recent blog post, Quad9 explains that its foundation doesn’t have this luxury. Big Questions In France, the courts have clearly decided that these blocking orders are warranted, and while some are under appeal, there’s no indication that they will be reversed anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874850"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://torrentfreak.com/dns-provider-quad9-sees-piracy-blocking-orders-as-existential-threat/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imustaskforhelp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; “At what point does legal compliance become de facto censorship?”&lt;p&gt;I genuinely agree with this statement a lot. Also another aspect of this is that the bigger companies can somehow &amp;quot;legally&amp;quot; do things which I don&amp;#x27;t think would work but they have so many resources to strech the court case for a long time.&lt;p&gt;And the fact is that even after that, even if they are fined for some dollars. They are more than likely to just pay than try to actually fix the core issues which effects everyone harmfully except the company.&lt;p&gt;All for profit smh. I sometimes wonder if there is a word for this phenomenon for how our system has gotten into such a rotten state from lobbying to this yet at the same time genuine non profits get existential threats for the same behaviour but they simply don&amp;#x27;t have the funds...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MangoToupe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve increasingly taken the attitude that digital media is simply lost to corporate interests and there&amp;#x27;s nothing we can do about it aside from not spending money or time on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://torrentfreak.com/dns-provider-quad9-sees-piracy-blocking-orders-as-existential-threat/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874850</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
