<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Agent design is still hard</title>
      <link>https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/11/21/agents-are-hard/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The different platforms have very different approaches to caching. It makes costs and cache utilization much more predictable. Otherwise, this would trash the cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013935"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/11/21/agents-are-hard/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mitchellh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is why I use the agent I use. I won&amp;#x27;t name the company, because I don&amp;#x27;t want people to think I&amp;#x27;m a shill for them (I&amp;#x27;ve already been accused of it before, but I&amp;#x27;m just a happy, excited customer). But it&amp;#x27;s an agentic coding company that isn&amp;#x27;t associated with any of the big model providers.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t want to keep up with all the new model releases. I don&amp;#x27;t want to read every model card. I don&amp;#x27;t want to feel pressured to update immediately (if it&amp;#x27;s better). I don&amp;#x27;t want to run evals. I don&amp;#x27;t want to think about when different models are better for different scenarios. I don&amp;#x27;t want to build obvious&amp;#x2F;common subagents. I don&amp;#x27;t want to manage N &amp;gt; 1 billing entities.&lt;p&gt;I just want to work.&lt;p&gt;Paying an agentic coding company to do this makes perfect sense for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moinism:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Amen. Been seeing these agent SDKs coming out left and right for a couple of years and thought it&amp;#x27;d be a breeze to build an agent. Now I&amp;#x27;m trying to build one for ~3 weeks, and I&amp;#x27;ve tried three different SDKs and a couple of architectures.&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s what I found:&lt;p&gt;- Claude Code SDK (now called Agent SDK) is amazing, but I think they are still in the process of decoupling it from the Claude Code, and that&amp;#x27;s why a few things are weird. e.g, You can define a subagent programmatically, but not skills. Skills have to be placed in the filesystem and then referenced in the plugin. Also, only Anthoripic models are supported :(&lt;p&gt;- OpenAI&amp;#x27;s SDK&amp;#x27;s tight coupling with their platform is a plus point. i.e, you get agents and tool-use traces by default in your dashboard. Which you can later use for evaluation, distillation, or fine-tuning. 
But: 
  2. They have agent handoffs (which works in some cases), but not subagents. You can use tools as subagents, though.
  1. Not easy to use a third-party model provider. Their docs provide sample codes, but it&amp;#x27;s not as easy as that.&lt;p&gt;- Google Agent Kit doesn&amp;#x27;t provide any Typescript SDK yet. So didn&amp;#x27;t try.&lt;p&gt;- Mastra, even though it looks pretty sweet, spins up a server for your agent, which you can then use via REST API. umm.. why?&lt;p&gt;- SmythOS SDK is the one I&amp;#x27;m currently testing because it provides flexibility in terms of choosing the model provider and defining your own architecture (handoffs or subagents, etc.). It has its quirks, but I think it&amp;#x27;ll work for now.&lt;p&gt;Question: If you don&amp;#x27;t mind sharing, what is your current architecture? Agent -&amp;gt; SubAgents -&amp;gt; SubSubAgents? Linear? or a Planner-Executor?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll write a detailed post about my learnings from architectures (fingers crossed) soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;havkom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My tip is: don’t use SDK:s for agents. Use a while loop and craft your own JSON, handle context size and handle faults yourself. You will in practice need this level of control if you are not doing something trivial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cedws:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Going to hijack this to ask a question that’s been on my mind: does anybody know why there’s no agentic tools that use tree-sitter to navigate code? It seems like it would be much more powerful than having the LLM grepping for strings or rewriting entire files to change one line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yokohiii:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most of it reads like too high expectation of overhyped technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_pdp_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve started a company in this space about 2 years ago. We are doing fine. What we&amp;#x27;ve learned so far is that a lot of these techniques are simply optimisations to tackle some deficiency in LLMs that is a problem &amp;quot;today&amp;quot;. These are not going to be problems tomorrow because the technology will shift. As it happened many time in the span of the last 2 years.&lt;p&gt;So yah, cool, caching all of that... but give it a couple of months and a better technique will come out - or more capable models.&lt;p&gt;Many years ago when disc encryption on AWS was not an option, my team and I had to spend 3 months to come up with a way to encrypt the discs and do so well because at the time there was no standard way. It was very difficult as that required pushing encrypted images (as far as I remember). Soon after we started, AWS introduced standard disc encryption that you can turn on by clicking a button. We wasted 3 months for nothing. We should have waited!&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#x27;ve learned from this is that often times it is better to do absolutely nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;srameshc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still feel there is no sure shot way to build an abstraction yet. Probably that is why Loveable decided to build on Gemini AI rather than giving options of choosing model. On the other hand I like Pydantic AI framework and got myself a decent working solution where my preference is to stick with cheaper models by default and only use expensive only in cases where failure rate is too high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CuriouslyC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The &amp;#x27;Reinforcement in the Agent Loop&amp;#x27; section is a big deal, I use this pattern to enable async&amp;#x2F;event steered agents, it&amp;#x27;s super powerful. In long context you can use it to re-inject key points (&amp;quot;reminders&amp;quot;), etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiveplus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I liked reading this but got a silly question as I am a noob in these things. If explicit caching is better, does that mean the agent is just forgetting stuff unless we manually save its notes? Are these things really that forgetful? Also why is there a virtual file system? So the agent is basically just running around a tiny digital desktop looking for its files? Why can&amp;#x27;t the agent just &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; where the data is? I&amp;#x27;m sorry if these are juvenile questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mritchie712:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some things we&amp;#x27;ve[0] learned on agent design:&lt;p&gt;1. If your agent needs to write a lot of code, it&amp;#x27;s really hard to beat Claude Code (cc) &amp;#x2F; Agent SDK. We&amp;#x27;ve tried many approaches and frameworks over the past 2 years (e.g. PydanticAI), but using cc is the first that has felt magic.&lt;p&gt;2. Vendor lock-in is a risk, but the bigger risk is having an agent that is less capable then what a user gets out of chatgpt because you&amp;#x27;re hand rolling every aspect of your agent.&lt;p&gt;3. cc is incredibly self aware. When you ask cc how to do something in cc, it instantly nails it. If you ask cc how to do something in framework xyz, it will take much more effort.&lt;p&gt;4. Give your agent a computer to use. We use e2b.dev, but Modal is great too. When the agent has a computer, it makes many complex features feel simple.&lt;p&gt;0 - For context, Definite (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.definite.app&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.definite.app&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) is a data platform with agents to operate it. It&amp;#x27;s like Heroku for data with a staff of AI data engineers and analysts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;postalcoder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been building agent type stuff for a couple years now and the best thing I did was build my own framework and abstractions that I know like the back of my hand.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d stay clear of any llm abstraction. There are so many companies with open source abstractions offering the panacea of a single interface that are crumbling under their own weight due to the sheer futility of supporting every permutation of every SDK evolution, all while the same companies try to build revenue generating businesses on top of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/11/21/agents-are-hard/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 11:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013935</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A looming 'insect apocalypse' could endanger global food supplies</title>
      <link>https://www.livescience.com/animals/insects/a-looming-insect-apocalypse-could-endanger-global-food-supplies-can-we-stop-it-before-its-too-late</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Insect populations are plummeting almost everywhere they've been studied. Now picture your car's windshield. But 30 years ago, there would have been significantly more buggy skid marks plastered on the front of your vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015262"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.livescience.com/animals/insects/a-looming-insect-apocalypse-could-endanger-global-food-supplies-can-we-stop-it-before-its-too-late'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.livescience.com/animals/insects/a-looming-insect-apocalypse-could-endanger-global-food-supplies-can-we-stop-it-before-its-too-late</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015262</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
