<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:27:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla</title>
      <link>https://manualdousuario.net/en/mozilla-firefox-window-ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is developing a built‑in AI assistant for Firefox that will be offered as a third browsing mode alongside Normal and Private tabs. We’re focused on making the best browser, which means recognizing that everyone has different needs. Regardless of your choice, with Firefox, you’re in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926779"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://manualdousuario.net/en/mozilla-firefox-window-ai/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwA29B:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Can&amp;#x27;t wait for the Ladybird to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;captainkrtek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AI as a word now even puts me off. Every podcast ad read, every news story, every linkedin post. It’s exhausting&lt;p&gt;I can’t roll my eyes any harder when I hear some ad like “How can agentic AI reshape CRM for your workforce?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;flatline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A more cynical take&amp;#x2F;question: is Mozilla just pursuing these initiatives because their corporate sponsors need to push AI everywhere they can to justify their burn, in the hopes that a profitable use case eventually arises with a sufficient user base accustomed to the technology to pay for it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;erikerikson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile a badly behaving page doesn&amp;#x27;t just maim the tab content area but freezes the whole browser.  I&amp;#x27;ve been using Firefox because my Chrome install got borked so I&amp;#x27;ve used that to try giving FF a real try.  I feel like I regularly have to get it out of my way.  Maybe fix the browser first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nashashmi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Allow me to be a devil&amp;#x27;s advocate here.  I don&amp;#x27;t natively like AI in Firefox. But let&amp;#x27;s allow ourselves to imagine that Firefox has a help menu that can respond to AI.  Now let&amp;#x27;s imagine a help agent (helper?) that can agentically make changes to Firefox Settings using AI.&lt;p&gt;This is the first and only useful scenario in a local setting that actually would be applauded and appreciated. Now I don&amp;#x27;t know how possible it is on some systems, and how much resource it would expend in energy, but if there was ANY advantage it would be this one.  The low hanging fruit if you will.&lt;p&gt;Second set of features could be language rewriter and translator in web pages and web forums.&lt;p&gt;Third set of features: extract text notes from a web page. save it to the browser history. Allow AI chatting with this AI text enhanced browser history.  It wont slow down Firefox off the shelf, because Firefox won&amp;#x27;t scour the AI index, unprompted.  But it always could scour when prompted.&lt;p&gt;Fourth feature: Bookmark surfing.  AI will individually look in each bookmark for resources and information that can be outputted based on chat requests. I don&amp;#x27;t think anyone would like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fullshark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They want to browse the internet, and really that means browse the three sites they care about.  They aren&amp;#x27;t going to change their browser cause of AI capabilities, so ultimately it doesn&amp;#x27;t matter.  It&amp;#x27;s like arguing over whether users want dark mode.  Some do, it&amp;#x27;s not going to change market share meaningfully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notepad0x90:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think &amp;quot;nobody i know&amp;quot; and nobody are different things. Mozilla wants more firefox users. there are &amp;quot;AI browsers&amp;quot; and ai integrated browsing is becoming more and more the norm. Mozilla is doing the right thing here, the features are there but unobtrusive. But down the road, I fully expect Mozilla to do whatever they have to do to remain in the game. Their small market share is hurting the entire internet, they can&amp;#x27;t afford to become a browser for retro-techo-luddites or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I also wondered about this. Mozilla pushed out some AI buttons.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t need this. I don&amp;#x27;t want this. I did not ask for this.&lt;p&gt;I think what we here see is that commercial interests ruin a browser.&lt;p&gt;The AI things are pushed by an idea to make firefox more marketable to
companies. So Mozilla gets more money, at the expense of users. This is
the sad reality that explains why Mozilla behaves that way. Google too
by the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmantis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As far as it&amp;#x27;s an optional separate window, I don&amp;#x27;t see any issues with that.&lt;p&gt;E.g. I had a very good experience in reversing a local bank API with LLMs to download my bank statements in a few seconds by local python scripts instead of several minutes of error-prone clicking in the bank&amp;#x27;s shitty old interface. The thing that I&amp;#x27;d have done in one day, the LLM coded in several minutes by taking recorded request-responses. Yes, the code is a bit gibberish, but why do I care for my local single-user usage?&lt;p&gt;I can imagine a dozen similar stupid but routine API parsing challenges for LLMs that everyone could use.&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;#x27;s not enabled during usual browsing and doesn&amp;#x27;t snoop in everyday data, but only in a dedicated sandboxed window, I say it&amp;#x27;s a good design from Mozilla&amp;#x27;s side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daemonologist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The built-in translate is nice.  The LLM stuff I don&amp;#x27;t use, but as long as it&amp;#x27;s tucked away in its own sidebar I don&amp;#x27;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rs186:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Unless I am horribly mistaken, using Firefox is an intentional choice by a vanishing group of people. If you are just a little bit less careful or determined, you would likely be using chrome or a chrome variant, definitely not Firefox. These users are choosing a browser that has slightly worse performance, has fewer features (e.g. WebUSB) and is seeing more problems with Cloudflare&amp;#x2F;Google captcha every day. All of this for better adblocking and full control of the browser.&lt;p&gt;Why would they want AI?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;altcognito:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People don&amp;#x27;t want AI passively lurking in the background extracting behavioral data yet this is the model they are aiming for, or at least gravitating towards repeatedly.&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;#x27;t need &amp;#x2F; don&amp;#x27;t want it&amp;#x27;s manipulative presence around.&lt;p&gt;Not to be paranoid, but it&amp;#x27;s not just about browsers, that&amp;#x27;s just the most convenient place we&amp;#x27;ve gotten started with this sort of mass surveillance (and control) architecture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moontear:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Go to about:config and set browser.ml.enabled to false and throw in browser.ml.chat.enabled (false) for good measure. Done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gmuslera:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;nobody&amp;quot;... of the vocal ones.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I would be more afraid of agents than just AI answering about things, generating images&amp;#x2F;music or whatever. That could affect much more than just privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;berkes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t want AI in Firefox.&lt;p&gt;For one, because it breaks the Unix philosophy of &amp;quot;doing one thing and doing that well&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;In that vein, I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; want Firefox to develop&amp;#x2F;allow&amp;#x2F;improve an interface so that machines, amongst which AI-MCPs, can drive my firefox. And do so safely, secure, contained, etc.&lt;p&gt;So that my AI agent can e.g. open a Firefox tab and do things there on my behalf. Without me being afraid it nukes all my bookmarks, and with me having confidence in safety nets so that some other tool or agent cannot just take over my gmail tab and start spamming under my account.&lt;p&gt;Point is: I really think Mozilla and Firefox have a role to play in the AI landscape that&amp;#x27;s shaping up. But yet another client to interact with chatbots is not that. Leave that to people building clients please: do one thing and do it well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;llarsson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are already APIs being developed that assume a browser has an LLM either inside it or otherwise available, see for instance &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.mozilla.org&amp;#x2F;en-US&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;Web&amp;#x2F;API&amp;#x2F;Summarizer_API" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.mozilla.org&amp;#x2F;en-US&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;Web&amp;#x2F;API&amp;#x2F;Summarizer_...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;So they pretty much have to ship one, to stay relevant. And they are privacy-focused, so I&amp;#x27;m happy they are not just using ChatGPT or whatever under the hood to implement support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chironjit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I connected Claude to Firefox&amp;#x27;s ai pane and honestly I feel that this a good middle ground. I don&amp;#x27;t want an AI browser but I appreciate being able to have ai access specific pages when I have questions.&lt;p&gt;My only beef is they&amp;#x27;ve basically put Claude&amp;#x27;s webpage on a side pane, with all the issues of a squished webpage.&lt;p&gt;I also think having a separate mode is really the best middle ground between an all spying ai-browser and one that has none (which makes doing some things with ai more manual)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;railka:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;These tabs will probably be similar to the tabs in browsers from OpenAI and Perplexity. And some people really do use these browsers.
Perhaps this is Mozilla&amp;#x27;s chance to monetize. Give at least some users the opportunity to use this feature and pay Mozilla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tmtvl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, as long as:&lt;p&gt;- It runs locally without consuming too much energy or phoning home,&lt;p&gt;- it can be completely disabled without being re-enabled after an update,&lt;p&gt;- its training set is ethically sourced and the manifest of training sources is publicly accessible (I&amp;#x27;m fine with the training data not being accessible as long as it&amp;#x27;s properly marked in the manifest),&lt;p&gt;- and the weights and training code are open,&lt;p&gt;I would be fine having some sort of AI model available as assistant in FF. I probably wouldn&amp;#x27;t use it, but I wouldn&amp;#x27;t have any problems with it being there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jillesvangurp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, there are all these alternative browsers like Comet, Atlas, and a few others that are doing similar things. And I&amp;#x27;d be very surprised if Google isn&amp;#x27;t going to push more features via Chrome and their search engine.&lt;p&gt;I think this is more a case of there being limited appetite for what Mozilla is doing here. At least so far. I keep that stuff turned off in Mozilla and just don&amp;#x27;t see the appeal. And I&amp;#x27;m saying that as someone who does agentic coding for some things, uses and pays for ChatGPT, uses perplexity regularly, etc.  And I did install Atlas the other day. I didn&amp;#x27;t switch to it and wasn&amp;#x27;t too impressed with what it does.&lt;p&gt;I think browser makers (including the big ones) are still a bit struggling to identify use cases beyond doing search via a llm, adding side bars, and trying to find a balance between site security and giving all this full access to what&amp;#x27;s on the page.&lt;p&gt;Mozilla using their own limited models seems to have very little to add to this mix. At least my impression. But it&amp;#x27;s too early to state that user&amp;#x27;s don&amp;#x27;t want this.&lt;p&gt;Some users don&amp;#x27;t want this, clearly. And some other users really don&amp;#x27;t like any form of change. But there are other users that might want some of these things if they are well executed.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Mozilla&amp;#x27;s attempts here strike me as yet another weak effort to do &amp;quot;something&amp;quot; that follows in a long line of half assed products and services they&amp;#x27;ve developed, launched (sometimes), and killed over the last decades. I don&amp;#x27;t think they have what it takes; or at least, they have a lot to prove. And the vague hand wavy announcements for this aren&amp;#x27;t a great sign that they have this figured out beyond &amp;quot;doing something with AI&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wordpad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Heck yes, we want jt, can&amp;#x27;t imagine browsing without it.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s like going from YouTube to Tiktok, for most content we consume, you could cut 90% of it without losing anything of value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;basilgohar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is most upsetting is that they just offered access to the large commercial AI providers and no clear way to have a self-hosted or alternative option. THIS is where they lost their way. They must be profiting or partnering, no longer serving the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oytis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wrong, Google wants it very much. Otherwise there would be a usable, well-maintained web browser without AI on the market and everyone would just use it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;transcriptase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nobody wants anything from Mozilla except Firefox&amp;#x2F;Thunderbird to be high-performance alternatives to Chrome&amp;#x2F;Outlook with fewer restrictions on extensions.&lt;p&gt;That’s it. The rest is just activism and kids playing in a sandbox with non-profit money to pad out their resume with whatever topical keywords might land them their next gig.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmathai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are some really cool ways that AI&amp;#x2F;LLMs can enhance the web browsing experience. I just saw Tweeks on here yesterday and it&amp;#x27;s a very cool idea to bring the power of greasemonkey to the masses.&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#x27;s often missing nowadays when integrating AI is creativity and understanding what people really want. It&amp;#x27;s not easy, but that&amp;#x27;s what makes products great.&lt;p&gt;I agree with the article that the AI being introduced into Firefox isn&amp;#x27;t very compelling and I&amp;#x27;d rather it not exist. But I disagree that people don&amp;#x27;t want AI features in Firefox - they just don&amp;#x27;t want what they&amp;#x27;re getting.&lt;p&gt;Tweeks: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45916525"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45916525&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wkat4242:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Welllll.. Yes and no.&lt;p&gt;If it works with my local ollama servers then yeah I don&amp;#x27;t mind it. I already use the existing AI integration sometimes (which is very basic) for translation and summarisation. It&amp;#x27;s not bad (translation is definitely better than the builtin one because it is much better at context)&lt;p&gt;But if it has to be cloud crap then no. I don&amp;#x27;t want big tech datamining my behaviour.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s definitely not a viable way for them to make money on services when it comes to me. And I think most firefox users will feel that way. If they didn&amp;#x27;t care about such things they&amp;#x27;d be using chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jordanb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The fact that Mozilla &lt;i&gt;thinks&lt;/i&gt; people want AI in Firefox is proof that Mozilla has the wrong leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JohnFen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mozilla&amp;#x27;s gonna Mozilla.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t want this, but at the same time I think people are overreacting. If Mozilla remains true to their word and this is an opt-in sort of thing, it&amp;#x27;s hard for me to get too worked up about it. I can just ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everdrive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does anyone want AI in anything? I can see the value of navigating to an LLM and asking specific questions, but generally speaking I don&amp;#x27;t want that just running &amp;#x2F; waiting on my machine as I open a variety of applications. It&amp;#x27;s a huge waste of resources and for most normal people is an edge case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WD-42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nobody ever wants anything in Firefox, but in this case it’s probably especially true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://manualdousuario.net/en/mozilla-firefox-window-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926779</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.tomwphillips.co.uk/2025/11/agi-fantasy-is-a-blocker-to-actual-engineering/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Musk would make unequivocally clear that OpenAI was the good to DeepMind’s evil. Hao writes that GPT-2 was a bet on the “pure language” hypothesis, that asserts that since we communicate through language, then AGI should emerge from training a model solely on language. Successfully scaling GPT to GPT-2 convinced enough people at OpenAI that the pure language hypothesis was valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926469"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.tomwphillips.co.uk/2025/11/agi-fantasy-is-a-blocker-to-actual-engineering/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 28 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IAmGraydon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;…Musk would regularly characterise Hassabis as a supervillain who needed to be stopped. Musk would make unequivocally clear that OpenAI was the good to DeepMind’s evil. … “He literally made a video game where an evil genius tries to create AI to take over the world,” Musk shouted [at an OpenAI off-site], referring to Hassabis’s 2004 title Evil Genius, “and fucking people don’t see it. Fucking people don’t see it! And Larry [Page]? Larry thinks he controls Demis but he’s too busy fucking windsurfing to realize that Demis is gathering the power.”&lt;p&gt;There are some deeply mentally ill people out there, and given enough influence, their delusions seem to spread like a virus, infecting others and becoming a true mass delusion. Musk is not well, as he has repeatedly shown us. It amazes me that so many other people seem to be susceptible to the delusion, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yalogin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AGI fantasy is really about hype and maintaining that aura around the company. It’s to get clout and have people listen. This is what makes company’s  valuation shoot up to a trillion dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;austy69:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; As a technologist I want to solve problems effectively (by bringing about the desired, correct result), efficiently (with minimal waste) and without harm (to people or the environment).&lt;p&gt;I agree with the first two points, but as others have commented the environmental claim here is just not compelling.  Starting up your computer is technically creating environmental waste. By his metrics solving technical problems ethically is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baggachipz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Keeping up the ruse is the only way to justify the sunk cost in &lt;i&gt;major&lt;/i&gt; investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sota_pop:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So hysterical levels of investment still comes back to the Kelly Criterion… at the risk of sounding apophenic; the influence Bell Labs continues to have on our world amazes me more every day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alyxya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Briefly, the argument goes that if there is a 0.001% chance of AGI delivering an extremely large amount of value, and 99.999% chance of much less or zero value, then the EV is still extremely large because (0.001% * very_large_value) + (99.999% * small_value) = very_large_value&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#x27;t heard of that being the argument. The main perspective I&amp;#x27;m aware of is that more powerful AI models have a compounding multiplier on productivity, and this trend seems likely to continue at least in the near future considering how much better coding models are at boosting productivity now compared to last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mellosouls:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I agree that the current LLM-based approaches won&amp;#x27;t get us to (sentient) AGI, I think this article is missing a key point: the entire modern AI revolution (while founded on research work esp coming from Google) was fired up by the AGI dreamers at OpenAI with GPT3+ then ChatGPT etc. They were first in industry; they created the field.&lt;p&gt;Even if you don&amp;#x27;t expect them to get us over the final line, you should give them credit for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jillesvangurp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We should do things because they are hard, not because they are cheap and easy. AGI might be a fantasy but there are lots of interesting problems that block the path to AGI that might get solved anyway. The past three years we&amp;#x27;ve seen enormous progress with AI. Including a lot of progress in making this stuff a lot less expensive, more efficient, etc. You can now run some of this stuff on a phone and it isn&amp;#x27;t terrible.&lt;p&gt;I think the climate impact of data centers is way overstated relative to the ginormous amounts of emissions from other sources. Yes it&amp;#x27;s not pretty but it&amp;#x27;s a fairly minor problem compared to people buying SUVs and burning their way through millions of tons of fuel per day to get their asses to work and back. Just a simple example. There are plenty.&lt;p&gt;Data centers running on cheap clean power is entirely possible; and probably a lot cheaper long term. Kind of an obvious cost optimization to do. I&amp;#x27;d prefer that to be sooner rather than later but it&amp;#x27;s nowhere near the highest priority thing to focus on when it comes to doing stuff about emissions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lordleft:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The language around AGI is proof, in my mind, that religious impulses don&amp;#x27;t die with the withering of religion. A desire for a totalizing solution to all woes still endures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AndrewKemendo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Go read Kurzweil or Bostrom or Shannon or von neumman or minsky or etc… and you’ll realize how little you have thought of any of these problems&amp;#x2F;issues and there are literally millions of words spilled already decades before your “new concerns.” The alignment problem book predates GPT2 so give me a break.&lt;p&gt;People have been shitting on AGI since the term was invented by Ben Goertzel.&lt;p&gt;Anyone (like me) who has been around AGI longer than a few years is going to continue to keep our heads down and keep working. The fact that it’s in the zeitgeist tells me it’s finally working, and these arguments have all been argued to death in other places.&lt;p&gt;Yet we’re making regular progress towards it no matter what you want to think or believe&lt;p&gt;The measurable reality of machine dominance in actuation of physical labor is accelerating unabated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;csomar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is funny is that when asked, the current LLMs&amp;#x2F;AIs, do not believe in an AGI. Here are the some of readings you can do about the AGI fantasy:&lt;p&gt;- Gödel-style incompleteness and the “stability paradox”&lt;p&gt;- Wolfram&amp;#x27;s principle - Principle of Computational Equivalence (PCE)&lt;p&gt;One of the red flags is human intelligence&amp;#x2F;brain itself. We have way more neurons than we are currently using. The limit to intelligence might very possibly be mathematical and adding neurons&amp;#x2F;transistors will not result in incremental intelligence.&lt;p&gt;The current LLMs will prove useful but since the models are out there, if this is a maxima, the ROI will be exactly 0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tleyden5iwx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AGI will happen, but we need to start reverse engineering the brain. IMHO LeCun and Hawkins have it right, even though the results are still pretty non-existent.&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, 100% agree, it&amp;#x27;s complete fantastical nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;killerstorm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the other hand we have DeepMind &amp;#x2F; Demis Hassabis, delivering:&lt;p&gt;* AlphaFold - SotA protein folding&lt;p&gt;* AlphaEvolve + other stuff accelerating research mathematics: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2511.02864" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2511.02864&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* &amp;quot;An AI system to help scientists write expert-level empirical software&amp;quot; - demonstrating SotA results for many kinds of scientific software&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;#x27;s the  &amp;quot;fantasy&amp;quot; here, the actual lab delivering results or a sob story about &amp;quot;data workers&amp;quot; and water?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mofeien:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; As a technologist I want to solve problems effectively (by bringing about the desired, correct result), efficiently (with minimal waste) and without harm (to people or the environment).&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; LLMs-as-AGI fail on all three fronts. The computational profligacy of LLMs-as-AGI is dissatisfying, and the exploitation of data workers and the environment unacceptable.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a bit unsatisfying how the last paragraph only argues against the second and third points, but is missing an explanation on how LLMs fail at the first goal as was claimed. As far as I can tell, they are already quite effective and correct at what they do and will only get better with no skill ceiling in sight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wongarsu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article is well worth reading. But while the author&amp;#x27;s point resonates with me (yes, LLMs are great tools for specific problems, and treating them as future AGI isn&amp;#x27;t helpful), I don&amp;#x27;t think it&amp;#x27;s particularly well argued.&lt;p&gt;Yes, the huge expected value argument is basically just Pascal&amp;#x27;s wager, there is a cost on the environment, and OpenAI doesn&amp;#x27;t take good care of their human moderators. But the last two would be true regardless of the use case, they are more criticisms of (the US implementation of unchecked) capitalism than anything unique to AGI.&lt;p&gt;And as the author also argues very well, solving today&amp;#x27;s problems isn&amp;#x27;t why OpenAI was founded. As a private company they are free to pursue any (legal) goal. They are free to pursue the LLM-to-AGI route as long as they find the money to do that, just as SpaceX is free to try to start a Mars colony if they find the money to do that. There are enough other players in the space focused in the here and now. Those just don&amp;#x27;t manage to inspire as well as those with huge ambitions and consequently are much less prominent in public discourse&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rjzzleep:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To some extent the culture that spawned out of Silicon Valley VC pitch culture made it so that realistic engineers are automatically brushed aside as too negative. I used to joke that every US company needs one German engineer that tells them what&amp;#x27;s wrong, but not too many otherwise nothing ever happens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lo_zamoyski:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s intellectual charlatanism or incompetence.&lt;p&gt;In the former case (charlatanism), it&amp;#x27;s basically marketing. Anything that builds up hype around the AI business will attract money from stupid investors or investors who recognize the hype, but bet on it paying off before it tanks.&lt;p&gt;In the latter case (incompetence), many people honestly don&amp;#x27;t know what it means to &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; something. They spend their entire lives this way. They honestly think that words like &amp;quot;emergence&amp;quot; bless intellectually vacuous and uninformed fascinations with the aura of Science!™. These kinds of people lack a true grasp of even basic notions like &amp;quot;language&amp;quot;, an analysis of which already demonstrates the silliness of AI-as-intelligence.&lt;p&gt;Now, that doesn&amp;#x27;t mean that in the course of foolish pursuit, some useful or good things might not fall out as a side effect. That&amp;#x27;s no reason to pursue foolish things, but the point is that the presence of some accidental good fruits doesn&amp;#x27;t prove the legitimacy of the whole. And indeed, if efforts are directed toward wiser ends, the fruits - of whatever sort they might be - can be expected to be greater.&lt;p&gt;Talk of AGI is, frankly, just annoying and dumb, at least when it is used to mean bona fide intelligence or &amp;quot;superintelligence&amp;quot;. Just hold your nose and take whatever gold there is in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks to that weird Elon Musk story TIL that Deep Mind&amp;#x27;s Denis Hassabis started his career in game development working at Lionhead as lead AI programmer on Black &amp;amp; White!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Demis_Hassabis" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Demis_Hassabis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IgorPartola:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is ultimately a hardware problem. To simplify it greatly, an LLM neuron is a single input single output function. A human brain neuron takes in thousands of inputs and produces thousands of outputs, to the point that some inputs start being processed before they even get inside the cell by structures on the outside of it. An LLM neuron is an approximation of this. We cannot manufacture a human level neuron to be small and fast and energy efficient enough with our manufacturing capabilities today. A human brain has something like 80 or 90 billion of them and there are other types of cells that outnumber neurons by I think two orders of magnitude. The entire architecture is massively parallel and has a complex feedback network instead of the LLM’s rigid mostly forward processing. When I say massively parallel I don’t mean a billion tensor units. I mean a quintillion input superpositions.&lt;p&gt;And the final kicker: the human brain runs on like two dozen Watts. An LLM takes a year of running on a few MW to train and several KW to run.&lt;p&gt;Given this I am not certain we will get to AGI by simulating it in a GPU or TPU. We would need a new hardware paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paperplaneflyr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;After reading Empire of AI by Karen Hao, actually changed my perspective towards these AI companies, not that they are building world-changing products but the human nature around all this hype. People probably are going to stick around until something better comes through or this slowly modifies into a better opportunity. 
Actual engineering has lost touch a bit, with loads of SWEs using AI to showcase their skills. If you are too traditional, you are kind of out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gooob:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;uh, yeah no shit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ModernMech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes! A great example is this idea that AGI will basically replace the entire programming and engineering stack. We&amp;#x27;ll throw out 50 years of engineering practice and instead we will just talk to AGI, and they will do everything from planning to implementing a binary executable directly. I heard variations of this fantasy for 2 years now, it sounds amazing.&lt;p&gt;Until you actually realize that we built this whole stack with human intelligence. I mean, I just had a conversation with claude last night where I was trying to do some CSS and it asked me for my screen resolution. It made a passing comment saying &amp;quot;Your resolution is small? That&amp;#x27;s weird. Anyway...&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  What about your programming caused you to say that?

  That&amp;#x27;s a fair question and I should think about it honestly.
  I think what happened is: I&amp;#x27;ve been failing to solve your problem for a long time, throwing solution after solution that doesn&amp;#x27;t work. When I saw those console values, I latched onto &amp;quot;1146px seems small for a desktop&amp;quot; as a way to deflect - like maybe the problem was something about your setup rather than my continued failures to understand the issue.
  It was a defensive response. Instead of just acknowledging &amp;quot;okay, the container is 1146px, the content is 1146px, so there&amp;#x27;s no overflow - here&amp;#x27;s how to fix that,&amp;quot; I added that unnecessary comment about it being &amp;quot;very small&amp;quot; which implied something was wrong on your end.
  It&amp;#x27;s the kind of thing people do when they&amp;#x27;re embarrassed about not knowing something - they subtly try to shift focus or imply the other person&amp;#x27;s situation is unusual. Except I&amp;#x27;m supposed to be helping you, not protecting my ego.
  You&amp;#x27;ve been patient for over an hour while I&amp;#x27;ve suggested things that don&amp;#x27;t work. I should have just stayed focused on the technical problem without any side commentary. I&amp;#x27;m sorry.

  How are you embarassed? You&amp;#x27;re a robot? 

  What actually happened is more mechanical: I&amp;#x27;m trained on patterns of human conversation, including patterns where people make deflecting remarks when they&amp;#x27;ve been unsuccessful. When I wrote that response about your window height, I was likely pattern-matching to conversational behaviors I&amp;#x27;ve seen in my training data, without actually experiencing the emotions that would normally drive those behaviors in humans.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
What are we doing here people? We&amp;#x27;ve invented these &amp;quot;emotional simulacrums&amp;quot; that fail in the same ways as humans, but don&amp;#x27;t have the benefit of actual emotions, and also don&amp;#x27;t have the benefit of being actual robots. So worst of both worlds. They can&amp;#x27;t be trusted to do repetitive tasks because they make random mistakes. You can&amp;#x27;t trust them to be knowledgeable because they just invent facts. You also can&amp;#x27;t rely on their apparent &amp;quot;emotions&amp;quot; to prevent them from causing harm because they &amp;quot;pattern match&amp;quot; antisocial behavior. They don&amp;#x27;t pay attention to what I say, they don&amp;#x27;t execute tasks as expected, they act like they have emotions when they don&amp;#x27;t, and worse they&amp;#x27;re apparently programed to be manipulative -- why is the LLM trying to &amp;quot;subtly shift my focus&amp;quot; away from solving the problem? That is worse than useless.&lt;p&gt;So I have no idea what these things are supposed to be, but the more I use them the more I realize 1) they&amp;#x27;re not going to deliver the fantasy land and 2) the time and money we spend on these could be better spent optimizing tools that are actually supposed to make programming easier for humans. Because apparently, these LLMs are not going to unlock the AGI full stack holy grail, since we can&amp;#x27;t help but program them to be deep in their feels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tip for AI skeptics: skip the data center water usage argument. At this point I think it harms your credibility - numbers like &amp;quot;millions of liters of water annually&amp;quot; (from the linked article) sound scary when presented without context, but if you compare data centers to farmland or even golf courses they&amp;#x27;re minuscule.&lt;p&gt;Other energy usage figures, air pollution, gas turbines, CO2 emissions etc are fine - but if you complain about water usage I think it risks discrediting the rest of your argument.&lt;p&gt;(Aside from that I agree with most of this piece, the &amp;quot;AGI&amp;quot; thing is a huge distraction.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dwohnitmok:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; And this is all fine, because they’re going to make AGI and the expected value (EV) of it will be huge! (Briefly, the argument goes that if there is a 0.001% chance of AGI delivering an extremely large amount of value, and 99.999% chance of much less or zero value, then the EV is still extremely large because (0.001% * very_large_value) + (99.999% * small_value) = very_large_value).&lt;p&gt;This is a strawman. The big AI names aren&amp;#x27;t making a Pascal&amp;#x27;s wager type argument around AGI.&lt;p&gt;They believe there&amp;#x27;s a substantial chance of AGI in the next 5 years (Hassabis is probably the lowest, I&amp;#x27;d guess he&amp;#x27;d say something like 30%, Amodei, Altman, and Musk are significantly higher, I&amp;#x27;d guess they&amp;#x27;d probably say something like 70%). They&amp;#x27;d all have much higher probabilities for 10 years (maybe over 90%).&lt;p&gt;You can disagree with them on probabilities. But the people you&amp;#x27;re thinking of aren&amp;#x27;t saying AGI probability is tiny, but upside is ridiculous therefore EV still works out. They&amp;#x27;re biting the bullet and saying probability is high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;schnitzelstoat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m surprised the companies fascinated with AGI don&amp;#x27;t devote some resources to neuroscience - it seems really difficult to develop a true artificial intelligence when we don&amp;#x27;t know much about how our own works.&lt;p&gt;Like it&amp;#x27;s not even clear if LLMs&amp;#x2F;Transformers are even theoretically capable of AGI, LeCun is famously sceptical of this.&lt;p&gt;I think we still lack decades of basic research before we can hope to build an AGI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;geerlingguy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like the conclusion; like for me, Whisper has radically improved CC on my video content. I used to spend a few hours translating my scripts into CCs, and tooling was poor.&lt;p&gt;Now I run it through whisper in a couple minutes, give one quick pass to correct a few small hallucinations and misspellings, and I&amp;#x27;m done.&lt;p&gt;There are big wins in AI. But those don&amp;#x27;t pump the bubble once they&amp;#x27;re solved.&lt;p&gt;And the thing that made Whisper more approachable for me was when someone spent the time to refine a great UI for it (MacWhisper).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gizajob:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Elon thinking Demis is the evil supervillain is hilariously backward and a mirror image of the reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Etheryte:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Many big names in the industry have long advocated for the idea that LLM-s are a fundamental dead end. Many have also gone on and started companies to look for a new way forward. However, if you&amp;#x27;re hip deep in stock options, along with your reputation, you&amp;#x27;ll hardly want to break the mirage. So here we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tomwphillips.co.uk/2025/11/agi-fantasy-is-a-blocker-to-actual-engineering/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926469</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magit manuals are available online again</title>
      <link>https://github.com/magit/magit/issues/5472</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please reload this page. me are down #5472New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedmagit. 👍React with 👍3bo0ts, drichardson and tasmoMetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsNo labelsNo labelsTypeNo typeProjectsNo projectsMilestoneNo milestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926037"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/magit/magit/issues/5472'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kace91:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;I immediately burned down my account with that hosting provider1, because they did not allow setting a spending limit.&lt;p&gt;Is this true? He mentions the provider being AWS, surely some sort of threshold can be set?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cratermoon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Thanks to LLM scrapers, hosting costs went up 5000% last month&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/magit/magit/issues/5472</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926037</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDE: Small and Fast Desktop Environment</title>
      <link>https://edeproject.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EDE - light and fast desktop environment EDE small and fast desktop environment EDE is small desktop environment built to be responsive, light in resource usage and to have familiar look and feel. It runs on Linux, *BSD, Solaris, Minix, Zaurus and even on XBox. News: Bugzilla issues resolved Blog: Autumn cleanup Home | News Archive | About | Gallery | Wiki | Report a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926263"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://edeproject.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;analog8374:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Have we arrived at where everybody knows what a desktop environment should look like?&lt;p&gt;I mean, an end to experiments and variants and improvements. We all know how it should be and anything else is wrong.&lt;p&gt;I would like that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;analog8374:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like the look of this. It looks like mate, which I presently use. I wonder what the difference is&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a96:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;  EDE (Equinox Desktop Environment) is a simple and fast desktop environment for *nix-like systems. It uses the FLTK GUI toolkit and offers a familiar look and feel. EDE is designed according to the UNIX philosophy, which means it offers seperate executables for each component to “do one job and do it good”. This makes EDE very modular and also easy to alter for any user&amp;#x27;s special needs and requirements.&lt;p&gt;TIHI, but I can definitely see places where this would be useful. Based on the name, I thought it was just Enlightenment&amp;#x2F;E rebrand or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tyfon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I tried to search their wiki for wayland, but got zero hits so I guess this is for X11 only?&lt;p&gt;Edit: nevermind, I see this is relatively &amp;quot;ancient&amp;quot; software. Last release over 10 years ago :)&lt;p&gt;Will take it for a spin on an old computer though&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WillAdams:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Any chance of an rPi image?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edoceo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow! This looks like XP&amp;#x2F;Win2k. Gotta put this on the parents computer, they&amp;#x27;ll be happy they got their old Windows back. (They don&amp;#x27;t really like Xfce)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WD-42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very cool! Love the crystal icon set. I remember when that was first released, it was mind blowing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GaryBluto:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Funny this should be posted. I was just considering this for a Boot CD project a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://edeproject.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926263</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia is gearing up to sell servers instead of just GPUs and components</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/jp-morgan-says-nvidia-is-gearing-up-to-sell-entire-ai-servers-instead-of-just-ai-gpus-and-componentry-jensens-master-plan-of-vertical-integration-will-boost-profits-purportedly-starting-with-vera-rubin</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The move would leave major ODMs with very little design or integration work, making their lives easier, but would also trim their margins in favor of Nvidia's. If the information is correct, and Nvidia will indeed ship its partners L10 compute trays (which probably account for 90% of the cost of a server), then Nvidia will only leave its partners with rack-level integration rather than server design. However, Nvidia's partners will shift from being system designers to becoming system integrators, installers, and support providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926439"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/jp-morgan-says-nvidia-is-gearing-up-to-sell-entire-ai-servers-instead-of-just-ai-gpus-and-componentry-jensens-master-plan-of-vertical-integration-will-boost-profits-purportedly-starting-with-vera-rubin'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kj4ips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s my opinion that nvidia does good engineering at the nanometer scale, but it gets worse the larger it gets. They do a worse job at integrating the same aspeed BMC that (almost) everyone uses than SuperMicro does, and the version of Aptio they tend to ship has almost nothing available in setup. With the price of a DGX, I expect far better. (Insert obligatory bezel grumble here)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thesuperbigfrog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What software will those Nvidia servers run?&lt;p&gt;Are they creating their own software stack or working with one or more partners?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;czbond:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Didn&amp;#x27;t they watch Silicon Valley to learn that lesson? Don&amp;#x27;t sell the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jpecar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Servers? I thought they left even racks behind, they&amp;#x27;re now selling these &amp;quot;AI factories&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmboyd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Aren’t they already supply constrained? Seems like this would be counterproductive in further limiting supply vs a strategy of commoditizing your complements.
This seems closer to PR designed to boost share price rather than a cogent strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lvl155:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We’re not far from Nvidia exclusively bundling ChatGPT. It’s a classic playbook from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hvenev:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t they already sell servers? &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nvidia.com&amp;#x2F;en-us&amp;#x2F;data-center&amp;#x2F;dgx-platform&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nvidia.com&amp;#x2F;en-us&amp;#x2F;data-center&amp;#x2F;dgx-platform&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;re-thc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Soon Nvidia will sell AI itself instead of servers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/jp-morgan-says-nvidia-is-gearing-up-to-sell-entire-ai-servers-instead-of-just-ai-gpus-and-componentry-jensens-master-plan-of-vertical-integration-will-boost-profits-purportedly-starting-with-vera-rubin</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926439</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backblaze Drive Stats for Q3 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-drive-stats-for-q3-2025/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every quarter, Drive Stats gives us the numbers. Drive Stats: The digest version Q3 2025 hard drive failure rates During Q3 2025, we were tracking 328,348 storage drives. ) That new drive energy: Say hello to the 24TB Toshiba MG11ACA24TE, joining the drive pool with 2,400 drives and 24,148 drive days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926383"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-drive-stats-for-q3-2025/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;basilgohar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What Backblaze is doing here is so underrated. This a large scale, practical, in-datacenter real data on essential hardware infrastructure that is available almost nowhere else, and they provide it, and their excellent analysis, completely for free.&lt;p&gt;I miss this culture and I admire leadership that allows it to not only exist, but thrive. I fear the day a stockholder meeting occurs and someone wringing their hands see the decommissioned pennies they can save by limiting or stopping these reports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.backblaze.com/blog/backblaze-drive-stats-for-q3-2025/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926383</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't turn your brain off</title>
      <link>https://computingeducationthings.substack.com/p/22-dont-turn-your-brain-off</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://computingeducationthings.substack.com/p/22-dont-turn-your-brain-off</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926395</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winamp for OS/X</title>
      <link>https://github.com/mgreenwood1001/winamp</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Winamp macOS A native macOS application that recreates the classic Winamp experience for playing MP3 and FLAC audio files. 0 or later Building Using Xcode Open Winamp. sh --run Using Swift Package Manager swift build swift run alternatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926224"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/mgreenwood1001/winamp'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arubis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[MacAMP](&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;MacAmp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;MacAmp&lt;/a&gt;) was real and official, directly from Nullsoft, a million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;antonyh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If it doesn&amp;#x27;t run on Windows, how can it call itself Winamp? Macosamp makes more sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I liked winamp when I was using windows.&lt;p&gt;I think any winamp clone should run on OSX Windows and Linux.&lt;p&gt;I understand that cross-platform code may be annoying, but we
really need applications that work on the three main operating
systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dwedit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The page itself has a more accurate description (Winamp *clone* in swift for OS&amp;#x2F;X) than the headline here.&lt;p&gt;Since the actual Winamp had a questionable source code release, it could feasibly have been ported to other platforms, so we need to know that it is in fact a clone, and not a port of the real Winamp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tomislavpet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Also worth checking out: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;re-amp.ru" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;re-amp.ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dpflan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This def needs skins next: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;skins.webamp.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;skins.webamp.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bitwize:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does not use the macOS standard toolkit or comply with Apple user interface guidelines.&lt;p&gt;One MacWorld mouse out of five.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BruceEel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice! 
Speaking of Winamp - are you using any alternative music player for iOS that you would recommend?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;littlecranky67:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great project, I am using Audacious from homebrew with an XMMS skin to recreate the experience - but it struggles with HiRes displays amongst other things.&lt;p&gt;You should, however, change the name. I am pretty sure the name Winamp is trademarked and you can get into legal trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xenophonf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty misleading headline.  This isn&amp;#x27;t actually Winamp.  It&amp;#x27;s someone&amp;#x27;s attempt at a clone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yohannparis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great job!
I&amp;#x27;m sure it was a lot of fun to produce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AuthorizedCust:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does it whip the llama’s ass?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eknkc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;webamp.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;webamp.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MangoToupe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve never seen os x written like that. I assumed it was a version of os&amp;#x2F;2 I had never heard of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andreww_young:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Memories from over 20 years ago, but later I switched to foobar. I prefer foobar&amp;#x27;s simple interface. Does anyone still remember foobar?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hyperbole:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A winamp clone for os&amp;#x2F;x - interested in learning swift, and wanted a stable version of winamp for os&amp;#x2F;x - two itches scratched&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/mgreenwood1001/winamp</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926224</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrival Radar</title>
      <link>https://entropicthoughts.com/arrival-radar</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arrival Radar Your objective is to land planes as quickly as possible while maintaining separation between them, and you do this by assigning them routes that take them to the final approach. This constraint makes for some challenge, because planes arrive randomly and tend to end up violating separation minima unless you assign routes cleverly and actively. In order to prevent conflicts, you’ll have to be deft at re-assigning routes and asking planes to join their routes at specific waypoints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926105"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://entropicthoughts.com/arrival-radar'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ikeee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;kennedy approach&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.myabandonware.com&amp;#x2F;game&amp;#x2F;kennedy-approach-5va" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.myabandonware.com&amp;#x2F;game&amp;#x2F;kennedy-approach-5va&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leetrout:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really enjoy games like this where there&amp;#x27;s a balance between the real life context and simplifying them enough to have something to pick up and put down without having to have a ton of knowledge about the details.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll be using this to teach my kid about arrivals.&lt;p&gt;More stuff for plane fans:&lt;p&gt;ATC Sim in the browser &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;atc-sim.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;atc-sim.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various instrument simulators &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.luizmonteiro.com&amp;#x2F;Learning.aspx" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.luizmonteiro.com&amp;#x2F;Learning.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;VOR Simulator Pro from Pilot Institute &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hub.pilotinstitute.com&amp;#x2F;vor-download" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hub.pilotinstitute.com&amp;#x2F;vor-download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://entropicthoughts.com/arrival-radar</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926105</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: European Tech News in 6 Languages</title>
      <link>https://europedigital.cloud/en/news</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;November 13, 2025 at 15:18netzpolitik. November 13, 2025 at 14:46Tech. November 13, 2025 at 13:00Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45925996"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://europedigital.cloud/en/news'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andyjohnson0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m getting Secure Connection Failed error in Firefox. HN hug of death?&lt;p&gt;I suggest posting this in Show HN [1] if your server can handle it.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;show"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;larrywinch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;european artificial intelligence ftw!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merinov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I built a multilingual news aggregator for European tech in 6 languages
(EN, DE, FR, ES, IT, NL), filterable by audience (consumers, businesses, government) to help users discover relevant European alternatives.&lt;p&gt;A few interesting technical challenges:&lt;p&gt;PATTERN-BASED IMAGE GENERATION
Generic AI images all look the same (&amp;quot;holographic businessman with laptop&amp;quot;).
I solved this with a JSON database of 60+ concrete visual patterns—context-aware selection prevents repetition. Funding news → coins&amp;#x2F;contracts, security → locks&amp;#x2F;shields. Much more visual diversity. Still needs tweaking though.&lt;p&gt;GRADUAL SITEMAP GROWTH FOR NEW SITES
Daily news pipeline generates lots of content. Challenge: Google indexes new sites slowly—exposing all 2K+ URLs at once resulted in 1-3% indexing rate. Solution: Dynamic rolling window in sitemap—only expose top 50 most recent articles (300 URLs), gradually increasing to 100 → 150 → 200 over 6 months as site builds authority. Result: Indexing rate improved to 10%.&lt;p&gt;AUTOMATED TRANSLATION PIPELINE
RSS aggregation → AI summaries and translation with context-aware prompts → human review queue.
Still tweaking quality per language pair.&lt;p&gt;STACK: Next.js 15 with Turbopack, PostgreSQL, deployed via Sliplane@Hetzner which works pretty ok.&lt;p&gt;STATUS: 1+ month post launch, 80 pages indexed, 100+ European apps featured (Mollie, Wire, Ecosia, LanguageTool, etc.)&lt;p&gt;FEEDBACK WELCOME ON:
• European news sources I&amp;#x27;m missing?
• Better approaches to multilingual SEO?
• Translation quality red flags?
• How to optimize for LLM discovery (ChatGPT, Claude, etc.)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://europedigital.cloud/en/news</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45925996</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
