<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:25:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>The lazy Git UI you didn't know you need</title>
      <link>https://www.bwplotka.dev/2025/lazygit/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What we can all learn from lazygit around designing incredible software with seamless UX. Other projects add more magic (e. What’s amazing in lazygit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878578"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bwplotka.dev/2025/lazygit/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 15 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rckt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Personally I just couldn&amp;#x27;t see all the extra layers as comfortable tools. It&amp;#x27;s a very rare thing that I need to see branches, relation between them etc. Using cli has always been the most reliable and simple way for me.The only git tool I need apart from cli is a convenient conflict resolver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mariusor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still prefer tig[1]. It has probably less features, but also a less cluttered UI and slightly faster interface.&lt;p&gt;But the main use I get from it is for incremental index adding, so maybe not as much as OP.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jonas.github.io&amp;#x2F;tig&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jonas.github.io&amp;#x2F;tig&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xeromal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m stuck on a mac these days and I miss Git Extensions, my favorite Windows git UI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;user432678:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe one day, but after almost 15 years of using handful of git aliases I just can’t switch to anything else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jannniii:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes! Godspeed to lazygit!&lt;p&gt;Really happy to see it featured here, I became a convert couple of years ago after switching to Astronvim (lazyvim is bundled with it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nicois:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A large percentage of git users are unaware of git-absorb (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;tummychow&amp;#x2F;git-absorb" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;tummychow&amp;#x2F;git-absorb&lt;/a&gt;). This complements just about any git flow, vastly reducing the pain of realising you want to amend your staged changes into multiple commits.
This sits well alongside many TUIs and other tools, most of which do not offer any similar capability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bdewberry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Simple, Clean, CLI, Vim navigation&lt;p&gt;Lazy git checks off a lot of boxes. Easy tool to adopt to speed up and simplify your git workflow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;submeta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Lazygit, WezTerm, NeoVim, Yazi (TUI file manager) are a fantastic combination! I have a tmuxniator config file for every project I work on. And open a tab in WezTerm, run „mx projectname“, it opens a split for Yazi, one for Lazygit, one for neovim, and one for my agentic coding tool. Lovely setup, super fast, all in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nice_byte:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the only good git GUI that exists is Fork. Unfortunately, it doesn&amp;#x27;t run natively on Linux, although some people have had luck running it under Wine.&lt;p&gt;I found lazygit specifically so bad to the point that I was better off typing in git commands into the terminal manually like some sort of caveman. Somehow, lazygit has found a way to make git even more confusing and user hostile than it already is, which is a significant achievement.&lt;p&gt;Using it was a harsh reminder of what people running emacs or vim for the first time have to go through.&lt;p&gt;This idiotic ui paradigm where you have to actively learn to use simple software by memorizing commands and shortcuts needs to die off. It&amp;#x27;s mind bogglingly inefficient and disrespectful of user&amp;#x27;s time.&lt;p&gt;Just think about it - I&amp;#x27;ve literally never had to open Fork&amp;#x27;s manual (I am not even sure it has one) whereas in lazygit it is utterly impossible to do the most basic things without referring to the manual. Why do we collectively keep tolerating these shitty tools?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prmph:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You might laugh, but in years of serious development, I have not come across a better git UI tool than SourceTree.&lt;p&gt;If I want to be hard-core, I&amp;#x27;d use the original git CLI. SourceTree is unmatched in how it makes using git so much more pleasant for when you need to do something relatively simple, but which would be quite cumbersome to do with the CLI and most other tools I&amp;#x27;ve tried.&lt;p&gt;Its file status and history view is unmatched IMO. I can easily stage&amp;#x2F;unstage hunks and even lines. The whole UI is generally quite polished and pleasant to use.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a real shame there is not a version for linux. I&amp;#x27;ve tried every other git interface under the sun and keep coming back to it. In the meantime, I tried lazygit the past weekend and I think it is one of the better TUI git tools out there, definitely better than GitUI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zambyte:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The less I use git directly, the more convinced I am that git is an absolutely awful interface to git repositories. I have been using jj for about two years now, and I literally cannot imagine going back to using the git cli. I have not used lazygit, but if you find it interesting, I say please go for it.&lt;p&gt;The please is because I am tired of fixing issues created by people being confused by git. Just use anything else than the git cli, it&amp;#x27;s probably better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tcoff91:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was a big fan of a good keyboard-driven git TUI like magit, neogit, lazygit, etc... (as long as you learn the CLI first and understand it).&lt;p&gt;Now I no longer directly use git, but instead use jujutsu (jj).&lt;p&gt;Once I became very proficient in the jj cli, I picked up jjui: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;idursun&amp;#x2F;jjui" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;idursun&amp;#x2F;jjui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, as splitting commits is an extremely frequent operation, this neovim plugin is really nice: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;julienvincent&amp;#x2F;hunk.nvim" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;julienvincent&amp;#x2F;hunk.nvim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also this neovim plugin is amazing for resolving jj conflicts: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;rafikdraoui&amp;#x2F;jj-diffconflicts" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;rafikdraoui&amp;#x2F;jj-diffconflicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now with jj instead of git I edit the commit graph as effortlessly as if I am moving lines of code around a file in my editor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aeve890:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d recommend lazydocker, from the same author IIRC. Awesome TUI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;magdyks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;lazygit rules!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;varunramesh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use lazygit when I want to stage specific lines rather than an entire file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bwplotka.dev/2025/lazygit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878578</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vibe Code Warning – A personal casestudy</title>
      <link>https://github.com/jackdoe/pico2-swd-riscv</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After about 3-4k lines of code I completely lost track of what is going on, and I woudn't consider this code that I have written, but adding more and more tests felt "nice", or at least reassuring. In this case it happened when the code grew about 4x, from 1k to 4k lines. When reading human code the symbols have a purpose, someone thought "I will put this in a variable, later I will check its status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874987"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/jackdoe/pico2-swd-riscv'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 18 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rzzzt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can ask for Mermaid syntax and receive nicely formatted block diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hackmack10:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is very well said.  I thought I was just burned out over the past several months.  Truth is, I&amp;#x27;m just reviewing AI code slop all day and I fucking hate it.  It&amp;#x27;s exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abathologist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A key -- perhaps THE key -- remark here, IMO is the following:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I do want to make things, and many times I dont want to know something, but I want to use it&lt;p&gt;This confesses the desire to make, to use, and to make use of, without ANY substantive understanding.&lt;p&gt;Of course this seems attractive for some reasons, but it is a wrong, degenerative way to be in the world. Thinking and being belong together. Knowing and using are two dimensions of the same activity.&lt;p&gt;The way of these tools is a making without understanding, a using without learning, a way of being that is thoughtless.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s nothing preventing us from thoughtful, rigorous, enriching use of generative ML, except that the systems we live and work in don&amp;#x27;t want us to be thoughtful and enriched and rigorous. They want us pliant and reactive and automated and sloppy.&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;#x27;t have to bend to their wants tho.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bdangubic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; After about 3-4k lines of code I completely lost track of what is going on&lt;p&gt;full stop here, there is nothing you can write after this…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;raphman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Given the code has been completely vibe-coded, what does this mean in practice?:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Copyright (c) 2025&lt;p&gt;Whose copyright? IIRC, it is consensus that AI cannot create copyrightable works. If the author does not own the copyright, can they add a legally binding license? If not, does this have any legal meaning?:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iammjm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel with people that say that &amp;quot;AI have take the fun out of programming&amp;quot; for them, but at the same time I think to myself: is it about doing, or is it about getting things done? Like I imagine someone in the past loved their job walking each night through their city, lighting up the gas-powered street lights. And then one day someone else implemented electric street lights, and the first person lost the job they loved. But in the end, its about providing light to the city streets, no? 
For the great majority of work, it is not about fun, but about doing something other people need or want. 
For me, AI allows me to realize my ideas, and get things done. Some of it might be good, some of it might be bad. I put at least as much time, attention and effort as the &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; programmers do, but my time goes into thinking and precisely defining what I want, cutting it up into smaller logical modules, testing, identifying and fixing bugs, iterating all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is reassuring. I started vime coding a side project and quickly got repulsed by the feeling of disconnection and lack of ownership. I put it on the shelf for a bit then came back and started over, writing all the code myself (but with a bit of VS Code autocomplete and a lot of assistance from ChatGPT). Super satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tcdent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s to be expected that HN would have a contrarian take but I find it ironic that the amount of criticism toward technological innovation in an industry that is rooted fundamentally in technological innovation is so common.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alganet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What Í&amp;#x27;m doing a lot is vibe coding and stashing. Not even a public branch, just git stash the whole thing the LLM writes.&lt;p&gt;Also, I stack the stash. When I vibe code, I pop it, let it work on its own mess, then I stash it again.&lt;p&gt;One project has almost 13.000 lines of vibe mess, all stashed.&lt;p&gt;One good thing, is that the stash &lt;i&gt;builds&lt;/i&gt;. It&amp;#x27;s just that I don&amp;#x27;t want to release more code than I can read. It&amp;#x27;s a long review queue that is pre-merged somehow.&lt;p&gt;Once in a while I pick something from there, then I review it and integrate into the codebase more seriously. I don&amp;#x27;t have the throughput to review it all, and not all projects can be yolo&amp;#x27;d.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;esafak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Suppose it was 10,000 lines of solid code. That would still require of dozens of PRs to be digestible, and the attendant time to review. Our attention is the bottleneck now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mentalgear:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This reflects my XP as well: use LLMs for semantic search. Do not trust it with your code.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Overall I would say it was a horrible experience, even though it took 10 hours to write close to 10000 lines of code, I don&amp;#x27;t consider this my project, and I have no sense of acomplishment or growth.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; In contrast, using AI to read all the docs (which are thousands of pages) and write helpful scripts to decode the oscilloscope data, create packed C structs from docs and etc, was very nice, and I did feel good after.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ipaddr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have felt similiar thoughts.  You start off with a mental model of how to develop an app based on experience.  You can quickly get the pieces working and wire them up.&lt;p&gt;What get&amp;#x27;s lost is when you normally develop an app that takes days you create a mind model as you go along that you take with you throughout the day.  In the shower you may connect some dots and reimagine the pieces in a more compelling way.  When the project is done you have mental model of all of the different pieces; thoughts of where to expand and fears of where you know the project will bottleneck with a mental note to circle back when you can.&lt;p&gt;When you vibe code you don&amp;#x27;t get the same highs and lows.  You don&amp;#x27;t mentally map each piece.  It&amp;#x27;s not a surprise that opening up and reading the code is the most painful thing but reading my own code is always a joy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yodsanklai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty much my experience, LLMs have taken the fun out of programming for me. My coding sessions are:&lt;p&gt;1. write prompt&lt;p&gt;2. slack a few minutes&lt;p&gt;3. go to 1&lt;p&gt;4. send code for review&lt;p&gt;I know what the code is doing, how I want it to look eventually, and my commits are small and self-contained, but I don&amp;#x27;t understand my code as much because I didn&amp;#x27;t spend so much time manipulate it. Often I spend more time in my loops than if I was writing the code myself.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure that with the right discipline, it&amp;#x27;s possible to tame the LLM, but I&amp;#x27;ve not been able to reach that stage yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onion2k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Is this what programming is now?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;p&gt;Vibe coding in the sense of handing all responsibility and accountability for the code in a change request over to AI &lt;i&gt;and then claiming the bad code is the fault of AI&lt;/i&gt; is not a thing. It&amp;#x27;s still &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; change request regardless of how you created it. If you write every line it&amp;#x27;s yours. If you copy it from SO into your editor and committed it, that&amp;#x27;s your choices, and therefore your code. If you prompted an LLM to write something, you are responsible for that.&lt;p&gt;If there is AI slop in your codebase it is only because you put it there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mronetwo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; After about 3-4k lines of code I completely lost track of what is going on, and I woudn&amp;#x27;t consider this code that I have written, but adding more and more tests felt &amp;quot;nice&amp;quot;, or at least reassuring.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; There was a some gaslighting, particularly when it misunderstood dap_read_mem32 thinking it is reading from ram and not MEM-AP TAR&amp;#x2F;DRW&amp;#x2F;RDBUFF protocol, which lead to incredible amount of nonsense.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Overall I would say it was a horrible experience, even though it took 10 hours to write close to 10000 lines of code, I don&amp;#x27;t consider this my project, and I have no sense of acomplishment or growth.&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, we can now mass produce faulty code, we feel even more alienated from our work, the sense of achievement gets taken away, no ownership, barely any skill growth. Wonderful technology. What a time to bring value to the shareholders!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;krainboltgreene:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Our products would be so many mirrors in which we saw reflected our essential nature.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;All the way from 1844.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;csallen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;After about 3-4k lines of code I completely lost track of what is going on... Overall I would say it was a horrible experience, even though it took 10 hours to write close to 10000 lines of code&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s hard to take very much away from somebody else&amp;#x27;s experiences in this area. Because if you&amp;#x27;ve been doing a substantial amount of AI coding this year, you know that the experience is highly dependent on your approach.&lt;p&gt;How do you structure your prompts? How much planning do you do? How do you do that planning? How much review do you do, and how do you do it? Just how hands-on or hands-off are you? What&amp;#x27;s in your AGENTS.md or equivalent? What other context do you include, when, why, and how? What&amp;#x27;s your approach to testing, if any? Do you break down big projects into smaller chunks, and if so, how? How fast vs slow are you going, i.e. how many lines of code are you letting the AI write in any given time period? Etc.&lt;p&gt;The answers to these questions vary extremely wildly from person to person.&lt;p&gt;But I suspect a ton of developers who are having terrible experiences with AI coding are quite new to it, have minimal systems in place, and are trying &amp;quot;vibe coding&amp;quot; in the original sense of the phrase, which is to rapidly prompt the LLM with minimal guidance and blindly trust its code. In which case, yeah, that&amp;#x27;s not going to give you great results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cnity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sometimes I read something on the internet and I think: finally someone has articulated something the way that I think about it. And it is very validating. And it cuts through a bunch of noise about how &amp;quot;oh you should be tuning and tweaking this prompt and that&amp;quot; and really speaks to the human experience. Thanks for this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/jackdoe/pico2-swd-riscv</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874987</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Safety for Skeptics</title>
      <link>https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=3773095</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rust, more than just promising memory safety, was demonstrably translating safety guarantees into practical improvements in software security. The benefits, supporters argue, are clear: comparable performance, modern tooling, and memory safety. Reflexive rejection of a move to memory safety is misguided, especially when the benefits of memory safety can be achieved in a cost- and schedule-efficient way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879012"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=3773095'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eptcyka:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Rust certainly was not the first &amp;quot;systems programming&amp;quot; language that was memory safe, ADA was aiming for the same title and I think achieved it way before Rust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kazinator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re tired of hearing about memory safety, this article is for you.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tell me more about memory safety, any time; just hold the Rust.&lt;p&gt;Rust skeptics are not memory safety skeptics. Hopefully, there are no memory safety skeptics, other than rhetorical strawmen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whobre:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ugh. I know all that and I am still sick of hearing about memory safety. My teammates spend way more time fixing security issues in “safe” languages than C&amp;#x2F;C++&amp;#x2F;whatever. It simply doesn’t matter…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=3773095</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879012</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Error ABI</title>
      <link>https://matklad.github.io/2025/11/09/error-ABI.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A follow-up on the “strongly typed error codes” article. Error virality is key here — just a single large error on however rare code path leads to worse code everywhere. Conclusion Your error ABI probably wants to be special, so the compiler needs to know about errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871688"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://matklad.github.io/2025/11/09/error-ABI.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://matklad.github.io/2025/11/09/error-ABI.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 02:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871688</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Head in the Zed Cloud</title>
      <link>https://maxdeviant.com/posts/2025/head-in-the-zed-cloud/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why Cloudflare Workers. At the heart of this framework is the Platform trait:pub trait Platform: Sized + Clone + 'static { type Cache: cache::Cache; type Clock: Clock; type KvStore: KvStore&lt;Self&gt;; type ServiceBinding: Fetcher&lt;Self&gt;; type DurableObjectNamespace: durable_object::DurableObjectNamespace&lt;Self&gt;; type DurableObjectStub: durable_object::DurableObjectStub&lt;Self&gt;; type DurableObjectState: durable_object::DurableObjectState&lt;Self&gt;; type RateLimiter: rate_limiter::RateLimiter&lt;Self&gt;; type SqlStorage: sql::SqlStorage; type PostgresConnection&lt;T&gt;: postgres::PostgresConnection&lt;Self, T&gt;; type PostgresTransaction&lt;T&gt;: postgres::PostgresTransaction&lt;Self, T&gt;; type ExecutionContext: ExecutionContext + Clone + Unpin; type Environment: Environment&lt;Self&gt; + Clone + Unpin; type ClientWebSocket: websocket::ClientWebSocket; type ServerWebSocket: websocket::ServerWebSocket&lt;Self&gt;; type WebSocketReceiver: websocket::WebSocketReceiver; type WebSocketSender: websocket::WebSocketSender; type HttpClient: http_client::HttpClient&lt;Platform = Self&gt;; type Queue&lt;T: Serialize + 'static&gt;: queue::Queue&lt;Self, T&gt;; type RawQueueMessageBatch: queue::RawQueueMessageBatch&lt;Self&gt;; type QueueMessageBatch&lt;T: DeserializeOwned + 'static&gt;: queue::QueueMessageBatch&lt;Self, T&gt;; type QueueMessage&lt;T: DeserializeOwned + 'static&gt;: queue::QueueMessage&lt;Self, T&gt;; type Rng: Clone + RngCore; fn websocket_pair() -&gt; Result&lt;(Self::ClientWebSocket, Self::ServerWebSocket)&gt;; } This trait allows us to write our code in a platform-agnostic way while still leveraging all of the functionality that Cloudflare Workers has to offer. We have a cloudflare_bindings crate2 that contains wasm_bindgen bindings to the Cloudflare Workers JS runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45876308"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://maxdeviant.com/posts/2025/head-in-the-zed-cloud/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cedws:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Post is a bit sparse on details and seems to be more about the backend than the infra itself. Would be interested to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mariopt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Been using CF Workers with JavaScript and I absolutely love it.&lt;p&gt;What is performance overhead when comparing rust against wasm?&lt;p&gt;Also think the time for a FOSS alternative is coming. Serverless without, virtually, cold starts is here to stay but being tied to only 1 vendor is problematic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://maxdeviant.com/posts/2025/head-in-the-zed-cloud/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45876308</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launch HN: Hypercubic (YC F25) – AI for COBOL and Mainframes</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877517</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hypercubic is an AI platform that helps Fortune 500 companies understand, preserve, and modernize their mainframe systems. These are the systems that run COBOL from the 1960s that still quietly power banking, insurance, airlines, and governments today. HyperDocs ingests that code and reconstructs it into readable, living documentation that shows how the black box system works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877517"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877517'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 15 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wiz21c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The goal is to build digital “twins” of the experts on how they debug, architect, and maintain these systems in practice.&lt;p&gt;Sounds great but... I have migrated a big cobol codebase several years ago. Knowledge stored in the experts is 1&amp;#x2F; very wide 2&amp;#x2F; full of special cases that pop up only a few times in a year 3&amp;#x2F; are usually complex cases involving analysing data, files which are on paper, etc. I strongly doubt an AI will be able to spot that.&lt;p&gt;The knowledge that usually misses  the most is not &amp;quot;how is that done&amp;quot;, because spending a few hours on COBOL code is frankly not that hard. What misses is: &amp;quot;why&amp;quot;. And that is usually stored in laws, sub-sub-laws, etc. You&amp;#x27;ll have to ingest the code and the law and pray the AI can match them.&lt;p&gt;So in the end the AI will make probably 50% of the effort  but then you&amp;#x27;ll need 150% to understand the AI job... So not sure it balances well.&lt;p&gt;But if it works, well, that&amp;#x27;s cool because re-writing cobol code is not exactly funny: devs don&amp;#x27;t want to do it, customers do it because they have to (and not because it&amp;#x27;ll bring additional value) and the best outcome possible is the customer saysing to you &amp;quot;okay, we paid you 2mio and the new system does the same things as before we started&amp;quot; (the most likely outcome, which I faced, is &amp;quot;you rewrote the system and its worse than before). So if an I can do it, well, cool.&lt;p&gt;(but then it means you&amp;#x27;ll fire the team who does the migration which, althgouhg is not funny and not rocket science, requires real expertise; it&amp;#x27;s not grunt work at all)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brightball:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In case you’re interested in learning more about COBOL, there was a great talk on it at Carolina Code Conference this year.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;RM7Q7u0pZyQ?si=zpP6mP7SYxLbuHqJ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;RM7Q7u0pZyQ?si=zpP6mP7SYxLbuHqJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cool-RR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; What’s left behind are opaque, black box systems with almost no one who understands how they work.&lt;p&gt;Maybe 50-year-old COBOL programs are the original neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29athrowaway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There is a large graveyard of people trying to escape the mainframe, replace COBOL, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iepathos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can tell they&amp;#x27;re using MkDocs for the HyperDocs static site gen based on the screenshot.  I&amp;#x27;m working on an open source solution to generating docs with AI for codebases and maintaining them for documentation drift.  I wrote a bit about it initially here &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;entropicdrift.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;prodigy-docs-automation&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;entropicdrift.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;prodigy-docs-automation&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; for anyone who is interested.  I&amp;#x27;m currently using mdbook instead of mkdocs, may add support for a mkdocs workflow to produce similar doc sites for just the cost of the LLM tokens.  I didn&amp;#x27;t realize COBOL had such a large market for documentation with code as the source of truth.  I&amp;#x27;ll have to try generating docs on an open source COBOL codebase to see how it fairs.  Would be nice if hypercubic had actual live doc examples for what hyperdocs generates instead of just a screenshot, hard to judge how good or bad it is with just a single screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;huevosabio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cool! I think this is a great use of LLMs.&lt;p&gt;The only other player I&amp;#x27;ve seen is Mechanical Orchard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vector_spaces:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Our other tool, HyperTwin, tackles the “tribal knowledge” problem. It learns directly from subject-matter experts, observing workflows, analyzing screen interactions, and conducting AI-driven interviews to capture how they debug and reason about their systems. The goal is to build digital “twins” of the experts on how they debug, architect, and maintain these systems in practice.&lt;p&gt;How do you consolidate this knowledge across disparate teams and organizational silos? 
How will you identify and reconcile subtle differences in terminology used across the organization?&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I misunderstood, but on your website you primarily identify technical implementors as SMEs. IME modernizing legacy data systems in high-stakes environments, the devil is more on the business side -- e.g. disparate teams using the same term to refer to different concepts (and having that reflected in code), or the exact stakeholders of reports or data systems being unknown and unknowable, and discerning between rules that are critical to a particular team or workflow that are opaque to you because e.g. you don&amp;#x27;t know who all relies on this data or are missing business context, or because the rule is not actually used anymore, or because the implementation of the rule itself is wrong.&lt;p&gt;Besides, both technical and non-technical stakeholders and SMEs lean heavily on heuristics to decision with the data they are looking at, but often struggle to explicitly articulate them. They don&amp;#x27;t think to mention certain conditions or filters because for them those are baked into the terminology, or it doesn&amp;#x27;t occur to them that the organization deals with broader data than what they interact with in their day-to-day.&lt;p&gt;And unfortunately in these settings, you don&amp;#x27;t get many chances to get it wrong -- trust is absolutely critical.&lt;p&gt;I am skeptical that what you will end up with at the end of the day will be a product, at least if your intent is to provide meaningful value to people who rely on these systems and solve the problems that keep them up at night. My feeling is that you will end up as primarily a consultancy, which makes sense given that the problem you are solving isn&amp;#x27;t primarily technical in nature, it just has technical components.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cess11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All I can think about when reading this presentation is that Glamorous Toolkit pretty much has this and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;le-mark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve witnessed two legacy migration projects, both failed. One was a source translation to Java, this one failed because they didn’t have the expertise to manage production Java applications and pulled the plug.  The other was a rewrite that went over budget and was cancelled.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; HyperDocs ingests COBOL, JCL, and PL&amp;#x2F;I codebases to generate documentation, architecture diagrams, and dependency graphs.&lt;p&gt;Lots of tools available that do this already without AI.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The goal is to build digital “twins” of the experts on how they debug, architect, and maintain these systems in practice.&lt;p&gt;That will be a neat trick, will the output be more than sparsely populated wiki?&lt;p&gt;My experience is there’s not a lot of Will or money to follow these things through.&lt;p&gt;Edit to add there was a lot of work around business rule extraction, automatic documentation, and static analysis of mainframe systems in 90s leading up to Y2K, but it all fizzled out after that. You all should search the literature if you haven’t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gregsadetsky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I submitted this [0] story a few weeks ago, which led to some discussion and then being flagged since (I think) people were unsure of how verifiable the stats around COBOL were (the submitted page had more than a tinge of self-promotional language).&lt;p&gt;I was curious to ask you, as domain experts, if you could talk more to the &amp;quot;70% of the Fortune 500 still run on mainframes&amp;quot; stat you mentioned.&lt;p&gt;Where do these numbers come from? And also, does it mean that those 70% of Fortune 500s literally run&amp;#x2F;maintain 1k-1M+ LoC of COBOL? Or do these companies depend on a few downstream specialized providers (financial, aviation&amp;#x2F;logistics, etc.) which do rely on COBOL?&lt;p&gt;Like, is it COBOL all the way down, or is everything built in different ways, but basically on top of 3 companies, and those 3 companies are mostly doing COBOL?&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45644205"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45644205&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koolba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Neat stuff. For more esoteric environments that could use this type of automated leg up, check out MUMPS: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;MUMPS" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;MUMPS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a bunch of mainly legacy hospital and government (primarily VA) systems that run on it. And where there&amp;#x27;s big government systems, there&amp;#x27;s big government dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is weird. Mainframes are the dinosaurs of tech. Never would I think, &amp;#x27;let&amp;#x27;s add some AI&amp;#x27; to a mainframe. It would be like adding opposable thumbs to dinosaurs. You are still solving the wrong problem, but it sure will be interesting watching the systems cope.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zurfer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I heard the story once on how you migrate these old systems:
1 you get a super extensive test suite of input - output pairs&lt;p&gt;2 you do a &amp;quot;line by line&amp;quot; reimplementation in Java (well banks like it).&lt;p&gt;3 you run the test suite and track your progress&lt;p&gt;4 when you get to 100 percent, you send the same traffic to both systems and shadow run the new implementation. Depending on how that goes you either give up, go back to work implementation or finally switch to the new system&lt;p&gt;This obviously is super expensive and slow to minimize any sort of risks for systems that usually handle billions or trillions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mkoubaa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m excited for you but nervous about the kinds of bugs that might get caused&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jclay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Exciting work! I’ve often wondered if an LLM with the right harness could restore and optimize an aging C&amp;#x2F;C++ codebase. It would be quite compelling to get an old game engine running again on a modern system.&lt;p&gt;I would expect most of these systems come with very carefully guarded access controls. It also strikes me as a uniquely difficult challenge to track down the decision maker who is willing to take the risk on revamping these systems (AI or not). Curious to hear more about what you’ve learned here.&lt;p&gt;Also curious to hear how LLMs perform on a language like COBOL that likely doesn’t have many quality samples in the training data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877517</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877517</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omnilingual ASR: Advancing automatic speech recognition for 1600 languages</title>
      <link>https://ai.meta.com/blog/omnilingual-asr-advancing-automatic-speech-recognition/?_fb_noscript=1</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automatic speech recognition (ASR) systems aim to make spoken language universally accessible by transcribing speech into text that can be searched, analyzed, and shared. We’re also open sourcing Omnilingual wav2vec 2. Our general-purpose speech foundation model wav2vec 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878826"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ai.meta.com/blog/omnilingual-asr-advancing-automatic-speech-recognition/?_fb_noscript=1'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stuffoverflow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This seems like a massive improvement for openly available local ASR. Even the 300M model outperforms whisper-large-v3 according to the paper&amp;#x27;s benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How hard is it to make TTS out of this? A few independent journalists from Belarus asked for TTS in their language, but I am no expert, was thinking about re-using Mozilla&amp;#x27;s work. What&amp;#x27;s the easiest way to get working TTS for a language?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tschellenbach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;any insights on latency?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meetpateltech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;HF Demo: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;spaces&amp;#x2F;facebook&amp;#x2F;omniasr-transcriptions" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;spaces&amp;#x2F;facebook&amp;#x2F;omniasr-transcription...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;facebookresearch&amp;#x2F;omnilingual-asr" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;facebookresearch&amp;#x2F;omnilingual-asr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ai.meta.com/blog/omnilingual-asr-advancing-automatic-speech-recognition/?_fb_noscript=1</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878826</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redmond, WA, turns off Flock Safety cameras after ICE arrests</title>
      <link>https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/law-justice/redmond-turns-off-flock-safety-cameras-after-ice-arrests/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The city suspended its Flock system because city officials could not guarantee they wouldn’t be forced to release data collected by those devices someday, she said. Their concerns may have been prescient. Police officials in Renton, Auburn, Mukilteo and Lakewood, Pierce County, changed their Flock settings after the UW report showed federal agencies had accessed their Flock data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879101"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/law-justice/redmond-turns-off-flock-safety-cameras-after-ice-arrests/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sleepybrett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No they turned them off because it turns out those cameras are public records and all their citizens can make requests for ALL THAT DATA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;outside1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We are all speed running our learning on how all of these systems can be used against us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seltzered_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;On Thursday, a Skagit County Superior Court judge ruled that pictures taken by Flock cameras in the cities of Sedro-Woolley and Stanwood qualify as public records, and therefore must be released as required by the state’s Public Records Act, court records show.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This video by Tom Lehto talks more about that court case that illustrates citizens can legally do FOIA requests for traffic cameras (e.g. Flock): &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;1vQn4MWBln0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;1vQn4MWBln0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notepad0x90:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Immigration is similar to the housing crisis and Nimbyism. Voters don&amp;#x27;t want a streamlined and efficient immigration system that lawfully allows a lot of migrants in (NIMBY). it is also similar to the war on drugs and its failure, ICE won&amp;#x27;t solve anything just as the DEA only made things worse with drugs.&lt;p&gt;No matter what, the whole ICE acting like the SS thing will only result in more illegal migration in the long term, like a lot more. Same with europe&amp;#x27;s far right teasing.&lt;p&gt;If the &amp;quot;infrastructure&amp;quot; can&amp;#x27;t support more people, we can build more here in the US. Borders shouldn&amp;#x27;t be open, but more health and able-bodied or skilled people wanting to migrate, so long as their criminal history is clear, should be let in, infrastructure should be scaled. It&amp;#x27;s more economic activity and wealth for the rest of us. More jobs, more workers. We need to do that for the housing crisis anyways.&lt;p&gt;We need more cities, more development, less NIMBY-thinking and less &amp;quot;beat them until they comply&amp;quot; thinking. Too many people who don&amp;#x27;t know or are unwilling to solve real problems but are eager to see cruelty and violence cause these untenable and regrettable situations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cipehr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A little annoyed, this seems like is has &lt;i&gt;nothing to do with the ICE arrests&lt;/i&gt;...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The city suspended its Flock system because city officials could not guarantee they wouldn’t be forced to release data collected by those devices someday, she said.&lt;p&gt;Key part is &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;someday&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;. Seems like the article is implying that flock &lt;i&gt;may&lt;/i&gt; have shared this data with ICE which led to the arrests... but there is no proof supporting this...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; On Thursday, a Skagit County Superior Court judge ruled that pictures taken by Flock cameras in the cities of Sedro-Woolley and Stanwood qualify as public records, and therefore must be released as required by the state’s Public Records Act, court records show.&lt;p&gt;This is the more likely reason. What do folks here think about this ruling?&lt;p&gt;IMO it seems obvious that this should be public records&amp;#x2F;data, but would love to hear alternative positions to this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pton_xd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What did they think would happen? Installing surveillance systems to monitor people is acceptable, as long as they&amp;#x27;re only used against the majority? I don&amp;#x27;t understand the logic here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;focusgroup0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ironically, there would be little need for surveillance state technology if the on-the-books immigration law had been enforced for the past few decades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dredmorbius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;NB:  Title edited to add &amp;quot;WA&amp;quot; for clarity.  I.e., this is the city of, not a toponym for another entity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/law-justice/redmond-turns-off-flock-safety-cameras-after-ice-arrests/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879101</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>European Commission plans “digital omnibus” package to simplify its tech laws</title>
      <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/brussels-knifes-privacy-to-feed-the-ai-boom-gdpr-digital-omnibus/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Commission should be fully aware that this is undermining European standards dramatically. European privacy regulators have already been spoiling Big Tech's AI party in recent years. Advertisement In past months, Commission officials have sought to preempt worries that it was overhauling the privacy rulebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878311"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.politico.eu/article/brussels-knifes-privacy-to-feed-the-ai-boom-gdpr-digital-omnibus/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cadamsdotcom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Biggest problem is you need two types economy at once.&lt;p&gt;You need the big paradigm shifts that come from an innovation economy; for that, capital must flow easily, risk-taking (both companies and individuals) be rewarded not punished, and a stable job is kind of a bad thing (people get too comfortable)..&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in more mature sectors, job security (so people can have mortgages and families) and market stability should be fostered and corporate overreach &amp;amp; power be checked.&lt;p&gt;Advanced economies are a mix of sectors which need almost opposite policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paganel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;EU dictatorship at its finest, love to see it. This whole thing cannot disintegrate soon enough, and I say that as a (still, unfortunately) EU citizen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nuffisnuff9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hopefully it&amp;#x27;s the end of GDPR and privacy laws that absolutely no one requested.&lt;p&gt;Like nobody requested that encrypted chats stop being encrypted or that X becomes a censorship target of EU comissars&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jnurmine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Draft changes would create new exceptions for AI companies that would allow them to legally process special categories of data (like a person’s religious or political beliefs, ethnicity or health data) to train and operate their tech.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fully anonymized health data I can somehow understand, but what kind of AI needs to be trained with &amp;quot;a person&amp;#x27;s religious or political beliefs [or] ethnicity&amp;quot;, anonymized or not?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrenBarn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m always boggled by the logic of thinking that somehow having big companies going around doing harmful actions to people is &amp;quot;good for the economy&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;keeps us competitive&amp;quot;.  If having strict AI regulations means AI companies leave Europe, that&amp;#x27;s &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt;!  I wish we could do the same and get them to leave the US.  These big AI companies are &lt;i&gt;bad&lt;/i&gt;.  We shouldn&amp;#x27;t want them, we shouldn&amp;#x27;t try to attract them, we shouldn&amp;#x27;t provide any conciliations or incentives.  The sooner and more completely they&amp;#x27;re eradicated from any jurisdiction, the better.  Forcing that kind of toxic waste out of your country should be perceived as a win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yaina:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like the EU, but what&amp;#x27;s annoying about things like this, or the Chat Control law that keeps getting pushed, is that civil society and privacy advocacy groups always need to stay vigilant and keep mobilizing people. It&amp;#x27;s an attrition game.&lt;p&gt;I wonder what harm companies are even claiming. But honestly makes perfect sense that Germany&amp;#x27;s current conservative government is in favor of it. Giant GDP boosts are always just one deregulation away, hm?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insanity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a tricky balance to strike. I don&amp;#x27;t want EU to fall behind further in the AI race, and I do want them to be more competitive in the tech landscape. At the moment, EU really isn&amp;#x27;t competitive in tech (and neither in tech salaries) and it leads to a certain amount of &amp;#x27;brain drain&amp;#x27; as people move abroad.&lt;p&gt;So while I do understand the need for regulations, they shouldn&amp;#x27;t regulate themselves into irrelevance. I don&amp;#x27;t think there&amp;#x27;s an easy solution to this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;impossiblefork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s really stupid that people imagine that the GDPR would hold back European AI.&lt;p&gt;Seeing as the Americans firms have in fact rolled out their systems, it&amp;#x27;s unlikely to be a legal problem withe GDPR. Maybe copyright is a problem.That would have been a solved problem if that regulation requiring people to list their training data had been applied fully.&lt;p&gt;This won&amp;#x27;t make any difference for AI and will reduce EU cohesion, as a belief in privacy is a shared European value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rckt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How about also reviewing the copyright laws in favour of the public? The AI actors consume everything for profit and nobody cares. But if an ordinary Joe does this for personal amusement, he should face consequences.&lt;p&gt;This whole thing is obviously biased, because of money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmholla:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Original title: Brussels knifes privacy to feed the AI boom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.politico.eu/article/brussels-knifes-privacy-to-feed-the-ai-boom-gdpr-digital-omnibus/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878311</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canadian military will rely on public servants to boost its ranks by 300k</title>
      <link>https://ottawacitizen.com/public-service/defence-watch/canadian-military-public-servants</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article contentArticle contentThe training focus would be on “basic skills (e. Article contentThe current reserve force would jump from 23,561 to 100,000 for the mobilization plan. Article contentArticle content“Defence will not accomplis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877892"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ottawacitizen.com/public-service/defence-watch/canadian-military-public-servants'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cmrdporcupine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Odd how this is on front page of HN but buried way down my feed on (Canadian) Google News and doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be front-page news?&lt;p&gt;Do you have to be a public servant or retired Canadian Forces, or do they take portly middle-aged out of shape software engineers, too?  Asking for a friend.&lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;#x27;t shot a gun since Bible Camp when I was 12.  Could be fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stackedinserter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Federal and provincial employees would be given a one-week training course in how to handle firearms, drive trucks and fly drones&lt;p&gt;What is the use of these &amp;quot;professionals&amp;quot;?&lt;p&gt;I know russians send these substandard soldiers to meat grinder (&amp;quot;infiltration in small groups&amp;quot; tactics). If they&amp;#x27;re killed with ukrainian FPV drone, it&amp;#x27;s fine, at least AFU spent a drone. Is it what Canadians are planning to do?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t using government employees for non-combat tasks to free up troops. It&amp;#x27;s more like the WWII Home Guard in the UK.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Federal and provincial employees would be given a one-week training course in how to handle firearms, drive trucks and fly drones...The public servants would be inducted into the Supplementary Reserve, which is currently made up of inactive or retired members of the Canadian Forces who are willing to return to duty if called.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sort of thing is usually a desperation measure in wartime. What threat does Canada see? US ICE goon squads crossing the border into Canada? Building up the regular military reserves is more normal. Further down, the article says that&amp;#x27;s happening.&lt;p&gt;A better use for a Home Guard of government employees would be civil defense. What to do when power goes out, food distribution breaks down, or gas deliveries cease.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ninalanyon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;24 000 reserves out of a population of 40 million seems like a rather small number.&lt;p&gt;Norway has 40 000 in the Home Guard (Heimevernet) rapid reaction force of volunteer part time soldiers and a further 20 000 reserves.  All from a population of about 5.5 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jjk166:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seems like a generally good idea for creating a large reserve force. It definitely beats general conscription.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t see why Canada in particular needs such a large reserve force. This would jump Canada from number 127 to number 52 in terms of percentage of population in reserves, and bump it up to 17th in terms of absolute reserves size. For a nation with basically zero chance of invasion of its home soil and an extremely low risk of internal conflict, it&amp;#x27;s hard to imagine a scenario where anywhere near this many reservists would be required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;groby_b:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just in case people miss the core message: This is something you do if you have a credible risk assessment that you think a big conflict is a possibility within the next decade or so.&lt;p&gt;And, as much as I&amp;#x27;d like to focus on deteriorating Canada&amp;#x2F;US relations, it&amp;#x27;s likely a dual purpose. The Ukraine&amp;#x2F;Russia&amp;#x2F;NATO situation would be the second factor. OK, a triad, China&amp;#x2F;US is also on the radar. Whatever the weighting, it&amp;#x27;s pushed Canada to work on a mobilization framework, because the combined risk is high enough.&lt;p&gt;Which means &amp;quot;oh shit&amp;quot; feelings are entirely appropriate, panic isn&amp;#x27;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;incomingpain:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Canada has been running about 1% of gdp military spending, despite obligation of 2%; with new promise to meet 5%. a 500% increase to the size of our military in short order is the promise.&lt;p&gt;Our reserves are at about 40,000. They announced the plan to go to 400,000. 10x the size. It&amp;#x27;s not so much about any outside fears, it&amp;#x27;s just meeting our obligations.The fear about Russia or China is unfounded. The problem is that the USA our greatest ally isn&amp;#x27;t letting us use them as a shield.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Federal and provincial employees would be given a one-week training course in how to handle firearms, drive trucks and fly drones, according to the directive, signed by Chief of the Defence Staff Gen. Jennie Carignan&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s only about 300,000 federal employees. Greater on the provincial sides, but Canada isn&amp;#x27;t that big. Conscription will be necessary to fulfill these numbers&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;The public servants would be inducted into the Supplementary Reserve, which is currently made up of inactive or retired members of the Canadian Forces who are willing to return to duty if called.&lt;p&gt;It says voluntary, but given the very significant % who need to join and be subject to immediate activation. I dont expect many to volunteer. Reserves at least pays you to have this cost. Conscription will be necessary. They are forcing those government employees ultimately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fidotron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The most damning thing about this is the Canadian gov would struggle to find 300k people in the rest of the population that it would trust with skilling up in those ways. Federal public servants will be the last bastion of the values they try to force on everyone else.&lt;p&gt;It is in the process of spending vast amounts of money to remove guns from legal gun owners that are subject to absolutely amazing amounts of oversight already.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;colechristensen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sign of the times, Canada is so afraid of the instability of America that they&amp;#x27;re low-key drafting public servants on a voluntary basis for now into the military.&lt;p&gt;Canadians are our closest brothers and sisters and it&amp;#x27;s just a historical quirk that we&amp;#x27;re separate countries at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abrichr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;G4oZo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;G4oZo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ottawacitizen.com/public-service/defence-watch/canadian-military-public-servants</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877892</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Generative AI in Content Production</title>
      <link>https://partnerhelp.netflixstudios.com/hc/en-us/articles/43393929218323-Using-Generative-AI-in-Content-Production</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What should we consider before using GenAI for talent enhancement. What use cases always require written approval. Data Use Protecting personal data and creative rights is essential when working with GenAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879793"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://partnerhelp.netflixstudios.com/hc/en-us/articles/43393929218323-Using-Generative-AI-in-Content-Production'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://partnerhelp.netflixstudios.com/hc/en-us/articles/43393929218323-Using-Generative-AI-in-Content-Production</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879793</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
