<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:46:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic's report smells a lot like bullshit</title>
      <link>https://djnn.sh/posts/anthropic-s-paper-smells-like-bullshit/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://djnn.sh/posts/anthropic-s-paper-smells-like-bullshit/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944296</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maybe You're Not Actually Trying</title>
      <link>https://usefulfictions.substack.com/p/maybe-youre-not-actually-trying</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://usefulfictions.substack.com/p/maybe-youre-not-actually-trying</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943979</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why are you (still) using OpenBSD?</title>
      <link>https://www.tumfatig.net/2025/why-are-you-still-using-openbsd/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tumfatig.net/2025/why-are-you-still-using-openbsd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944595</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Text Log Between Mark Zuckerberg and Kevin Systrom(Instagram Cofounder)</title>
      <link>https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fo/0e4qbvj7w8cwxdlpo010c/AHCMfNHmj03nPnJ-VKDYRvA?dl=0&amp;e=1&amp;noscript=1&amp;preview=Facebook%2Btext%2Blog%2Bbetween%2BMark%2BZuckerberg%2Band%2BKevin%2BSystrom.pdf&amp;rlkey=43f3smc5zi5v82h986hujmvfb</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fo/0e4qbvj7w8cwxdlpo010c/AHCMfNHmj03nPnJ-VKDYRvA?dl=0&amp;e=1&amp;noscript=1&amp;preview=Facebook%2Btext%2Blog%2Bbetween%2BMark%2BZuckerberg%2Band%2BKevin%2BSystrom.pdf&amp;rlkey=43f3smc5zi5v82h986hujmvfb</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943486</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK's first small nuclear power station to be built in north Wales</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c051y3d7myzo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visiting a further education college in north Wales on Thursday, Sir Keir said the development would bring jobs for "decades to come" and that work would begin "virtually straight away". Mims Davies MP, the Shadow Secretary of State for Wales, said it will bring much-needed jobs and investment but "the current plan will only generate a fraction of the power that a Gigawatt-powered plant would". The company will report back by autumn 2026, officials said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944056"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c051y3d7myzo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;testdelacc1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This live dashboard puts this number in perspective - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;grid.iamkate.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;grid.iamkate.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roughly: the demand is about 33-35GW. That’s projected to become 50GW by 2050 as transportation and home heating become electrified. So that’s the puck we’re skating towards.&lt;p&gt;Nuclear supplies a constant 10% of the demand today (more, if you count imports from France). The goal is to power 20% of the 50GW demand through nuclear. If it’s cheap, even more. Each of these Small Modular Reactors (SMRs) generates 470MW, so we’d need about 20 of them.&lt;p&gt;The plan is to set up a factory near Sheffield and produce the reactor parts like IKEA, so they can be assembled on site. The hope is that manufacturing and assembling the same product repeatedly makes people more efficient. That’s the main problem with nuclear - over budget and delays - that SMRs aim to fix.&lt;p&gt;I’m glad the UK is taking electrification seriously, and is investing in domestic industry that will hopefully export reactors if it’s successful. Some folks might look at the estimated date of completion (2035) and get discouraged, but I wouldn’t. The best time to plant this tree was 20 years ago. The second best time is now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;irthomasthomas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anglesey is beautiful[0]. My ancestors came from there and I used to holiday there as a child. Today it is somewhat blighted by those ugly and noisy turbines[1]. I am in favor of this if it reduces the number of onshore turbines on the island.&lt;p&gt;0 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.celtictrailswalkingholidays.co.uk&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;uploads&amp;#x2F;Llanddwyn-Island-Anglesey-2000x985.jpg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.celtictrailswalkingholidays.co.uk&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;upl...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;i2-prod.walesonline.co.uk&amp;#x2F;article21841043.ece&amp;#x2F;ALTERNATES&amp;#x2F;s1200&amp;#x2F;0_AFR_DPW161117BeltexRowlands_29.jpg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;i2-prod.walesonline.co.uk&amp;#x2F;article21841043.ece&amp;#x2F;ALTERN...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jorisboris:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I believe the more technologically advanced we live the more energy we will use. Travel requires energy, ai models require energy, healthy food requires energy&lt;p&gt;The cheaper and more abundant we can make electricity, the faster we can reap the benefits of new technology&lt;p&gt;imo nuclear is an important part to have abundant energy at all times&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oras:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hopefully not another HS2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;perihelions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;The old nuclear power plant at Wylfa was switched off in 2015&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tangentially—this is a brownfield site, where there once was an early generation of nuclear fission reactor, cooled by CO2 gas. Here&amp;#x27;s a brief description of what those machines looked like (not this exact one):&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29890470"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=29890470&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Nothing like this will be built again&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;—263 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archelaos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Horrible news. The next 50.000 generations will have to pay for this. Will this madness never stop?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philip-J-Fry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Producing power by the mid 2030s? Isn&amp;#x27;t the entire point of SMRs that they are effectively a complete package and it takes very little effort to ship them out and getting them to produce power. Or is this just a pipe-dream we were sold?&lt;p&gt;Like, I imagined these things being compact enough to be shipped to the outskirts of towns and producing power. Afterall, they are from the same technology that was powering nuclear subs, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;londons_explore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nuclear is an industry that strangled itself with red tape and harmful PR, making every project fiendishly expensive and take so many decades that cost-of-capital costs are insane.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think it will ever again beat solar+wind+battery for grid scale carbon-free power pricing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mikaeluman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great news. Lets hope this is just the start.&lt;p&gt;The whole of Europe needs to get on with energy security and Britain can and should be a leader here, next to Netherlands, Sweden and France.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c051y3d7myzo</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944056</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing the Branch Predictor</title>
      <link>https://nicula.xyz/2025/03/10/bypassing-the-branch-predictor.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those attributes will typically just reorder some labels/paths around to make sure that the path which we mark as [[likely]] will require less jumps. L2: pop rbx jmp abandon(Transaction*) It won’t really matter that the send() branch doesn’t need to do the jump at line 7, because the branch predictor will be primed to assume the abandon() branch nonetheless. We have to do this enough times such that the mocked transaction data becomes the vast majority over the real data, so the branch predictor will be primed to assume that the send() path will be executed practically on every resolve() call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943279"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://nicula.xyz/2025/03/10/bypassing-the-branch-predictor.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; On modern x86 processors, those instruction prefixes are simply ignored&lt;p&gt;This sucks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bluGill:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do cpus really track that much about branches? I know JIT does but where does a cpu find the needed memory to store those counters - and them how does reading those not result in a different miss because the cpu can&amp;#x27;t speculate until it does the if prediction?&lt;p&gt;last time I checked a cpu documentation they had a simple rule that branches are always taken, that would be easy for the compiler to code order first. However I don&amp;#x27;t recall which CPU that was. Still this whole thing feels like a citation needed with me being suspicious it is false. CPU designers know this matters and sometimes compilers have information they don&amp;#x27;t that users care about: they document how it works.  (This is the CPU not the instruction set)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ViolentTurkey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Make sure your global branch history is the same when &amp;quot;mistraining&amp;quot; and predicting with your BTB. You may end up in the wrong BTB entry and still mess up your prediction :).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kklisura:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I asked Claude if there is such a way to basically hard-code branch prediction rules into the machine code, and the answer was that there’s no way to do this on x86, but there is a way on ARM: the BEQP (predict branch taken) and BEQNP (predict branch not taken) instructions.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Those ARM instructions are just hallucinated, and the reality is actually the other way around: ARM doesn’t have a way of hard-coding ‘predictions’, but x86 does.&lt;p&gt;This made me chuckle. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jcul:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why not just make all the abandon transactions into fake discarded transactions, discard them at the send later. E.g. by poisoning the frame checksum or setting something invalid on them, so they get discarded.&lt;p&gt;Seems you&amp;#x27;d be doing this anyway with the dummy transactions.&lt;p&gt;Then you have no branch, though may want to add dummy transactions anyway to keep the code in cache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nneonneo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What a fun problem to think about.&lt;p&gt;My first instinct, knowing less about this domain than maybe I should, would be to abuse the return address predictor. I believe  CPUs will generally predict the target of a “ret” instruction using an internal stack of return addresses; some ARM flavours even make this explicit (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.arm.com&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;den0042&amp;#x2F;0100&amp;#x2F;Unified-Assembly-Language-Instructions&amp;#x2F;Branch-prediction&amp;#x2F;Return-stack-prediction" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.arm.com&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;den0042&amp;#x2F;0100&amp;#x2F;Unified...&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;p&gt;The way to abuse this would be to put send() on the normal return path and call abandon() by rewriting the return address. In code:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  void resolve(Transaction *t) {
    predict(t);
    send(t);
  }

  void predict(Transaction *t) {
    if (!should_send(t)) *(void **)__builtin_return_address(0) = &amp;amp;abandon;
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
This isn’t exactly correct because it ignores control flow integrity (which you’d have to bypass), doesn’t work like this on every architecture, and abandon() would need to be written partly in assembly to deal with the fact that the stack is in a weird state post-return, but hopefully it conveys the idea anyway.&lt;p&gt;The if in predict() is implementable as a branchless conditional move. The return address predictor should guess that predict() will return to send(), but in most cases you’ll smash the return address to point at abandon() instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IshKebab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting problem! Not a very satisfying solution but I can&amp;#x27;t think of anything better. Even if there were hints that were respected, you&amp;#x27;d still have the problem of the code not being in icache, unless you actually execute it occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tux3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My first instinct for a poorly predicted branch would be to use a conditional move.&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t always a win, because you prevent the CPU from speculating down the wrong path, but you also prevent it from speculating the correct path.&lt;p&gt;If you really don&amp;#x27;t care about the failure path and really don&amp;#x27;t mind unmaintainable low-level hacks, I can think of a few ways to get creative.&lt;p&gt;First there&amp;#x27;s the whole array of anti uarch-speculation-exploit tricks in the Kernel that you can use as inspiration to control what the CPU is allowed to speculate. These little bits of assembly were reviewed by engineers from Intel and AMD, so these tricks can&amp;#x27;t stop working without also breaking the kernel with it.&lt;p&gt;Another idea is to take inspiration from anti-reverse engineering tricks. Make the failure path an actual exception. I don&amp;#x27;t mean software stack unwinding, I mean divide by your boolean and then call your send function unconditionally. If the boolean is true, it costs nothing because the result of the division is unused and we just speculate past it. If the boolean is false, the CPU will raise a divide by 0 exception, and this invisible branch will never be predicted by the CPU. Then your exception handler recovers and calls the cold path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nicula.xyz/2025/03/10/bypassing-the-branch-predictor.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943279</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An exposed .git folder let us dox a phishing campaign</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943802</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past Friday afternoon, a member in our Discord server reported a phishing email pointing to a fake login page. With the source code, repo and the active Telegram bot token, we filed detailed abuse reports:- GitHub: We reported the repository containing the phishing kit's source code. The crowdsourced speed and collaboration helped us take this down very fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943802"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943802'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CGamesPlay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What leads to the secret being stored in git&amp;#x27;s config file like that? None of my repositories have that, the remote URLs all just say &amp;quot;git@github.com:foo&amp;#x2F;bar.git&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArcHound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is great that they got taken down. From my experience, these sites are usually parasites on misconfigured Wordpresseses.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re you able to get the phishing data so that you can help the victims? Is it a good idea to try and do so?&lt;p&gt;Also, can you please share some bits of the phishing kit for easier detection?&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your efforts!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ekjhgkejhgk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like they got off easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;poly2it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could&amp;#x27;ve traced the attacker for a bit before burning all bridges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943802</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943802</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don't Need a Steam Machine</title>
      <link>https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That you don’t like playing. You don’t have time to play games anyway. Your MacBook can emulate Windows games just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943992"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 29 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;accrual:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the author could use another TV if they have the space. Solves both the missing HDMI input and the &amp;quot;TV in use&amp;quot; error. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ivanjermakov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; You can’t buy this without buying the Steam Controller.&lt;p&gt;Oh, this is ugly! Haven&amp;#x27;t noticed this being mentioned anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ivanjermakov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; With The Steam Machine, you might be able to finally properly run DOOM Eternal and all of the Assassin’s Creed games. That you don’t like playing.&lt;p&gt;In my experience, relation of game&amp;#x27;s hardware requirements to the amount of fun it provides is inversely proportional. Best games of all time (opinionated, of course) run well on integrated graphics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;haunter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Funnily Valve doesn’t need it either to some extent. It’s almost like a pet project. They won’t sell it retail, no ads, so certainly won’t even hurt the sales of Switch 2 and PS5. Mind you the former just sold more than 10m units in less than 6 months.&lt;p&gt;Secondly Valve makes disgusting amount of money from the lootboxes and the unregulated underage gambling market (estimated billions) which are almost a 0 effort system. Running an API and releasing a new lootbox every 2nd month or so are peanuts compared to the development, manifacturing, and distribution of the Steam Machine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whitehexagon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m doing a Needs-only-November - Non to &amp;#x27;wants&amp;#x27;.  But this was top of my list of 2026 &amp;#x27;wants&amp;#x27;.&lt;p&gt;Your list has hopefully saved me ~300eur thanks.  And to add to your list, hopefully it comes non-upgradable, choca full of adverts, forced AI, spyware&amp;#x2F;root-kit&amp;#x2F;anti-cheat, mandatory age verified account requirements, and all the other modern essentials to make me never ever want one.&lt;p&gt;Still, it is kinda cute.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ramon156:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;all that matters is price. if it&amp;#x27;s a bang-for-your-buck (similar to the steamdeck) then i&amp;#x27;m in. I don&amp;#x27;t have a PC in my current living space and it takes up as much space as my laptop, if not less.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ibizaman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was going through the list, nodding as I read all the reasons, agreeing with them all. But also thinking each time I’ll get one anyway. I guess I agree with the last sentence of the post haha. If anything, I’ll justify this by saying I want to choose with my money and encourage this further. But that’s really just to give me good conscience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoric:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Let me be that guy: we live in a time of collapse, for both the environment and international relationships – do we really need more gaming rigs?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;avyeed_desa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why can&amp;#x27;t i just shake the feeling that Steam Machines will Valve&amp;#x27;s gateway to release Half-Life 3 as a Steam Machine title exclusive? Furthermore, HL will only be Linux exclusive, at least for the first few months to put pressure on Sony, MS and Nintendo and the GTA6 launch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ntoskrnl_exe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I too won&amp;#x27;t be getting one, especially since I already have enough power at my desk.&lt;p&gt;But I love how amazing of an idea it is. A form factor and ease-of-setup of a console that brings all the best features of PC gaming (inter-generational compatibility, free multiplayer...) into the living room. And unlike with the original Steam Machine, the market is ready this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zmmmmm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s truly crazy is the VR headset is the same architecture as the Steam Machine. As in, it&amp;#x27;s a completely open Linux system you can &lt;i&gt;wear on your face&lt;/i&gt;. They are literally telling the community to go nuts and hack it and install whatever you want on there.&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;#x27;s any time for people who believe in open systems and open software to step up and buy the hell out of something, this it it. It will be very interesting to see if the play works out our not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;torginus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When I first saw the Arduino I didn&amp;#x27;t see the point - after all there were boards that cost less, did more, and the Arduino IDE seemed very barebones compared to what you could do with GCC and a custom toolchain.&lt;p&gt;Then eventually I saw how much community support, ready made hardware emerged around it, to the point that after a while, not going the Arduino route was a decision you needed to justify heavily.&lt;p&gt;Same thing with the Raspberry Pi - there are commercial devices now running or more or less stock Pi hardware with some accomodations - the power of the community is just too large - you can either spend an insane amount of time getting things working on your custom SBC, or get something well-supported for free.&lt;p&gt;I hope that the same thing will happen with the Steam Machine - the pull of the community will result in a well-supported &amp;#x27;default&amp;#x27; device where people (and Valve) will put in the effort to create a comparable desktop experience to the commercial OSes.&lt;p&gt;Valve already helped immensely with Wayland - it&amp;#x27;s crazy to think that the project was stared cca. 2008, and today there&amp;#x27;s still arguments to be made it&amp;#x27;s not mature yet - by investing the necessary energy to make sure games run well, the drivers are optimized, and there&amp;#x27;s a high-quality end-user library (wlroots) for writing compositors has been the push that Wayland needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yoz-y:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Back during Covid I bought a PC tower just to play PC games. Later I also bought a PlayStation because the couch experience is better. If the steam machine was available I’d definitely opt for that instead of both.&lt;p&gt;If steam continues the way it is, it will be hard for me to justify having a gaming PC and a console instead of just one machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hollowturtle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In two years, you’ll upgrade your M1 to an M4+: there’s the power upgrade.&lt;p&gt;Only to play almost nothing or very badly if not supported natively. And no devs won&amp;#x27;t support mac games there is no incentive. Emulation is subpar compared to Proton on Linux, Apple people should really start stop thinking macbooks can do modern gaming, excepts for a couple of Capcom portings that were paid by apple to have them and some retro gaming&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shantara:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It ultimately comes down to the price. If it’s low enough, I’ll get Steam machine as a living room indie box and for streaming from my main desktop. I would feel bad for overpaying for 8 gigs of VRAM in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phito:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s the same as the steam deck: I don&amp;#x27;t enjoy video games anymore, I&amp;#x27;ve actually never really enjoyed gaming except for a handful of titles. But I&amp;#x27;ll be damned, I love that Valve is bringing gaming to Linux and I&amp;#x27;ll buy the hardware just to support the cause. The people in my life that have been using the &amp;quot;I need Windows for my games&amp;quot; reason (or excuse ;)) to not switch to Linux are now slowly but surely leaving Windows!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Kudos to the author. I also will not buy a steam Box. But i appreciate the effect it will have on gaming and Linux. I use Mint and use steam to play my games just fine. For some games it is a little bit shaky. Game company’s now have a incentive to make gaming just feel right on a Linux machine much more than like the switch deck. Just my thinking of course&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrec:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand the &amp;quot;You can’t buy this without buying the Steam Controller.&amp;quot; bit. If you want one, great, if not, it&amp;#x27;s no more necessary than with any other PC.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been gaming for ~40 years without ever touching a controller, why would I start now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seanalltogether:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m also one of those people who does everything on my mac laptop, but hits a kvm switch to jump onto a PC to play games at night (when I have time, which I don&amp;#x27;t). At this point I&amp;#x27;ve stopped pretending that I want a PC that I can upgrade and swap out parts. I just want a little box that doesn&amp;#x27;t make any noise and works as is. Framework desktop and now this steam machine look like good options. I&amp;#x27;m a bit disappointed at the 8gb gpu though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mariopt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Steam Machines can become an existencial crisis for PlayStation and Xbox.&lt;p&gt;A “console” that I can use as a PC? I am in 100%. You’ll get the world biggest game library at a discount, this is why I sold my PlayStation after spending 200 euros and watching it becoming useless.&lt;p&gt;I also suspect a lot of game devs will optimize for steam machine and finally we’ll get a console like experience on PC.&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the “low specs” fool you, it has the same specs or better as 70% of steam users.&lt;p&gt;Given Valve gave money to a lot of open source maintainers , it’s also great for Linux.&lt;p&gt;Just take my money&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sylens:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have been trying for a long time to find a way to play my PC games from my couch without dragging my desktop into the living room.&lt;p&gt;Steam Link works okay but is still noticeable for some games. Docking a Steam Deck wasn’t powerful enough. Running a long HDMI cable isn’t feasible in my current living space. So I’m very intrigued to have this lower powered cube sit under my TV for when I just want to do some couch co-op or play something more casual to wind down at night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koolala:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I need a VR linux environment. With eye tracking letting you use a mouse without taking your hands off the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chocalot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fair reasons. I won&amp;#x27;t be getting one, because the Steam Deck is enough for me.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; It’s Steam, not Good Old Games.
Sure it can run GOG games but the Machine is primarily designed to run Steam. You avoid purchasing from Steam like the plague, yet you’re willing to buy a Machine dedicated to it? Are you crazy?&lt;p&gt;I prioritise getting games on GOG, and the Steam Deck experience with it is good.&lt;p&gt;I use Heroic Launcher to install them, and Steam mode to play it.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; You don’t have time to fiddle with configuration. Button and trackpad mappings to get the controls just right enough to play strategy games designed to be played with keyboard and mouse will only leave you frustrated.&lt;p&gt;+1. I don&amp;#x27;t bother with configuration. If a game only supports keyboard and mouse I just play it when docked.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Fuck it, I’m getting one.&lt;p&gt;Haha.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0x073:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the Steam Machine has to succeed for SteamOS on Linux to keep growing, and for the niche of the Linux desktop to become larger.&lt;p&gt;Steam has already failed at this once, and it won’t try a third time.&lt;p&gt;(And Windows is currently at its lowest point, so it’s the perfect opportunity.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;confident_inept:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been using a somewhat low-spec PC to play games and for general desktop usage. Finding stuff in this form factor, that you can guarantee will be well put together and worth the money is a rarity.&lt;p&gt;Highly likely this could replace my desktop, as I don&amp;#x27;t need something much more powerful, just with more modern hardware. I don&amp;#x27;t do much AAA gaming and nearly game in my Steam library would run on this just fine. My regular daily computing needs can reasonably be satisfied with the compute power of a Raspberry Pi. I can swap flatpak based immutable SteamOS with plain Arch without losing the advantages (i.e. custom hardware settings integration) that one might sacrifice doing so on the Steam Deck.&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a no-brainer for my next upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Read all the way to the end: &amp;quot;I’m getting one.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;So will I, if anything to support the effort, and check it out maybe I&amp;#x27;ll buy more for my kids or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sm0ke21:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t need it either. I &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; it so I&amp;#x27;m going to get it. I also don&amp;#x27;t need the controller and the VR headset. But again, I am going to get it. I am the master of my life. Whatever I say goes. I am getting all 3. But I don&amp;#x27;t need them. No, no no.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tatjam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m looking for it as a general development machine, sometimes I do stuff that requires GPUs so if they can get a competitive price wrt. building a custom PC then I&amp;#x27;m all in for the convenient form factor!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aeolun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All of this is true, but Valve is one of the best companies I know and for now, I’ll happily give them money.&lt;p&gt;It’s not about the fact that I’m actually going to use it. It’s about the fact that I want people to keep making things like this. It’s about the fact I want to reward them for not locking it down completely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943992</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is our death from a hydrogen sulfide event inevitable in climate warming? (2005)</title>
      <link>https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/global-warming-led-climatic-hydrogen-sulfide-and-permian-extinction</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These bacteria strip oxygen from the compounds and produce hydrogen sulfide. Hydrogen sulfide kills aerobic organisms. The hydrogen sulfide dispersing in the atmosphere would kill most terrestrial life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942649"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/global-warming-led-climatic-hydrogen-sulfide-and-permian-extinction'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;acetofenone:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My main concern is the acidification of the ocean due to the carbon dioxide equilibrium between the atmosphere and the sea.
There is a threshold level threshold at wich the shell of plankton just dissolves. After that happens I think the whole ocean ecosystem will collapse (maybe no more fishes?) 
Also the deep ocean has an inertia of thousands years meaning that we are going to stick with industrial coal revolution levels of co2 in the atmosphere for a lot of time even if we emit nothing.&lt;p&gt;People wasn&amp;#x27;t seeing immediate effects because it was hidden in saturating the ocean and now there&amp;#x27;s no way back in my opinion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;perihelions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Today, there are not enough organics in the oceans to go anoxic,&amp;quot; says Kump. &amp;quot;But in the Permian,&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The editorialized HN title misrepresents what the article says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OgsyedIE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(2010) should be in the title, presumably?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;metalman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;this is one of several &amp;quot;failure modes&amp;quot; connected to climate change that are bieng dissmissed out of hand
and in spite of all the blither blather about humans determining our own future as seperate from anything as trivial as the &amp;quot;weather&amp;quot;, we exist as the prime exploiter of what can be summed up as the carbohydrate production of nature, a single number of X millions of tons per anum, which our breathable atmosphere, is a byproduct of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.psu.edu/news/research/story/global-warming-led-climatic-hydrogen-sulfide-and-permian-extinction</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 04:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942649</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
