<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:35:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>I just want working RCS messaging</title>
      <link>https://wt.gd/i-just-want-my-rcs-messaging-to-work</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is what it looks like: In short, it’s probably Apple or Google and there’s zero accountability from Apple. Carriers are incompetent with this sort of interoperability and they gave up on running their own RCS servers to let Google do it through something called Google Jibe, I’ll talk about that soon. It just aims to hurt users that want some control of their device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974869"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://wt.gd/i-just-want-my-rcs-messaging-to-work'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yellowapple:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;RCS has been a royal pain for me on Android, too.  Partially my fault since I&amp;#x27;m using non-default ROMs (LineageOS on my Fairphone 4, which I then replaced with GrapheneOS on my Pixel 9a), but also mostly Google&amp;#x27;s fault for taking as janky of an approach as possible when it comes to its Messages app (which seems to be the only actively-maintained Android SMS app with RCS support, because of course it is).&lt;p&gt;The Graphene folks have at least been making progress on getting it working (my understanding is that Messages expects special permissions from Android and Play Services that GrapheneOS has to specifically whitelist without blowing massive holes in the Google Play sandbox, and without those permissions it fails to verify the phone number for certain carriers — T-Mobile included, in my case).  Hopefully whatever fix they come up with works for the long haul; it was really annoying to have RCS working fine for all of two weeks only for it to immediately start failing again when the required RCS endpoint switched from Google&amp;#x27;s Jibe instance to whatever T-Mobile is allegedly maintaining themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SamDc73:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s weird to me when Google market RCS as universal protocol when it doesn&amp;#x27;t work on Android devices without Google services.&lt;p&gt;(I use GraphenOS and couldn&amp;#x27;t make it work for the life of me)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SanjayMehta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve seen this same behaviour with IOS messaging ten years ago; I would travel between countries with roaming enabled and every time I changed countries and turned on my iPhone, iMessage would be waiting for activation.&lt;p&gt;Once spent 5 hours on the phone with an iMessage developer in Ireland helping them debug the issue.&lt;p&gt;At that time, we didn&amp;#x27;t have eSIM so I ended up with an Android phone for roaming and my iPhone for home country.&lt;p&gt;Many months later I got an update from Apple. It was something to do with activation. iOS used to send a hidden SMS to a server in the UK and sometimes while roaming it would time out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTPenis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most of my friends here in Sweden use Signal. But on the rare occasions that we had to switch back to messages lately, for example when Signal was down, I noticed RCS has been working flawlessly.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s quite the nice surprise because it&amp;#x27;s a technology you heard about years ago and now suddenly it crops up in daily life. We all gave up on it years ago too and used other IM apps like Signal, Briar or SimpleX.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebelgecko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It looks like they&amp;#x27;re using US Mobile (which resells T-Mobile as &amp;quot;Death Star&amp;quot;). IIRC US Mobile has some big gaps, I wouldn&amp;#x27;t be surprised if RCS if one of them. With their rebadged Verizon service you don&amp;#x27;t even get Visual Voicemail&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smelendez:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t fully get what he thinks the issue is and how it relates to Google Jibe (which apparently is the RCS-as-a-service platform the US carriers use).&lt;p&gt;Has Jibe somehow blacklisted his phone? In that case, Apple might technically be right — it’s a carrier issue, but with all major carriers, since he says they’re all using Jibe on the backend.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I doubt he’d sound crazy, as he puts it, to the Apple Store people making this case. They might even be sympathetic, but this is probably the best he’ll get, since Apple’s whole protocol is to get you on one centrally preauthorized track or another to having a working phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barrin92:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have sympathy with the technical and debugging plight but genuinely why are people still dealing with this, SMS&amp;#x2F;RCS is to the US what fax machines are to Japan. You can only put so much lipstick on a pig. Any bog standard IP based messenger has had none of these issues and all of the features that RCS is supposed to fix for a decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;charcircuit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why bother with Google&amp;#x27;s new, shiny chat app. Why not use WhatsApp, Signal, Telegram, Discord, etc which are more neutral apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OptionOfT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Have you tried a Visible Trial to see if RCS activates there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;par:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;i Have no idea what RCS is but i know i disabled it on my iphone because it basically always makes my phone fall back to SMS when i have even the slightest lapse in network connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wrs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was in a working RCS chat with two Android users. One of them switched to iOS and it’s been sheer chaos ever since. The conversation splits and rejoins, messages randomly choose which copy to appear in, my view is full of little daily notes that I added and removed the switcher from the conversation (of course I didn’t), old titles for the group are resurrected and then disappear…and the Mac client has a few of its own quirky ways of destroying the same chat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmitrygr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;RCS issue on iPhone, reminds me of an old movie qupte... &amp;quot;Lex, this is Detroit. You think the cops are gonna waste city-dollars on a stolen Swedish car?&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;clip.cafe&amp;#x2F;detroit-rock-city-1999&amp;#x2F;we-must-get-the-cops-in-on-volvo-situation-s1&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;clip.cafe&amp;#x2F;detroit-rock-city-1999&amp;#x2F;we-must-get-the-cop...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, if iMessage was broken, apple would surely care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oblio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had working RCS on Android.&lt;p&gt;Turns out that random people can add you to groups, send spam and from what I can see you can do nothing to prevent it. I&amp;#x27;ve disabled it.&lt;p&gt;So don&amp;#x27;t fret too much about not having it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moto7451:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My sister had an issue with RCS not working on her Samsung. It turned out she had a SIM card too old for AT&amp;amp;T to support RCS on it and some Samsung related software issues related to their SMS apps and Google’s SMS apps conflicting. A fresh SIM and a couple software tweaks netted her RCS.&lt;p&gt;I’d assume this isn’t the issue here but RCS seems to be a bit fickle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;edbaskerville:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oh man. It&amp;#x27;s not just Apple. I&amp;#x27;ve had months of RCS not working on GrapheneOS, and have no idea who to blame. The first time it stopped working, I fixed it by switching carriers (AT&amp;amp;T -&amp;gt; T-Mobile). Maybe I&amp;#x27;ll try switching back! Or maybe I&amp;#x27;ll switch back to an iPhone and give in to iMessage. :(&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;worthless-trash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; say “I have been using opensource tools to analyze the logs from this phone and think it’s a failure with Jibe”. Do you get how crazy this sounds?&lt;p&gt;No sir, this isnt crazy, the problem is that we&amp;#x27;re paying for a service that isnt accountable for their issues.&lt;p&gt;Thats crazy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wt.gd/i-just-want-my-rcs-messaging-to-work</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 01:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974869</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I made a down detector for down detector</title>
      <link>https://downdetectorsdowndetector.com</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://downdetectorsdowndetector.com</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974012</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
