<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:24:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Compiling Ruby to Machine Language</title>
      <link>https://patshaughnessy.net/2025/11/17/compiling-ruby-to-machine-language</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) YJIT Blocks While compiling your Ruby program, YJIT saves the machine language instructions it creates into YJIT blocks. Each Ruby function or block typically consists of several YJIT blocks. YJIT compiles or translates the Ruby YARV instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957629"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://patshaughnessy.net/2025/11/17/compiling-ruby-to-machine-language'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pasxizeis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Really happy to see Pat keeping it up! His Ruby under a Microscope book but also his blog posts are amazing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://patshaughnessy.net/2025/11/17/compiling-ruby-to-machine-language</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957629</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: PrinceJS – 19,200 req/s Bun framework in 2.8 kB (built by a 13yo)</title>
      <link>https://princejs.vercel.app</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://princejs.vercel.app</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957402</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: ESPectre – Motion detection based on Wi-Fi spectre analysis</title>
      <link>https://github.com/francescopace/espectre</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🛜 ESPectre 👻 Motion detection system based on Wi-Fi spectre analysis (CSI), with Home Assistant integration. 📑 Table of Contents In 3 Points Mathematical Approach What You Need Quick Start How It Works What You Can Do With It Sensor Placement Guide System Architecture FAQ Security and Privacy Technical Deep Dive Future Evolutions References Changelog License Author 🎯 In 3 Points What it does: Detects movement at home using Wi-Fi (no cameras, no microphones) What you need: A ~€10 device (ESP32-S3) + Home Assistant or MQTT server + ESP-IDF development tools Setup time: 30-45 minutes (first time, including ESP-IDF setup) 🔬 Mathematical Approach This project currently does NOT use Machine Learning models. md 🚀 Quick Start Setup time: ~30-45 minutes (first time) Difficulty: Intermediate (requires ESP-IDF setup) Setup &amp; Installation: Follow the complete guide in SETUP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45953977"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/francescopace/espectre'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting! Are you familiar with tommysense.com? I think it doing something similar? Did not yet have time to try it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;roger_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Been working on this very idea casually for couple years with ESP-IDF and I could never get the statistical signal processing just right (by my definition). Things I&amp;#x27;ve tried: adapting filtering (LMS, Kalman), kernel methods (NEWMA, MMD), detectors (CUSUM, GLR), dimensionality reduction (random projection, online PCA), whitening, etc.&lt;p&gt;I use a single ESP32 in STA&amp;#x2F;AP mode which sniffs ACK packets with a specific destination mac, which come from any server on my WiFi network (uses a special sniffing mode IIRC). This way I can receive regular CSI packets originating from a fixed location and doesn&amp;#x27;t need another device running.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll have to look at this code, maybe I just overlooked the obvious or my requirements were too high!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tetris11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Amazing stuff!&lt;p&gt;Am I right in understanding that only a single ESP32 device is needed (plus a router)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/francescopace/espectre</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45953977</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israeli-founded app preloaded on Samsung phones is attracting controversy</title>
      <link>https://www.sammobile.com/news/israeli-app-app-cloud-samsung-phones-controversy/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEST PICKS BY OUR SAMSUNG EXPERTS Best Samsung Galaxy Earbuds in 2025 Best Samsung Galaxy Phones in 2025 Best Samsung Watch in 2025 Best Samsung Galaxy Tablets in 2025 Best cheap Android phones 2025 by Samsung HOT RIGHT NOW Galaxy Z Flip 7 Galaxy Z Fold 7 Galaxy S25 Ultra Galaxy S25 Edge Galaxy A56 Galaxy A36 Galaxy Z Flip FE Galaxy Ring 2 Galaxy Watch 8 Galaxy S24 Ultra Follow us on social media Order the King of Android. Buy now Latest reviews Samsung Galaxy Watch 8 review Samsung Bespoke AI Jet Ultra review Samsung Galaxy Z Fold 7 review Samsung Galaxy Z Flip 7 review Samsung Galaxy S25 Edge review Samsung S95F OLED TV review Samsung Q7F QLED TV review: A no-brainer purchase at its low price Samsung S90F OLED TV review: Unreal value for money Samsung Galaxy S25+ review: Nails the big phone basics Follow us on social media Feel the power of Galaxy AI in the palm of your hands. Gifts from Samsung Samsung Galaxy AI vs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955424"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.sammobile.com/news/israeli-app-app-cloud-samsung-phones-controversy/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;donohoe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;…and this, and similar stories, continues to be why I will never trust or own an Android phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;naIak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Even worse is that Samsung phones, at least in my region, come with a &amp;quot;Samsung Global Goals&amp;quot; app installed by default; an app that serves to push a certain political agenda that many find unpalatable. Imagine if your new Xiaomi phone came with an app telling you how good the CCP is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why do android phone companies load up the bloatware on their phones? Why can&amp;#x27;t they provide a plain vanilla version of android and let users to choose the stuff?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baklavaEmperor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What’s striking is how often these ‘small’ surveillance tech stories trace back to the same state-aligned ecosystem. When Israel does it, it’s treated as a complex security issue. When another ‘bad’ country does the same thing, we immediately call it espionage. And almost on cue, the discussion drifts anywhere except the uncomfortable fact that it’s the same ecosystem from the same country showing up again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thehoneybadger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty disappointed with Hacker News allowing bigotry onto its platform. I&amp;#x27;ve been here for over a decade. Count me out. Enjoy mixing politics onto your platform. The mind virus has truly spread far and wide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coffeecoders:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I bought an Ipad yesterday. The setup was almost the same, except all the bloat was from Apple itself. Numbers, GarageBand, iMovie, Keynote, Pages, Clips… even the Tips app felt like bloatware.&lt;p&gt;Wild how every ecosystem has its own &amp;quot;preloaded surprise pack.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rs186:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AppCloud is not only in India. It is on some OEM version of the phone in the US as well.&lt;p&gt;How did I know? My phone had random notifications promoting apps that I had never heard of, and I couldn&amp;#x27;t find a way to disable them. Eventually I found and removed it via adb.&lt;p&gt;These scumbags.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;SpyApps everywhere.&lt;p&gt;Hopefully one day we not only have open software, open hardware but also reproducibly guaranteed secure systems. Now I don&amp;#x27;t have any idea how this could be verified (and no, Microsoft&amp;#x27;s &amp;quot;Trusted Computing&amp;quot; is not what I have in mind), but I hope we&amp;#x27;ll see to this eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hyghjiyhu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Edited. This seems to be according worldwide despite the article saying it&amp;#x27;s in West Asia and Africa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hersko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So a Unity owned bloatware company being used by Samsung is now somehow controversial because it was founded in Israel? Am i reading this right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;duxup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I recently bought a cheap android device because I needed to test something on Android.   The setup was about 3 hours of the device starting up, asking me questions, installing apps I explicitly told it not to, and then all sorts of other apps and OS updates trying to do their thing seemingly at once.   I wasn&amp;#x27;t even transferring data, just a brand new phone, new google account.&lt;p&gt;What a horrible experience you get with some providers and phones.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s to the point that I think there should be some sort of regulation that involves you getting a baseline experience on the OS rather than a bunch of malware out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sammobile.com/news/israeli-app-app-cloud-samsung-phones-controversy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955424</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aldous Huxley predicts Adderall and champions alternative therapies</title>
      <link>https://angadh.com/inkhaven-7</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some fairly well known means for self-actualisation that Huxley discusses are Alexander technique and Gestalt therapy. It proposes an ideal and provides means whereby that ideal can be realised. Aldous Huxley paraphrasing John Dewey While this is mentioned much later in his lecture, a Huxley-like figure today might need to lead their lecture with this part to convey the import and validity of such approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954140"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://angadh.com/inkhaven-7'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;earlyriser:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I read champignons and it kind of fit even better. Adderall (Brave New World) and mushrooms (Island).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gnatman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Substituted amphetamines were already very popular in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://angadh.com/inkhaven-7</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954140</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EEG-based neurofeedback in athletes and non-athletes</title>
      <link>https://www.mdpi.com/2306-5354/12/11/1202</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;org Google Scholar 1,*, Darshika Thejani BulathwattaDarshika Thejani Bulathwatta SciProfiles Scilit Preprints. org Google Scholar 2, Ilona Bidzan-BlumaIlona Bidzan-Bluma SciProfiles Scilit Preprints. org Google Scholar 1 and João Mendonça CorreiaJoão Mendonça Correia SciProfiles Scilit Preprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955921"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.mdpi.com/2306-5354/12/11/1202'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lapsa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;more or less same crap is achieved via radiomyography from your local telecom towers. down to deciphering your inner monologue&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.mdpi.com/2306-5354/12/11/1202</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955921</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Building WebSocket in Apache Iggy with Io_uring and Completion Based IO</title>
      <link>https://iggy.apache.org/blogs/2025/11/17/websocket-io-uring/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;However, it also presents different challenges when integrating with the wider Rust ecosystem. They expect shared buffers and readiness-based I/O, fundamentally incompatible with compio's completion-based model that requires owned buffers. We need an adapter that: Works with compio's owned-buffer async I/O Presents synchronous Read/Write traits to tungstenite Efficiently bridges sync and async world Challenge with Tungstenite Tungstenite is the de-facto Rust WebSocket protocol implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956111"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://iggy.apache.org/blogs/2025/11/17/websocket-io-uring/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jauntywundrkind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fun write-up. Good stuff, very nice contribution to to compio of compio-ws. Looks like the Iggy switched to thread-per-core compio back in July.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;apache&amp;#x2F;iggy&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;1960" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;apache&amp;#x2F;iggy&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;1960&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I saw mentioned in the 0.5.0 release notes (which happened shortly after migrating to compio): trying to switch to a Sans-IO model design (but maybe just for clients?). It feels like there&amp;#x27;s similar ownership concerns that might arise, as seen here with the poll-vs-completion challenges faced here. A lot of good learnings to be had, as we go forth to faster better io, eager to keep tuning in &amp;amp; hearing more. Thanks for the write up!
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;iggy.apache.org&amp;#x2F;blogs&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;release-0.5.0&amp;#x2F;#whats-next" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;iggy.apache.org&amp;#x2F;blogs&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;release-0.5.0&amp;#x2F;#what...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.firezone.dev&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;sans-io"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.firezone.dev&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;sans-io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swiftcoder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Having worked on a number of message brokers, but not really fucked with append-only log streams, what&amp;#x27;s the actually selling point here?&lt;p&gt;Feels like the simplicity wins are made by only solving one half of the problem space (only writes), and it introduces new problems of its own (like how do we truncate the append-only log once readers are done with it?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://iggy.apache.org/blogs/2025/11/17/websocket-io-uring/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956111</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DESI's Dizzying Results</title>
      <link>https://www.universetoday.com/articles/desis-dizzying-results</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a galaxy survey, and to accomplish this survey they have 5,000 robotically controlled fiber optic cables underneath the telescope. Like any dense material, there were sound waves – waves of pressure that crisscrossed the universe. They stuck around, and slowly slowly slowly over billions of years more matter accumulated on those shells than the surrounding regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955904"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.universetoday.com/articles/desis-dizzying-results'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swiftcoder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; They’re aiming for 50 million galaxies once the survey is complete... Sure, the DESI survey is less than 1% of all the galaxies in the observable volume of the cosmos&lt;p&gt;That just broke my brain. Had to look it up. 2+ trillion galaxies in the observable universe? That puts things in perspective all right&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.universetoday.com/articles/desis-dizzying-results</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955904</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
