<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>AMD GPUs Go Brrr</title>
      <link>https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-amd-brr</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We show the MI355X memory hierarchy below. SpecNVIDIA B200 SXM5AMD MI355X OAMBF16 matrix / tensor2. Scheduling within processors: We need to rely on our register file and small matrix core instructions instead of shared memory and bulky wgmma/tcgen05 instructions to establish deep pipelines and hide memory costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934416"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-amd-brr'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alex1138:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not my favorite internet meme but I&amp;#x27;m tickled to see &amp;quot;go brr&amp;quot; on a website&amp;#x2F;university like Stanford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;homarp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;see &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45923188"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45923188&lt;/a&gt; for HipKittens discussion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-amd-brr</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934416</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I can't recommend Grafana anymore</title>
      <link>https://henrikgerdes.me/blog/2025-11-grafana-mess/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;yaml with Loki, Prometheus and Grafana. On the same day they deprecated the Grafana Agent, they announced Grafana Alloy. Grafana just released Mim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934940"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://henrikgerdes.me/blog/2025-11-grafana-mess/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mgedde:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s the most promising alternative to Prometheus&amp;#x2F;Grafana if you&amp;#x27;re developing a new solution around OTEL? If you could start today and pick tools, what would you go for?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tamnd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Signoz is good, and active development &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;SigNoz&amp;#x2F;signoz" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;SigNoz&amp;#x2F;signoz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;morganherlocker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I frequently use a docker-compose template with prometheus pushgateway + grafana for deploying on single node servers, as described at the start of the article. It works well and is trivial to setup, but the complexity explodes once your metric volume or cardinality requires more scale like prometheus alternatives a la mimir.&lt;p&gt;I think this would not need to be an issue as frequently if prometheus had a more efficient publish&amp;#x2F;scraping mechanism. iirc there was once a protobuf metric format that was dropped, and now there is just the text format. While it wouldn&amp;#x27;t handle billions of unique labels like mimir, a compact binary metric format could certainly allow for millions at reasonable resolution instead of wasting all that scale potential on repeated name strings. I should be able to push or expose a bulk blob all at once with ordered labels or at least raw int keys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Szpadel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;what are tested and fairly lightweight alternatives for Loki?&lt;p&gt;elastic stack is so heavy it&amp;#x27;s out of question for smaller clusters, loki integration with grafana is nice to have but separate capable dashboard would be also fine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zer00eyz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;FTA &amp;gt; &amp;quot;I know for a fact that that pace is partially driven by career-driven development.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t a Grafana problem, this is an industry wide problem. Resume driven product design, resume driven engineering, resume driven marketing. DO your 2-3 years, pump out something big to inflate your resume. Apply elsewhere to get the pay bump that almost no company is handing out. After the departures there is no one left who knows the system and the next people in want to replace the things they don&amp;#x27;t understand to pad their resume for the next job.&lt;p&gt;Wash, rinse, repete.&lt;p&gt;Loyalty, simply goes unrewarded in a lot of places in our industry (and at a many corporations). And the people who do stay... in many cases they turn into furniture that ends up holding potential good evolution back. They loose out to the technological magpies the bring shiny things to management because it will &amp;quot;move the needle&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Sadly this is just one facet of the problems we are facing, from how we interview to how we run (or rent) our infrastructure things have gotten rather silly...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seymon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;But are there good alternatives to grafana in the foss space nowadays?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gtrealejandro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone who runs SaaS products, this post resonates painfully well.&lt;p&gt;The author is 100% correct: Monitoring should be the most boring tool in the stack. Its one and only job is to be more reliable than the thing it&amp;#x27;s monitoring.&lt;p&gt;The moment your monitoring stack requires a complex dependency like Kafka, or changes its entire agent flow every 18 months, it has failed its primary purpose. It has become the problem.&lt;p&gt;This sounds less like a technical evolution and more like the classic VC-funded push to get everyone onto a high-margin cloud product, even at the cost of the open-source soul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stym06:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;off topic, but prometheus pushgateway is such a bad implementation (once you push the metrics, it always stays there until it&amp;#x27;s restarted, like counter does not increase, it just pushes a new metric with the new value) that we had to write our own metrics collector endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stym06:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;But I got it all working; now I can finally stop explaining to my boss why we need to re-structure the monitoring stack every year.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Prometheus and Grafana have been progressing in their own ways and each of them is trying to have a fullstack solution and then the OTEL thingy came and ruined the party for everyone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;datadrivenangel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Building an elaborate pile of technical debt is a great way to have an elaborate pile of technical debt, but the lifespan of services being 2-3 years gets painful as you start composing a stack out of enough products that every quarter you need to replace something big.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nacozarina:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like grafana needed to fork&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YZF:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not sure what&amp;#x27;s an alternative for Grafana in the open source world in terms of building dashboards for o11y? I&amp;#x27;m not aware of one and Grafana is used very extensively in my company...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BarryMilo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is pretty interesting to me, as I do use Grafana in my current role. But none of their other products, and not their helm chart (we&amp;#x27;re on the Bitnami chart if that&amp;#x27;s a thing).&lt;p&gt;So far it&amp;#x27;s pretty good. We&amp;#x27;re at least one major version behind, but hey everything still works.&lt;p&gt;I cannot imagine other products support as many data sources (though I&amp;#x27;m starting to think they all suck, I just dump what I can in InfluxDB).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eduction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I find the color of the text so light as to be unreadable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://henrikgerdes.me/blog/2025-11-grafana-mess/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 03:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934940</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawmakers want to ban VPNs and have no idea what they're doing</title>
      <link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/lawmakers-want-ban-vpns-and-they-have-no-idea-what-theyre-doing</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses run on VPNs. Students need VPNs for school. Domestic abuse survivors use VPNs to hide their location from their abusers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924483"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/lawmakers-want-ban-vpns-and-they-have-no-idea-what-theyre-doing'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 20 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;etchalon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Couldn&amp;#x27;t all of this be handled by META tags, request&amp;#x2F;response headers and some &amp;quot;they&amp;#x27;ll obviously do it&amp;quot; laws aimed at operating systems, device manufacturers and browser companies?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1vuio0pswjnm7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Here&amp;#x27;s what happens if VPNs get blocked: everyone has to verify their age by submitting government IDs, biometric data, or credit card information directly to websites-without any encryption or privacy protection.&lt;p&gt;We already know how this story ends. Companies get hacked. Data gets breached. And suddenly your real name is attached to the websites you visited, stored in some poorly-secured database waiting for the inevitable leak. This has already happened, and is not a matter of if but when. And when it does, the repercussions will be huge.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Then&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Let&amp;#x27;s say Wisconsin somehow manages to pass this law. Here&amp;#x27;s what will actually happen:&lt;p&gt;People who want to bypass it will use non-commercial VPNs, open proxies, or cheap virtual private servers that the law doesn&amp;#x27;t cover. They&amp;#x27;ll find workarounds within hours. The internet always routes around censorship.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Even in a fantasy world where every website successfully blocked all commercial VPNs, people would just make their own. You can route traffic through cloud services like AWS or DigitalOcean, tunnel through someone else&amp;#x27;s home internet connection, use open proxies, or spin up a cheap server for less than a dollar.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;EFF presents two versions of &amp;quot;here&amp;#x27;s what will happen&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If we accept both as true then it appears a law targeting commercial VPNs would create evolutionary pressure to DIY rather than delegate VPN facility to commercial third parties.  Non-commercial first party VPNs only service the person who sets them up.  If that person is engaged in criminal activity, they can be targeted by legislation and enforcement specifically. Prosecution of criminals should not affect other first party VPNs set up by law-abiding internet users&lt;p&gt;Delegation of running VPNs to commercial third parties carries risks.  Aside from obvious &amp;quot;trust&amp;quot; issues, reliability concerns, mandatory data collection, potential data breach, and so on, when the commercial provider services criminals, that&amp;#x27;s a risk to everyone else using the service&lt;p&gt;This is what&amp;#x27;s going on with so-called &amp;quot;Chat Control&amp;quot;.  Commercial third parties are knowingly servicing criminals.  The service is used to facilitate the crime. The third parties will not or cannot identify the criminals. As a result, governments seek to compel the third party to do so through legislation. Every other user of the service may be affected as a result&lt;p&gt;Compare this with a first party VPN set up and used by a single person.  If that person engages in criminal activity, other first party VPNs are unaffected&lt;p&gt;EFF does not speculate that third parties such AWS, DigitalOcean, or &amp;quot;cheap server[s] for less than a dollar&amp;quot; will be targeted with legislation in their second &amp;quot;here&amp;#x27;s what will happen&amp;quot; scenario&lt;p&gt;Evolutionary pressure toward DIY might be bad news for commercial third party intermediaries^1&lt;p&gt;But not necessarily for DIY internet users&lt;p&gt;1.  Those third parties that profit from non-DIY users may invoke the plight of those non-DIY users^2 when arguing against VPN legislation or &amp;quot;Chat Control&amp;quot; but it&amp;#x27;s the third parties that stand to lose the most.  DIY users are not subject to legislation that targets third party VPNs or third party chat services&lt;p&gt;2. Like OpenAI invoking the plight of ChapGPT users when faced with discovery demands in copyright litigation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rileymat2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Here&amp;#x27;s what happens if VPNs get blocked: everyone has to verify their age by submitting government IDs, biometric data, or credit card information directly to websites—without any encryption or privacy protection.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Can someone explain how this is true? Even if there is not a VPN, there should be https encryption and privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crontab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been thinking a lot about VPNs lately, mainly for 2 reasons:&lt;p&gt;1) In my home state I can no longer access Pornhub&lt;p&gt;2) Last month I visited Mississippi and could not access BlueSky, even though I can from my home state.&lt;p&gt;[I personally blame this on the &amp;quot;holier then thou&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;don&amp;#x27;t tread of me&amp;quot; conservatives who cannot resist the urge to try to rule over the activities of others.]&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#x27;t selected a VPN provider because I have heard that a lot of websites create barriers to people who use VPNs. For example, I&amp;#x27;ve seen people say that couldn&amp;#x27;t access Reddit via a VPN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dpoloncsak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder if all of the journalism on Epstein would be considered &amp;quot;Sexual content&amp;quot; and if journalists would be forced to self-doxx to report in these states&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;txrx0000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A device-side IP filter locked behind a password that parents can configure in the device&amp;#x27;s settings would be much more effective and easier to implement than censoring the Internet. This should be the default solution, yet it&amp;#x27;s never brought up for whatever reason.&lt;p&gt;Not to mention these online content censorship laws for kids are wrong in principle because parents are supposed to be in control of how they raise each of their own kids, not the government or other people.&lt;p&gt;And these laws make authoritarian surveillance and control much easier. It&amp;#x27;s hard to not see this as the main objective at this point. And even if it isn&amp;#x27;t, this level of stupidity is harmful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skeledrew:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And cue the rise of self-hosted VPNs. 1 click to get a VPS instance, install VPN software, and make a connection. Automatically destroy the instance with another click or after a certain amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throw7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wisconsin &amp;quot;porn&amp;quot; websites will just move out of Wisconsin.&lt;p&gt;The bill reads like you would think from someone who&amp;#x27;s been talking with the ceo of an age verification company.  The bill gives the website two options: use a _commercial_ age verification product tied to gov&amp;#x27;t id checking, or &amp;quot;digitize&amp;quot; the web user&amp;#x27;s gov&amp;#x27;t id.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pona-a:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone born in a post‑Soviet country with rather many odd digital laws--including one requiring that any use of encryption be registered with the department of commerce and the secret service (meaning no TLS unless you get a permit)--I can clearly see the endgame of similar proposals.&lt;p&gt;These laws aren’t meant to be followed. Their text is deliberately vague, and their demands are impossible by design. They aren&amp;#x27;t foolish, or at least their ignorance isn&amp;#x27;t needed to explain the system&amp;#x27;s broader function. They are meant to serve as a Chekhov&amp;#x27;s gun that may or may not fire over your head, depending solely on whether the people holding it decide like you.&lt;p&gt;In peaceful times, they fade into the background, surfacing only when it’s convenient to blackmail some company for cash or favors. In times of crisis, they declare a never-ending war on extremism, sin, and treason, fought against an inexhaustible supply of targets to take down in front of their higher‑ups, farming promotions, contracts for DPI software, and jobs updating its filters.&lt;p&gt;Historically, such controls were limited by the motivation and competence of the arms dealers, usually taking the form of DNS or IP blocks easily bypassed with proxies. With modern DPI, it&amp;#x27;s entire protocols going dark. Even so, those able to learn easily find a way around them. The people who suffer most are seniors, unable even to call family across the border without a neighbor&amp;#x27;s help, and their relatives forced into using least trustworthy messengers (such as Botim, from the creators of ToTok, a known UAE intel operation [0]) thinking they&amp;#x27;re the only way to stay in touch, not knowing how or wanting to use mainstream IM over a VPNs that may or may not live another month.&lt;p&gt;If wherever you are your votes still matter, please fight this nonsense. Make no mistake, your enemies are still more ridiculous than Voltaire could hope they&amp;#x27;d be, but organizing against or simply living through a regime constantly chewing on the internet&amp;#x27;s wires is going to be a significantly greater inconvenience than taking _real_ action now.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;ToTok" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;ToTok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TZubiri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;Businesses run on VPNs. Every company with remote employees uses VPNs. Every business traveler connecting through sketchy hotel Wi-Fi needs one. Companies use VPNs to protect client and employee data, secure internal communications, and prevent cyberattacks.&lt;p&gt;Oh look, someone&amp;#x27;s conflating business VPNs and consumer VPNs again. This time to legitimize consumer VPNs.&lt;p&gt;The cited laws propose to ban pornography for minors, and ban VPNs that hide geolocation and their use in accessing pornography. Nothing to do with businesses using private VPNs to encrypt employee traffic.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Vulnerable people rely on VPNs for safety. Domestic abuse survivors use VPNs to hide their location from their abusers.&lt;p&gt;Woah, maybe VPNs have some uses I haven&amp;#x27;t considered, let&amp;#x27;s take a look at the linked article.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Use a virtual private network (VPN) to remain anonymous while browsing the internet, signing a new lease or applying for a new home loan. This will also keep your location anonymous from anyone who has gained access to or infiltrated your device.&lt;p&gt;I think the loan thing is rubbish I don&amp;#x27;t get it, and it&amp;#x27;s unaffected by the law. But the idea of installing a VPN in case the device is compromised might make sense, if the device is compromised it might still be trackable, especially while downloading the VPN, but maybe if it connects at startup, and the RAT isn&amp;#x27;t configured to bypass the VPN bridge, it might work.&lt;p&gt;Quite a stretch if you ask me. And again, not relevant to adult sites blocking VPNs.&lt;p&gt;The rest of the example are the usual &amp;quot;people use it to evade the government and regulations but it can be THE BAD GOVERNMENt AND REGULAtiONS&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ManuelKiessling:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, let’s be honest — &lt;i&gt;users&lt;/i&gt; of VPNs regularly don’t know what they are doing, too.&lt;p&gt;Can’t count how often I‘ve heard otherwise technologically literate people saying how they use a VPN (NordVPN e.a.) because „something something security“.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cornonthecobra:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m reminded of efforts in the 1990s to ban strong encryption in email and websites because governments tried to tell us it was used by drug dealers and pedos to do their nefarious activities.&lt;p&gt;Yes, governments really did want to force us to use HTTPS with only broken&amp;#x2F;weak crypto.&lt;p&gt;Same propaganda, different buzzwords.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TZubiri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;So when Wisconsin demands that websites &amp;quot;block VPN users from Wisconsin,&amp;quot; they&amp;#x27;re asking for something that&amp;#x27;s technically impossible. Websites have no way to tell if a VPN connection is coming from Milwaukee, Michigan, or Mumbai. The technology just doesn&amp;#x27;t work that way.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;Pr4v725LPOE?si=ih3gfTSpiHumtrFs&amp;amp;t=79" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;Pr4v725LPOE?si=ih3gfTSpiHumtrFs&amp;amp;t=79&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;That&amp;#x27;s not how apps work&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Then make it work you think we are stupid but we are not, we know&amp;quot; VPNs have something to do with IPs which are necessarily geolocatable , and also users need to make an account to connect to a VPN, you can just ask them what country and State they are in.&lt;p&gt;Being willfully obtuse draws no sympathy, and will not exclude companies from compliance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tamimio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;20 years ago the boogeyman was &amp;quot;the terrorists!&amp;quot; And now the boogeyman is &amp;quot;not the children!!&amp;quot; Or &amp;quot;immigrants!!&amp;quot; Depending on your audience&amp;#x27;s political views, but the ultimate goal is more surveillance, more control and more power abuse by who’s in control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;conartist6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t it Wisconsin law that lets the Governor change any numeric digits in a law while it&amp;#x27;s on his or her desk?&lt;p&gt;One of the most bizarre legal opinions I&amp;#x27;ve ever heard of, but if they used any digits in the writing of the law those are up for grabs. Law makes a 30 day window or something? The governor can just change it to a million days with a stroke of the pen and then sign the edit into law with the same pen!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codedokode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s funny how democratic countries copy whatever laws authoritarian regimes passed, but with a 5-year lag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;create-username:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why ban VPNs when you can freely force social networks like HN to tie nickname registration to an state issued digital ID certificate to guarantee freedom of speech and legal accountability?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;old.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;XGramatikInsights&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1ovd88s&amp;#x2F;spanish_pm_pedro_s%C3%A1nchez_demands_the_end_of&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;old.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;XGramatikInsights&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1ovd88s&amp;#x2F;...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjc50:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Republican&lt;/i&gt; lawmakers, in this case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Havoc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Stuff like this really reminds me how nobody is actually in control. Entire countries are just going where ever the rivers takes them with those supposed in charge not knowing any better and often worse than the rest and functionally being so clueless they’re passengers too&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ktallett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Lawmakers in general have less than one percent knowledge on what they make laws on. I look forward to them all logging in remotely after the ban.&lt;p&gt;The key change is needed with things such as meshtastic and lora. Taking things out of the hands of regulators is key&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/lawmakers-want-ban-vpns-and-they-have-no-idea-what-theyre-doing</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924483</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over-reliance on English hinders cognitive science</title>
      <link>https://www.cell.com/trends/cognitive-sciences/fulltext/S1364-6613(22)00236-4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cell.com/trends/cognitive-sciences/fulltext/S1364-6613(22)00236-4</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934683</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
