<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:43:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 for developers: New reasoning, agentic capabilities</title>
      <link>https://blog.google/technology/developers/gemini-3-developers/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Pro scores 54. Google AntigravityTo advance how the model and IDE work together, we’re introducing Google Antigravity to showcase what’s possible with Gemini 3. Additionally, Gemini hosted tools Grounding with Google Search and URL context can now be combined with structured outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968043"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.google/technology/developers/gemini-3-developers/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 27 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DanMcInerney:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A 50% increase over ChatGPT 5.1 on ARC-AGI2 is astonishing. If that&amp;#x27;s true and representative (a big if), it lends credence to this being the first of the very consistent agentically-inclined models because it&amp;#x27;s able to follow a deep tree of reasoning to solve problems accurately. I&amp;#x27;ve been building agents for a while and thus far have had to add many many explicit instructions and hardcoded functions to help guide the agents in how to complete simple tasks to achieve 85-90% consistency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jennyholzer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; benchmarks are and have consistently been lies and misinformation. Gemini is dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jennyholzer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;boooooooooooooo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catigula:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The problem with experiencing LLM releases nowadays is that it is no longer trivial to understand the differences in their vast intelligences so it takes awhile to really get a handle on what&amp;#x27;s even going on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SXX:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Static Pelican is boring. First attempt:&lt;p&gt;Generate SVG animation of following:
1 - There is High fantasy mage tower with a top window a dome
2 - Green goblin come in front of tower with a torch
3 - Grumpy old mage with beard appear in a tower window in high purple hat
4 - Mage sends fireball that burns goblin and all screen is covered in fire.&lt;p&gt;Camera view must be from behind of goblin back so we basically look at tower in front of us:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;codepen.io&amp;#x2F;Runway&amp;#x2F;pen&amp;#x2F;WbwOXRO" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;codepen.io&amp;#x2F;Runway&amp;#x2F;pen&amp;#x2F;WbwOXRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aerhardt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Combining structured outputs with search is the API feature I was looking for. Honestly crazy that it wasn’t there to start with - I have a project that is mostly Gemini API but I’ve had to mix in GPT-5 just for this feature.&lt;p&gt;I still use ChatGPT and Codex as a user but in the API project I’ve been working on Gemini 2.5 Pro absolutely crushed GPT-5 in the accuracy benchmarks I ran.&lt;p&gt;As it stands Gemini is my de facto standard for API work and I’ll be following very closely the performance of 3.0 in coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dudeinhawaii:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Gemini has been so far behind agentically it&amp;#x27;s comical. I&amp;#x27;ll be giving it a shot but it has a herculean task ahead of itself. It has to not only be &amp;quot;good enough&amp;quot; but a &amp;quot;quantum leap forward&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;That said, OpenAI was in the same place earlier in the year and very quickly became the top agentic platform with GPT-5-Codex.&lt;p&gt;The AI crowd is surprisingly not sticky. Coders quickly move to whatever the best model is.&lt;p&gt;Excited to see Gemini making a leap here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eknkc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks like it is already available on VSCode Copilot. Just tried a prompt that was not returning anything good on Sonnet 4.5. (Did not spend much time though, but the prompth was already there on the chat screen so I switched the model and sent it again)&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 worked much better and I actually committed the changes that it created. I don&amp;#x27;t mean its revolutionary or anything but it provided a nice summary of my request and created a decent simple solution. Sonnet had created a bunch of overarching changes that I would not even bother reviewing. Seems nice. Will probably use it for 2 weeks until someone else releases a 1.0001x better model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syedshahmir7214:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think from last few releases of these models from all companies, I have not observed much improvements in the response of these models. Their claims and launches are a little over hyped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pgroves:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was hoping Bash would go away or get replaced at some point. It&amp;#x27;s starting to look like it&amp;#x27;s going to be another 20 years of Bash but with AI doodads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vivzkestrel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;has anyone managed to use any of the AI models to build a complete 3D fps game using web GL or open GL?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bityard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Whether you’re an experienced developer or a vibe coder&lt;p&gt;I absolutely LOVE that Google themselves drew a sharp distinction here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m3kw9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If it ain&amp;#x27;t quantum leap, new models are just &amp;quot;OS updates&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alach11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a really impressive release. It&amp;#x27;s probably the biggest lead we&amp;#x27;ve seen from a model since the release of GPT-4. Seems likely that OpenAI rushed out GPT-5.1 to beat the Gemini 3 release, knowing that their model would underperform it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;icapybara:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone know how Gemini CLI with this model compares to Codex and Claude Code?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slackerIII:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s the easiest way to set up automatic code review for PRs for my team on GitHub using this model?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clusterhacks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish I could just pay for the model and self-host on local&amp;#x2F;rented hardware. I&amp;#x27;m incredibly suspicious of companies totally trying to capture us with these tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hubraumhugo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No gemini-3-flash yet, right? Any ETA on that mentioned? 2.5-flash has been amazing in terms of cost&amp;#x2F;value ratio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dankobgd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;every day, new game changer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jordanpg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is Gemini 3 under the hood?  Is it still just a basic LLM based on transformers?  Or are there all kinds of other ML technologies bolted on now?  I feel like I&amp;#x27;ve lost the plot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deanc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The AntiGravity seems to be a bit overwhelmed. Unable to set up an account at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mccoyb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I truly do not understand what plan to use so I can use this model for longer than ~2 minutes.&lt;p&gt;Using Anthropic or OpenAI&amp;#x27;s models are incredibly straightforward -- pay us per month, here&amp;#x27;s the button you press, great.&lt;p&gt;Where do I go for this for these Google models?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fosterfriends:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Gemini 3 and 3 pro are good bit cheaper than Sonnet 4.5 as well. Big fan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;srameshc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think I am in this AI fatigue phase. I am past all hype with models, tools and agents and back to problem and solution approach, sometimes code gen with AI , sometimes think and ask for a piece of code. But not offloading to AI and buying all the bs, waiting it to do magic with my codebase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ponyous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just generated a bunch of 3D CAD models using Gemini 3.0 to see how it compares in spatial understanding and it&amp;#x27;s heaps better than anything currently out there - not only intelligence but also speed.&lt;p&gt;Will run extended benchmarks later, let me know if you want to see actual data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aliljet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Understanding precisely why Gemini 3 isn&amp;#x27;t front of the pack on SWE Bench is really what I was hoping to understand here. Especially for a blog post targeted at software developers...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wohoef:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Curious to see it in action. Gemini 2.5 has already been very impressive as a study buddy for courses like set theory, information theory, and automata.
Although I’m always a bit skeptical of these benchmarks. Seems quite unlikely that all of the questions remain out of their training data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.google/technology/developers/gemini-3-developers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968043</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pebble, Rebble, and a Path Forward</title>
      <link>https://ericmigi.com/blog/pebble-rebble-and-a-path-forward/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rebble is a non-profit organization that has supported the Pebble community since 2017. 20/user/month to support Rebble services. Rebble believes that they ‘100%’ own the data of the Pebble Appstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969250"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ericmigi.com/blog/pebble-rebble-and-a-path-forward/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jamesbelchamber:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What an entirely avoidable lose-lose bust-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;micromacrofoot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why is Rebble so set on protecting this code that would have an incredibly limited shelf life if not for the new Pebble devices? It seems like an incredibly short-sighted fight against someone who (legally) owes them 0 unless they can substantiate the allegation that Pebble stole their code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John-Tony:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good write‑up. Eric Migicovsky’s “Pebble, Rebble, and a Path Forward” lays out a hopeful but tense reboot: the Pebble OS is now open‑source, new devices are in the works, but there’s a growing rift with the Rebble community over data ownership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xyzzy_plugh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I view this entire thing through an extremely simple, reductive lens:&lt;p&gt;Rebble effectively had free reign on this ecosystem for years, and could have at any time decided to try and capitalize on it further. They still can! But instead they&amp;#x27;re apparently interested in rent seeking while Core makes real headway.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s clear that Eric and Core want to make something now. It&amp;#x27;s not clear what Rebble wants, but it&amp;#x27;s clear they are feeling left out. That obviously sucks but it&amp;#x27;s clear from what both sides are saying that Core has been trying to involve Rebble in their efforts. That&amp;#x27;s certainly noble and I&amp;#x27;m not sure others would do the same.&lt;p&gt;Would Eric be able to do this all without Rebble? Lots of commenters have been saying &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; but I&amp;#x27;m skeptic. I was an early Pebble user. I stopped using it before they went bust, and while I was aware of Rebble, there was nothing compelling there for me. It&amp;#x27;s neat that they have maintained a copy of the original watchfaces but beyond that I don&amp;#x27;t perceive a ton of value. I don&amp;#x27;t like the subscription fee. I&amp;#x27;m sad they never took a serious crack at making a Rebble watch.&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone finds a way forward, together, but I&amp;#x27;m not optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pokoleo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Summarizing the dispute, for anyone interested:&lt;p&gt;Rebble&amp;#x27;s &amp;quot;one red line&amp;quot; is &amp;quot;there has to be a future for Rebble in there.&amp;quot; They fear being replaced&amp;#x2F;made irrelevant after Core builds their own infrastructure using Rebble&amp;#x27;s work. They want guarantees that if they give Core access to the app store data, Core won&amp;#x27;t build a proprietary&amp;#x2F;walled garden that cuts Rebble out. There&amp;#x27;s also emphasis on &amp;quot;our work,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;we built this,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;we spent hundreds of thousands of dollars.&amp;quot; They feel Eric isn&amp;#x27;t acknowledging where his infrastructure came from.&lt;p&gt;Core Devices&amp;#x27; thing is explicitly stating concern about relying on a third party (Rebble) for &amp;quot;critical services&amp;quot; his customers depend on. If &amp;quot;Rebble leadership changes their mind,&amp;quot; they can&amp;#x27;t guarantee customer experience. They wants the app store archive to be &amp;quot;freely available&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;not controlled by one organization.&amp;quot; They don&amp;#x27;t want to need &amp;quot;permission from Rebble&amp;quot; before building features (like free weather, voice-to-text) that might compete with Rebble&amp;#x27;s paid services. The fundamental fear seems to be business risk: being at the mercy of a nonprofit&amp;#x27;s decisions when his company has customers and obligations.&lt;p&gt;Neither side seems to trust the other&amp;#x27;s long-term intentions, creating an impasse where both feel existentially threatened by the other&amp;#x27;s preferred arrangement.&lt;p&gt;My take: I bought a watch in 2014. After the pebble 2 duo black fiasco (they ran out of stock, offered a white instead which I accepted 2 weeks ago, never shipped, and have ghosted my emails asking for shipping timelines.) I had high hopes, but given the messy interaction with the OSS world I&amp;#x27;m considering cancelling my order for the duo and time two.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoredPositron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Now I am glad I didn&amp;#x27;t order a new one. Drama everywhere nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bigstrat2003:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a pretty predictable response. The problem is, this is a classic &amp;quot;he said, she said&amp;quot; situation. So it&amp;#x27;s pretty tough to tell whom you should believe, unless you are close enough to the situation to see it first-hand. Clearly someone is not playing nice, but it&amp;#x27;s not clear which party that is. Sucks for the user community though, either way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dewey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The mentioned blog post (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rebble.io&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;17&amp;#x2F;core-devices-keeps-stealing-our-work.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rebble.io&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;17&amp;#x2F;core-devices-keeps-stealing-our...&lt;/a&gt;) is a pretty great example why using Discord as your main communication tool for an open source project is the wrong choice. The only way to read about the decisions (&amp;quot;Shortly after, Core forked PebbleOS1 away from public maintainership. Back in June, they said that they would merge back periodically2;&amp;quot;) is to read the manual transcript they added to the blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not_your_vase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a followup on &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45960893"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45960893&lt;/a&gt; from a few hours ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ericmigi.com/blog/pebble-rebble-and-a-path-forward/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969250</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day at Hetzner Online in the Falkenstein Data Center</title>
      <link>https://www.igorslab.de/en/a-day-at-hetzner-online-in-the-falkenstein-data-center-insights-into-server-technology-cooling-production-rma-and-sustainability/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This segment shows particularly clearly that Hetzner deliberately relies on functional design and regional suppliers. Anyone interested in infrastructure, technology and data center processes will gain an in-depth insight that goes far beyond what you would expect from the outside. Falkenstein is not an anonymous data location, but a highly organized interplay of production, service, operation and security that is rarely seen in this form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968235"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.igorslab.de/en/a-day-at-hetzner-online-in-the-falkenstein-data-center-insights-into-server-technology-cooling-production-rma-and-sustainability/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John-Tony:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great piece — the day-in-tour of Hetzner’s Falkenstein data center shows how efficient, green, and well-engineered their operations are, with clever free‑cooling, strong security, and very low energy waste.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noir_lord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Had a server in that DC for a few years until recently (no knock on Hetzner they where excellent, just didn&amp;#x27;t need it any more).&lt;p&gt;Robot is a brutally functional tool but it does function (well) and had zero issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;esafak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do tech companies like Hetzner count as &lt;i&gt;mittelstand&lt;/i&gt;s?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArtTimeInvestor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hetzner is awesome.&lt;p&gt;I wish they would go public.&lt;p&gt;Would be very interesting to see how their business is doing compared to IONOS and OVH.&lt;p&gt;We need more public cloud companies in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;boldlybold:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Video didn&amp;#x27;t display for me even after turning off content blockers, here&amp;#x27;s the url: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=gIjdKIMQh4s" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=gIjdKIMQh4s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freak_NL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Location of Hetzner&amp;#x27;s Falkenstein data centre, for the curious:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.openstreetmap.org&amp;#x2F;way&amp;#x2F;606528332#map=13&amp;#x2F;50.46220&amp;#x2F;12.35567&amp;amp;layers=P" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.openstreetmap.org&amp;#x2F;way&amp;#x2F;606528332#map=13&amp;#x2F;50.46220&amp;#x2F;...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.igorslab.de/en/a-day-at-hetzner-online-in-the-falkenstein-data-center-insights-into-server-technology-cooling-production-rma-and-sustainability/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968235</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Things to Try with Gemini 3 Pro in Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://developers.googleblog.com/en/5-things-to-try-with-gemini-3-pro-in-gemini-cli/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Pro is available starting now in Gemini CLI for Google AI Ultra subscribers (Gemini 3 Pro is available starting now in Gemini CLI for Google AI Ultra subscribers (Google AI Ultra for Business access coming soon) and for those who have access via paid Gemini API key. For Gemini Code Assist Enterprise users, access is coming soon. Start using Gemini 3 Pro with Gemini CLIIf you’re a Google AI Ultra subscriber or have a paid Gemini API key, get started immediately by upgrading your Gemini CLI version to 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968104"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://developers.googleblog.com/en/5-things-to-try-with-gemini-3-pro-in-gemini-cli/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eptcyka:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why would you `git bisect` when you can `git log -p` and search for “dark”? Why is a marketing listicle on top of HN?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lefrenchy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t even sign in via the CLI, it&amp;#x27;s opened the browser window and had me sign in multiple times and can&amp;#x27;t proceed past that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ipsum2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow, so excited to try!&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; gemini&lt;p&gt;It seems like you don&amp;#x27;t have access to Gemini 3.
Learn more at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;goo.gle&amp;#x2F;enable-preview-features" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;goo.gle&amp;#x2F;enable-preview-features&lt;/a&gt;
To disable Gemini 3, disable &amp;quot;Preview features&amp;quot; in &amp;#x2F;settings.
• 1. Switch to gemini-2.5-pro
• 2. Stop
Note: You can always use &amp;#x2F;model to select a different option.&lt;p&gt;Google never disappoints with their half-ass-launches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alecco:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t like Javascript for CLI. I think OpenAI did the right thing by switching to Rust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;embedding-shape:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Correct me if I&amp;#x27;m wrong, but in this demo video of the user instructing the model to use `git bisect` to find a commit (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;gweb-developer-goog-blog-assets&amp;#x2F;original_videos&amp;#x2F;Demo_3_of_5._Git_bisect.mp4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;gweb-developer-goog-blog-asse...&lt;/a&gt;), doesn&amp;#x27;t this actually showcase a big issue with today&amp;#x27;s models?&lt;p&gt;In the end, the model only ran `git bisect` (if we&amp;#x27;re to believe the video at least) for various pointless reasons, it isn&amp;#x27;t being used for what it&amp;#x27;s usually used for. Why did it run bisect at all? Well, the user asked the LLM to use `git bisect` to find a specific commit, but that doesn&amp;#x27;t make sense, `git bisect` is not for that, so what the user is asking for, isn&amp;#x27;t possible.&lt;p&gt;Instead of the model stopping and saying &amp;quot;Hey, that&amp;#x27;s not the right idea, did you mean ... ?&amp;quot; so to ensure it&amp;#x27;s actually possible and what the user wants, the model runs its own race and start invoking a bunch of other git commands, because that&amp;#x27;s how you&amp;#x27;d find that commit the user is looking for, and then finally does some git bisecting stuff just for fun, it had already found the right commit.&lt;p&gt;I think I see the same thing when letting LLMs code as well. If you give them some work to do that is actually impossible, but the words kind of make sense, and it&amp;#x27;ll produce something but not what you wanted, I think they&amp;#x27;re doing exactly the same thing, bypassing what you clearly instructed so they at least do something.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure if I&amp;#x27;m just hallucinating that they&amp;#x27;re acting like that, but LLMs doing &amp;quot;the wrong thing&amp;quot; has been hitting me more than once, and imagining something more dangerous than `do a git bisect`, it seems to me like that video is telling us Gemini 3 Pro will act exactly the same way, no improvements on that front.&lt;p&gt;Also, do these blog posts not go through review from engineering before they&amp;#x27;re published? Besides the video not really showcasing anything of interest, the prompt itself doesn&amp;#x27;t make any sense and would have been caught if a engineer who uses git at least weekly reviewed it before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;More discussion:  &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45968043"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45968043&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recitedropper:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice, without this thread I would never have known Gemini 3 released today.&lt;p&gt;Going to download Gemini CLI right now™ and see how it performs™ against Cursor, Claude Code, Aider, OpenCode, Droid, Warp, Devin, and ForgeCode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Has anyone switched to Gemini CLI?  It&amp;#x27;s so important but also exhausting keeping up with which model is the leading edge.  Especially since every model has different idiosyncrasies you have to learn to work with it effectively.&lt;p&gt;Currently my ranking is&lt;p&gt;* Cursor composer: impressively fast and able but not tuned to be that agentic, so it&amp;#x27;s better for one-shot code changes than long-running tasks.  Fantastic UI.&lt;p&gt;* Claude Code: Works great if you can set up a verifiable environment, a clear plan and set it loose to build something for an hour&lt;p&gt;* Grok: Similar to cursor composer but slower and more agentic.  Not currently using.&lt;p&gt;* ChatGPT Codex, Gemini: Haven&amp;#x27;t tried yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://developers.googleblog.com/en/5-things-to-try-with-gemini-3-pro-in-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968104</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.google/products/gemini/gemini-3/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can now access Gemini 3 across Google products like the Gemini app, AI Studio, and Vertex AI. Gemini 3 is available now in various Google products, with Deep Think coming soon. And starting today, we’re shipping Gemini at the scale of Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967999"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.google/products/gemini/gemini-3/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 24 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ilaksh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;okay since Gemini 3 is AI mode now, I switched from the free perplexity back to google as being my search default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zone411:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sets a new record on the Extended NYT Connections benchmark: 96.8 (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;lechmazur&amp;#x2F;nyt-connections&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;lechmazur&amp;#x2F;nyt-connections&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;p&gt;Grok 4 is at 92.1, GPT-5 Pro at 83.9, Claude Opus 4.1 Thinking 16K at 58.8.&lt;p&gt;Gemini 2.5 Pro scored 57.6, so this is a huge improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crawshaw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Has anyone who is a regular Opus &amp;#x2F; GPT5-Codex-High &amp;#x2F; GPT5 Pro user given this model a workout? Each Google release is accompanied by a lot of devrel marketing that sounds impressive but whenever I put the hours into eval myself it comes up lacking. Would love to hear that it replaces another frontier model for someone who is not already bought into the Gemini ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;energy123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Impressive. Although the Deep Think benchmark results are suspicious given they&amp;#x27;re comparing apples (tools on) with oranges (tools off) in their chart to visually show an improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;poemxo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s amazing to see Google take the lead while OpenAI worsens their product every release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;briga:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Every big new model release we see benchmarks like ARC and Humanity&amp;#x27;s Last Exam climbing higher and higher. My question is, how do we know that these benchmarks are not a part of the training set used for these models? It could easily have been trained to memorize the answers. Even if the datasets haven&amp;#x27;t been copy pasted directly, I&amp;#x27;m sure it has leaked onto the internet to some extent.&lt;p&gt;But I am looking forward to trying it out. I find Gemini to be great as handling large-context tasks, and Google&amp;#x27;s inference costs seem to be among the cheapest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pflenker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Since then, it’s been incredible to see how much people love it. AI Overviews now have 2 billion users every month.&lt;p&gt;Come on, you can’t be serious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WXLCKNO:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Valve could learn from Google here&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;serjester:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s disappointing there&amp;#x27;s no flash &amp;#x2F; lite version - this is where Google has excelled up to this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qustrolabe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Out of all other companies Google provide the most generous free access so far. I bet this gives them plenty of data to train even better models&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;casey2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The first paragraph is pure delusion. Why do investors like delusional CEOs so much? I would take it as a major red flag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tylervigen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am personally impressed by the continued improvement in ARC-AGI-2, where Gemini 3 got 31.1% (vs ChatGPT 5.1&amp;#x27;s 17.6%).  To me this is the kind of problem that does not lend itself well to LLMs - many of the puzzles test the kind of thing that humans intuit because of millions of years of evolution, but these concepts do not necessarily appear in written form (or when they do, it&amp;#x27;s not clear how they connect to specific ARC puzzles).&lt;p&gt;The fact that these models can keep getting better at this task given the setup of training is mind-boggling to me.&lt;p&gt;The ARC puzzles in question: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arcprize.org&amp;#x2F;arc-agi&amp;#x2F;2&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arcprize.org&amp;#x2F;arc-agi&amp;#x2F;2&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scrollop:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here it makes a text based video editor that works:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;MPjOQIQO8eQ?si=wcrCSLYx3LjeYDfi&amp;amp;t=797" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;MPjOQIQO8eQ?si=wcrCSLYx3LjeYDfi&amp;amp;t=797&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevesimmons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A nice Easter egg in the Gemini 3 docs [1]:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    If you are transferring a conversation trace from another model, ... to bypass strict validation in these specific scenarios, populate the field with this specific dummy string:

    &amp;quot;thoughtSignature&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;context_engineering_is_the_way_to_go&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ai.google.dev&amp;#x2F;gemini-api&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;gemini-3?thinking=high#migrating_from_other_models" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ai.google.dev&amp;#x2F;gemini-api&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;gemini-3?thinking=high...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coffeecoders:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Feels like the same consolidation cycle we saw with mobile apps and browsers are playing out here. The winners aren’t necessarily those with the best models, but those who already control the surface where people live their digital lives.&lt;p&gt;Google injects AI Overviews directly into search, X pushes Grok into the feed, Apple wraps &amp;quot;intelligence&amp;quot; into Maps and on-device workflows, and Microsoft is quietly doing the same with Copilot across Windows and Office.&lt;p&gt;Open models and startups can innovate, but the platforms can immediately put their AI in front of billions of users without asking anyone to change behavior (not even typing a new URL).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bilekas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The Gemini app surpasses 650 million users per month, more than 70% of our Cloud customers use our AI, 13 million developers have built with our generative models, and that is just a snippet of the impact we’re seeing&lt;p&gt;Not to be a negative nelly, but these numbers are definitely inflated due to Google literally pushing their AI into everything they can, much like M$. Can&amp;#x27;t even search google without getting an AI response. Surely you can&amp;#x27;t claim those numbers are legit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rvz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I expect almost no-one to read the Gemini 3 model card. But here is a damning excerpt from the early leaked model card from [0]:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The training dataset also includes: publicly available datasets that are readily downloadable; data obtained by crawlers; licensed data obtained via commercial licensing agreements; user data (i.e., data collected from users of Google products and services to train AI models, along with user interactions with the model) in accordance with Google’s relevant terms of service, privacy policy, service-specific policies, and pursuant to user controls, where appropriate; other datasets that Google acquires or generates in the course of its business operations, or directly from its workforce; and AI-generated synthetic data.&lt;p&gt;So your Gmails are being read by Gemini and is being put on the training set for future models. Oh dear and Google is being sued over using Gemini for analyzing user&amp;#x27;s data which potentially includes Gmails by default.&lt;p&gt;Where is the outrage?&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.g...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.yahoo.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;articles&amp;#x2F;google-sued-over-gemini-ai-151508072.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.yahoo.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;articles&amp;#x2F;google-sued-over-gemini-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gertrunde:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;AI Overviews now have 2 billion users every month.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Users&amp;quot;? Or people that get presented with it and ignore it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;icyfox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty happy the under 200k token pricing is staying in the same ballpark as Gemini 2.5 Pro:&lt;p&gt;Input: $1.25 -&amp;gt; $2.00 (1M tokens)&lt;p&gt;Output: $10.00 -&amp;gt; $12.00&lt;p&gt;Squeezes a bit more margin out of app layer companies, certainly, but there&amp;#x27;s a good chance that for tasks that really require a sota model it can be more than justified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bnchrch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been so happy to see Google wake up.&lt;p&gt;Many can point to a long history of killed products and soured opinions but you can&amp;#x27;t deny theyve been the great balancing force (often for good) in the industry.&lt;p&gt;- Gmail vs Outlook&lt;p&gt;- Drive vs Word&lt;p&gt;- Android vs iOS&lt;p&gt;- Worklife balance and high pay vs the low salary grind of before.&lt;p&gt;Theyve done heaps for the industry. Im glad to see signs of life. Particularly in their P&amp;#x2F;E which was unjustly low for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;svantana:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Grok got to hold the top spot of LMArena-text for all of ~24 hours, good for them [1]. With stylecontrol enabled, that is. Without stylecontrol, gemini held the fort.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lmarena.ai&amp;#x2F;leaderboard&amp;#x2F;text" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lmarena.ai&amp;#x2F;leaderboard&amp;#x2F;text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meetpateltech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;DeepMind page: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Pro DeepMind Page: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;pro&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;pro&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developer blog: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.google&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;developers&amp;#x2F;gemini-3-developers&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.google&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;developers&amp;#x2F;gemini-3-developer...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Docs: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ai.google.dev&amp;#x2F;gemini-api&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;gemini-3" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ai.google.dev&amp;#x2F;gemini-api&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;gemini-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Antigravity: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;antigravity.google&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;antigravity.google&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thedelanyo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reading the introductory passage - all I can say now is, Ai is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;denysvitali:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Finally!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.google/products/gemini/gemini-3/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967999</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Brings Gemini 3 AI Model to Search and AI Mode</title>
      <link>https://blog.google/products/search/gemini-3-search-ai-mode/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Search with Gemini 3: Our most intelligent search yet Nov 18, 2025 · Share Twitter Facebook LinkedIn Mail Copy link Gemini 3’s state-of-the-art reasoning grasps depth and nuance, and unlocks new generative UI experiences with dynamic visual layouts, interactive tools and simulations tailored specifically for your query. Here’s how Gemini 3 is supercharging Search. And in the coming weeks, we’re also enhancing our automatic model selection in Search with Gemini 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968091"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.google/products/search/gemini-3-search-ai-mode/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;More discussion: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45967999"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45967999&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45968043"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45968043&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macintux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do we need 6 front page topics on Gemini? (Plus 2-3 on Antigravity)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.google/products/search/gemini-3-search-ai-mode/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968091</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving a Million-Step LLM Task with Zero Errors</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09030</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968362"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09030'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Worth opening the pdf just for the graph on page 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have ADHD and the same approach works for me. (In fact, most days it is essential!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;htrp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The approach relies on an extreme decomposition of a task into subtasks, each of which can be tackled by focused microagents. The high level of modularity resulting from the decomposition allows error correction to be applied at each step through an efficient multi-agent voting scheme.&lt;p&gt;Big if that the decomposition and the voting happen accurately for anything other than toy problems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;awei:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;one issue I see is when steps in a plan depend on one another, when you cannot know all the next steps exactly before seeing the results of the previous ones, when you may have to backtrack sometimes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zer00eyz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the surface this is an interesting concept...&lt;p&gt;The paper however, meh...&lt;p&gt;No mention of MoE. One would think this is a logical evolution of that but not a mention (that I saw). Its own rubric for the task, Towers of Hanoi, was admittedly weak.&lt;p&gt;LLM papers are starting to look like the last decade of JS frameworks and Tools. Only with less code and more academics, and thats disappointing, because I think a lack of pragmatism and grounding is now holding the field back...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cs702:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice!&lt;p&gt;Briefly, the idea is recursively to decompose tasks into the simplest possible steps, recursively call (relatively small) LLMs as agents to execute one step at a time, and using a clever voting scheme to choose how to execute each step. The authors use this technique to get a relatively small LLM to solve Towers of Hanoi with 20 rings (1M steps). All of it using natural language.&lt;p&gt;The most obvious question is whether other tasks, more interesting -- less &amp;quot;rote&amp;quot; -- than Towers of Hanoi, can similarly be recursively decomposed into simple steps. I&amp;#x27;m not sure that&amp;#x27;s always possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LMKIIW:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I dunno, even though the authors address its use, making the task Tower of Hanoi doesn&amp;#x27;t meet the excitement of the title.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.09030</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968362</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strix Halo's Memory Subsystem: Tackling iGPU Challenges</title>
      <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/p/strix-halos-memory-subsystem-tackling</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nemes’s Vulkan bandwidth test achieves just under 1 TB/s from Infinity Cache. Therefore, Infinity Cache policy can change on the fly from software control. I’m not sure why it affects Infinity Cache behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968611"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://chipsandcheese.com/p/strix-halos-memory-subsystem-tackling'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dontlaugh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If only you could buy the hardware. There are very few laptops or similar with the chip. Even the Z13 is difficult to find and (at least in Europe) only with 32 GB of RAM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://chipsandcheese.com/p/strix-halos-memory-subsystem-tackling</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968611</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Guts – convert Golang types to TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://github.com/coder/guts</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;// Step 1: Create a new Golang parser golang, _ := guts. com/coder/guts/example/simple") // Step 3: Convert the Golang to the typescript AST ts, _ := golang. Using goja, these types are then serialized to typescript using the typescript compiler API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969708"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/coder/guts'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;flashgordon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really like the idea of it.   My dream has always been to work with &amp;quot;types&amp;quot; first and foremost across any and all languages (yep it is a dream).   And little tools like these are really nice to see push that boundary.&lt;p&gt;One feedback - if you are truly comparing with &amp;quot;other&amp;quot; tools - you should be looking at grpc and protoc plugins.   I have used to great effect for things like:&lt;p&gt;1. Generating wasm bindings for grpc services&lt;p&gt;2. Generating &amp;quot;data access layer&amp;quot; types so you can choose how a api proto is transformed to a data domain type and vice versa&lt;p&gt;3. MCP bindings for APIs&lt;p&gt;4. GraphQL&amp;#x2F;BFF bindings with multiple services&lt;p&gt;5. All of the above &amp;quot;across&amp;quot; langauges.&lt;p&gt;The tooling is fantastic and extensible - if you are ok to start with a proto view of your world - it sounds wierd and like an N+1 problem but once you are used to it it is surprisingly fun (ok we may have different ideas of fun)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cube2222:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We&amp;#x27;ve been using guts basically since it was published on GitHub (almost a year now), and it&amp;#x27;s so nice! We have a &amp;quot;custom POST-based JSON-rpc&amp;quot;-style api, so we have request and response bodies defined as Go types, and are generating the whole TS schema from it.&lt;p&gt;It basically lets you generate typescript types from your Go types. However, it&amp;#x27;s very customizable - you can post-process the AST. In our case, we have a custom generic Go type that indicates an optional (not nullable) field, and we can easily translate it to optional TS types (e.g. for sparse updates).&lt;p&gt;All in all, great tool&amp;#x2F;library, thanks for building it!&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I know a developer at Coder (not the author), who also recommended me guts back then, but am unaffiliated other than that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/coder/guts</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969708</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Optimizing LiteLLM with Rust – When Expectations Meet Reality</title>
      <link>https://github.com/neul-labs/fast-litellm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installation pip install fast-litellm Quick Start import fast_litellm # Automatically accelerates LiteLLM import litellm # All LiteLLM operations now use Rust acceleration where available response = litellm. sh # Run LiteLLM tests with acceleration. py This ensures Fast LiteLLM doesn't break any LiteLLM functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968461"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/neul-labs/fast-litellm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmalicki:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The benchmarks in your README.md state that it is several times faster for those operations, are they a lie?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aaronblohowiak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;measure before implementing &amp;quot;improvements&amp;quot;, you&amp;#x27;ll develop a sense over time of what is taking too long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;solidsnack9000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting write-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/neul-labs/fast-litellm</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968461</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Antigravity</title>
      <link>https://antigravity.google/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://antigravity.google/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967814</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Antigravity, a New Era in AI-Assisted Software Development</title>
      <link>https://antigravity.google/blog/introducing-google-antigravity</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://antigravity.google/blog/introducing-google-antigravity</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968065</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
