<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 21:21:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Consciousness from AI</title>
      <link>https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On social media, people are using LLMs to generate posts just for impressions, instead of going through the process of finding sources and creating authentic content themselves. I want to bring back authentic forum posts, where people can share their ideas and thoughts, with less algorithmic influence than platforms like X. LLMs can be prompted into agreeing with you, which is less likely than with a licensed therapist - it's important to have human to human feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868271"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tyleo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve found the hesitation to shovel text into AI weird given the _lack_ of hesitation to shovel text into search engines.&lt;p&gt;Either case is weird in absolute terms but in relative terms, it all goes to the same place. The human-like nature of AI seems to make people realize this more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chance-Device:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was expecting something about &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; to protect your consciousness from (or during) AI use, but I got a short 200 word note rehashing common sentiments about AI. I guess it’s not wrong, it’s just not very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrloba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is everywhere. Even on birthday invites for my kids there&amp;#x27;s nonsense from an LLM. At work I review PRs with code that doesn&amp;#x27;t even run. Doing research is harder than ever as more and more references are completely made up.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re too lazy and too obsessed with getting ahead to use this technology responsibly in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tmaly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am perfectly okay with offloading low value mental work to an LLM just to recoup time to spend with my family.  The modern world has way too many demands that just suck up time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bukhmanizer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Culturally we are going through a phase where thought is getting massively devalued.  It’s all well and good to say “I’m using AI responsibly”, but it won’t matter if at the end of the day no one values your opinion over whatever ChatGPT spewed out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;satisfice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I always thought hacker culture was independent and skeptical. Somehow AI has turned a lot of them into drooling fanboys.&lt;p&gt;It’s embarrassing. Don’t rely on AI, guys. Have pride in yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thundergolfer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t a new problem at all. If you only started noticing it as a problem with &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot;, as the author apparently did, then you were blind to how our mediums and tools have always shaped us, alienated us from the world and each other, and made us dependent on mechanism. This has happened hugely already with television.&lt;p&gt;You can go back and read McLuhan, he&amp;#x27;s great, but a recent and more approachable book on this is _God, Human, Animal, Machine: Technology, Metaphor, and the Search for Meaning_.&lt;p&gt;Way back in 1969 the utopian vision of technology put humans at the centre. The Whole Earth Catalogue&amp;#x27;s slogan was “access to tools.” Just _tools_. That same year, technology put a man on the moon.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, if you realize the extent and the history of the problem, you see we&amp;#x27;re so far gone, miles away from getting a grip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delichon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This creates a sea of noise and misinformation that people unknowingly consume at scale.&lt;p&gt;The same objections apply to the written word. A culture that succeeded in not succumbing to writing and reading may indeed have been better off in the short term, depending on the quality of the memes. But it would have been at a competitive disadvantage to cultures that were permissive with knowledge transfer.&lt;p&gt;The main advantage of AI so far has been as a distiller of the knowledge embedded in the written word. It&amp;#x27;s another  leap in knowledge transfer. That&amp;#x27;s still a competitive advantage to any culture that doesn&amp;#x27;t abjure it. This particular consciousness intends to leverage the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nvllsvm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In the professional world, I see software developers blindly copying and pasting code suggestions from LLM providers without testing it, or understanding it.&lt;p&gt;When you see that, call them out on it. Not understanding copy+pasted code is one thing, but not testing it is a whole other level of garbage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noir_lord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m far too lazy to be able to responsibly use a machine that can give me semi-sensible answers.&lt;p&gt;I saw the danger of it as a form of learned helplessness down the line and swore off using LLM&amp;#x27;s for that reason, that and I feel no need to delegate my thinking to a machine that can&amp;#x27;t think and I &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; thinking.&lt;p&gt;Same reason snacks are upstairs in the kitchen and not in my office on the ground floor - I&amp;#x27;m too lazy and if they are easily available I&amp;#x27;ll eat them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jordangoodman.bearblog.dev/protect-your-consciousness-from-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868271</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sega Master System</title>
      <link>https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only real candidate for this is an SG-1000 in different packaging that came out along the way. The Famicom doubled that to 2KB, and the Master System jumped it up to 8. The only addition on this side is that its palette information is stored in an independent “Color RAM” that only holds 32 bytes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868259"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aledalgrande:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Was just a few days ago in a shop in Den Den town in Osaka, where they still sell original Master System, NES and PS1 games, so many memories!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bumbershootsoft.wordpress.com/2025/11/08/the-sega-master-system/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868259</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drilling Down on Uncle Sam's Proposed TP-Link Ban</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TP-Link Systems told The Post it has sole ownership of some engineering, design and manufacturing capabilities in China that were once part of China-based TP-Link Technologies, and that it operates them without Chinese government supervision. That price point (and consistently excellent performance ratings) has made TP-Link a favorite among Internet service providers (ISPs) that provide routers to their customers. TP-Link rightly points out that most of its competitors likewise source components from China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867717"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 15 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;burnt-resistor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Per company government acquisition &amp;quot;bans&amp;quot; are stupid for PR and security reasons. Brand-specific banlists are whackamole when the same hardware and software will be immediately duplicated with another cat-walks-on-keyboard brand name that will disappear within a year.&lt;p&gt;Instead, there should be in-depth, enforced audit, compliance, and evaluation standards for gear for particular purposes. If it doesn&amp;#x27;t meet particular standard(s), then it can&amp;#x27;t be purchased or used.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BobbyTables2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Virtually every home router and a whole lot of small business routers should be considered “national security risks”.&lt;p&gt;TP-Link may be sore for getting singled out but they are certainly not unique.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nickpsecurity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;TP-Link Systems told The Post it has sole ownership of some engineering, design and manufacturing capabilities in China that were once part of China-based TP-Link Technologies, and that it operates them without Chinese government supervision.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Is that even possible? Or do you always have to be on good terms with the Chinese government to own engineering, design, and manufacturing capabilities in China?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SilverElfin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t like that TP Link routers regularly force you to accept new terms of service within their app. If you don’t, then you can’t access much of their configuration options. Basically you get locked out of your own device. I feel like these dark patterns should be illegal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abridgett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll just leave this little NSA intercepting Cisco products reminder here:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arstechnica.com&amp;#x2F;tech-policy&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;photos-of-an-nsa-upgrade-factory-show-cisco-router-getting-implant&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arstechnica.com&amp;#x2F;tech-policy&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;photos-of-an-nsa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ComplexSystems:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t get what to make of this. Is it all just security theater? The idea of having consumer networking hardware that isn&amp;#x27;t riddled with security vulnerabilities seems to be a ship that sailed long ago. I doubt this move will prevent major nation states from hacking into whatever they want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imagetic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have TP-Link Deco&amp;#x27;s for our WiFi, sitting behind a Firewalla Gold. This has been by far the nicest, simplest at home setup I&amp;#x27;ve ever deployed. Do I love that I chose TP-Link? No. But price to purpose it was the best product available to me at the time.&lt;p&gt;If TP-Link gets banned, my concern is what that means for the massive market share in the US. Warranty? Software updates? Or maybe that action is what turns them into an agent of the state. Or do you horde all the hardware until its valuable like DJI parts are today?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chatmasta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TP-Link makes really solid products, and if you don’t want to use their firmware then almost all of them can easily flash OpenWRT. In fact most of their routers are built from OpenWRT anyway.&lt;p&gt;I installed their mesh Wi-Fi system for my parents recently and was really impressed how seamless the process was. It did involve making a cloud account which I wasn’t thrilled about, however.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bethekidyouwant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t get the end game here D-link isn’t any better. Are we heading for isp enforced hardware in our homes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cflewis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been really happy with the TP-Link smart plugs. I keep upgrading them as The Latest Standard That&amp;#x27;s Definitely The Real One This Time Trust Us Bro comes out, and the Matter ones are excellent. Getting an instant response from them is really nice. I see no reason to buy others.&lt;p&gt;I would buy only Hue but that&amp;#x27;s because I have more money than sense, and they don&amp;#x27;t actually make smart plugs last time I looked, they make plugs but label them all as lights in the app, which is more annoying than it sounds.&lt;p&gt;The real problem to solve ditching TP-Link _routers_ is that all routers are uniformly fucking awful, and all you are doing is choosing your particular poison. This is especially true after Apple exited the game so long ago. I use Google Wifi because it mostly works most of the time, but that&amp;#x27;s not glowing praise. But the world has become trained that rebooting a router once a week and praying that it works when it comes back is a perfectly normal state of affairs and we couldn&amp;#x27;t possibly do this any better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WheatMillington:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So much freedom in America lately. TP-Link, DJI, BYD, must be great to never have these options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;riskable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The real lesson here: If you&amp;#x27;re successful, &lt;i&gt;don&amp;#x27;t skimp&lt;/i&gt; on security&amp;#x2F;software! Also, don&amp;#x27;t abandon software&amp;#x2F;firmware security support for your products so quickly.&lt;p&gt;If I was in charge over at TP-Link, getting news that tens of thousands of MY company&amp;#x27;s routers were compromised would have me furious! I&amp;#x27;d be freaking out, making sure that we take immediate steps to improve software&amp;#x2F;firmware quality and to make sure we&amp;#x27;re in a constant state of trying to compromise our own hardware... To ensure no one else finds vulnerabilities before we do.&lt;p&gt;Instead, TP-Link seems to have just laughed and focused &lt;i&gt;strictly&lt;/i&gt; on profit margins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeroConcerns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t have any particular opinion on TP-Link (never used their products), but the idea that a low-cost vendor targeting home and SMB users is somehow a state-level agent trying to compromise those users... needs evidence.&lt;p&gt;I mean, in the case of actors like Huawei, you can at least credibly make the argument that the continued access of their support staff to internal provider networks is a significant risk, but that vector is &lt;i&gt;entirely&lt;/i&gt; absent here.&lt;p&gt;Sure, embedded firmware has been, is, and will continue to be a tire fire prone to embarrassing compromises, but containing those is mostly about notification and containment by government agencies (which the current US administration is doing their utmost best to kneecap) and&amp;#x2F;or large ISPs (which in the US have traditionally never cared).&lt;p&gt;Forcing &amp;quot;foreign&amp;quot; products off the market in favor of &amp;quot;domestic&amp;quot; replacements with the exact same, if not worse, flaws won&amp;#x27;t fix a thing, unless you put some pretty significant controls into place that nobody is willing to enforce or even outline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vjvjvjvjghv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If only there were US manufacturers that could produce things at a decent price and  didn&amp;#x27;t actively hate their customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ddtaylor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The company says it researches, designs, develops and manufactures everything except its chipsets in-house.&lt;p&gt;So, the plastic bits?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/drilling-down-on-uncle-sams-proposed-tp-link-ban/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 18:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867717</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Computer Church – Pennsylvania Computer and Technology Museum</title>
      <link>https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open by Appointment Fall 2025 Staff Sign-in Home of the Computer Museum ISEC250 Stock Market Computer DONNER 3500 Analog Computer RangeKeeper Mark 7 Reeves Electronic Analogue Computer: P-101 EAI Early Logo Hollerith Model 1 Card Punch Donner 3000 Analog Computer EAI TR-48 Analog Computer •O U R C O L L E C T I O N• ANALOG COMPUTERS Our collection of over 50 analog computers is the largest known collection in the world. READ MORE ANALOG SUPERPOWERS But this particular computer is very special for an entirely different reason. 1976 READ MORE Hollerith Tabulating Machine This is Hollerith personal copy of his article about the Tabulating Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868533"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.thecomputerchurch.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868533</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups are pushing the boundaries of reproductive genetics</title>
      <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/biotech/genetically-engineered-babies-tech-billionaires-6779efc8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wsj.com/tech/biotech/genetically-engineered-babies-tech-billionaires-6779efc8</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865956</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Software Foundation gets a donor surge after rejecting federal grant</title>
      <link>https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The support from the Python community in response has been overwhelming,” Seth Larson told me last week. Please read and share their story. Their announcement also received 1,400 upvotes in Reddit’s Python subreddit and another 355 comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867277"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MarsIronPI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the brief reading of the article that I had time for, I couldn&amp;#x27;t find the exact reason why the grant was rejected.  Does anti-DEI automatically mean discrimination?  Call me naive, but as far as I can see, DEI isn&amp;#x27;t necessary for a volunteer project.  Why does it matter how many of a project&amp;#x27;s contributors are transgender?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buckle8017:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The grant simply required that the recipient comply with the equal protection clause of the constitution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;add-sub-mul-div:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It wasn&amp;#x27;t exactly the Streisand effect, but I remember thinking the whole flourishing of trans rights and acceptance between 2017 and 2021 never would have happened if Hillary had won. Is there a name for this phenomenon?&lt;p&gt;Did both parties implicitly understand up until 2017 that going too hard too fast is counterproductive?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thenewstack.io/psf-gets-a-donor-surge-after-rejecting-anti-dei-federal-grant/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867277</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Heart Association says melatonin may be linked to serious heart risks</title>
      <link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Date: November 4, 2025 Source: American Heart Association Summary: Long-term melatonin use for sleep problems may come with unexpected heart dangers. 5 times more likely to be hospitalized for heart failure. Long-Term Melatonin Use Linked to Higher Heart Failure Risk People who regularly take melatonin to improve sleep may face serious health risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867371"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;apatheticonion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d been taking 3mg slow release melatonin daily for years up until a few months ago. To be honest, I&amp;#x27;m not sure it has any significant effect.&lt;p&gt;Regular exercise and a consistent sleep routine (cardio, weight lifting, going to bed early, and waking up early) has been more effective for me.&lt;p&gt;According to my fitbit, my average sleep duration is 6hr 30min over the last 2 years, down from 7hr30. When I wake up, there&amp;#x27;s no going back.&lt;p&gt;The biggest contributor to my reduction in sleep is my job, which in the last few years added stack ranking and by-annual performance reviews which requires daily book keeping of my &amp;quot;company impact&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I also got an echo-cardiogram last week (unrelated) and it came back in top shape (have a calcium score test coming up). Not saying melatonin isn&amp;#x27;t a risk for cardio health, but as a male in his early 30s with a family history of heart disease, nothing seems to indicate an increase in damage in my case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lateforwork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sleep experts say it is not possible to draw conclusions about melatonin from this study&amp;#x27;s findings — it did not prove cause and effect. A more likely explanation of the results is that insomnia itself could be to blame. In that case, melatonin would be an “innocent bystander”.&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;well&amp;#x2F;melatonin-heart-health-study.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;well&amp;#x2F;melatonin-heart-heal...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smileyferret:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an abstract that hasn’t been peer-reviewed… based on prescription data for an over-the-counter medication. This will be horribly inaccurate because it will miss all the folks who just buy the medication on their own and never have it documented.&lt;p&gt;These TriNetX studies are usually garbage because they’re entirely dependent on how accurate&amp;#x2F;up-to-date the medical record is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;almosthere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;probably written by a statin exec. There is no reason to trust anything anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crdrost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;PSA that melatonin use was way out of control before this study was even published.&lt;p&gt;Sleep aid melatonin is shipped in pills containing ridiculous amounts of the stuff—I’ve seen 10, 12, and 20mg myself, Amazon has a 40mg fast dissolve and 60mg gummies.&lt;p&gt;This spikes your blood amount with 100x-1000x of your natural cycle of melatonin. Why? Because melatonin is not, repeat not, the signaling molecule that makes you sleepy. It responds to light levels and triggers the cascade of &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; molecules that make you sleepy, several hours after it peaks. So that&amp;#x27;s why the 100x overdose—you are trying to kick those secondary mechanisms into overdrive, “hey everyone it is black as the abyss of hell I guess we gotta sleep!!”, because Americans taking melatonin want to pop one just before bed and have it knock them out.&lt;p&gt;And it does that for like 2 or 3 days before your body starts down-regulating all of its sensitivities to those melatonin byproducts. Nerve cells like to be tickled, not zapped, when you shock them like this they react angrily.&lt;p&gt;You want to use melatonin to reinforce circadian rhythm and fight jet lag, you do it with amounts in the ~100 &lt;i&gt;micrograms&lt;/i&gt; range, slow release if you can find it, and you take that &lt;i&gt;at sunset&lt;/i&gt; and let it reinforce your normal cycle. If you&amp;#x27;re looking for an acute sleep aid, take a walk, get fresh air, drink water, and if those don&amp;#x27;t help pop a Benadryl&amp;#x2F;Unisom (it&amp;#x27;s the same drug either way). If you have doctor’s orders of course follow those, but if you&amp;#x27;re just trying to self-medicate that’s how you do it.&lt;p&gt;Absolutely unsurprising that punching your sleep apparatus in the gut once every day for five years increases some sort of stress on your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bilsbie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’d guess it’s just correlated with poor sleepers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;michaelcampbell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This whole thing is akin to the &amp;quot;I&amp;#x27;m just asking questions&amp;quot; crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cultofmetatron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;insomnia is also highly correlated with heart attack risk so there&amp;#x27;s that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pogue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I tried to make the title a little less hyperbolic than the article starts out, as it&amp;#x27;s not a published study and it&amp;#x27;s basically a huge meta analysis that has no other information on age range, dosage, other health problems, etc. But the implications are worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251104012959.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867371</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
