<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 03:48:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Why top firms fire good workers</title>
      <link>https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/employee-turnover-why-top-firms-churn-good-workers-681832/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workers accept being underpaid temporarily because remaining at a top firm signals their elite status to the market. Churning happens not because these employees have failed but because they may be just somewhat lower-skilled than their peers. Workers accept being underpaid temporarily because remaining at a top firm serves as a signal to the market about their elite status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45999872"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/employee-turnover-why-top-firms-churn-good-workers-681832/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alexpotato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My favorite example of why managers fire good workers:&lt;p&gt;- You are a manager of a team of 4&lt;p&gt;- You hear layoffs are coming&lt;p&gt;- You have one amazing direct report, 2 just ok and 1 awful&lt;p&gt;Who do you fire?&lt;p&gt;Most people say &amp;quot;Of course, fire the awful person&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I say: &amp;quot;When this actually happened, the manager fired their best person&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Other: &amp;quot;But, but why? That&amp;#x27;s not fair!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Me: &amp;quot;You know layoffs are coming. You are the most expensive person on the team. If you fire the awful person there may be questions about why you even hired them. They then fire you and keep your amazing person as the manager (probably for less money).&lt;p&gt;You fire your best person, well then now you as the manager are the best person AND you can make the argument that that awful person needs &amp;#x27;more managing to be effective&amp;#x27;&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not pretty or noble or heartwarming but this is how the logic goes in a lot of big firms (especially around layoff season).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amitav1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TL;DR
When workers start out, the firms know a lot more about their abilities than the clients do (they have an &amp;quot;information advantage&amp;quot;) as the worker has very few ways through which to prove their abilites. Over time, though, as the employee&amp;#x27;s public performance increases (through successful cases, good investments, etc.) the information advantage the firm has becomes lower. Eventually, the firm lets the employee go in order because the worker now has proof of their competencies that they can show to clients to demand higher wages directly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;awesome_dude:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It looks (to me) like they&amp;#x27;re saying that the margin (amount that firms can charge clients less the cost of the employee&amp;#x27;s compensation package) is what&amp;#x27;s at stake.&lt;p&gt;As employees rise up the corporate ladder, their compensation packages increase, but the amount that the company can charge for that employee&amp;#x27;s work is limited (clients will be wanting to keep a certain margin for themselves too)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inetknght:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How to tell that some &amp;quot;researchers&amp;quot; spent too much time in economics classes and not enough time in ethics classes: they publish stuff like this (source [0]).&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aeaweb.org&amp;#x2F;articles?id=10.1257&amp;#x2F;aer.20200169" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aeaweb.org&amp;#x2F;articles?id=10.1257&amp;#x2F;aer.20200169&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting though one would think this is also an obvious finding.&lt;p&gt;Quantifying this would be interesting though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mcoliver:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No.  The reason top firms part ways with good workers is usually political.  Either the manager doesn&amp;#x27;t like the person regardless of their work abilities, or the manager is not politely savvy enough to ensure their team is being recognized for work that grows or is valuable to the business.  Or they get caught up in the endlessly popular reorgs (again management failure).  It&amp;#x27;s a failure of management. Nothing more. Nothing less.   A healthy market would encourage good workers to move around freely (through compensation, opportunity, benefits, location, etc..), not force their hand.  And healthy organizations would recognize talent and retain&amp;#x2F;retrain as needed.&lt;p&gt;I think the other thing that&amp;#x27;s perhaps missing is that some companies have so much momentum (with thousands of people) that it probably doesn&amp;#x27;t matter when they lose people. The company will continue to thrive because there is demand for the product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;camel_gopher:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Evil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/employee-turnover-why-top-firms-churn-good-workers-681832/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45999872</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over-regulation is doubling the cost</title>
      <link>https://rein.pk/over-regulation-is-doubling-the-cost</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re unintentionally blocking the very things that would improve our environment. We’ve become a society that blocks all things, and we need to be a society that builds great things every day. A regulator faces little cost to moving incredibly cautiously, but a major cost if they approve something that triggers activist pushback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45999038"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://rein.pk/over-regulation-is-doubling-the-cost'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;inetknght:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Your &amp;quot;over-regulation&amp;quot; is my &amp;quot;safety first&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JohnnyLarue:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It takes a brave businessman to speak out about how government regulations are killing their business. Thank you for your service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ETH_start:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Incredibly brave post from Peter about the insane regulatory friction our society must endure and which is directly responsible for the premature deaths of the startups attempting to build wealth for our future, as well as millions of people whose emancipation from (inter alia) air pollution is delayed for &lt;i&gt;decades&lt;/i&gt; by the same regulations that were intended to drive improvement of the environment.&lt;p&gt;Peter is brave because, descriptively, the regulatory state functions collectively as a cartel with a monopoly on the veto and can apply it essentially at will with no real accountability. If one of the thousands of officials Peter&amp;#x27;s companies work with takes a dim view of this post, they could quietly and anonymously kill the company by shadow banning progression of any of hundreds of strands of regulatory approvals needed to obtain permission to operate.&lt;p&gt;What are Peter&amp;#x27;s companies trying to do? Crush babies into gold? No, they&amp;#x27;re finding economic ways to fix air pollution. He&amp;#x27;s going to spend the better part of a decade of his life fighting some avatar of &amp;quot;the department of improving the environment&amp;quot; for the right to spend his own money improving the environment.&lt;p&gt;I too have heard, and experienced, insane horror stories.&lt;p&gt;The US is currently rapidly losing an energy production war with China. We have all the money and natural resources anyone could ever want, and China - a communist dictatorship - is deploying more electricity generation capacity in months than the US has deployed, ever, since the invention of electricity.&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;p&gt;Solar photovoltaic power, which is approximately free and works best in uninhabitable deserts that are otherwise so economically useless that they remain federal land and are used for such things as atomic bomb testing, must go through the same environmental impact assessments, which take many years, as an oil refinery or explosives plant. Solar energy, which has a lower impact than practically any other land use and is by far the best per dollar spend for improving the environment. We should be granting 99 year solar leases on BLM land and inviting the top 10 deployers to an annual dinner at the White House!&lt;p&gt;This is not a market failure. This is a regulatory failure, and it is actively killing us. More Americans die every month than on 9&amp;#x2F;11 from the impacts of air pollution that would have been addressed a decade ago if builders were allowed to build. This is not some academic niche issue. Thousands of people are actively killed by our neglect of this problem.&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I wrote this: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;terraformindustries.wordpress.com&amp;#x2F;2023&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;permitting-reform-or-death&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;terraformindustries.wordpress.com&amp;#x2F;2023&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;permitt...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The situation, expressed in real world time-to-deployment, has not materially improved. The regulatory state is a bizarre hydra where, somehow, painstaking reforms to speed up review often end up taking longer. Such is the case for California&amp;#x27;s fire hazard reduction burn process, which takes so long that the forests often burn up in the mean time. (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;caseyhandmer.wordpress.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;01&amp;#x2F;17&amp;#x2F;the-los-angeles-wildfires-are-self-inflicted&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;caseyhandmer.wordpress.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;01&amp;#x2F;17&amp;#x2F;the-los-angele...&lt;/a&gt;) Earlier this year, the fires took 10,000 houses and nearly 100 people with them, and now, nearly a year later, almost none have been rebuilt, while the city council&amp;#x27;s response to housing scarcity is ... rent control. Elon, I&amp;#x27;m ready to go to Mars!&lt;p&gt;My radical view is that if McMaster-Carr can fit 500,000 SKUs into its 4000 page catalog, the federal government should be able to fit all its laws and regulations into the same space. The constitution can be on page 1. In 1875, the federal code was less than 2000 pages. Today it is over 12 million. At the current rate we are generating new law faster than anyone could ever read it.&lt;p&gt;The law of the land should be portable.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;CJHandmer&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1991589814865654084?s=20" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;CJHandmer&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1991589814865654084?s=20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MangoToupe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It ain&amp;#x27;t regulation holding back america, it&amp;#x27;s profit. Our investors have failed us in every way imaginable, and our inability to consider any other manner of funding means we&amp;#x27;re dead in the water.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__MatrixMan__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the trouble is that regulators have done a bad job at setting themselves up to learn from their mistakes.  Regulations should  expire more quickly so their next incarnation can be better sooner.&lt;p&gt;Instead we&amp;#x27;re so afraid that the other guys will be in power in the future that we make them hard for people in the future to alter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stego-tech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While I am firmly in the “de-regulation is bad, because every single one of those is written in blood” camp, I also sympathize with startups and businesses desperately trying to innovate in a regulated market and being stymied by said bureaucracy.&lt;p&gt;What I’ve come around to is the exact opposite of most de-regulation stans: &lt;i&gt;bigger government&lt;/i&gt;. The tradeoff for regulations &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; the government is having said government shoulder the burden of helping new businesses successfully navigate said regulations quickly and efficiently. It shouldn’t be on the small business owner or startup founder to trawl through thousands of pages of texts and attempt to figure out where their business sits within them, the government should instead have an ombudsman or agent - paid with by tax dollars from successful businesses - work full-time with that business to figure things out.&lt;p&gt;Want to start a bar? Here’s the application for a liquor license, here’s the plain-language requirements for accessibility and hygiene, here’s a taxpayer-supported payroll system to ensure labor law compliance, and here’s the map of areas where you can setup shop without requiring a separate permit process.&lt;p&gt;Of course, the problem with said approach is that it requires funding, which requires more tax revenue, which means higher taxes. Under the current neoliberal, laissez-faire Capitalism system in the USA, that simply isn’t happening at present, if for no other reason than established players have captured regulatory agencies and government officials to deliberately hamstring new businesses.&lt;p&gt;Selling deregulation in business, &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; “hardtech”, is exactly what those ghouls want. Don’t take the bait. Be better, even if it’s harder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This company&amp;#x27;s business is regulatory arbitrage. Of course they have to deal with regulators. Capturing CO2 and pumping it into the ground is not a commercial enterprise. It&amp;#x27;s something done to get some sort of regulatory credit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;protocolture:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;I’ve been shocked to find that the single biggest barrier—by far—is over-regulation from the massive depth of bureaucracy.&lt;p&gt;Every regulation loving person who is exposed to a tiny fragment of how actually terrible most regulatory frameworks are immediately have this thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XorNot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good lord the tone of this article is insufferable. &amp;quot;We&amp;#x27;re saving the world! It&amp;#x27;s so unreasonable anyone ask us to verify these claims because &lt;i&gt;we&amp;#x27;re saving the world!&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hn_acc1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a reason for most regulations - most of them are written in blood.&lt;p&gt;Now sure, you may be the one &amp;quot;good corporation&amp;quot; out there, who will do things the right way and (edit: not) sell a cheap product or mislead anyone. But if the regulations aren&amp;#x27;t super stringent, others will undercut you by skimping on safety&amp;#x2F;emissions and selling a similar product for way less.&lt;p&gt;It becomes too tempting to cheat otherwise - see Dieselgate &amp;#x2F; VW, for example. Make it possible to easily profit by cheating (via relaxed regulations) and people will. Again, not you specifically (maybe), but people in general.&lt;p&gt;Since we can&amp;#x27;t tell what kind of person you are, REALLY - SBF also told people to trust him, for example - onerous regulations are required.&lt;p&gt;Plus, I love how on the main page advertising to companies, Revoy advertises 3x-to-5x better fuel efficiency - I&amp;#x27;m guessing this one is the one they&amp;#x27;ll need to back up and officially achieve or companies will dump them &amp;#x2F; sue.&lt;p&gt;In the blog post, he claims 94% less fuel and 7 mpg to 120 mpg. I don&amp;#x27;t see how 7 mpg to 120 mpg is &amp;quot;only&amp;quot; 3x-5x better fuel efficiency - it seems like it&amp;#x27;s more 17x. Sounds to me like he&amp;#x27;s exaggerating the effect in the blog to try to get sympathy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samdoesnothing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Everyone should read or at least be familiar with Joseph Tainter and his research on societal collapse.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; “It is suggested that the increased costs of sociopolitical evolution frequently reach a point of diminishing marginal returns. This is to say that the benefit&amp;#x2F;investment ratio of sociopolitical complexity follows the marginal product curve… After a certain point, increased investments in complexity fail to yield proportionately increasing returns. Marginal returns decline and marginal costs rise. Complexity as a strategy becomes increasingly costly, and yields decreasing marginal benefits.”&lt;p&gt;Government regulation and intervention are one such contributor to complexity, and as Michael Huemer demonstrates in his paper &lt;i&gt;In Praise of Passivity&lt;/i&gt; we are akin to medieval doctors administering medical procedures on society that are more likely to cause harm than create benefits.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fairly clear to me that our civilization is in decline, and it pains me to no end to see people push for &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; regulation and government intervention. &amp;quot;The patient is getting sicker, we need to let more blood! Fetch me more leaches!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The good news is that collapse, as Tainter puts it, isn&amp;#x27;t necessarily a bad thing. It&amp;#x27;s a return to less complexity, and it often brings great benefits to large swathes of people. For example, the collapse of the Roman Empire was beneficial to serfs who would actually welcome raiding parties into their villages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nocoiner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He described “the missed acceleration in sales” of pumping Liquid Smoke down old oil wells as “a direct hard cost” of the regulatory regime. That tells me all I need to know about our narrator’s intellectual honesty.&lt;p&gt;I’m open to being convinced that there are better ways of doing things, but despite what half a century of propaganda has been saying, regulations generally aren’t enacted for funsies. They’re there for a reason, specially the reason that in the absence of those regulations, commercial actors were privatizing profit at the expense of society as a whole, and democratic society made a decision to make rules to stop that from happening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;faidit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile the established players with connections can break all the laws they want, and pay zero taxes to boot.&lt;p&gt;I think the problem isn&amp;#x27;t regulation (which the current admin is aggressively destroying, e.g. with the EPA) so much as corruption - which manifests partly as critical government functions being deliberately starved of resources. Regulatory bodies should get more funding to study and approve new technologies, and there should be more subsidies available for smaller innovators to offset the R&amp;amp;D investments and application waiting periods. That wouldn&amp;#x27;t be in the interest of big polluters and their captive politicians though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;k1musab1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Edison Motors, a manufacturer of hybrid and electric semi and other trucks in Canada, is currently battling regulation. They have a series of videos on their Youtube channel going over what&amp;#x27;s been taking place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dangus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was just reading an NYT article about lead battery recyclers in Africa and how their operations are basically unregulated and are poisoning entire towns.&lt;p&gt;Things going a little slow or costing a little more is very often preferable to the alternative where you begin operations recklessly and negatively impact neighbors, sometimes irreparably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;itsdrewmiller:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; As one example, one state agency has asked Revoy to do certified engine testing to prove that the Revoy doesn’t increase emissions of semi trucks. And that Revoy must do this certification across every single truck engine family. It costs $100,000 per certification and there are more than 270 engine families for the 9 engines that our initial partners use. That’s $27,000,000 for this one regulatory item. And keep in mind that this is to certify that a device—whose sole reason for existence is to cut pollution by &amp;gt;90%, and which has demonstrably done so across nearly 100,000 miles of testing and operations—is not increasing the emissions of the truck. It’s a complete waste of money for everyone.&lt;p&gt;Wild - whoever did this should lose their job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rein.pk/over-regulation-is-doubling-the-cost</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45999038</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virgin and Qantas to ban use of portable power banks after string of fires</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/airlines-virgin-australia-qantas-ban-power-banks/106033982</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From December 1, Virgin Australia passengers will be required to keep power banks within sight and easily accessible throughout the flight. Qantas, QantasLink and Jetstar will all ban the use of power banks from December 15. Power banks are prohibited in checked-in baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998396"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/airlines-virgin-australia-qantas-ban-power-banks/106033982'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aetherspawn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The issue is that these power banks are often cheapo corporate gifts or bought out of vending machines, catering to the cheapest possible price and not certified to anything.&lt;p&gt;In this case they have crappy BMS that doesn’t have thermal sensors or even make sure the cells are balanced during charging, and no mechanical integrity so the cell can just get crushed and explode.&lt;p&gt;The solution is to require all consumer electronics with batteries to be certified (if carried on a plane or in the post), and part of that certification process needs to be mechanical; including crushing with normal levels of in-transit forces, and electrical testing; including charging the device at a high temperature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jMyles:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s nice when rules can be written in sense instead of blood.  I don&amp;#x27;t know if that&amp;#x27;s the case here.  But any fire on an aircraft is close to the latter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helithumper:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Title should be updated to Virgin Australia. The article doesn&amp;#x27;t reference Virgin Atlantic or any other Virgin brands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;musicale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As batteries pack more and more energy into smaller and smaller spaces, what could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;polishdude20:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would use a battery pack less if the outlets on the planes actually worked! On my last 4 flights I&amp;#x27;ve had outlets completely disabled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joeblubaugh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve been getting this message on international flights for the last two months already - no using power banks at any time on the plane.&lt;p&gt;At some point lithium ion battery packs are going to be completely excluded from luggage and it’ll be chaos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;etempleton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is the issue that many power banks have cheaply made batteries compared to phones, tablets, and laptops? Why power banks specifically?&lt;p&gt;If the issue is quality control is there certification that airlines might require?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jerlam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;China bans non-certified power banks on their domestic flights, even if they&amp;#x27;re not in use. And the certification authority is China-specific, they don&amp;#x27;t care about UL or any others.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.travelofchina.com&amp;#x2F;china-power-bank-ban-2025-xiaomi-3c-travel-guide&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.travelofchina.com&amp;#x2F;china-power-bank-ban-2025-xiao...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;instagib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“Australian airlines will ban the use of portable power banks… and Emirates”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ars:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The title is misleading unless you read it carefully.&lt;p&gt;They are not banning &lt;i&gt;bringing&lt;/i&gt; power banks, they are banning &lt;i&gt;using&lt;/i&gt; power banks. On the plane you have to keep the power bank on your person, but not use it.&lt;p&gt;This would be a lot more defensible if they had high-power USB-C ports by every seat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workaccount2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;five in-flight fires involving power banks on Australian or Australian-registered aircraft since 2016.&lt;p&gt;So about one every two years. Better ban everything with a battery before this gets out of control...&amp;#x2F;s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lisbbb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Doesn&amp;#x27;t every cell phone have a highly volatile, made in China battery in it as well?  What if they started banning smartphones on flights!  Oh the humanity!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JumpinJack_Cash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile you can carry a nuclear bomb on a train and nobody even bothers to check the id or ticket up until you are on board.&lt;p&gt;Irrational fear of flight strikes again, it&amp;#x27;s a very long list actually of standards that aviation has to comply with in order not to thrive but to merely exist , all because people are irrationally fearful about being suspended mid air.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s the same thing for nuclear&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AtlasBarfed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t LFP dense enough for power banks now? And far more stable&amp;#x2F;safe?&lt;p&gt;Heck, isn&amp;#x27;t Sodium Ion getting good enough now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-21/airlines-virgin-australia-qantas-ban-power-banks/106033982</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998396</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Latency (2015)</title>
      <link>https://bravenewgeek.com/everything-you-know-about-latency-is-wrong/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;” The problem with this is that there is a lot more to latency behavior than the common case. That is not noise, that is the signal. Is the 99th percentile rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000303"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bravenewgeek.com/everything-you-know-about-latency-is-wrong/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rdtsc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10 years old and still relevant. Gil created a wrk fork &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;giltene&amp;#x2F;wrk2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;giltene&amp;#x2F;wrk2&lt;/a&gt; to handle coordinated omission better. I used using his fork for many years. But I think he stopped updating it after a while.&lt;p&gt;Good load testing tools will have modes to send in data at a fixed rate regardless of other requests to handle coordinated omission. k6 for instance defined these modes are &amp;quot;open&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;closed&amp;quot;: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;grafana.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;k6&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;using-k6&amp;#x2F;scenarios&amp;#x2F;concepts&amp;#x2F;open-vs-closed&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;grafana.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;k6&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;using-k6&amp;#x2F;scenarios&amp;#x2F;concep...&lt;/a&gt;. They mention the term &amp;quot;coordinated omission&amp;quot; on the page however I feel like they could have given a nod to Gil for the inventing term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fripplebubby:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This is partly a tooling problem. Many of the tools we use do not do a good job of capturing and representing this data. For example, the majority of latency graphs produced by Grafana, such as the one below, are basically worthless. We like to look at pretty charts, and by plotting what’s convenient we get a nice colorful graph which is quite readable. Only looking at the 95th percentile is what you do when you want to hide all the bad stuff. As Gil describes, it’s a “marketing system.” Whether it’s the CTO, potential customers, or engineers—someone’s getting duped. Furthermore, averaging percentiles is mathematically absurd. To conserve space, we often keep the summaries and throw away the data, but the “average of the 95th percentile” is a meaningless statement. You cannot average percentiles, yet note the labels in most of your Grafana charts. Unfortunately, it only gets worse from here.&lt;p&gt;I think this is getting a bit carried away. I don&amp;#x27;t have any argument against the observation that that average of a p95 is not something that mathematically makes sense, but if you actually understand what it is, it is absolutely still meaningful. With time series data, there is always some time denominator, so it really means (say) &amp;quot;the p95 per minute averaged over the last hour&amp;quot;, which is or can be meaningful (and useful at a glance).&lt;p&gt;Also, the claim that &amp;quot;[o]nly looking at the 95th percentile is what you do when you want to hide all the bad stuff&amp;quot; is very context dependent. As long as you understand what it actually means, I don&amp;#x27;t see the harm in it. The author makes this point that, because a load of a single webpage will result in 40 requests or so, you are much more likely to hit a p99 and so you should really care about p99 and up - more power to you, if that&amp;#x27;s the contextually appropriate, then that is absolutely right, but that really only applies to a webserver serving webpage assets which is only one kind of software that you might be writing. I think it is definitely important to know, for one given &amp;quot;eyeball&amp;quot; waiting on your service to respond, what the actual flow is - whether it&amp;#x27;s just one request, or multiple concurrent requests, or some kind of dependency graph of calls to your service all needed in sequence - but I don&amp;#x27;t really think that challenges the commonsense notion of latency, does it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tomhow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One previous discussion at time of publication:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;A summary of how not to measure latency&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10732469"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10732469&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2015 (3 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bravenewgeek.com/everything-you-know-about-latency-is-wrong/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 01:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000303</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autocomp: An ADRS Framework for Optimizing Tensor Accelerator Code</title>
      <link>https://adrs-ucb.notion.site/autocomp</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://adrs-ucb.notion.site/autocomp</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998649</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
