<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:29:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'</title>
      <link>https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/metas-chief-ai-scientist-yann-lecun-depart-and-launch-ai-start-focused-world-models</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/metas-chief-ai-scientist-yann-lecun-depart-and-launch-ai-start-focused-world-models</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897271</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>.NET 10</title>
      <link>https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-10/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NET yet with improvements across the runtime, workloads, and languages. Stephen Toub’s performance improvements deep dive highlights the latest optimizations. _expression_] spread syntax Enhanced overload resolution: [OverloadResolutionPriority] attribute for better method selection Partial properties and constructors: Complete the partial members story with properties, constructors, and events ref struct interface implementations: Better performance with zero-allocation patterns F# 10 highlights F# 10 is a refinement release focused on clarity, consistency, and performance with meaningful improvements for everyday code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888620"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-10/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jve:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How come this quickly fell off main page and is ranked 395 right now?&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t know how trustworthy is this but it seems like it never was on top30: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hnrankings.info&amp;#x2F;45888620&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hnrankings.info&amp;#x2F;45888620&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This has 74 upvotes and posted 16hrs ago.. @dang?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nozzlegear:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a daily user of F#, I&amp;#x27;m most looking forward to the support for &amp;quot;and!&amp;quot; in computation expressions. There are a few performance-critical pieces of code I can think of that are currently wrapped up in &amp;quot;Task.WhenAll&amp;quot; &amp;#x2F; &amp;quot;Parallel.ForEachAsync&amp;quot; that I&amp;#x27;d like to extract back into &amp;quot;native&amp;quot; F# task computations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jitbit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For us, every .NET upgrade since .NET 5 has gone surprisingly smoothly and reduced CPU&amp;#x2F;RAM usage by 10–15%.&lt;p&gt;We were even able to downgrade our cloud servers to smaller instances, literally.&lt;p&gt;I wish .NET was more popular among startups, if only C# could get rid of the &amp;quot;enterpisey&amp;quot; stigma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/announcing-dotnet-10/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888620</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating a Planet on the GPU: Part 1 (2022)</title>
      <link>https://www.patrickcelentano.com/blog/planet-sim-part-1</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I liked the direction this adventure in compute shaders had taken me, I needed some new technique which could realistically deform crust at convergent plate boundaries. Could I simulate little bits of “crust” which could bump into one another, forming mountains and valleys. More in depth, I’d highly recommend this incredible talk on compute shader performance optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897122"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.patrickcelentano.com/blog/planet-sim-part-1'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jkhdigital:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The tectonics.js blog has some really incredible write-ups on how to do &lt;i&gt;proper&lt;/i&gt; simulation of plate tectonics: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;davidson16807.github.io&amp;#x2F;tectonics.js&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;news.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;davidson16807.github.io&amp;#x2F;tectonics.js&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;news.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;janpmz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish I had an intuitive understanding of how much I can do with a GPU. E.g. how many points can I move around? A simulation like this would be great for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lukan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ah yes, I dreamed about doing something like this, just with even more details ages ago, but concluded, I won&amp;#x27;t get even close to what I want, without having a big team at disposal and a supercomputer and&amp;#x2F;or a couple of universities collaborating interdisciplinary. But so far I was buisy with other things and reading about his experience unsurprisingly kind of confirms the challenge there is - mainly performance. But GPUs are on the rise and I am optimistic for the future. If the AI bubble bursts, I suppose lots of cheap GPU power will be avaiable for experiments like these and more elaborate ones. And if not, compute power&amp;#x2F;money will likely rise anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;montebicyclelo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a hobbyist, shaders is up there as one of the most fun types of programming.. Low-level &amp;#x2F; relatively simple language, often tied to a satisfying visual result. Once it clicks, it&amp;#x27;s a cool paradigm to be working in, e.g. &amp;quot;I am coding from the perspective of a single pixel&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.patrickcelentano.com/blog/planet-sim-part-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897122</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You will own nothing and be (un)happy</title>
      <link>https://racc.blog/you-will-own-nothing-and-be-unhappy/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From food delivery apps to beer subscription. People might just sigh, mutter “this bloody subscription rahhh,” and cancel it so it won’t charge them again. They won’t disappear, not unless they find something more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897016"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://racc.blog/you-will-own-nothing-and-be-unhappy/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fredkin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Subscriptions make companies lazy and it degrades the product. I&amp;#x27;m looking at you: Foundry, Adobe, Maxon, heated seats on BMWs ...&lt;p&gt;They rest on their laurels, enjoy the increased cash flow, say it allows them to work on regular updates. But this goes from being useful bug fixes, to merely shuffling the UI around, changing the fonts, introducing nonsensical features nobody asked for or can make use of, and gutting useful features for &amp;quot;streamlining&amp;quot; purposes... while longstanding bugs that actually need fixing are still unfixed.&lt;p&gt;Eventually customers become dissatisfied with the product and make up for lost features and degraded user experience with a smörgåsbord of perpetually licensed or FOSS alternatives from various competitors because they too will want to improve their cash-flow instead of being bled dry every month.&lt;p&gt;Companies that choose to offer lump-sum permanent licenses have to make a bigger effort to convince customers to upgrade, which means the product improves. Also it makes your customers more committed to your product. You should &lt;i&gt;invite&lt;/i&gt; this kind of challenge and forgo the temptation to boost cash-flow because it keeps you on your toes. Subscription-only will seem great for a while but eventually you&amp;#x27;ll atrophy and fail.&lt;p&gt;Something similar happened when software went from being released on CDs&amp;#x2F;DVDs to regular patches and downloads. Not saying we need to go back to that era, but QAs had to work harder back then because distribution was expensive. Nowadays you can release things in an unfinished and broken state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lrvick:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I own everything I rely on in my digital life and am pretty happy.&lt;p&gt;Just stop using proprietary software, as it is never possible to own it no matter how much money you pay.&lt;p&gt;FOSS solves every software need I have, and likely for most people that choose to invest in learning it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theturtlemoves:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;With subscription software, or subscription music, you&amp;#x27;re not paying for a thing, object, device. You&amp;#x27;re paying for someone&amp;#x27;s mind. The value isn&amp;#x27;t you using the app or playing the mp3. The value you pay for is someone else&amp;#x27;s mind having thought up something and creating that from pure thought stuff. The alternative is building your own from pure thought stuff, ie using your mind. You&amp;#x27;re subscribing to the creator, not the created result.&lt;p&gt;Side note: I&amp;#x27;m not such a fan of FOSS, free for all get it here no conditions and no questions asked, when we&amp;#x27;re actually just giving away our mind for free. That&amp;#x27;s fine as long as others reciprocate, but many don&amp;#x27;t. The few who reciprocate might be worth it. In essence you&amp;#x27;re trading between minds, which is the payoff then, not the money.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not for or against, just thinking out loud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;laurynas-s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Everything comes full circle.&lt;p&gt;Companies own you - they pay a subscription (your salary) to rent you. Wouldn&amp;#x27;t it be great if they could pay a one-time fee to own you forever?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;donperignon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yeah, this really hits home. Everything’s turning into a subscription lately, even simple tools that should just run on your own machine.&lt;p&gt;That’s why we built ChannelVault (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mestr.io&amp;#x2F;channelvault.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mestr.io&amp;#x2F;channelvault.html&lt;/a&gt;), as a desktop app (made with Wails + Go) to archive and search Slack workspaces locally for eDiscovery and backups. No SaaS, no recurring fees, no cloud dependency. It just runs on your computer and keeps your data with you. Trying to defy that general trend.&lt;p&gt;I miss when software felt like something you actually owned, not rented month to month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fokamul:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you don&amp;#x27;t own it, then pirating it isn&amp;#x27;t a crime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whstl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just earlier this month I was at a recording studio and no ILok plugin worked because of a connectivity issue god knows where. Plugins that did cost a lot of cash for them and were in the advertisement material of the studio.&lt;p&gt;Now even hardware things that used to work for decades need apps. Some guitar pedals need apps to operate. The first generation of those has already become paper weight: after Digitech was bought by Samsung, all the app servers died.&lt;p&gt;Apps that need a server are never for my behalf, they are purely for creating a dependency. The real feature is allowing an actual backup of the data.&lt;p&gt;Streaming has the even worse issues. It promises to pay creators, but after listening to only two bands in a month, as an experiment, no visible fraction of the $10 didn’t went to neither of those bands. It probably went to some major label, of course.&lt;p&gt;I am 100% disillusioned on anything touched by tech and see piracy as a way to resist this crap. So far only piracy has been reliable in having things work as they should when they should.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;saubeidl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Get an Android device.&lt;p&gt;Install F-Droid.&lt;p&gt;Have a wide array of apps that are free as in beer as well as in freedom.&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#x27;t &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to use rent-seeking proprietary junk. There&amp;#x27;s alternatives out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dwoldrich:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;True ownership of software requires the ability to tinker and repair via open or at least licensed source code.  But source code almost never makes sense to release for commercial products that must grow to survive and requiring funding to do that.&lt;p&gt;In the little software business I have been working towards creating, my desire was to offer a educational product for aspiring programmers as a monthly subscription.&lt;p&gt;Then, once the subscription product is paying the bills and successful, create a single seat offline version of the software and sell that as a package with a book.  The book would be a user&amp;#x27;s guide for the programming language with fun example programs to type in suitable for families and schools who don&amp;#x27;t have internet to connect to my site.&lt;p&gt;I have planned networking and sharing features for the online edition that the offline book edition wouldn&amp;#x27;t have, so there&amp;#x27;d be an incentive to pay the subscription to get all that.  Nevertheless, I feel an offline version should be made available with a perpetual license in case my company dies, taking the website and web-based programming environment with it and leaving people with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CGamesPlay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I sympathize with not owning stuff, but I don&amp;#x27;t get this part:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I bought the previous “lifetime” version of the app, but for WHAT, since I have to pay for the subscription to access the newest features.&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that&amp;#x27;s how &amp;quot;ownership&amp;quot; works. When you own something, nobody else changes it–for better or worse–out from under you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shoobiedoo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Feels like every day I run into another reason to never stop taking notes by hand in good old cursive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tpoacher:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Coming up next, at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;StallmanWasRight" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;StallmanWasRight&lt;/a&gt; ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cthulhu_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;With notes, if I ever have the need, I just use plain text &amp;#x2F; markdown files in a shared folder (I went back to the Dropbox free plan but there are plenty of alternatives). I don&amp;#x27;t have a habit of note taking though so I never had any attachment to any particular app for that.&lt;p&gt;I just wish the file sharing things didn&amp;#x27;t feel so entrenched. I think it&amp;#x27;s only a matter of time before Dropbox becomes unavailable or no longer offers a free plan (plus it&amp;#x27;s already restricted to 2 or 3 devices). Using Apple&amp;#x27;s thing feels unnatural on my Windows PC, using Microsoft&amp;#x27;s feels unnatural on my Apple devices, using Google&amp;#x27;s feels like it would require a separate app on every device and you&amp;#x27;d still end up in the (imo unnatural feeling) web interface a lot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neuroelectron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As far as I&amp;#x27;m concerned, the iPad is just a web browser with some messaging features. There is no App Store.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ifh-hn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why would you trust any company Google, Apple, Microsoft, any company like them, to be in control of stuff that&amp;#x27;s important to you.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s really no excuse if you&amp;#x27;re talking about notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Y444:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I share the general sentiment of the post. But I have to say this is one of the multitude posts exactly like that, condemning subscription based model, closed ecosystems etc. without proposing even a theoretical solution.&lt;p&gt;Yes, things are messed up, FSF is just some fringe radical micro-organisation with no real power, open source movement get EEE&amp;#x27;d by the likes of MS, hardware is locked down, your always online games stop working the moment their publishers deem them unprofitable, so what are we doing now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;teekert:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;It’s funny how “ownership” in the digital world has become an illusion.&lt;p&gt;I always say that &amp;quot;Privacy is for Nerds&amp;quot;, guess I can start adding Ownership as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aldipower:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;It’s funny how “ownership” in the digital world has become an illusion. You don’t really own your apps, your music, or even your tools anymore.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s your decision. I&amp;#x27;ve published an music album on Bandcamp. You can buy it, I&amp;#x27;ll send you a real physical tape and you can _download_ high quality FLAC you own then.&lt;p&gt;If you like to own things, you have all the possibilities.&lt;p&gt;But I agree, we maybe tend to forget about high quality stuff, if we consume conveniently low quality streaming content for example on Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shubhamjain:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Companies prey on those who forget to cancel their free trial. So far, it only happened once to me, but thankfully, I managed to get my refund.&lt;p&gt;This dark pattern has completely taken over the iOS ecosystem. Apps hide the fact that they’re paid until you’ve gone through several steps—registration, login, setup—making you believe the what you downloaded it for is just one the next screen. And then, bang, a paywall! with a “generous” 3-day free trial and a $3.99&amp;#x2F;week subscription.&lt;p&gt;I uninstall such apps immediately and leave a one-star review. I get it, devs need to make money, but there are better ways than this sleazy bs. Unfortunately, too many gurus have normalized this practice by constantly bragging how much revenue they are making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;firer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I agree with the general sentiment, but it seems fair to me that an old &amp;quot;lifetime&amp;quot; license won&amp;#x27;t have access to new features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;renewiltord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seems fine to me. Guy bought Goodnotes 5, and can use Goodnotes 5. He wants Goodnotes 6 to be included for free, but it isn&amp;#x27;t. That&amp;#x27;s life. When I got Invasion of the Vorticons, I didn&amp;#x27;t expect to get Keen Dreams for free too. Nothing new about that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timeon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Yesterday, I checked out the Goodnotes app because I’m planning to buy an iPad to give note-taking on it a try again.&lt;p&gt;I would also reconsider HW manufacturer that tries to push Newspeak &amp;quot;side-loading&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;installing&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quapster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We used to own tools that made us productive. Now we rent tools that make someone else profitable. Subscriptions are not about recurring value but recurring billing and at some point every product decision starts bending toward dependence instead of ownership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;apples_oranges:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s asymmetrical, you publish something online, immediately it is used by social networks or AIs for profit. Vice versa you get an app, it&amp;#x27;s not even yours.&lt;p&gt;I think we should strive to avoid playing this game..&lt;p&gt;But in the end i feel in this particular case, it’s ops fault. He can avoid using that app there’s a world of alternatives for writing apps and organizing apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cjfd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If others control the things that are important to you, they will at some point find a way to abuse that power. A very important point to keep in mind when making technology choices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tropicalfruit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; It’s funny how “ownership” in the digital world has become an illusion.&lt;p&gt;it&amp;#x27;s like every &amp;quot;innovation&amp;quot; now brings with it convenience at a higher cost and takes away ownership and often features&lt;p&gt;personally i&amp;#x27;m quite sick of digital nothingness. its all transient.&lt;p&gt;i want to get more into real world things that have texture, weight and permanence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://racc.blog/you-will-own-nothing-and-be-unhappy/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897016</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
