<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:32:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly all UK drivers say headlights are too bright</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1j8ewy1p86o</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly all drivers say headlights are too bright5 November 2025ShareSaveNathan BriantSouth of England ShareSaveGetty ImagesNearly all UK drivers said they thought headlights were too bright and that they have been dazzled by oncoming vehicles, according to a major study. TRL's data suggests that LED and whiter headlamps may be linked to glare and that drivers might find their whiteness harder to cope with. More on this storyHeadlights to be reviewed after drivers complain of being 'blinded' at nightOver-70s face driving ban for failing eye testsDo ultra bright headlights really blind drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966251"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1j8ewy1p86o'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lonelyasacloud:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Empirically on UK roads it&amp;#x27;s as much about the car industry getting away with selling vehicles that are too large for our roads i.e. oversized SUV&amp;#x27;s and trucks, as anything else. The combination of driver&amp;#x27;s side closer to crown, and higher mounting, mean the light&amp;#x27;s from these behemoths tend to cast more of their beams into the eye line of anyone coming the other way, particularly in smaller, lower to the ground vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dredmorbius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So ... how does a problem such as this get remedied?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m thinking a mandatory recall order &amp;#x2F; fix-it ticket for &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; offending makes&amp;#x2F;models.  The sticker shock alone might get manufacturers attention.&lt;p&gt;That and contributory liability in any associated accidents.&lt;p&gt;(Insurance costs &amp;#x2F; liability is a highly under-appreciated regulatory mechanism.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;helle253:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the longest time, i thought random drivers were flashing their brights at me all over chicago&lt;p&gt;only recently did i realize, it was the regular headlight LEDs being shined directly at me as they went over a speedbump&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fghorow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I need the brights at night for deer (in N. America) and kangaroos (in Oz).&lt;p&gt;Steering them away automagically from oncoming traffic is a better solution than abandoning them altogether.&lt;p&gt;(And yes, I do have cataracts. So oncoming lights _are_ a problem for me.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;njarboe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One of the main reasons people want&amp;#x2F;need brighter headlights is that there is much more light inside the car from screens. These don&amp;#x27;t let your eyes adjust to the dark properly. Older cars had dim green lighting for the gauges and even had a knob to adjust the brightness up and down. You could create a very dim interior instead of the huge amount of white light you get with modern cars and the multiple screens.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m happy my Tesla does a decent job of having the screen be quite dark at night but the headlights are quite bad with the horizontal cutoff style that only lights the first few feet of horizontal ahead of the car. I need to see those deer and elk on the side of the road, damn it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xzjis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are two situations where I have problems with being dazzled by headlights:
- low beams on roads that aren&amp;#x27;t flat, because they shine right into my eyes
- the high beams of cars behind me (sometimes close), which reflect in my mirrors but also off my ceiling, my dashboard, etc.&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;#x27;t necessarily have a problem with the headlights just because they&amp;#x27;re too powerful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;monegator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The headlights are most definetly not too bright.&lt;p&gt;Instead, they are too high, because the idiots with new cars rely on the automatic beam positioning which is always too slow.&lt;p&gt;Or they are fitting led bulbs in an halogen fixture and never bother to make the adjustments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ghusto:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; A study commissioned by the Department for Transport (DfT) found 97% of people surveyed found they were regularly or sometimes distracted by oncoming vehicles and 96% thought most or some headlights were too bright.&lt;p&gt;1% said they were sometimes distracted by incoming vehicles, and that was fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daemonologist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I find this problem to be most severe as a pedestrian - when my eyes have adjusted to the darkness (even if I&amp;#x27;m carrying a flashlight, it pales in comparison) and a modern car is oncoming, I cannot see _anything_.  Out here in the sticks where there are no sidewalks I can either take it on blind faith that the driver has seen and will avoid me, or I can step way off into the ditch (but not everyone has that option).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rckt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a pedestrian I can say that the headlights are too bright everywhere I visit. If a car goes up a slope and I go down it&amp;#x27;s like somebody holds a flashlight right up my eyes. I don&amp;#x27;t understand why these mandatory lights should be so bright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neilv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;TRL&amp;#x27;s data suggests that LED and whiter headlamps may be linked to glare and that drivers might find their whiteness harder to cope with.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a long-time walker in the US, anecdotally, I&amp;#x27;ve noticed some especially blinding car headlights, and they seem to be among the whiter ones.  &amp;quot;Hey, thanks for ruining my night vision &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; my sleep cycle.&amp;quot;  But I usually can&amp;#x27;t tell whether the cause of the problem is the the aiming, brightness, or temperature.  I thought headlights were carefully regulated.&lt;p&gt;(There&amp;#x27;s something about LED lights that brings out oblivious or indifferent behavior.  Maybe involving efficiency improvements, and people not reassessing requirements (e.g., when you couldn&amp;#x27;t get a too-bright light, or it would be too expensive to operate, you didn&amp;#x27;t have to think about other not-too-bright requirements).  In recent years, we got municipalities installing miserable bright white street lamps, prompting complaints from walkers and people who don&amp;#x27;t have blackout curtains anywhere that shines in at night.  And the last couple years, some individual residential properties in my very dense neighborhood are installing crazy-bright white LED floodlights outdoors, shining at sidewalks and adjacent property windows, brighter than even the new street lamps.  I&amp;#x27;m starting to see walkers at night going out into the street (which isn&amp;#x27;t very safe), just to avoid the blast.  The first too-bright property lights to appear on a block&amp;#x27;s street are very easy to spot, because they&amp;#x27;re obviously the brightest thing there.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;afandian:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The excellent Mike Harrison has a couple of good videos on YT tearing down modern headlamps:&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=7fRjMHtnShs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=7fRjMHtnShs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=DZJoPbk53ug" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=DZJoPbk53ug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(all his videos are good)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aachen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Where I live, it&amp;#x27;s customary to let other drivers know by flashing your brights when they&amp;#x27;re blinding you or if there&amp;#x27;s some other issue with their vehicle like a broken tail light or such. Maybe less now that you can&amp;#x27;t easily change the bulb yourself but as a principle&lt;p&gt;In recent years I&amp;#x27;ve started being unable to tell who&amp;#x27;s intentionally blinding traffic and who&amp;#x27;s just got misconfigured lamps (shining at eye level instead of angled down at the road). It used to be feasible to also let people know when their lights are misconfigured, I&amp;#x27;d probably decide 1 warrants a signal across several hours of driving (also because of avoiding collateral targets), but the most recent time I drove, I think there was always at least one car in sight that had the issue. It&amp;#x27;s completely constant. It was worsening a few years ago but it&amp;#x27;s really getting out of hand now, in Germany and the Netherlands at least. Some people&amp;#x27;s lights are even piercing by day! Thankfully that is quite rare yet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cpfleming:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;More that they&amp;#x27;re misaligned than too bright...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skylurk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Recently I was driving in the daytime and got temporarily blinded by a BMW SUV with its high beams on. Not sure where to draw the line, but &amp;quot;brighter than the sun&amp;quot; is too bright.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wkoszek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;US is the same. I no longer know is someone is using long-distance lights or normal lights, or whether they are wrongly adjusted. But driving at knight, especially with folks right behind you is hard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gbil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A few things I&amp;#x27;ve experienced:&lt;p&gt;- In many new cars the headlights do indeed appear as very bright. In the Xenon era the headlight height adjustment per occupancy was done automatically but at least in a few new cars I&amp;#x27;ve been in with LED headlights this is not the case and the driver needs to adjust it by hand and I&amp;#x27;m pretty sure the vast majority doesn&amp;#x27;t do that.&lt;p&gt;- Many new cars offer automated switching of high beam lights and the results vary to say the least.&lt;p&gt;- Small experience from UK highways gave me the same impression, the middle strip is not a solid one which is a huge issue when the lights from the other side blind you and I&amp;#x27;m talking about normal headlights just because of road curvature or height difference of the opposing lanes while there are no overhead  road lights.&lt;p&gt;EDIT:format&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_joel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Totally, especially the big chelsea tractors that seem to be even more direct to retina.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PunchyHamster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No wonder. We need standard both on the brightness and the height of the headlights off the ground. Try driving normal sized car or anything sporty and it&amp;#x27;s blindness central any time modern SUV shows up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oldjim798:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Desperately we need to reign in car &amp;quot;style&amp;quot; choices like this. Beyond headlights being too bright, lift kits should be banned and tint regulations should be enforced. Same with sound regulations.&lt;p&gt;Public roads are not race tracks; they are for people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alexpadula:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All new car head lights are too bright.  I miss the old warm yellow lights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crazygringo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some US context:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard 108 (FMVSS 108) regulates all automotive lighting, signalling and reflective devices in the United States.&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, FMVSS 108 was amended to allow automakers to install adaptive driver beam (ADB) headlamps on new vehicles. However, carmakers have not implemented ADB because of contradictions in the rule.&lt;p&gt;As of December 2024, FMVSS 108 has not been updated to adapt to widespread use of LED headlamps, which are criticized for being too bright and blinding other drivers. Some manufacturers have reportedly engineered headlamps to have a dark spot where they are measured according to the regulation while being over-illuminated in the rest of the field.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Federal_Motor_Vehicle_Safety_Standard_108?wprov=sfti1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Federal_Motor_Vehicle_Safety_S...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Adaptive Highbeam Assist is Mercedes-Benz&amp;#x27;s marketing name for a headlight control strategy that continuously automatically tailors the headlamp range so the beam just reaches other vehicles ahead, thus always ensuring maximum possible seeing range without glaring other road users.&lt;p&gt;This technology is also known as Adaptive Driving Beams (ADB).&lt;p&gt;Until February 2022, this technology had been illegal in the US, as FMVSS 108 specifically stated that headlamps must have dedicated high and low beams to be deemed road-legal. An infrastructure bill enacted in November 2021 included language that directs the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to amend FMVSS 108 to allow the use of this technology, and set a two-year deadline for implementing this change. In February 2022, the NHTSA amended FMVSS 108 allowing adaptive headlights for use in the US. However, the new regulations are quite different from the ones in effect in Europe and Asia and prevent car manufacturers from easily adapting their systems to the US market.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Headlamp?wprov=sfti1#Adaptive_highbeam" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Headlamp?wprov=sfti1#Adaptive_...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamustico:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think it&amp;#x27;s the brightness but the type of light.&lt;p&gt;LED white lights are the actually the problem&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HPsquared:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A lot of this is due to differing heights. There are more tall vehicles with headlights that are high off the ground, which dazzle drivers of regular cars.&lt;p&gt;Even if the dip angle is the same (1% gradient or so), this can still dazzle most people nearby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MarcScott:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think this is an area where stricter regulation would be appreciated. Just needs an additional checkbox on the regular MOT forms, and all cars would be compliant within a year.&lt;p&gt;Additionally, car designers should leave headlights and indicators alone, unless they are making the vehicles safer. The first time I encountered an oncoming car with a horizontal LED strip between the lights, I had no idea what style of vehicle was oncoming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everdrive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I understand that currently this is sort of a collective action problem, but I&amp;#x27;m a bit baffled why people ever thought they needed brighter headlights in the first place. In the city, it&amp;#x27;s so bright that you don&amp;#x27;t even need headlights to see whatsoever. When cars started automatically dimming the dash via a light sensor, there was actually a period of time where I totally forgot to turn on my headlights because things were so well lit -- even at night -- that I didn&amp;#x27;t need them whatsoever.&lt;p&gt;Out in the country, you still don&amp;#x27;t really need brighter headlights. Other cars&amp;#x27; headlights will always be visible and they have reflectors, so it&amp;#x27;s not as if you&amp;#x27;ll struggle to spot other cars. The road lines are actually reflective, so it&amp;#x27;s not as if you&amp;#x27;ll struggle to see the road lines. And generally speaking out in the country, there won&amp;#x27;t be pedestrian foot traffic, so it&amp;#x27;s not as if you need the bright lights for them.&lt;p&gt;So who are they for? I think broadly people may just not be able to avoid excess unless restricted by the facts of their environment. Allow people a plethora of calories, they&amp;#x27;ll get too fat. Allow them a plethora of entertainment, they&amp;#x27;ll drive themselves insane. And somehow .. allow them too many bright lights and they&amp;#x27;ll all just blind each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spike021:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s also like this in America.&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year I got a replacement rear-view mirror with an anti-glare coating and it&amp;#x27;s paid dividends. It helps so much at night on dark sections of road when newer cars with bright headlights are around me. Finally decided to also replace my side mirrors with ones that have a similar coating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macintux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meanwhile, brake lights and running lights are frequently too dim because of an aesthetic obsession with &amp;quot;blacking out&amp;quot; tail lights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;touristtam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ooooh so I am not the only one to swear at those blinding headlights? Interestingly (or not), I think there should be a regulated height for the headlights all private cars; I drive a B-segment type of car, and I find all those European SUVs have their headlights right at my shoulder level meaning I will always be subject to be blinded by this type of vehicle vs a similar lower car. That goes for the vans as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel the same way in America, I think there should be stricter regulations on how bright a car&amp;#x27;s headlights are allowed to be for it to be street legal. Wouldn&amp;#x27;t mind having a cap on blue-light levels in addition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1j8ewy1p86o</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966251</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Put Your Site Behind Cloudflare If You Don't Need To</title>
      <link>https://huijzer.xyz/posts/123/do-not-put-your-site-behind-cloudflare-if-you-dont</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people use Cloudflare because they have been scared into the idea that you need DDoS protection. Many people keep talking about the importance of a decentralized web, and then continue putting their site behind Cloudflare. Put your service on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965060"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://huijzer.xyz/posts/123/do-not-put-your-site-behind-cloudflare-if-you-dont'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 29 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;conradfr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well good news, the Cloudflare error page gave me a perfect PageSpeed Insights score for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;saltywhistle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use Cloudflare tunnels to expose lots of small projects to the internet that I host on my home server. I don&amp;#x27;t want my home internet to be knocked offline because someone decides to hammer my network and knock me offline for a while.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare handles caching of static resources, rate limiting, and blocking of bots with very little configuration.&lt;p&gt;Also, my ISP here in the UK doesn&amp;#x27;t provide static IP addresses, so Cloudflare allows me to avoid using a dynamic DNS service, and avoid exposing ports on my router.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;julianozen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;IMO this is terrible advice.&lt;p&gt;1. Put a moderate amount of money toward having the world&amp;#x27;s experts in uptime keep your site performing fast, and accept that occasionally your service goes down at the same time as everyone else.&lt;p&gt;2. Roll your own service, hire a large number of expensive experts to try to solve these problems yourself, and be responsible for your own outages and failures which will happen eventually and probably more frequently.&lt;p&gt;If no one is going to die from your service going down, it seems like this is a perfectly reasonable third-party dependency. And if the issue is just your contract&amp;#x27;s SLA or a financial customer, the saving that comes from using Cloudflare can probably be worked through via negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;retrofuturism:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m running a Raspberry Pi 5 at home as a lightweight web server. I put it behind `cloudflared` as to not leak my home IP address, and today I got to pay for it.&lt;p&gt;Should I just stop being paranoid about &amp;quot;leaking my IP address&amp;quot; and self-host it 100%? All I fear is that my family will have to live with degraded internet experience because some script kiddie targeted me for fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kopirgan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;At the hosting provider level don&amp;#x27;t they have such protection? I mean good ones..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;evolve2k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We mainly use  cloudflare due to the first class DNS experience.  Free and super easy to work with.&lt;p&gt;Anyone have a suggestion for an alternative? I don’t want to pay per domain but I would pay an agency fee for like 100 domains for a few hundred bucks sorta think, like migadu offers for email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tedggh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you have a blog with 100 visitors per month why would you worry about being hit by an 4-8 hours outage once every year or two? I like Cloudflare because it is easy to setup and manage and because the amount of value you get for free or just a few bucks per month can’t be matched by any other company. Sure, if my income depends on my website&amp;#x2F;service uptime then I would probably consider other options. I think for most folks that’s not the case. Just chill and wait it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stroebs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I get your gripe, but the free protection that Cloudflare offers automatically often far exceeds the effort required to thwart some random script kiddie’s attacks on my client’s Wordpress site. Add easy caching, tunnels, automated certificate management, etc. to that and it’s obvious why a lot of sites use them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bilekas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t use even close to all the services they offer, mostly just DNS and some web workers but the convenience of it as opposed to rolling my own is, excluding down time, an incredible free offering.&lt;p&gt;Way back years ago when I used to roll my own, any problems I had to fix took extremely long and painful. Could I do it again today ? Yeah sure, but I know I couldn&amp;#x27;t do a better job than Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;k__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve learned this the hard way, by putting an Arweave gateway behind Cloudflare.&lt;p&gt;The gateway was checked regularly for random data and the client would stop a download after 1MB, causing the gateway to stop sending the rest of the file.&lt;p&gt;However, Cloudflare CDN wouldn&amp;#x27;t stop when the client stop, causing the gateway to send the whole file. Some files are multiple GBs big, so I suddenly got an invoice of 600€.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spoaceman7777:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;?? It&amp;#x27;s free, and it protects you from all sorts of nasty things.&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t think of any reason not to use cloudflare. It&amp;#x27;s _dead easy_ to set up too.&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t help but think that the author understands what cloudflare actually does, or just has a poor understanding of what goes on on the internet. Probably a bit of just being in a bad mood about cloudflare being down too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exuma:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is such an idiotic article. Quite literally the exact inverse is true.&lt;p&gt;If you are a small site, it means that on the rare occurrence that CF goes down, you will have hardly any exposure to upset users.&lt;p&gt;And... if you are a small site, it probably means you&amp;#x27;re not going to be constantly logging into your shitty small VPS trying to do security audits and updates, mitigate new zero days, keep every single piece of software in your stack up to date, and CF is an excellent security blanket.&lt;p&gt;Even on top of ALL of that, you literally are going to propose to change away from a piece of software with quite literally hundreds of convenience benefits (free CDN, workers that can act as reverse proxies, security layers, instant DNS, argo routing which anecdotally seems to help, blah blah blah), because of......... a few hours of downtime in a year? really?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phoenix_x:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I actually would argue against this idea, it is quite resource intensive to keep your sites up-to-date with latest security patches (think something like webservers, openssl, tls cipher suites ...). Putting your site behind a CDN makes you not so vulnerable to these attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;osigurdson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d happily use Cloudflare&amp;#x27;s proxy as it does a good job of serving static assets. The problem I have is the root certificate that it uses doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be universally trusted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;osigurdson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; if you put your site behind a centralized service, then this service is a single point of failure&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think it is fair to characterize Cloudflare as a single point of failure, at least in the tradition sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sammy2255:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think anyone is arguing that.. the truth is that all these big companies do actually need to&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ottoflux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;this. despite all the ghost stories and war stories. it’s how apple sells you the watch to save you from that bear attack or that time you got trapped somewhere.&lt;p&gt;the stories are real, and in some cases you may need it — in most cases you don’t. and it clearly doesn’t always protect you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;herbst:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I get constantly attacked.&lt;p&gt;Usually it&amp;#x27;s big actors like Facebook, Azure and OpenAI who bombard my servers without any respect or logic. I need to update my access rules constantly to keep them away (using Cloudflare) Sometimes it&amp;#x27;s clustered traffic, more classic DDoS, from China, Russia or America. That I could easily filter with the DDos protection from my hosting (which is cheaper than cloudflare anyway)&lt;p&gt;What should I do if not Cloudflare to block with &amp;quot;complex rules&amp;quot; that is strong enough to survive hundreds of concurrent requests by big companies?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comrade1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The one time my company suffered a denial-of-service attack we were able to get support from our colo provider to stop the attack. This was years ago and our provider has been bought a couple of times and while the company has grown the staff are more remote and fewer in number so I&amp;#x27;m not sure if we&amp;#x27;d get the same support today.&lt;p&gt;So, every now and then I think about at least putting our assets on a cdn with the option of using it in the case of a ddos attack but then I see things like today and the recent Aws problems and I just get the feeling I should keep everything close.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codegeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cloudflare is still down and now its been 5+ hours. Having said that, the thing about &amp;quot;if you don&amp;#x27;t need to&amp;quot; is not that simple. FOr personal sites&amp;#x2F;blogs, I can agree but then it really doesnt matter for those. For a real business, the value of cloudflare (As centralized as it gets) is the proxy especially against attacks. The other stuff like CDN&amp;#x2F;Caching etc are bonus on top.&lt;p&gt;Unless there is a better option, just asking real businesses (no matter how small) to not use cloudflare is not an option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwaway150:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; For your small blog with one hundred visitors per month, it&amp;#x27;s probably the same: &amp;quot;no one will burn their DDoS capabilities on you!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If this is their core argument for not using CDN, then this post sounds like a terribly bad advice. Hopes and prayers do not make a valid security strategy. Appropriate controls and defenses do. The author seems to be completely missing that it takes only a few bucks to buy DDoS as a service. Sometimes people do DDoS your small blog because some random stranger didn&amp;#x27;t like something you said somewhere online. Speaking from experience. Very much the reason I&amp;#x27;m posting this with a throwaway account. If your website receives DDoS, your hosts will take down your server. Nobody wants to be in this situation even if for a personal, small blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adityar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Using cloudflare really helps cut the bandwidth bill for free for smaller self-hosted sites. That was my primary motivation - not security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeroConcerns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fun fact: a whole bunch of local (as opposed to global: the distinction here is important) Cloudflare-related outages were caused by exactly this thinking: see &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.cloudflare.com&amp;#x2F;going-bgp-zombie-hunting&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.cloudflare.com&amp;#x2F;going-bgp-zombie-hunting&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; and related HN discussion at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45775051"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45775051&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;But yeah, if you don&amp;#x27;t need Cloudflare, like, &lt;i&gt;at all&lt;/i&gt;, obviously don&amp;#x27;t use them. But, who can predict whether they&amp;#x27;re going to be DDOS-ed in advance? Fact is, most sites are better off &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; Cloudflare than without.&lt;p&gt;Until something like &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; happens, of course, but even then the question of annual availability remains. I tried to ask Claude how to solve this conundrum, but it just told me to allow access to some .cloudflare.com site, so, ehhm, not sure...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fionic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cloudflare tunnels makes it dead simple these days. Like some others in the comments it seems; I&amp;#x27;d rather Cloudflare fighting the war against hacker armies than me. Once our networks become compromised from opening our firewalls (possibly even not) our routers and IOT devices become unwillingly complicit in the army that&amp;#x27;s bringing the internet down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The lesson I learned is it&amp;#x27;s OK to put your site with Cloudflare. It&amp;#x27;s not ok to put your DNS on a registrar who is also on Cloudflare. We got locked out because our registrar is also on Cloudlfare, and now I can&amp;#x27;t even switch DNS to get the site back up. Keep your domain name registrar, DNS service provider and application infrastructure provider separately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mariopt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Enterprise self hosting is an expensive nightmare for most companies.
I think it is time to discuss multi cloud deployments to escape outages.&lt;p&gt;I am hosted on Cloudflare but my stack is also capable of running on a single server if needed, most libraries are not design with this in mind.&lt;p&gt;I’m also wondering if all these recent outages are connected to cyber attacks, the timing is strange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xacky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t consider Cloudflare part of the &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; internet anymore, instead it&amp;#x27;s a private intranet that got too big.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zikero:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If we&amp;#x27;re talking about putting static assets (like basic websites) on their CDN, or moving your backend to Workers, (etc...) you are by definition moving _away_ from single point-of-failure.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Maybe that&amp;#x27;s the core of this message. Face your fears. Put your service on the internet. Maybe it goes down, but at least not by yet another Cloudflare outage.&lt;p&gt;Well I&amp;#x27;d rather have my website going down (along with half the internet) be the concern of a billion dollar corporation with thousands of engineers - than mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thejazzman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the big error here is thinking cloud flare is DDoS when it’s an entire self contained platform with workers and pages etc..&lt;p&gt;You’d see those same errors if someone took their own site down while working on it , probably accidentally&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://huijzer.xyz/posts/123/do-not-put-your-site-behind-cloudflare-if-you-dont</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965060</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Preview Live in AI Studio</title>
      <link>https://aistudio.google.com/prompts/new_chat?model=gemini-3-pro-preview</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aistudio.google.com/prompts/new_chat?model=gemini-3-pro-preview</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967211</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Short Little Difficult Books</title>
      <link>https://countercraft.substack.com/p/short-little-difficult-books</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://countercraft.substack.com/p/short-little-difficult-books</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966435</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiment: Making TypeScript Immutable-by-Default</title>
      <link>https://evanhahn.com/typescript-immutability-experiment/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cannot find global type 'Boolean'. Cannot find global type 'Function'. Cannot find global type 'IArguments'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966018"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://evanhahn.com/typescript-immutability-experiment/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phplovesong:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds easier to just use some other compile to js languge, its not like there are no other options out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tyleo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is tangential but one thing that bothers me about C# is that you can declare a `readonly struct` but not a `readonly class`. You can also declare an `in` param to specify a passed-in `struct` can’t be mutated but again there’s nothing for `class`.&lt;p&gt;It may be beside the point. In my experience, the best developers in corporate environments care about things like this but for the masses it’s mutable code and global state all the way down. Delivering features quickly with poor practices is often easier to reward than late but robust projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;voidUpdate:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How do immutable variables work with something like a for loop?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jbreckmckye:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; If you figure out how to do this completely, please contact me—I must know!&lt;p&gt;I think you want to use a TypeScript compiler extension.&lt;p&gt;This is a bit difficult as it&amp;#x27;s not very well documented, and, the API might change with the Go rewrite.&lt;p&gt;But, you can basically invent a middleware to the compilation process.&lt;p&gt;It could quietly transform all object like types into having read-only semantics. This would then make any mutation error out, with a message like you were attempting to violate field properties.&lt;p&gt;You would need to decide what to do about Proxies though. Maybe you just tolerate that as an escape hatch (like eval or calling plain JS)&lt;p&gt;Could be a fun project!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://evanhahn.com/typescript-immutability-experiment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966018</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruby 4.0.0 Preview2 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2025/11/17/ruby-4-0-0-preview2-released/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SIZE: 23444451 SHA1: 132e450bbee3f61ed0b463ed1e2bd3a3a324339c SHA256: 0a3330dae710302e11f7f0323e83219ab3c6517984691a312c662f329c5120e1 SHA512: b5e681cc84be59148485b9a2212dcf54d61cfee27431ceddb49bedc8baa913ec8b36da43242cb4f1791b25e4bfc1dcf72b5527288a0656f2933da898d0e0b40f.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965664"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2025/11/17/ruby-4-0-0-preview2-released/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ksec:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nothing about Fibres and Async from Samuel Williams ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is 4.0.0 largely because matz created ruby 30 years ago.&lt;p&gt;matz is no longer the youngest - although he does look young,
he is already 60 years old. He also said he has a retirement
plan, e. g. avoiding a situation such as when Guido quit (or
semi-quit) from Python (due to fatigue&amp;#x2F;frustration; Guido is not 100% retired but he is also not necessarily the solo-design-dev either, so it is a bit of a semi-retirement). So we won&amp;#x27;t know how long matz will be the lead designer of ruby - and who will succeed. Which may be reason to worry depending on who it would be. Imagine DHH takes over - man, there would be an insta-exodus of people ...&lt;p&gt;So while this release does not have a lot of content as such,
one thing that is quite big, even though right now it is not,
is Ruby::Box. There are many who don&amp;#x27;t understand it. The thing
is ... I understand the use cases for it. I was not involved in
any way with regards to its design, mind you - that was mostly a
japanese-group in design. But there are objective use cases for
it.&lt;p&gt;Many years ago I recall on IRC (we oldschool people used IRC back
in the pre-discord stone age) some C# hacker said he won&amp;#x27;t use ruby
because there are no strong namespaces, that is, someone else can 
just overwrite things and then nothing works. Although I think he 
was a drama guy, and any &amp;quot;danger&amp;quot; to be minimal, objectively he has
had a point, simply because ruby had no strong concept of isolation
here. Lateron there came refinements. Now refinements are strange,
because while I think the use case makes sense, the syntax is strange.
Syntax is one huge reason why I do not use refinements; but also because
I try to avoid putting my own modifications all over the place, largely
because I&amp;#x27;d have to distribute that too, and also because modifying core
classes, while that has a use, should not be done excessively, IMO.&lt;p&gt;Ruby::Box kind of builds on that and makes the refinement use case more
generic (eventually; I am aware that right now this is not the case but
you need a transition stage. Syntax-wise Ruby::Box is also weird, so 
hopefully the syntax gets easier too, but I instantly understood the use
cases. Many people don&amp;#x27;t, in particular about 95% who demanded a name 
change away from Namespace to something else, really don&amp;#x27;t understand the
underlying use case.)&lt;p&gt;Now - making isolated per-project changes is not the only use case. For
instance, ractors could be simplified if you know that there are separate
ruby processes; ruby threads probably too. These I consider secondary 
benefits though (and yes, that may be far in the future, who knows; when
python removed its GIL though, it put ruby under pressure, aka shape-up-or-go-extinct mode).&lt;p&gt;One thing I would complain a lot is that on rubygems.org, before RubyCentral went shopify-controlled-only, that people would occupy namespaces. Such as Configuration. I wanted to have a project called Configuration so I can do Configuration.new or Configuration.parse_this_file(). This is possible of course, but when it comes to distributing code, who owns that toplevel namespace? Normally the one who occupied the name first on rubygems.org, sort of. Via Ruby::Box, it should be possible to have ownerships. This could be strong or weak; weak as a hint, aka &amp;quot;psych is owned by ruby core ownershiper but it can be modified&amp;quot;, or strong aka making it immutable. Both have use cases. Could also be both. Having this more organized would be really convenient for developers. I would not have to worry whether anyone else uses that &amp;quot;namespace&amp;quot;. And of course we need a way to query this state from within ruby code too aka, say immutable:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If psych is owned by ruby-core, continue to use it.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;psych (for yaml) is not a good example here but you can think of any other namespace where you may only want to consider some gems&amp;#x2F;projects but not others. (Again, the use case may differ between strong and weak ownership, but the thing is that this is an improvement over the prior status quo.)&lt;p&gt;There are several additional use cases to be had but I&amp;#x27;ll stop here. What I find strange is that many people who complain, don&amp;#x27;t refer to the old issues and discussions. We had discussions before refinements were added. About 80% of the people involved, DON&amp;#x27;T EVEN KNOW THESE OLD DISCUSSIONS. Either they have dementia, or these are young ruby users who never were active in the old days. It&amp;#x27;s very strange.&lt;p&gt;I am not saying all is perfect about Ruby::Box, in particular syntax-wise I&amp;#x27;d like improvements, but many people don&amp;#x27;t seem to understand the use cases, and this is very very strange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;falcor84:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Any particular changes of interest?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lloydatkinson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I didn&amp;#x27;t know Ruby has three different JITs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2025/11/17/ruby-4-0-0-preview2-released/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965664</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathematics and Computation (2019) [pdf]</title>
      <link>https://www.math.ias.edu/files/Book-online-Aug0619.pdf</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;-nG__'�ռG���`߯x��#ر������JDS=�2��W�Y�dt2ԝ5����� �=&lt;���]��� �t� �"[ endstream endobj 206 0 obj &lt;&lt; /Type /ObjStm /N 100 /First 868 /Length 1517 /Filter /FlateDecode &gt;&gt; stream xڝV�nI}�W�#H$L_�� �( ,+�xi�;v+s���$1_���bǁx&amp;+. �*����C� endstream endobj 407 0 obj &lt;&lt; /Type /ObjStm /N 100 /First 863 /Length 1621 /Filter /FlateDecode &gt;&gt; stream xڕW�n�6}߯��&amp;�//�A�MS ��F��Bk�kՒ��(_��=����Ij)�R$���9�. �{��|����5P endstream endobj 608 0 obj &lt;&lt; /Type /ObjStm /N 100 /First 866 /Length 1548 /Filter /FlateDecode &gt;&gt; stream xڍW�n�6}߯��&amp;@숤$Ji�"7�E���/}�Jܕ`ID����{FҮ/IW�a�&amp;5�g�� �8�P,���Xa�(M1�$B���D�e� �.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964816"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.math.ias.edu/files/Book-online-Aug0619.pdf'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vatsachak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I bought this book and the title is misleading.&lt;p&gt;The book should be called Mathematics and Theory of computation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;marcofloriano:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.math.ias.edu/files/Book-online-Aug0619.pdf</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964816</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Digital Ocean services down</title>
      <link>https://status.digitalocean.com/incidents/lgt5xs2843rx</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DigitalOcean Services Status x Get email notifications whenever DigitalOcean creates, updates or resolves an incident. Country code: Afghanistan (+93) Albania (+355) Algeria (+213) American Samoa (+1) Andorra (+376) Angola (+244) Anguilla (+1) Antigua and Barbuda (+1) Argentina (+54) Armenia (+374) Aruba (+297) Australia/Cocos/Christmas Island (+61) Austria (+43) Azerbaijan (+994) Bahamas (+1) Bahrain (+973) Bangladesh (+880) Barbados (+1) Belarus (+375) Belgium (+32) Belize (+501) Benin (+229) Bermuda (+1) Bolivia (+591) Bosnia and Herzegovina (+387) Botswana (+267) Brazil (+55) Brunei (+673) Bulgaria (+359) Burkina Faso (+226) Burundi (+257) Cambodia (+855) Cameroon (+237) Canada (+1) Cape Verde (+238) Cayman Islands (+1) Central Africa (+236) Chad (+235) Chile (+56) China (+86) Colombia (+57) Comoros (+269) Congo (+242) Congo, Dem Rep (+243) Costa Rica (+506) Croatia (+385) Cyprus (+357) Czech Republic (+420) Denmark (+45) Djibouti (+253) Dominica (+1) Dominican Republic (+1) Egypt (+20) El Salvador (+503) Equatorial Guinea (+240) Estonia (+372) Ethiopia (+251) Faroe Islands (+298) Fiji (+679) Finland/Aland Islands (+358) France (+33) French Guiana (+594) French Polynesia (+689) Gabon (+241) Gambia (+220) Georgia (+995) Germany (+49) Ghana (+233) Gibraltar (+350) Greece (+30) Greenland (+299) Grenada (+1) Guadeloupe (+590) Guam (+1) Guatemala (+502) Guinea (+224) Guyana (+592) Haiti (+509) Honduras (+504) Hong Kong (+852) Hungary (+36) Iceland (+354) India (+91) Indonesia (+62) Iraq (+964) Ireland (+353) Israel (+972) Italy (+39) Jamaica (+1) Japan (+81) Jordan (+962) Kenya (+254) Korea, Republic of (+82) Kosovo (+383) Kuwait (+965) Kyrgyzstan (+996) Laos (+856) Latvia (+371) Lebanon (+961) Lesotho (+266) Liberia (+231) Libya (+218) Liechtenstein (+423) Lithuania (+370) Luxembourg (+352) Macao (+853) Macedonia (+389) Madagascar (+261) Malawi (+265) Malaysia (+60) Maldives (+960) Mali (+223) Malta (+356) Martinique (+596) Mauritania (+222) Mauritius (+230) Mexico (+52) Monaco (+377) Mongolia (+976) Montenegro (+382) Montserrat (+1) Morocco/Western Sahara (+212) Mozambique (+258) Namibia (+264) Nepal (+977) Netherlands (+31) New Zealand (+64) Nicaragua (+505) Niger (+227) Nigeria (+234) Norway (+47) Oman (+968) Pakistan (+92) Palestinian Territory (+970) Panama (+507) Paraguay (+595) Peru (+51) Philippines (+63) Poland (+48) Portugal (+351) Puerto Rico (+1) Qatar (+974) Reunion/Mayotte (+262) Romania (+40) Russia/Kazakhstan (+7) Rwanda (+250) Samoa (+685) San Marino (+378) Saudi Arabia (+966) Senegal (+221) Serbia (+381) Seychelles (+248) Sierra Leone (+232) Singapore (+65) Slovakia (+421) Slovenia (+386) South Africa (+27) Spain (+34) Sri Lanka (+94) St Kitts and Nevis (+1) St Lucia (+1) St Vincent Grenadines (+1) Sudan (+249) Suriname (+597) Swaziland (+268) Sweden (+46) Switzerland (+41) Taiwan (+886) Tajikistan (+992) Tanzania (+255) Thailand (+66) Togo (+228) Tonga (+676) Trinidad and Tobago (+1) Tunisia (+216) Turkey (+90) Turks and Caicos Islands (+1) Uganda (+256) Ukraine (+380) United Arab Emirates (+971) United Kingdom (+44) United States (+1) Uruguay (+598) Uzbekistan (+998) Venezuela (+58) Vietnam (+84) Virgin Islands, British (+1) Virgin Islands, U. (+1) Yemen (+967) Zambia (+260) Zimbabwe (+263) Phone number: Change number Enter OTP: Resend OTP in: 30 seconds Didn't receive the OTP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964987"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://status.digitalocean.com/incidents/lgt5xs2843rx'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrkramer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Who is next?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;igtztorrero:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I knew it, DigitalOcean CDN is using Cloudflare behind the scenes. Why DO ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aforty:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cloudflare outage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drob518:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Dominos falling into dominos falling into dominos…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;showerst:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use DO&amp;#x27;s load balancers in a couple of projects, and they don&amp;#x27;t list Cloudflare as an upstream dependency anywhere that I&amp;#x27;ve seen. It&amp;#x27;s so frustrating to think you&amp;#x27;re clear of a service then find out that you&amp;#x27;re actually in their blast radius too through no fault of your own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giancarlostoro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So yesterday Azure got hit hard, today CF and DO are down, bad week or something else?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;archerx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have two projects on DO using droplets and they are still running fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TechRemarker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes all sites showing the CloudFlare error due to the massive outage.  Seems their outages are getting more frequent and taking down the internet in new ways each time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jsheard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They don&amp;#x27;t name names but it&amp;#x27;s probably due to the ongoing Cloudflare explosion. I know the DigitalOcean Spaces CDN is just Cloudflare under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://status.digitalocean.com/incidents/lgt5xs2843rx</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964987</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Fear really drives him': is Alex Karp of Palantir the world's scariest CEO?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/nov/18/fear-really-drives-him-is-alex-karp-of-palantir-the-worlds-scariest-ceo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Composite: Guardian Design; Kevin Dietsch;NurPhoto;Bloomberg/Getty Images‘Fear really drives him’: is Alex Karp of Palantir the world’s scariest CEO. Does this make Karp the scariest CEO in the world. Karp grew up very much feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965796"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/nov/18/fear-really-drives-him-is-alex-karp-of-palantir-the-worlds-scariest-ceo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jebarker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Fear really drives him&lt;p&gt;This is very common in the defense and national security industries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wiz21c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can assure you its tai chi stance on the picture is absolutely wrong.&lt;p&gt;arms way too open, body weight on both legs, right arm should not be bended, distance between two feet is way to long, left hand should be pointing up, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ecshafer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Palantir is along with SpaceX, Anduril, and a few others some of the most important companies in America. They are the ones that are pushing America forward. Not selling ads. But upsetting the incumbents that are undermining the DoD and national security, and making real technical progress. These are the companies that if it comes to war are going to be pushing us forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;devJdeed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;this guy allows other people to invest money into killing others, mostly it&amp;#x27;a arabs so far but yet again he looks like a chosen one. I hope his shit crashes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andsoitis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; African American artist mother&lt;p&gt;I had no idea Alex Karp was black.&lt;p&gt;Anyhow:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; On CNBC’s Squawk Box, he shook both fists simultaneously as he railed against short sellers betting against Palantir, whose share price has climbed nearly 600% in the past year: “It’s super triggering,” he complained. “Why do they have to go after us?”&lt;p&gt;This and a few other sections make me wonder how much introspection the guy has and whether he ever concedes that he is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0_____0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The US&amp;#x27;s power comes from its ability to project organized violence? What was Vietnam then? And what would have come of the Vietnam era if people could be individually and effortlessly targeted in their daily lives for going against it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JohnFen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fear is the most dangerous of human emotions. Fear makes us stupid, compliant, and cruel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/nov/18/fear-really-drives-him-is-alex-karp-of-palantir-the-worlds-scariest-ceo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965796</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
