<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:28:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Erlang Meets Idris: Cure Programming Language</title>
      <link>https://cure-lang.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cure Programming Language v0. A strongly-typed, dependently-typed programming language that brings mathematical correctness guarantees to the battle-tested BEAM virtual machine. Build systems where verification matters more than convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832954"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://cure-lang.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h4kor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is 100% LLM generated; website, documentation and tutorials. 
There is no link to downloads or a repository. No way to use anything.&lt;p&gt;Why should anyone care about this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCUMstlyHarmls:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Curious what the E, e, e, L and G stand for in the logo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;josefrichter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How does this compare to Gleam, in terms of goals, features, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cure-lang.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832954</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I am deeply integrating Emacs</title>
      <link>https://joshblais.com/blog/how-i-am-deeply-integrating-emacs/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;config/hypr/scripts/emacs-launcher '(progn (select-frame-set-input-focus (selected-frame)) (find-file "~/org/notes. config/hypr/scripts/emacs-launcher '(progn (select-frame-set-input-focus (selected-frame)) (=calendar))' bind = $mainMod, N, exec, ~/. config/hypr/scripts/emacs-launcher '(progn (select-frame-set-input-focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832341"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://joshblais.com/blog/how-i-am-deeply-integrating-emacs/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;voidUpdate:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I keep hearing about emacs and how awesome it is, is there a good resource for a complete beginner who is familiar with programming but not necessarily editors like vim or emacs, just to get started?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This may sound strange, but I actually think we need just ... one editor.&lt;p&gt;Now, this is not a &amp;quot;we need to favour vim over emacs&amp;quot;. I think this is a stupid war, the vim versus emacs war.&lt;p&gt;What I mean is ... basically most editors do almost the same exact thing. They look at some buffer for a file and help the user modify this. There is a finite number of operations possible. Why do people keep on re-implementing basic things here? Why can it not be solved once and for all and then everyone uses that implementation?&lt;p&gt;We really should have that; and then people can decide ON THEIR OWN what kind of editor they want to use. Many years ago I started with crimson editor as my main editor on windows. I have since then hopped to many other editors. My favourite one was oldschool bluefish in gtk2. I am not saying it was perfect, but I found it much easier to go on my poor brain than e. g. remembering all vim shortcuts. But, it would need xorg + gtk2, so if that is not available, then I can not edit things - that&amp;#x27;s bad. That was (and still is) also one reason why I use e. g. nano. But this in turn requires ncurses and I hate ncurses with a passion (nano is great though, I can recommend it for quick ad-hoc editing; for larger things it is not quite as good, but if you have to just change some value in a config file, nano is really great).&lt;p&gt;Even then I used only like 20% of what bluefish offered (the newer bluefish releases are also nowhere near as good as the old releases, also because GTK really sucks nowadays). I&amp;#x27;d like to cherry-pick on my editor and declare what I want it to be, without needing to implement everything on my own. Why can&amp;#x27;t we transition into this? Why do we need to reimplement everything almost from scratch? That just makes no sense to me.&lt;p&gt;We live in the age where AI autogenerates code (which they heavily drew from stealing people&amp;#x27;s code). Why can&amp;#x27;t AI autogenerate the best, most perfect editor&amp;#x2F;IDE?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;globular-toast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The bit about enabling org capture from &amp;quot;outside&amp;quot; Emacs is really interesting. It&amp;#x27;s been so important for me to have a system that enables me to make notes, todos etc. with extremely low friction. At any time, without my hands leaving the keyboard, I can take a note that is either directly attached to what I&amp;#x27;m currently working on, arbitrarily file it somewhere if I know where it should go, or just let it go into the general inbox (the other part of the system is actually getting to those things in the inbox at some point). Up until this point I have had to be &amp;quot;in&amp;quot; Emacs, though, which accounts for most of my time, but not all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;omnicognate:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Re EXWM and:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Emacs is single threaded, therefore if anything in the system hangs, the whole system hangs&lt;p&gt;For development work I haven&amp;#x27;t found this to be an issue. Generally when coding I use very few X apps - pretty much just a web browser and maybe occasionally a PDF preview or docs browser. I don&amp;#x27;t think I&amp;#x27;ve ever had a problem with the single-threaded behaviour blocking window management there. (And as an aside, while proper threading would be nice for things that actually should be concurrent - such as EXWM&amp;#x27;s duties as a window manager - I &lt;i&gt;massively&lt;/i&gt; prefer emacs&amp;#x27; synchronous processing of input over the JetBrains horror of pressing a key combination and then having to wait for some asynchronous UI behaviour to occur, with different outcomes depending on whether the next keypress occurs before or after the UI behaviour the first one triggered.)&lt;p&gt;For other, more GUI-focused activities I just run a separate (wayland) session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hsbauauvhabzb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like eMacs but I feel the whole workflow is wrong. Buffers are a stacked tiled window manager inside your window manager. Your browser is a tabbed window manager, and many other applications are also window managers. I wish any sub buffer of any application was for all intents and purposes a dedicated window, so the WM can take care of the rest. Maybe it’s an adjustment that I could make in my workflow, but a global solution would have been nice. Too late now I guess though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sim04ful:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The more I learn about emacs the more I feel we took the wrong fork on road in terms of the desktop metaphor decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scandox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This is how world class athletes, musicians, artists, writers, and of course programmers take what is in their mind and translate it into reality.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; It is the ultimate sharpening of the axe before chopping the tree[1]&lt;p&gt;But if part of our axe sharpening is listening to music, reading email, catching up with your feeds and so on then perhaps we need to take a step back and ask if we&amp;#x27;re just invading our working thought-space with boondoggles.&lt;p&gt;[1] &amp;quot;Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.” - apparently Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joshblais.com/blog/how-i-am-deeply-integrating-emacs/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832341</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the hell have you built</title>
      <link>https://wthhyb.sacha.house/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wthhyb.sacha.house/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832803</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Flutter_compositions: Vue-inspired reactive building blocks for Flutter</title>
      <link>https://github.com/yoyo930021/flutter_compositions</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flutter Compositions Vue-inspired reactive building blocks for Flutter Flutter Compositions brings Vue 3's Composition API patterns to Flutter, enabling fine-grained reactivity and composable logic with a clean, declarative API. dart'; import 'package:flutter_compositions/flutter_compositions. value++, child: const Icon(Icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832198"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/yoyo930021/flutter_compositions'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SquareWheel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Should this be a &lt;i&gt;Show HN&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/yoyo930021/flutter_compositions</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 06:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832198</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
