<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:31:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>The Peaceful Transfer of Power in Open Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/11/the-peaceful-transfer-of-power-in-open-source-projects/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They become tyrannical despots, lashing out at their own volunteers. They execute takeovers of community projects. They demand fealty and tithes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45979232"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/11/the-peaceful-transfer-of-power-in-open-source-projects/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 15 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ferguess_k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think it depends on what kind of OSP they are.&lt;p&gt;For example, Linux kernel is definitely widely used and I&amp;#x27;d argue that it is one of the few things that have achieved globally acknowledgement and usage, i.e. a &amp;quot;human&amp;quot; thing, as the aliens said. Such a project would naturally require some strong leader (Linus is famous for being straightforward and none-BS) and a bunch of able enforcers (maintainers). I don&amp;#x27;t think we are short of able enforcers, although the total number of Linux maintainers who understand the full picture may be small, but we don&amp;#x27;t need a lot of them anyway. The key is to elect an equally good and strong leader, without which the project may degrade slowly, like all human projects. I&amp;#x27;d hope someone with both the technical knowledge as well a strong character to take over whence Linus retires -- but Linus is only 55 years old so I believe he and the community still have many years to search for the next leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asim:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have tried to hand off a project for years with many failed attempts. In the case of Mastodon they have some very high profile names that effectively want to relive the glory days of Twitter and take it over. In the case of smaller projects, you have to very diligent when deciding who to hand off too. I don&amp;#x27;t think there are great answers here.&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;go-micro.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;go-micro.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ziml77:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sorry for commenting about the page itself, but did anyone else have to go into reader mode to read it? The page is bouncing up and down, the text is extremely blurry and varying in size letter by letter, and every element seems randomly slanted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Linux will be the ultimate test for this. Linus will eventually retire or die. The individual that takes it from there sets the future for all open source. I cannot imagine open source existing if the kernel maintenance is squandered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theoldgreybeard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why would I care when I am dead.  It&amp;#x27;s just software and &amp;quot;bloody civil wars&amp;quot; is not something that happens over software governance.  Oh no, some people might say mean things to eachother and someone might fork the software.  Big Deal.  Figure it out for yourselves like adults.  Remember, the license says AS-IS and NO WARRANTY.  Use at your own risk.  I don&amp;#x27;t owe you anything.  If you want work done on it - do it yourself or pay me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;purple_turtle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I&amp;#x27;m begging project leaders everywhere - please read up on the social contract and the consent of the governed.&lt;p&gt;I do not need consent as I am not governing anyone like king or president governs.&lt;p&gt;If someone is using my project they are also not really entitled to anything, beyond what stated in license and similar documents if any.&lt;p&gt;If they dislike it, they can fork my project and go away.&lt;p&gt;If someone wants to be entitled to anything, they are free to make a contract and pay for service they desire. But while many are happy to demand nearly noone is willing to help. Or even fork project.
Instead they make entitled demand and treat open source developers as servants or slaves or their pets.&lt;p&gt;No, you are not entitled to your preferred governance model to be used in my software project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;muragekibicho:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;#x27;or if reading is too woke&amp;#x27; Amazing piece and oddly relatable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bodhi_mind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The whole “why I contribute to open source” has been on my mind lately after I published my first open source project and it’s gotten moderate attention from the data engineering community (200 GitHub stars):&lt;p&gt;TinyETL - Fast, zero-config ETL in a single binary
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;alrpal&amp;#x2F;TinyETL" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;alrpal&amp;#x2F;TinyETL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The transition from being the sole architect of “my” project into more of a maintainer, organizer, director, has been a unique experience and interesting to reflect on.&lt;p&gt;What’s the future hold? I really don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gassi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I run a semi-popular open source project (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;romm.app&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;romm.app&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;), and this is a topic we tend to revisit regularly. While there will always have to be &lt;i&gt;someone&lt;/i&gt; at the top who owns the project, we&amp;#x27;ve tried to organize ourselves in a way that should prevent a complete hostile takeover:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  * Gihub organization is co-owned (2 Owners)
  * I own the domain, they run the Discord server
  * Finances are handled by https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;opencollective.com&amp;#x2F;
  * All code is GPL or AGPL licensed
  * Name and branding are owned by The Project itself, or CC-BY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
In the event either (or both) of us step away, temporarily or permanently, the core team is has the power and permissions to continue running the project indefinitely. While I would be able to remove them as co-owner on Github in a takeover scenario, I won&amp;#x27;t have access to the finances or the Discord community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;szszrk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I struggle to find out who is this aimed at, really.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s clear there is a lot of drama in Opensource projects lately, but there are countless projects where the maintainer would be thrilled to have one or two people that would actually want to invest their time into reviewing some code with him. Day they find others pumped by their work and willing to invest some time would be celebrated with cake each year.&lt;p&gt;Just because someone else&amp;#x27;s broken CI pipeline does &amp;quot;Several thousands of downloads of NPM package per day&amp;quot; should not make you feel bad that you have not &amp;quot;Build an organisation which won&amp;#x27;t crumble&amp;quot; yet.&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s backwards. You want to help those people? Create that organization. Create another Apache org and take over important projects that need that.&lt;p&gt;It really feels like banging the wrong drum. Just another person having a broken curl setup and blaming Daniel Stenberg for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smashah:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There should be P.E Firms run by OSS devs concentrating in being the succession and exit plan for OSS founders while charging big tech cos ($1bn+) for support.&lt;p&gt;Might sound a bit evil at first but it is the way to bolster the whole xkcd issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bArray:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Which is why I am delighted that the Mastodon project has shown a better way to behave.&lt;p&gt;I think we should hold our breath for a moment. The wars waged over concession don&amp;#x27;t always happen immediately, and not always involving the expected parties [1].&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Today, we’re marking another momentous step in this ongoing process as our Founder and now former CEO Eugen Rochko begins his transition into a new role with Mastodon. We are thrilled that he will continue on in an advisory role with our team.&lt;p&gt;The problem with the undead King is if they ever feel the need to exercise any form of power.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Battle_of_Hastings" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Battle_of_Hastings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alphazard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Comparing software projects to governments usually produces the wrong intuition.  The stakes are much lower, and risk tolerance should be much higher with a software project.  Dictators are good, forks are good, even conflict can be good because it means people care.  On the contrary, democracy leads to mediocre decisions, designs by committee, and sluggishness.&lt;p&gt;Unlike with a government, you can easily walk a way from a software project or create a fork.  There is almost zero friction to &amp;quot;voting with your feet&amp;quot; in software and it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lapcat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure there&amp;#x27;s much utility in this article. It feels like the point was mainly to dunk on Ruby on Rails and WordPress without mentioning them by name. And such dunking may be justified, but it&amp;#x27;s not particularly interesting and won&amp;#x27;t lead to an enlightening discussion.&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#x27;s crucial to point out, though, that Eugen Rochko&amp;#x27;s motives for stepping down were explicitly &lt;i&gt;personal&lt;/i&gt;. He&amp;#x27;s still quite young, Mastodon itself is still quite young, less than a decade old, and Rochko could have continued in his position for some time. He stepped down because he &lt;i&gt;wanted&lt;/i&gt; to step down, not for some selfless reason like succession planning. And I&amp;#x27;m not criticizing Rochko for that; he can live his life the way he chooses and do what makes him happy, avoid what he finds unpleasant. And he&amp;#x27;s to be commended for the mentioned peaceful transition of power. However, there&amp;#x27;s no inherent reason why Matt Mullenweg or DHH should step down just because Rochko stepped down; their personal goals are obviously different. And Rochko behaved very differently while he was still leading Mastodon.&lt;p&gt;The author clearly wants those other leaders to step down because he doesn&amp;#x27;t like those leaders and how they behave, not because of some abstract idea of succession planning. I don&amp;#x27;t think the metaphor of a king&amp;#x27;s death is apt here, because nobody has died or become incapacitated. They&amp;#x27;ve just become overtly contemptible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JimDabell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A long-standing succession plan also reduces the likelihood of a supply-chain attack. A fed-up maintainer deciding to quit is the worst possible time to pick a successor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/11/the-peaceful-transfer-of-power-in-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45979232</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Smartphone, Their Rules: App Stores Enable Corporate-Government Censorship</title>
      <link>https://www.aclu.org/news/free-speech/app-store-oligopoly</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although most installations default to getting apps from the Play Store, the availability of sideloading means that even if Google censors apps in the Play Store, people can still install them. Unfortunately that is all set to change with a recent Google announcement that it will block apps from “certified Android” devices (which is nearly all Android phones) unless they come from what Google calls a “verified developer. ” This means that the common Android user trying to install an app will have to get Google’s blessing: does this app come from someone that Google has “verified”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45979297"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.aclu.org/news/free-speech/app-store-oligopoly'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lenerdenator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is why a real, committed FLOSS OS is needed for smartphones. Something like how Debian works. You have a non-commercial entity steering the project, it has a governance model, and the goal is to create something that ultimately, no one owns or can take full control over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fithisux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The title is correct. The landscape became dangerous because governments withdraw from regulating the space unleashing big corporates on citizen&amp;#x27;s privacy and options.&lt;p&gt;It is a Corporate-Government dystopia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mosura:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most people on here should consider the opposite extreme: a free for all where millions of idiots are carrying devices where they can install and run anything on a device where arbitrary radio signals can be transmitted and received at will under software control. Once you accept that would be ridiculous then the question becomes where to draw the line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viktorcode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How about app creators sue DOJ and&amp;#x2F;or Apple if the law is on their side?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mark_l_watson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I get some push back from a few tech friends because I avoid using apps (except for things like Chess game apps). I can’t say for sure that preferring web versions of services helps with censorship, but it can’t hurt.&lt;p&gt;Using web versions, not apps, is important because companies keep user device statistics and if enough people insist in using web versions, the the web will continue to be at least partially supported by big tech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chaostheory:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, there is the issue of security. While the app stores are also far from perfect on that issue, it’s still better than the Wild West given the sheer number of apps they have to do deal with. Then there’s also the issue of hosting and deploying the client app. Convenience has a cost&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AlgebraFox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While censorship is one thing, they forgot another overlooked ability of these app stores: pushing unwanted apps&amp;#x2F;services to our personal devices without our knowledge.The fact that the majority of people don’t care about this censorship and backdoors makes me think we don’t really appreciate the concept of freedom, and maybe we are okay with being slaves—at least until we cannot take it anymore. Maybe that’s why history repeats itself every few decades to remind us about these values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;isodev:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m very happy to see a US organisations picking this up finally. Apple&amp;#x2F;Google clearly want to fight this on a country by country basis so they can stretch it until forever. Hope the pressure results in meaningful changes for all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;analog8374:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When is censorship ok?&lt;p&gt;We have moderators, here in hn. We also have them in reddit.&lt;p&gt;So sometimes we like censorship and sometimes we don&amp;#x27;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.aclu.org/news/free-speech/app-store-oligopoly</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45979297</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The $1k AWS Mistake</title>
      <link>https://www.geocod.io/code-and-coordinates/2025-11-18-the-1000-aws-mistake/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even better, Gateway Endpoints for S3 are completely free. VPC Endpoints are your friend. Always validate your assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45977744"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.geocod.io/code-and-coordinates/2025-11-18-the-1000-aws-mistake/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 23 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whalesalad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wait till you encounter the combo of gcloud parallel composite uploads + versioning + soft-delete + multi-region bucket - and you have 500TB of objects stored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tlaverdure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Abolish NAT Gateways. Lean on gateway endpoints, egress only internet gateways with IPv6, and security groups to batten down the hatches. All free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wulfstan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This happens so often that the S3 VPC endpoint should be setup by default when your VPC is created. AWS engineers on here - make this happen.&lt;p&gt;Also, consider using fck-nat (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fck-nat.dev&amp;#x2F;v1.3.0&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fck-nat.dev&amp;#x2F;v1.3.0&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) instead of NAT gateways unless you have a compelling reason to do otherwise, because you will save on per-Gb traffic charges.&lt;p&gt;(Or, just run your own Debian nano instance that does the masquerading for you, which every old-school Linuxer should be able to do in their sleep.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fergie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it possible for hobbyists to set a hard cut off for spending? Like, &amp;quot;SHUT EVERYTHING DOWN IF COSTS EXCEED $50&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;torginus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I&amp;#x27;ve been using AWS since around 2007. Back then, EC2 storage was entirely ephemeral and stopping an instance meant losing all your data. The platform has come a long way since then.&lt;p&gt;Personally I miss ephemeral storage - having the knowledge that if you start the server from a known good state, going back to that state is just a reboot away. Way back when I was in college, a lot of out big-box servers worked like this.&lt;p&gt;You can replicate this on AWS with snapshots or formatting the EBS volume into 2 partitions and just clearing the ephemeral part on reboot, but I&amp;#x27;ve found it surprisingly hard to get it working with OverlayFS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;auggierose:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Are there any cloud providers that allow a hard cap on dollars spent per day&amp;#x2F;week&amp;#x2F;month? Should there not be a law that they have to?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stef25:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Made a similar mistake like this once. While just playing around to see what&amp;#x27;s possible I upload some data to the AWS algo that will recommended products to your users based on everyone&amp;#x27;s previous purchases.&lt;p&gt;I uploaded a small xls with uid and prodid columns and then kind of forgot about it.&lt;p&gt;A few months later I get a note from bank saying your account is overdrawn. The account is only used for freelancing work which I wasn&amp;#x27;t doing at the time, so I never checked that account.&lt;p&gt;Looks like AWS was charging me over 1K &amp;#x2F; month while the algo continuously worked on that bit of data that was uploaded one time. They charged until there was no money left.&lt;p&gt;That was about 5K in weekend earnings gone. Several months worth of salary in my main job. That was a lot of money for me.&lt;p&gt;Few times I&amp;#x27;ve felt so horrible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4gotunameagain:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m still adamant about the fact that the &amp;quot;cloud&amp;quot; is a racket.&lt;p&gt;Sure, it decreases the time necessary to get something up running, but the promises of cheaper&amp;#x2F;easier to manage&amp;#x2F;more reliable have turned out to be false. Instead of paying x on sysadmin salaries, you pay 5x to mega corps and you lose ownership of all your data and infrastructure.&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;#x27;s bad for the environment, bad for industry practices and bad for wealth accumulation &amp;amp; inequality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hikikomori:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Saved &amp;gt;120k&amp;#x2F;month by deploying some vpc endpoints and vpc peering (rather than tgw).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ryanjshaw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a bootstrapped dev, reading stories like these gives me so much anxiety.  I just can’t bring myself to use AWS even despite its advantages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Havoc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;These sort of things show up about once a day between the three big cloud subreddit. Often with larger amounts&lt;p&gt;And it’s always the same - clouds refuse to provide anything more than alerts (that are delayed) and your only option is prayer and begging for mercy.&lt;p&gt;Followed by people claiming with absolute certainty that it’s literally technically impossible to provide hard capped accounts to tinkerers despite there being accounts like that in existence already (some azure accounts are hardcapped by amount but ofc that’s not loudly advertised).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just curious but if you are already on Hetzner, why not do the processing also there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrewstuart:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why are people still using AWS?&lt;p&gt;And then writing “I regret it” posts that end up on HN.&lt;p&gt;Why are people not getting the message to not use AWS?&lt;p&gt;There’s SO MANY other faster cheaper less complex more reliable options but people continue to use AWS. It makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;belter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Talking how the Cloud is complicated, and writing a blog about what is one of the most basic scenarios discussed in every Architecture class from AWS or from 3rd parties...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mgaunard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you want to avoid any kind of traffic fees, simply don&amp;#x27;t allow routing outside of your VPC by default.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;krystalgamer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ah, the good old VPC NAT Gateway.&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to have experienced all of the same mistakes for free (ex-Amazon employee). My manager just got an email saying the costs had gone through the roof and asked me to look into it.&lt;p&gt;Feel bad for anyone that actually needs to cough up money for these dark patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dabiged:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I made the same mistake and blew $60k.&lt;p&gt;I have never understood why the S3 endpoint isn&amp;#x27;t deployed by default, except to catch people making this exact mistake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;merpkz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; AWS charges $0.09 per GB for data transfer out to the internet from most regions, which adds up fast when you&amp;#x27;re moving terabytes of data.&lt;p&gt;How does this actually work? So you upload your data to AWS S3 and then if you wish to get it back, you pay per GB of what you stored there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viraptor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The service gateways are such a weird thing in AWS. There seems to be no reason not to use them and it&amp;#x27;s like they only exist as a trap for the unaware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CjHuber:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does Amazon refund you for mistakes, or do you have to land on HN frontpage for that to happen?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nrhrjrjrjtntbt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;NAT gateway probably cheap as fuck for Bezos &amp;amp; co to run but nice little earner. The parking meter or exit ramp toll of cloud infra. Cheap beers in our bar but $1000 curb usage fee to pull up in your uber.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;harel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You probably saved me a future grand++. Thanks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fragmede:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just $1,000? Thems rookie numbers, keep it up, you&amp;#x27;ll get there (my wallet won&amp;#x27;t, ow).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.geocod.io/code-and-coordinates/2025-11-18-the-1000-aws-mistake/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45977744</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proxmox Virtual Environment 9.1 available</title>
      <link>https://www.proxmox.com/en/about/company-details/press-releases/proxmox-virtual-environment-9-1</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proxmox Virtual Environment 9. Highlights in Proxmox Virtual Environment 9. Availability Proxmox Virtual Environment 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980005"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.proxmox.com/en/about/company-details/press-releases/proxmox-virtual-environment-9-1'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hendersoon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So with support for OCI container images, does this mean I can run docker images as LXCs natively in proxmox? I guess it&amp;#x27;s an entirely manual process, no mature orchestration like portainer or even docker-compose, no easy upgrades, manually setting up bind mounts, etc. It would be a nice first step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmward01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Watching hypervisors slowly improve over the last few years has been amazing. They aren&amp;#x27;t quite to the point that I will install them under any new hardware I buy and then put my daily driver OS on top, but they are very close. I think a strong focus on creating &amp;#x27;the OS under your OS&amp;#x27; experience seamless could open up a lot more here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;veidr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nah. Incus.&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but I bought Proxmox 7, but it is not comparable. Incus does everything (and more) with better interface, WAY better reliability, and also not like a hundred EUR or whatever. (100 EUR is fine with me if better, but not if &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; better...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throw0101c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Proxmox (and XCP-ng?) seems to be &amp;quot;the&amp;quot; (?) popular alternative to VMware after Broadcom&amp;#x27;s private equity-fuel cash grab.&lt;p&gt;(Perhaps if you&amp;#x27;re a Microsoft shop you&amp;#x27;re looking at Hyper-V?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.proxmox.com/en/about/company-details/press-releases/proxmox-virtual-environment-9-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980005</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Stay Sane in a World That Rewards Insanity</title>
      <link>https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/how-to-stay-sane-in-a-world-that-rewards-insanity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one who tribalized every issue found a ready-made community that validated every prior. That audience expects consistency. Start by diversifying your information diet in ways that feel actively uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980106"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/how-to-stay-sane-in-a-world-that-rewards-insanity'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lkey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Capital &amp;#x27;T&amp;#x27; Truth isn&amp;#x27;t correlated to the American political &amp;#x27;center&amp;#x27; or &amp;#x27;liberalism&amp;#x27; or the maximally &amp;#x27;nuanced&amp;#x27; position. It&amp;#x27;s insane to think that it would be.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;#x27;manufactured consent&amp;#x27;, &amp;quot;liberal&amp;quot; as a slur...&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m going to go out on a limb here and say that Joan has lost relationships with her lefty friends because she doesn&amp;#x27;t think that the apartheid state of Israel is committing a genocide on the Palestinians using American weapons.&lt;p&gt;I also believe she doesn&amp;#x27;t want to say that directly, hence this nebulous essay.&lt;p&gt;Relatedly, y&amp;#x27;all should read &lt;i&gt;One Day, Everyone Will Have Always Been Against This&lt;/i&gt;, by Omar El Akkad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lazide:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The challenge is that short-term incentives can easily lead to long-term problems, as the short-term min&amp;#x2F;maxing can leave you stuck in a particular global minimum, with no clear way out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rsynnott:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;  But exposing yourself to articulate versions of positions you oppose does something valuable: it makes you realize that intelligent people can disagree with you without being monsters or morons.&lt;p&gt;The idea that being articulate implies intelligence and&amp;#x2F;or sanity is very common, but really a bit weird. You can find plenty of articulate defences of, say, flat earth theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HeinzStuckeIt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I do wonder about the claim, “You end up in a world where changing your mind becomes impossible because you&amp;#x27;ve built your entire identity around being right”. It regularly happens that social-media personalities do a 180° turn on some issue (e.g. pro-Ukraine to anti-Ukraine or vice versa) and still keep their following and ability to monetize it.&lt;p&gt;Social media is so full of parasocial relationships that a lot of followers are in love with an influencer’s personality (or, often, the sponsor relationships whose merchandise they hawk), not their views or factual content. So, the influencer can completely change his mind about stuff, as long as he still has the engaging presentation that people have come to like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/how-to-stay-sane-in-a-world-that-rewards-insanity</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980106</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do the pros get someone to leave a cult?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/nov/19/how-to-leave-a-cult-experts-intervention</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What Ryan and Kelly do is unusual: they help people leave cults. They say they have even been hired by government agencies, and that some cults they have investigated have left them genuinely afraid for their lives. Instead, Ryan and Kelly will act covertly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978813"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/nov/19/how-to-leave-a-cult-experts-intervention'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delichon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  cult (noun): A religion or religious sect generally considered to be extremist or false, with its followers often living in an unconventional manner under the guidance of an authoritarian, charismatic leader -- American Heritage Dictionary
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Without the &amp;quot;generally considered to be extremist or false&amp;quot; it would be quite hard to even identify a cult. It&amp;#x27;s mostly used as way to slur a disfavored group. It&amp;#x27;s an element of a Russell conjugation, like I am part of a spiritual awakening, you belong to a religious sect, they are in a mind-control cult.&lt;p&gt;I was raised as a Jew. I consider that to be a cult, if one of the milder religious ones. My peewee football team was a cult. I belonged to a cultic political party, and worked for a startup that closely met the definition.&lt;p&gt;So getting someone to leave a cult is going to be the same as getting them to forsake any other community, just with the added coercion of social acceptability. There&amp;#x27;s no magic, no brain unwashing, it&amp;#x27;s the same kind of persuasion used to sell a vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FooBarBizBazz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fantastic article. And their &amp;quot;light touch&amp;quot; approach seems very correct.&lt;p&gt;Now --&lt;p&gt;What counts as a cult?&lt;p&gt;One sufficient condition, in my opinion, would be ritualized sexual abuse, especially of children.&lt;p&gt;But this is baked even into several mainstream religions, if you only open your eyes.&lt;p&gt;What is good, at least, is that, like viruses, cults&amp;#x2F;religions generally evolve to be less harmful to their hosts over time. (This is over time scales of multiple human generations. Within a single generation, a cult may do just the opposite, as it becomes marginalized from society and increasingly normalizes deviance, e.g. Aum reacting to humiliation in Japanese elections by releasing Sarin.)&lt;p&gt;Examples of this &amp;quot;taming&amp;quot; process: Flayed prisoners of the Aztecs are now dancing skeletons, &amp;quot;local color&amp;quot;, used in America to sell tacos. Likewise the Abrahamic religions are an evolution of animal sacrifice cults, themselves echoing earlier human sacrifice cults; they are still shaking off frankly-insane practices, but could be worse. The history of LDS provides a less dramatic example, but one recent-enough that early stages are still well-documented in the historical record.&lt;p&gt;And if all this sounds New Atheistic, note that I am actually quite sympathetic to (almost &lt;i&gt;apologetic&lt;/i&gt; for) certain aspects of religion (though I increasingly do wonder whether it is religions that teach goodness, or whether it is goodness that religions must attach themselves to for legitimacy, mixing it with other content). (For example I have pushed back, here, against characterizations of Christianity as &amp;quot;right wing&amp;quot;, as that is not at all the content of the New Testament.)&lt;p&gt;One thing is certain: If a religious identity has bound itself to a person, then attacking the person will only strengthen the identity. The memetic parasite and the human victim must be clearly distinguished. Failure to do this results in violence against people which only strengths the meme. Blood for the blood god.&lt;p&gt;I suspect many of these memes can be tamed to the point of decency over multiple generations. Though they always carry the risk of reversion to older forms. Somehow the &amp;quot;DNA&amp;quot; is still there. So I&amp;#x27;m not sure. They have to be stabilized to their nondestructive manifestations.&lt;p&gt;I also wonder about &amp;quot;non-religious&amp;quot; cult dynamics, e.g. those attached to political movements (both MAGA and woke), or financial&amp;#x2F;moral&amp;#x2F;credit systems, e.g. crypto.&lt;p&gt;One of my concerns also is the way that Silicon Valley leaders may study these methods not to defend against them but to exercise them in the formation of totalizing company cultures. Theil and Karp have been explicit about this. It distresses me: You should read about the scapegoat mechanism to destroy it, not to start using it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The best thing I have ever read on this subject is &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;harpers.org&amp;#x2F;archive&amp;#x2F;2013&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;the-man-who-saves-you-from-yourself&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;harpers.org&amp;#x2F;archive&amp;#x2F;2013&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;the-man-who-saves-you-fr...&lt;/a&gt; - it is a truly wild ride, profiling David Sullivan, a private investigator who specialized in helping people get their loved ones out of cults and was based in the San Francisco Bay Area for many years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gwbas1c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For those who are interested:&lt;p&gt;I recently read the book &amp;quot;Combatting Cult Mind Control&amp;quot; by Steven Hassan, a professional who also helps people leave cults. His approach isn&amp;#x27;t as much of a &amp;quot;long game&amp;quot; as Ryan and Kelly&amp;#x27;s approach. One thing that Hassan explains is that MLMs are often very similar to cults, and he also explains the difference between cults and religion.&lt;p&gt;Another book to read is The Running Grave by Robert Galabraith (pen name for J.K. Rownling.) One of the detectives joins a cult to try and get someone out. The book is well researched and gives an insider&amp;#x27;s view of a cult.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mikkupikku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I went down the rabbit hole of researching both cults and deprogramming groups a few years ago and one of the things which I found remarkable was how much overlap in methods there was between the two.  Different groups go to different extremes, but the overlap between the two is such that in many cases they can only be distinguished using social context, and in some cases I am pretty sure the deprogramming groups are in fact cults masquerading as groups to help former cult members because those make the best members for new cults.&lt;p&gt;Interesting space.  I&amp;#x27;m glad I don&amp;#x27;t have any personal reason to be involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dap:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’d strongly recommend the documentary “Behind the Curve”. The close look at people in (not quite a cult) gave me a visceral appreciation for what draws people to it (it provides acceptance for people who sorely lack it) and why it can be so hard to leave (one’s identity becomes so tied up in it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derbOac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting read. Framing things as a &amp;quot;cultic relationship&amp;quot; makes a lot of sense to me. The part about using your experience as a basis of truth determination being flawed and a source of vulnerability also was pretty insightful.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m a little surprised by mention of pushback and accusations of being cult apologists, only because what they&amp;#x27;re describing as their method is pretty similar in principle to some widespread and empirically validated therapies for more common things. It&amp;#x27;s just much more invasive, to understate things. I guess at some point there are probably basic immediate safety issues that arise, where taking time has its own risks.&lt;p&gt;The piece left me thinking that the reasons people become involved with and attached to cults might not be different at some fundamental level from a lot of other psychological problems they get themselves in — just a matter of degree or pervasiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjc50:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some pull quotes, since people seem to be struggling with page loading:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; his client, a woman who had recently finished her master’s at a prestigious university, had been drawn into a scam job. It was essentially a pyramid scheme built around a health regimen. Before you could sell it, you had to try it, so you knew what you were selling.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The regimen? Multiple enemas a day. “It escalated to 40 to 60 enemas a day,”&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; All groups have a rhythm, like a pulse across the calendar year. We have holidays, and we have tax season. There are highs and lows.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;  Furthermore, Kelly and Ryan urge their clients not to speak with the media. The firmest “no” I ever got was when I asked Ryan if I could speak to a former client.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; One of their cases in the 90s involved a cult leader who was systematically sexually assaulting the group’s members. [NB: do you have any idea how little that narrows it down]&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; the girl’s uncle, their client, had a very difficult time finding anything positive about the group or the leader who had allegedly raped his niece&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; What Kelly and Ryan mean when they say these groups are “offering something” to people, it is exactly that. There is a hole a group fills: alienation from community, family, sexuality; pressure to follow a certain life plan, addiction, unrealized spirituality, economic catastrophe – all reasons to join a group&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulHoule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;See &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.deccanherald.com&amp;#x2F;world&amp;#x2F;china-woman-counsels-mistresses-to-leave-married-men-in-extra-marital-affairs-3177817" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.deccanherald.com&amp;#x2F;world&amp;#x2F;china-woman-counsels-mist...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dzink:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Trying to read this to the end feels impossible - the Guardian keeps flicking the page to show ads and the page refreshes for no reason and I’m sure their ads impressions numbers are going through the roof. Feels like ad fraud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fascinating. I would totally watch a TV series on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;internet_points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So that works if it&amp;#x27;s possible to actually reach the person and the family agrees that they need help to get out. What if the family is part of the problem or is tricked? (I recently read &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;elan.school&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;elan.school&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; about this unimaginably horrible Kids for Cash-like scheme&amp;#x2F;cult. The only thing I can think of to prevent such things would be to get parents, teachers, lawmakers and social workers to read those stories too.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/nov/19/how-to-leave-a-cult-experts-intervention</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978813</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Boot from PXE</title>
      <link>https://blog.imraniqbal.org/learning-to-boot-from-pxe/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PXE reads the boot file (usually something. Other boot files are then retrieved as needed from the TFTP server. To get iPXE running, the iPXE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978245"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.imraniqbal.org/learning-to-boot-from-pxe/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pzmarzly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TFTP is crazy slow, even with RFC 7740 (buffering), but the payloads are usually small so few people care.&lt;p&gt;Thankfully modern BIOSes tend to implement HTTP boot option, where you can point to any HTTP or HTTPS URL (as long as the URL ends with &amp;quot;.efi&amp;quot;, which is a pretty dumb limitation if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zorlack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The fun thing about learning to boot from PXE, is that you have to learn it every time you onboard a new type of hardware... or a new VM hypervisor... or new NIC firmware... or new BIOS firmware.&lt;p&gt;God help you if you actually want to install an operating system.&lt;p&gt;PXE is such a vital capability for working with on-prem servers. But it&amp;#x27;s ten different things which all have to play nicely together. Every time I build a PXE system I feel like I&amp;#x27;m reinventing the universe in my tiny subnet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theandrewbailey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oh oh oh I know this!&lt;p&gt;I work in the refurb division of an ewaste recycling company[0]. To prepare a machine for sale, the drive needs to be wiped, and (optionally) an OS loaded. Wiping happens in WipeOS[1], which loads when you PXE boot on the internal company network. To install an OS, I have a separate network on my desk that will load iVentoy[2] when PXE booted, where I can further boot from ISOs I have on my server, but I almost always install Linux Mint. With those 2 things, I can largely do my job without fumbling with and losing USB drives.&lt;p&gt;I have 2 16 port switches on my desk, with over a dozen ethernet cables plugged into each. The yellow cables will PXE boot WipeOS, and the black ones PXE boot iVentoy.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ebay.com&amp;#x2F;str&amp;#x2F;evolutionecycling" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ebay.com&amp;#x2F;str&amp;#x2F;evolutionecycling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.wipeos.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.wipeos.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.iventoy.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;index.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.iventoy.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.imraniqbal.org/learning-to-boot-from-pxe/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978245</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Killed Perl?</title>
      <link>https://entropicthoughts.com/what-killed-perl</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll show you what I mean, and then still answer what I think killed Perl. Through that period, Perl grew rapidly, as indicated by the graph. And even then they didn’t have all that many packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45977900"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://entropicthoughts.com/what-killed-perl'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;woof:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It was never about Perl, it was the plethora of alternatives.&lt;p&gt;Python evolved, PHP had 1000 times more &amp;quot;how to get started&amp;quot; articles, Node happened. And LAMP became the default for noobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bluedino:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nobody we&amp;#x27;ve hired in the last 10 years wants to touch anything Perl.&lt;p&gt;That said, we re-wrote all of our monitoring scripts in....Bash.&lt;p&gt;Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HeinzStuckeIt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Already in the very early millennium, jokes like “Perl is an explosion in an ASCII factory” were going around the computer-nerd community, while several publishers were putting out affordable and fun and engaging books were published to learn Python. No surprise that it quickly declined in popularity for scripting. It has been amusing to watch the continual waves of reawakened interest in awk, while Perl seems to remain perennially marginalized now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mono442:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think it is due to the fact that Perl has some confusing bits like those variable prefixes ($@%), the lack of function arguments (I know that this has changed recently), not really great error handling, etc and so people started using languages which seemed easier to use like Python.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SanjayMehta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Python.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSR_FDED:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it worth learning Perl 5 these days? Maybe to use as a better Bash?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone that was already working during the dotcom wave, Perl is a tool I would still reach for, given the problem I might trying to sort out, if on an UNIX like platform.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Binary package managers that chase down dependencies on their own weren’t a thing until the early 2000s, I think?&lt;p&gt;UNIX package managers started to be made available during the 1990&amp;#x27;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7thaccount:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s been discussed before, but Python just seemed more straightforward to a lot of people. It had a built-in object oriented model as well when that was the rage instead of the weak default one and dozen modules on CPAN to do object oriented programming. There was generally one way to do something and that was easier to learn than TIMTOWTDI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HumanOstrich:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I learned and used Perl professionally from around 2005-2015 and experienced first-hand the ossification, fear of change, and lack of innovation in Perl 5 development. It seems all the talent and effort started being wasted on making Perl 6 the bestest, most elegant, most useful programming language in the world. Just seeing the neglect of Perl 5 kept me from ever considering Perl 6 and motivated me to move to other languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bhaak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Easier to learn languages came along.&lt;p&gt;Perl stems from a time where COBOL, FORTRAN, and SQL made sense and it was already mind bending for those accustomed to those old languages.&lt;p&gt;Modern minds can&amp;#x27;t comprehend Perl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crmd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I heard a fascinating theory a few years ago on the decline of Perl:&lt;p&gt;In the early aughts, Google recruiting had such a strong, selective focus on A-player Perl programmers that it drained the market of top talent. Within google these people began to adopt, and eventually create and evangelize newer, Googlier programming languages.&lt;p&gt;In other words, Perl expertise was the skills filter, and Perl itself a technological ancestor of certain modern languages like Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rwky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still use perl. It&amp;#x27;s my go to for string parsing (think pipe log file, do something with it and send it to stdout). It&amp;#x27;s also my go to for anything that I still want to work in 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brianhorakh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Raku&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cafard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;About a dozen years ago, I noticed that the young all seemed to know Python, and did not seem to know Perl. Given that they would be maintaining such code as I wrote and was worth keeping around, I moved to writing in Python. Now when I write Perl, I do silly things like forget semicolons.&lt;p&gt;Perl can be very well written. I deeply regret not encountering &lt;i&gt;Perl Best Practices&lt;/i&gt; when it came out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rurban:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know, but I won&amp;#x27;t tell you&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nabla9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have a problem. I know, I&amp;#x27;ll use Perl. Now I have two problems.&lt;p&gt;Perl, Tcl, bash are debugging and maintenance nightmares. People realized that Perl does not work, so they decided to start over and call it Perl. Thus Perl 6, Raku, Perl 7.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;In Perl 6, we decided it would be better to fix the language than fix the user.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt; — Larry Wall&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://entropicthoughts.com/what-killed-perl</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:25:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45977900</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
