<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:42:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>I am just sooo sick of AI prediction content, let's kill it already</title>
      <link>https://verdikapuku.com/posts/i-am-just-so-sick-of-ai-prediction-content/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I swear to God if I read another sensationalist headline that says “How AI will change software engineering” I will set the us-east-1 and us-west-2 data centers on fire myself. Just “AI will change everything about bakeries in this imaginary future world in my head. Dear Internet, I beg of you, please do not produce another piece like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982542"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://verdikapuku.com/posts/i-am-just-so-sick-of-ai-prediction-content/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeswin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This has already been discussed so many times. No good discussion will come out of this - and it&amp;#x27;ll just be people moping.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s much better content on Show HN, one of which won&amp;#x27;t hit the homepage because this has more votes. It&amp;#x27;s a problem that HN has to fix - people upvote because they agree, and that vote carries the same weight as another which required far more effort (trying a product, looking at code etc).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dinobones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve felt the same. Also the AGI outcome for software engineers is:&lt;p&gt;A) In 5 years no real improvement, AI bubble pops, most of us are laid off.
B) In 5 years near—AGI replaces most software engineers, most of us are laid off.&lt;p&gt;Woohoo. Lose-lose scenario! No matter how you imagine this AI bubble playing out, the musics going to stop eventually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nathan_compton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The worse thing about this parasitic trend is that most of the time it’s basically a dude who wants to appear visionary and so he makes a prediction of the future.&lt;p&gt;This is basically an entire genre of low effort Hackernews posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avicebron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I pretty much agree but using &amp;quot;As an AI engineer myself&amp;quot; or a variation of that in your blog post should get you ridiculed. Who exactly are you trying to impress&amp;#x2F;differentiate yourself from?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rvz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; On the weekend, I hack around with ML &amp;amp; AI to build cool stuff.&lt;p&gt;Stopped reading this rage-bait.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;riazrizvi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This stuff is like the monster in The Blob. The more energy you direct at it, the bigger it gets. So your post, and my comment are just feeding it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paulpauper:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The biggest growth industry in AI is people doing podcasts and writing blog posts  about the implications of AI or predictions of AI. It seems like &amp;gt;90% of articles from major media sources mention AI  somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kittikitti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;None of the predictions have any substance. It&amp;#x27;s always vague. Where are the ideas around which algorithms will be next after Transformers? Why is there no thought around the real planning on HBM memory and what we will do with the increased throughput? The forecasts, as the author aptly mentioned, are for the headlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agentifysh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The only prediction that I think is robust is: Those who use AI as tool today will replace those that aren&amp;#x27;t tomorrow.&lt;p&gt;Same situation with internet, we saw a bubble but ultimately those that changed their business around it monopolized various industries where they were slow to react.&lt;p&gt;Some jobs will be replaced outright but most will use AI tools and we might see reduced wages&amp;#x2F;positions available for a very long time coupled with economic downturn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hyperhello:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The AI writes the AI prediction content. It can’t give you any new information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://verdikapuku.com/posts/i-am-just-so-sick-of-ai-prediction-content/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982542</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building more with GPT-5.1-Codex-Max</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1-codex-max/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openai.com/index/gpt-5-1-codex-max/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982649</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launch HN: Mosaic (YC W25) – Agentic Video Editing</title>
      <link>https://mosaic.so</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mosaic.so</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980760</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/823750/european-union-ai-act-gdpr-changes</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The EU folds under Big Tech’s pressure. This is being done in the European way: by making sure that fundamental rights of users remain fully protected. Leaked drafts have already provoked outrage among civil rights groups and politicians, who have accused the Commission of weakening fundamental safeguards and bowing to pressure from Big Tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980117"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theverge.com/news/823750/european-union-ai-act-gdpr-changes'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 21 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qwertious:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cowards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pdimitar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is EU suffering from FOMO?&lt;p&gt;As an EU citizen,  this is shameful and even kind of pathetic to read.&lt;p&gt;Will we start outsourcing all our IT needs to USA again?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cm2012:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is such an important change for Europe. I&amp;#x27;ve worked with 100+ start-ups as a consultant, and I&amp;#x27;ve talked to EU ones who have been strangled by some of the regulations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blablabla123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That&amp;#x27;s a pity, the government fails to capitalize on its own policies because they fail to set up long term investment. First environmental and e-Mobility and now AI.&lt;p&gt;Sure, there&amp;#x27;s way too much bureaucracy. But I see there things like taxes, regulations about the cucumber radius etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nalekberov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;EU introduces Chat Control, then scales back GDPR, what&amp;#x27;s left? Digital ID and digital currency (with no possibility of paying by cash)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhereIsTheTruth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yet again, European countries are showing who their leaders are: US Big Tech&lt;p&gt;No wonder we default to Google Chrome on Microsoft&amp;#x2F;Apple systems, and American social platforms, to debate issues affecting EU citizens&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nikanj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Companies made cookie banners as obnoxious as possible, because they knew that by making people hate the banners, the population would turn against the GDRP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Poor Europe - lobbyists make sure that Europe stays weak.&lt;p&gt;That statement includes Ursula by the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Europe&amp;#x27;s cookie nightmare is crumbling. EC wants preference at browser level&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45979527"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45979527&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theptip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; users would be able to control others from central browser controls that apply to websites broadly.&lt;p&gt;Great to see this finally. It’s obviously the way it should have been implemented from the beginning.&lt;p&gt;We still see this technically myopic approach with things like age verification; it’s insane to ask websites to collect Gov ID to age verify kids (or prove adulthood for porn), rather than having an OS feature that can do so in a privacy-preserving way. Now these sites have a copy of your ID! You know they are going to get hacked and leak it!&lt;p&gt;(Parents should opt their kids phones into “kid mode” and this would block age-sensitive content. The law just needs to mandate that this mode is respected by sites&amp;#x2F;apps.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GardenLetter27:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;About time. Startups and innovative business simply cannot get investment when there&amp;#x27;s the constant risk of a new AI Act massively increasing compliance and legal costs.&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#x27;s not enough - they need to completely repeal the DSA, AI Act, ePrivacy Directive, and Cybersecurity Act at least. And also focus on unifying the environment throughout the EU - no more exit taxes, no need for notaries and in-person verbal agreements, etc.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s just so much red tape and bureaucracy it&amp;#x27;s incredible. You can&amp;#x27;t hire or pay payroll taxes across the EU (without the hire relocating) - that&amp;#x27;s a huge disadvantage compared to the USA before you even get into the different language requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbiote:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does anyone have a link to the proposal, preferably on the EU website?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d like to see for myself, as I don&amp;#x27;t consider moving the consent method from the webpage to the browser settings &amp;quot;watering down&amp;quot; — it&amp;#x27;s the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mikece:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How about this as a privacy law: if you collect data about people without their EXPLICIT permission[1] you can be charged with digital stalking.  Same principle as stalking; escalating penalties for repeat offenses and for doing so in bulk or en masse.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: And you cannot share information gained by permitted collection unless EXPLICIT permission to share is granted.&lt;p&gt;[1] Eg: it&amp;#x27;s not sufficient to disclose this in equivocal text buried in 25k lines of EULA text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Previously:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;European Commission plans “digital omnibus” package to simplify its tech laws&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45878311"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45878311&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bitpush:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Incredible to see the 180 both from EU and also from the HN sentiment. HN was cheering on as EU went after Big Tech companies, especially Meta. Meta is no perfect company, but the amount of &amp;#x27;please stick it to them&amp;#x27; was strong (I reckon that is still a bridge too far for a lot of folks here).&lt;p&gt;Even extreme proponents of big tech villanery in the US (Lina Khan&amp;#x27;s FTC) is also facing losses (They just lost their monumental case against Meta yesterday).&lt;p&gt;What I really want to see is Meta getting irrelevant ON MERIT. People stop using Meta products, and then I want to see it die. But not by forcing the hand - that&amp;#x27;s bad for everyone, especially the enterpreuer &amp;#x2F; hacker types on this site&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m3kw9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the consequences of their laws is pushing their hands&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m00dy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used to live and work in EU, get out of EU before it is too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bpodgursky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The EU folds under Big Tech’s pressure.&lt;p&gt;This is a very odd framing, because the actual reason from quotes in the article is that the EU is acutely feeling the pain of &lt;i&gt;having no big tech companies&lt;/i&gt;, due in part to burdensome privacy regulations.&lt;p&gt;The pressure isn&amp;#x27;t really from big tech, it&amp;#x27;s from feeling poor and setting themselves up as irrelevant consumers of an economy permeated by AI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;schnitzelstoat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; One change that’s likely to please almost everyone is a reduction in Europe’s ubiquitous cookie banners and pop-ups. Under the new proposal, some “non-risk” cookies won’t trigger pop-ups at all, and users would be able to control others from central browser controls that apply to websites broadly.&lt;p&gt;Finally!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;josefritzishere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is criminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AndrewKemendo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The changes, proposed by the European Commission, the bloc’s executive branch, changes core elements of the GDPR, making it easier for companies to share anonymized and pseudonymized personal datasets. They would allow AI companies to legally use personal data to train AI models, so long as that training complies with other GDPR requirements.&lt;p&gt;Put together and those two basically undo the entire concept of privacy as it’s trivially easy to target someone from a large enough “anonymous” set (there is no anonymous data, there only exists data that’s not labeled with an ID yet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/news/823750/european-union-ai-act-gdpr-changes</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980117</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in upgrading Proxmox</title>
      <link>https://blog.vasi.li/adventures-in-upgrading-proxmox/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It's containers on top of other container, and there was a fairly recent issue with AppArmor that prevented some functionality from running inside a docker container with very cryptic error. I guess that error is relevant. After another quick Google search I've found this Reddit thread which provided the steps to solve this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981666"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.vasi.li/adventures-in-upgrading-proxmox/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4fterd4rk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Man Proxmox... I love it, I use it, but I swear there has to be a more straightforward way to implement this technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throw0101c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;See also &amp;quot;Upgrade from 8 to 9&amp;quot;:&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pve.proxmox.com&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Upgrade_from_8_to_9" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pve.proxmox.com&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Upgrade_from_8_to_9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And &amp;quot;Known Issues &amp;amp; Breaking Changes (9.1)&amp;quot;:&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pve.proxmox.com&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Roadmap#9.1-known-issues" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pve.proxmox.com&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Roadmap#9.1-known-issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeff-Collins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Very helpful tips for a smooth Proxmox upgrade!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Clear and practical steps—thanks for sharing!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This guide is a lifesaver for sysadmins upgrading Proxmox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related ongoing thread:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Proxmox virtual environment 9.1 available&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45980005"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45980005&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 2025 (56 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;generalizations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; As an aside... Because one node didn&amp;#x27;t start, and my Proxmox cluster has only two nodes, it can&amp;#x27;t reach quorum, meaning I can&amp;#x27;t really make any changes to my other node, and I can&amp;#x27;t start any containers that are stopped.
I&amp;#x27;ve recently added another Zigbee dongle, that supports Thread, and it happens to share same VID:PID combo as the old dongle, so due to how these were mapped into guest OS, all my light switches stopped working. I had to fix the issue fast.&lt;p&gt;Lesson in here somewhere. Something about about a toaster representing the local intelligence maxima?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zer00eyz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Running docker inside LXC is weird.&lt;p&gt;Knowing when to use a vm and when to use a container is sometimes an opaque problem.&lt;p&gt;This is one of those cases where a VM is a much better choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;evanjrowley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I ran into the same issue over the weekend. The end-goal for my Proxmox setup is basically the same deployment you have. It&amp;#x27;s good to see the issue was addressed quickly by the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.vasi.li/adventures-in-upgrading-proxmox/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981666</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Launch Something New, You Need "Social Dandelions"</title>
      <link>https://www.actiondigest.com/p/to-launch-something-new-you-need-social-dandelions</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you maximize the odds that a community will embrace your idea. An idea that began as an online screenshot quickly vaporized $6. Communities that are more open minded and risk tolerant are likely to be receptive to taking on that risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982818"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.actiondigest.com/p/to-launch-something-new-you-need-social-dandelions'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.actiondigest.com/p/to-launch-something-new-you-need-social-dandelions</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982818</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: DNS Benchmark Tool – Compare and monitor resolvers</title>
      <link>https://github.com/frankovo/dns-benchmark-tool</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DNS Benchmark Tool Part of BuildTools - Network Performance Suite Fast, comprehensive DNS performance testing with DNSSEC validation, DoH/DoT support, and enterprise features pip install dns-benchmark-tool dns-benchmark benchmark --use-defaults 🎉 1,400+ downloads this week. log Table of Contents DNS Benchmark Tool Part of BuildTools - Network Performance Suite 🎉 Today’s Release Highlights Table of Contents 🎯 Why This Tool. DNS resolution is often the hidden bottleneck in network performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982526"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/frankovo/dns-benchmark-tool'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffbee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You are, presumably, already familiar with the ISC Looking Glass?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;isc.sans.edu&amp;#x2F;api&amp;#x2F;dnslookup&amp;#x2F;google.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;isc.sans.edu&amp;#x2F;api&amp;#x2F;dnslookup&amp;#x2F;google.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;johng:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very neat tool!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/frankovo/dns-benchmark-tool</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982526</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thunderbird Adds Native Microsoft Exchange Email Support</title>
      <link>https://blog.thunderbird.net/2025/11/thunderbird-adds-native-microsoft-exchange-email-support/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Graph support–❌ Not yet implemented – Microsoft Graph integration will be added in the future. Exchange Web Services and Microsoft Graph While many people and organizations still rely on Exchange Web Services (EWS), Microsoft has begun gradually phasing it out in favor of a newer, more modern interface called Microsoft Graph. If you want to know more about Exchange support in Thunderbird, please refer to the dedicated page on support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978423"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.thunderbird.net/2025/11/thunderbird-adds-native-microsoft-exchange-email-support/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stackskipton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As former Exchange admin&amp;#x2F;Office365, it&amp;#x27;s use EWS (Exchange Web Services) which is being removed in October 2026 for Office365. So for most, this is extremely time limited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tacker2000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks!&lt;p&gt;I have a few Exchange inboxes and once MS forces the “New Outlook” design, without allowing the legacy option anymore, im gone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MrZander:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Awesome news, can&amp;#x27;t wait until they implement calendar support and I can get rid of Outlook once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this good?&lt;p&gt;This is a genuine question. I am not sure whether this is good or not.&lt;p&gt;It seems to only extend existing options? Or is there some trade-off?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jchw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I generally like Thunderbird... but something is weird. What ever happened to Sync? It was around the corner for next release like two years ago. And I&amp;#x27;m not complaining about Exchange support, but I am a bit sad that JMAP is nowhere to be found yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cosmic_cheese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice to see, but unfortunately it&amp;#x27;s not uncommon for orgs using Outlook&amp;#x2F;Office to disable Exchange client support and require use of the official clients. It&amp;#x27;s highly unlikely and maybe not even possible, but I&amp;#x27;d like to see desktop and mobile mail clients implement some kind of workaround.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeff-Collins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Great news! This makes Thunderbird much more versatile for business use.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Native Exchange support is a game-changer for Thunderbird users.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Thrilled to see Thunderbird improving integration with Microsoft Exchange&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yellowapple:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fantastic news!  I&amp;#x27;ve been hoping for Exchange support for a long while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zipy124:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Guess this means I can cancel all my OWL subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bnchrch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While its been a long time since Ive used Thunderbird, I just wanted to take the time to publicly say thank you.&lt;p&gt;Many HNers probably wont (or cant) remember the world of desktop mail clients but basically during the height of MSFT dominance there was only one real mail client: Outlook. Which Microsoft was starting to monetize heavily, ignore UX, and keep it windows only (cant blame them for that).&lt;p&gt;Then Thunderbird arrived on the scene, an OSS mail client that beat the pants off of Outlook in features, spam detection, IMAP support and a bunch of other things.&lt;p&gt;And it was free.&lt;p&gt;And you could use it on any machine.&lt;p&gt;This was a huge moment for OSS.&lt;p&gt;We owe a lot of credit to Mozilla and Thunderbird for rescuing us from a closed source world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ivanbakel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What I&amp;#x27;m most curious about, and what the docs are light on detail about: does this mean Thunderbird complies with remote deletion requests (which IIRC, the Exchange protocol suppports)? I have the impression that Microsoft makes this a requirement for Exchange implementations, which is why third-party devices and apps like Apple&amp;#x27;s Mail cooperate with those requests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.thunderbird.net/2025/11/thunderbird-adds-native-microsoft-exchange-email-support/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978423</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netherlands returns control of Nexperia to Chinese owner</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-19/dutch-hand-back-control-of-chinese-owned-chipmaker-nexperia</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PoliticsFacebookXLinkedInEmailLinkGiftFacebookXLinkedInEmailLinkGiftGift this articleContact us:Provide news feedback or report an errorConfidential tip. Send a tip to our reportersSite feedback:Take our SurveyNew WindowFacebookXLinkedInEmailLinkGiftBy Patrick Van Oosterom and Sarah JacobNovember 19, 2025 at 8:50 AM UTCUpdated on November 19, 2025 at 2:20 PM UTCBookmarkSaveThe Dutch government suspended its powers over chipmaker Nexperia, handing back control to its Chinese owner and defusing a standoff with Beijing that had begun to hamper automotive production around the world. The order that gave the Netherlands powers to block or revise decisions at Nijmegen-based Nexperia was dropped as “a show of goodwill,” Economic Affairs Minister Vincent Karremans said Wednesday, adding that discussions with Chinese authorities are continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982874"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-19/dutch-hand-back-control-of-chinese-owned-chipmaker-nexperia'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-11-19/dutch-hand-back-control-of-chinese-owned-chipmaker-nexperia</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982874</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outdated Samsung handset linked to fatal emergency call failure in Australia</title>
      <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/18/samsung_emergency_call_failure/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Telstra also warned last month that older, non-upgradeable Samsung devices could fail Triple Zero calls and that such devices face mandatory blocking from all Australian networks if left unresolved. Customers with mobile devices requiring updates or replacements have been notified by their mobile carrier with instructions," it added. Get our Tech Resources Share More about Australia Mobile Network Samsung More like these × More about Australia Mobile Network Samsung Narrower topics 6G EE Five Eyes Orange Samsung Galaxy Samsung Galaxy Ace Square Kilometre Array Vodafone Broader topics APAC Telecommunications More about Share 54 COMMENTS More about Australia Mobile Network Samsung More like these × More about Australia Mobile Network Samsung Narrower topics 6G EE Five Eyes Orange Samsung Galaxy Samsung Galaxy Ace Square Kilometre Array Vodafone Broader topics APAC Telecommunications TIP US OFF Send us news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981608"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/18/samsung_emergency_call_failure/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WarOnPrivacy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Wireless Telco: &amp;quot;Telstra also warned last month that older,
    non-upgradeable Samsung devices could fail Triple Zero calls
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Which can be less of a problem if there are full-digit emergency numbers that could be saved as a contact (preferably quick-dial).&lt;p&gt;Auto-call routing can fail if you&amp;#x27;re on one side of a regional border but are connected to a cell on the other - and local EMS can&amp;#x27;t forward calls to the neighboring EMS (or just suck at it).&lt;p&gt;I used to live on a border and local EMS was 3-digit only. The only way to call the correct EMS was to call their non-emergency number and get forwarded - but only after getting scolded first for not calling the 3-digit number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WarOnPrivacy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Handset Manufacturer: &amp;quot;We strongly encourage customers
    to keep their mobile devices updated with the latest software&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
After a decade or two in a world where updates (routinely!) sabotage user experience (including handset updates), users have learned to not trust manufacturer recommendations.&lt;p&gt;When manufactures say &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;We strongly encourage customers to update&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;, we hear &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;To juice short-term shareholder value, our product will suck more than ever&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;. Because that was the actual message the last 5x.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tlb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m trying to imagine a conversation with a Bell engineer in the 80s explaining that, in the future, a 4-year old phone won&amp;#x27;t be expected to call 911 any more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skeezyjefferson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the price you pay for making telephones into computers. i love em but boy do they fuck up regularly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SketchySeaBeast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow, that list on the Samsung site is concerning.  The S21 is a 2021 phone.  Absolutely realistic people would still be using it, and outside of a tired battery I&amp;#x27;ll bet it&amp;#x27;s performing just fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everdrive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Customer safety remains our highest priority,&amp;quot; said CEO Iñaki Berroeta.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fun to imagine a world where a lie like this could be a legal liability. I mean an actual court case, where evidence is brought and the claim is tested. &amp;quot;Is customer safety a higher priority than shareholder value?&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;why don&amp;#x27;t you support old devices&amp;quot; and then Samsung would need to produce internal evidence to try to make their case.&lt;p&gt;Nothing like that will ever happen, but I can dream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drcongo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why would an outdated OS prevent emergency calls specifically?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theregister.com/2025/11/18/samsung_emergency_call_failure/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981608</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emoji evidence errors don’t undo a murder conviction</title>
      <link>https://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2025/11/emoji-evidence-errors-dont-undo-a-murder-conviction-people-v-harmon.htm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One troubling possibility is that Delarosa’s lawyers should have spotted that the exhibit didn’t accurately reflect the evidence, but didn’t. Note 2: it’s possible/probable that the trial outcomes would have been the same with or without the Facebook message evidence. 18, 2025) Share this: Click to email a link to a friend (Opens in new window) Email Click to print (Opens in new window) Print Click to share on Facebook (Opens in new window) Facebook Click to share on LinkedIn (Opens in new window) LinkedIn Click to share on X (Opens in new window) X Click to share on Tumblr (Opens in new window) Tumblr Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window) Pinterest Click to share on Pocket (Opens in new window) Pocket Click to share on Reddit (Opens in new window) Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981009"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2025/11/emoji-evidence-errors-dont-undo-a-murder-conviction-people-v-harmon.htm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EdwardCoffin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the same vein was an incident where an improperly localized phone in Turkey caused a sent message to arrive with different characters, with very different meaning, and the fallout was two deaths [1], discussed here [2]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu&amp;#x2F;nll&amp;#x2F;?p=73" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu&amp;#x2F;nll&amp;#x2F;?p=73&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=9900758"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=9900758&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;layer8:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a side note, the FACE WITH TEARS OF JOY emoji doesn’t actually depict tears of joy, but laughing so hard that tears come out of your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skeezyjefferson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;i love how after having actual law professionals take a look at his appraisal, he has to retract all the things he said about law, leaving you with how he noticed emjois werent rendered on a printout. typical internet know nothing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;josefritzishere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The year is 2025 and the courts are debating &amp;quot;emoji evidence.&amp;quot;  That is where we are as a species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lanyard-textile:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Given it was not directly brought up in the motion in limine, it sounds like there were other concerns with the message anyway?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; it’s possible&amp;#x2F;probable that the trial outcomes would have been the same with or without the Facebook message evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;opwieurposiu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have noticed that men and women tend to use different emoji and ascribe different meaning to them.   Ex. I see the skull emoji used to indicate laughter more often used by women and crying face used more by men.&lt;p&gt;There are some tribes where men and women have completely different languages, I wonder if we will end up that way with emojis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wongarsu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; instead of being followed by two emojis, the message is followed by four closely-spaced rectangles. Neither the text of Delarosa’s in limine motion, nor anything said during the in limine hearing would have informed the trial court that the four rectangles represented two emojis&lt;p&gt;So I know nothing about this trial and have limited knowledge of the US legal system, but didn&amp;#x27;t one party just misrepresent evidence here? They would probably argue that it wasn&amp;#x27;t intentional and thus not perjury, but it still sounds pretty serious. The emojis are just as much part of the message as the latin characters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ekjhgkejhgk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; he argues the court should have excluded a Facebook message that&lt;p&gt;OT: Don&amp;#x27;t use Facebook or anything by that company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;philipallstar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Lawyers in getting paid to debate their guess of meanings of emojis shocker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mindslight:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The issues with emojis go much deeper than this. Even if we agree on how exactly they displayed, their social meaning is highly dependent on the context of a conversation. Instead of allowing outside investigators to divine their own meanings and introduce them as evidence, courts should insist on testimony from the person or people those communications were meant for. If said people give wildly differing testimony to what investigators think is truthful, then they can go down the rabbit hole of how the codepoints were displayed and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s interesting because like the article says legal teams may have to get smarter about recreating all the context when evidence like this is used. Even if the emojis rendered the reference implementation of Unicode and what vendors actually represent can vary quite a bit by platform or OS version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.ericgoldman.org/archives/2025/11/emoji-evidence-errors-dont-undo-a-murder-conviction-people-v-harmon.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981009</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build vs. Buy: What This Week's Outages Should Teach You</title>
      <link>https://www.toddhgardner.com/blog/build-vs-buy-outages</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When something goes wrong, it’s understandable. They thought their needs were unique. They thought they could do it better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981626"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.toddhgardner.com/blog/build-vs-buy-outages'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dan353hehe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Here’s the thing, if your core business function depends on some capability, you should own it if at all possible.&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;#x27;m building something that allows my customers to do X, then yes I will own the software that allows my customers to do X. Makes sense.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; They’ll craft artisanal monitoring solutions while their actual business logic—the thing customers pay for—runs on someone else’s computer.&lt;p&gt;So instead I should build an artisanal hosting solution on my own hardware that I purchase and maintain? I could drop proxmox on them and go from there, or K8s, or even just bare metal and systemd scripts.&lt;p&gt;But my business isn&amp;#x27;t about any of those things, its about X. How does owning and running my own hardware get me closer to delivering on X?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;juancn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s no easy answer, but you should definitely model what happens when X goes down if you depend on X.&lt;p&gt;It may even be a rational decision to take the downtime if the cost of avoiding it exceeds the expected cost of an eventual downtime, but that&amp;#x27;s a business decision that requires some serious thought.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mannyv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What this outage teaches you is that when a third party vendor fails and the internet breaks you can point the finger at them with no issues.&lt;p&gt;If your shit breaks and everyone else&amp;#x27;s shit is still working that&amp;#x27;s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vivzkestrel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Instead we need a startup that builds over every cloud provider. Think of a web server for example. AWS has EC2, GCP has its own equivalent and Azure has its own and so on. What if we had a startup that virtualizes a layer on top of these such that we AWS has an outage, you lose 1&amp;#x2F;3rd of your operating capacity, when Azure has an outage you lose 1&amp;#x2F;3rd of your operating capacity. In order for you startup s virtual webserver to go down, all of AWS, GCP and Azure wil have to go down simultaneously. Basically build on top of everyone s cloud service into one single unified virtual layer that offers end products to consumers. A 6GB RAM server that the end consumer purchases has 2GB of RAM running on AWS, 2GB on Azure and 2GB on GCP. I am sure we can also strategize something along the same lines for a database server with the added question of the database sharding strategy at play&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onion2k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can&amp;#x27;t build your own Cloudflare in any meaningful sense. You can choose not to have the functionality Cloudflare provides because you prioritize the risk of a Cloudflare outage as more important than the benefits Cloudflare gives you, but that probability tree is &lt;i&gt;probably&lt;/i&gt; going to land in Cloudflare&amp;#x27;s favor for 99.99% of businesses.&lt;p&gt;If you can build a system with redundancy to continue working even if Cloudflare is unavailable then you should, but most years that&amp;#x27;s going to be a waste of time.&lt;p&gt;I think you&amp;#x27;d be better off spending the time building good relationships with your customers and users so that in the event of an outage that&amp;#x27;s beyond your control they trust your business and continue to be happy customers when you&amp;#x27;re back up and running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;righthand:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yeah but my DevOps only know Aws or Cloudflare UIs and refuse to consider any other platforms. The leadership sees multiple bills as bad. Back to square one? No one will learn anything because people enjoy the pseudo holiday for problems they set themselves up to do nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;almosthere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Recoverable master and short dns ttl&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codingdave:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Redundancy is a proven way to build resilience into your infrastructure. Ownership does not mean you have to build it. OP is correct that you need to understand it all, but that understanding also allows for solid DR plans that use multiple providers for a resilient infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meh. This opinion highlights the fact that availability is the least understood pillar in security. The Right Way to Think About It is having good security analysis and doing proper Risk Management. This means it is their job to do business impact analysis, 3rd party assessments, and run tabletop exercises on all your critical systems to tell you what is rock solid and what is a house of cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.toddhgardner.com/blog/build-vs-buy-outages</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981626</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
