<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nextcloud feels slow to use</title>
      <link>https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2025/11/03/nextcloud-slow/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nextcloud Calendar app Javascript assets. Nextcloud Files app Javascript assets. Nextcloud Notes app Javascript assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2025/11/03/nextcloud-slow/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2025/11/03/nextcloud-slow/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798681</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VimGraph</title>
      <link>https://resources.wolframcloud.com/FunctionRepository/resources/VimGraph/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Function Repository Resource: VimGraph Source Notebook Construct a graph of simple Vim-style movements in text Contributed by: Pavel Hajek ResourceFunction["VimGraph"][text] returns a graph with letters as vertices and Vim-style movements as edges. Details and OptionsVim is a cult-favorite text editor known for its modal editing—In Normal mode, certain keys are mapped to movements forward or backward to the nearest pattern, reducing keystroke distance and enabling fast editing without using the mouse. Also supported are Graph options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://resources.wolframcloud.com/FunctionRepository/resources/VimGraph/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://resources.wolframcloud.com/FunctionRepository/resources/VimGraph/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798838</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problem with Farmed Seafood</title>
      <link>https://nautil.us/the-problem-with-farmed-seafood-1243674/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Environment Nature’s Prescription for Our Future Zoology Naked Clams and Sunken Ships Technology The Divers Who Stretch the Limits of Human Biology Environment Modeling the Deep Environment The Deep Ocean Is a Global Public Good Environment It’s a Plastic World, After All Environment We Are the Ocean Philosophy Hope Catches a Tailwind Environment Our Boiling Seas Evolution How Fishing Could Change the Evolution of Fish Environment Finding a Sense of Place in the Ocean Anthropology How Indigenous Knowledge Could Save Fishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://nautil.us/the-problem-with-farmed-seafood-1243674/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nautil.us/the-problem-with-farmed-seafood-1243674/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798898</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Case Against PGVector</title>
      <link>https://alex-jacobs.com/posts/the-case-against-pgvector/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;×Understanding Vector Search and HNSW Index with pgvectorHNSW Indexes with Postgres and pgvectorUnderstand Indexes in pgvectorExternal Indexing for pgvectorExploring Postgres pgvector HNSW Index Storagepgvector v0. pgvector gives you two index types: IVFFlat and HNSW. On your production database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://alex-jacobs.com/posts/the-case-against-pgvector/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alex-jacobs.com/posts/the-case-against-pgvector/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798479</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: a Rust ray tracer that runs on any GPU – even in the browser</title>
      <link>https://github.com/tchauffi/rust-rasterizer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ppm # Or build first, then run cargo build --release. # Build and run cargo run --bin gpu_raytracer --release &gt; output. ppm # Or build separately cargo build --bin gpu_raytracer --release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/tchauffi/rust-rasterizer'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/tchauffi/rust-rasterizer</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798871</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A collection of links that existed about Anguilla as of 2003</title>
      <link>https://web.ai/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not all of them are stll alive, but it's a fun glimpse back to Anguilla online. Generic of furosemideHow much does propranolol cost ukBuy orlistat genericWhere to buy zoloft in the uk Land For Sale Behind Cap Juluca Buy clomiphene citrate 50 mg onlineGeneric viagra 123Zovirax online pharmacy canadaBuy clomid tablet Excellent Limousine Service Buy clomid and nolvadex pctWhere can i get amoxicillin over the counterViagra uk otcValacyclovir generic brand E &amp; L Babysitting Buy cheap viagra online in canadaBuy citalopram 10mg online ukBuy orlistat 120mg ukPrix du cialis au quebec Fairplay Jewelry and Perfumes Phenergan in the usKamagra oral jelly come si usaCialis dose consigliataBuy generic viagra in australia Swinghigh Apartments Health pharmacy online discount codeXenical 120 mg saleBuy azithromycin 500mg chlamydiaBuying ventolin online in uk A Trip to Dominica Drugstore makeup free shippingViagra online express deliveryProscar ohne rezept kaufen Cheers Charters Buy albuterol inhaler online cheapPhenergan uk pharmacyGeneric cymbalta online Be Aware Environmental Club Explore the sea or learn to waterski with Nature Boy Expeditions at natureboy. See an action-packed visit to Anguilla by two teenage girls, written as a Science Project Visit the Gardens of Anguilla at Palms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://web.ai/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://web.ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798892</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Offline Math: Converting LaTeX to SVG with MathJax</title>
      <link>https://sigwait.org/~alex/blog/2025/10/07/3t8acq.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;getInternalVMContext() script. defaultReady() MathJax. createElement('script') script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://sigwait.org/~alex/blog/2025/10/07/3t8acq.html'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sigwait.org/~alex/blog/2025/10/07/3t8acq.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798746</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skyfall-GS – Synthesizing Immersive 3D Urban Scenes from Satellite Imagery</title>
      <link>https://skyfall-gs.jayinnn.dev/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we take an alternative route to create large-scale 3D scenes by synergizing the readily available satellite imagery that supplies realistic coarse geometry and the open-domain diffusion model for creating high-quality close-up appearances. We propose Skyfall-GS, the first city-block scale 3D scene creation framework without costly 3D annotations, also featuring real-time, immersive 3D exploration. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Skyfall-GS provides improved cross-view consistent geometry and more realistic textures compared to state-of-the-art approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://skyfall-gs.jayinnn.dev/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfall-gs.jayinnn.dev/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798881</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geonum – geometric number library for unlimited dimensions with O(1) complexity</title>
      <link>https://github.com/mxfactorial/geonum</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;cos() into any dimension without defining it first dual() = blade + 2, duality operation adds π rotation and involutively maps grades (0 ↔ 2, 1 ↔ 3) grade() = blade % 4, geometric grade differentiate() = angle + π/2, polynomial coefficients computed from sin(θ+π/2) = cos(θ) quadrature identity replaces "pseudoscalar" with blade arithmetic how dimensions work dimensions = blade, how many dimensions the angle spans traditional: dimensions are coordinate axes - you stack more coordinates Geonum: dimensions are rotational states - you rotate by π/2 increments dimension traditional Geonum 1D (x) [length, 0] 2D (x, y) [length, π/2] 3D (x, y, z) [length, π] 4D (x, y, z, w) [length, 3π/2] geometric numbers break numbers free from pencil &amp; paper math requiring everything to be described as scalars and roman numeral stacked arrays of scalars a bladed angle lets them travel and transform freely without ever needing to know which dimension theyre in or facing use cargo add geonum example compute components and length with angle. project — dimension free use geonum::*; // origin is an angle let origin = Angle::new(0. 41 µs baseline tensor (O(n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/mxfactorial/geonum'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/mxfactorial/geonum</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799096</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSS Alternative to Open WebUI – ChatGPT-Like UI, API and CLI</title>
      <link>https://github.com/ServiceStack/llms</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Configure additional providers and models in llms. " Enable Providers Any providers that have their API Keys set and enabled in llms. Providers can be enabled or disabled in the UI at runtime next to the model selector, or on the command line: # Disable free providers with free models and free tiers llms --disable openrouter_free codestral google_free groq # Enable paid providers llms --enable openrouter anthropic google openai grok z.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/ServiceStack/llms'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/ServiceStack/llms</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798193</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google suspended my company's Google cloud account for the third time</title>
      <link>https://www.agwa.name/blog/post/google_suspended_sslmates_cloud_account_again</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only problem is that Google keeps suspending our Google Cloud access. com stating that my access to Google Cloud Platform had been restricted. com stating that my access to Google Cloud Platform had been restored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.agwa.name/blog/post/google_suspended_sslmates_cloud_account_again'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.agwa.name/blog/post/google_suspended_sslmates_cloud_account_again</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798827</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Illustrated Introduction to Linear Algebra, Chapter 2: The Dot Product</title>
      <link>https://www.ducktyped.org/p/linear-algebra-chapter-2-the-dot</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dot product using vectorsRemember vectors from last chapter. We just took a dot product of two vectors. Three citiesLet’s see the same example with three cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ducktyped.org/p/linear-algebra-chapter-2-the-dot'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ducktyped.org/p/linear-algebra-chapter-2-the-dot</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798741</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I analyzed 180M jobs to see what jobs AI is replacing today</title>
      <link>https://bloomberry.com/blog/i-analyzed-180m-jobs-to-see-what-jobs-ai-is-actually-replacing-today/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ByHenley Wing ChiuDecember 31, 2023 How to AI-Proof Your Career As a Knowledge Worker Last Updated: March 20, 2024 Like most people, I’ve been experimenting with ChatGPT these days. At first, it… AI Learning &amp; Development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bloomberry.com/blog/i-analyzed-180m-jobs-to-see-what-jobs-ai-is-actually-replacing-today/'&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bloomberry.com/blog/i-analyzed-180m-jobs-to-see-what-jobs-ai-is-actually-replacing-today/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798489</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
