<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:47:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>SSL Configuration Generator</title>
      <link>https://ssl-config.mozilla.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla SSL Configuration Generatormoz://a SSL Configuration Generator SSL Config GeneratorServer Software Apache AWS ALB AWS ELB Caddy Coturn Dovecot Exim Go HAProxy Jetty lighttpd MySQL nginx Oracle HTTP Postfix PostgreSQL ProFTPD Redis Squid stunnel Tomcat TraefikMozilla Configuration Modern Services with clients that support TLS 1. 3 and don't need backward compatibility Intermediate General-purpose servers with a variety of clients, recommended for almost all systems Old Compatible with a number of very old clients, and should be used only as a last resortEnvironmentServer VersionOpenSSL VersionMiscellaneousThis also redirects to HTTPS, if possiblejavascript required Copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932798"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ssl-config.mozilla.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bender:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In a similar spirit there is also a site to scan security headers of any site [1] and another to verify the TLS settings from the Mozilla SSL Configuration Generator [2] and a git repo with code to scan sites from the command line [3] &lt;i&gt;useful if the site is not reachable on the internet or automated scans to HTML reports&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;securityheaders.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;securityheaders.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ssllabs.com&amp;#x2F;ssltest&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ssllabs.com&amp;#x2F;ssltest&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;testssl&amp;#x2F;testssl.sh" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;testssl&amp;#x2F;testssl.sh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;accrual:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why are we still using the term &amp;quot;SSL&amp;quot; anywhere? It feels immediately like someone forgot the last 10 years of tech.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quesera:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This looks like something that&amp;#x27;s been around forever, but it&amp;#x27;s the first time I&amp;#x27;ve seen it. xkcd:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;{{derive_from_context}}&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a great idea. I&amp;#x27;ve created (or copied) at least half of these output formats, a few of which I remember being annoyingly difficult to surface from the project docs.&lt;p&gt;But in the moment today, it&amp;#x27;s mostly interesting to see the different ways of saying the same things in various configuration languages. And thinking that this might be why so many people with different brains find the technology world so obtuse and off-putting.&lt;p&gt;The joke&amp;#x27;s on them, of course. We like it this way! (Never wrestle with a pig...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ssl-config.mozilla.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932798</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HipKittens: Fast and furious AMD kernels</title>
      <link>https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-hk</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The existing software offerings fail to consistently achieve peak performance. CK kernels frequently underperform (see our evaluations below). Opinionated primitives are simplifying the process of writing performant NVIDIA kernels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923188"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-hk'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;georgehotz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Full disclosure, we have a contract with AMD to get Llama 405B training on MI350X on MLPerf.&lt;p&gt;Things are turning around for AMD. If you have an AMD card, go to pytorch.org, click Linux+ROCm and install PyTorch. 3 years ago, this was hopeless. Today, most mainline things work. I ran nanochat on MI300X and it just worked. I think that&amp;#x27;s true about MI350X now too. The MI350X machine is stable.&lt;p&gt;They are clearly behind NVIDIA, nobody doubts that. And a lot of investment into software will be required to catch up, ecosystem, compiler, and driver. But 2 years ago they seemed hopeless, now they don&amp;#x27;t. Things take time. HipKittens is a great codebase to study to see where AMD&amp;#x27;s LLVM backend is still lacking; compare it to the CUDA Kittens.&lt;p&gt;For training, it&amp;#x27;s NVIDIA and Google in first. AMD in second. And nobody in third. Intel and Tenstorrent are not remotely close. Huawei examples segfaulted. Groq gave up selling chips. Cerebras isn&amp;#x27;t available anywhere. Trainium had a 5 day wait time to get one instance and I lost interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LtdJorge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ahh, composable-kernel. The highest offender in the list of software that have produced unrecoverable OOMs in my Gentoo system (it’s actually Clang while compiling CK, which uses upwards of 2.5GB per thread).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wewewedxfgdf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You&amp;#x27;d think AMD would swing in on something like this and fund it with the money needed to succeed.  I have no knowledge of it but my guess is no, AMD never misses an opportunity to miss an opportunity - when it comes to GPUs and AI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bratao:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One thing I don&amp;#x27;t understand about Nvidia’s valuation is that right now a small number of algorithms have &amp;#x27;won,&amp;#x27; such as Transformers. The data is very important. Compared to the past where customized code was much more common, such as modeling code and HPC, the ecosystem was very important and it was almost impossible to implement all CUDA and related code.&lt;p&gt;Competitors now only need to optimize for a narrow set of algorithms. If a vendor can run vLLM and Transformers efficiently, a massive market becomes available. Consequently, companies like AMD or Huawei should be able to catch up easily. What, then, is Nvidia’s moat? Is InfiniBand enough?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hazyresearch.stanford.edu/blog/2025-11-09-hk</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923188</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Leak, No Problem – Bypassing ASLR with a ROP Chain to Gain RCE</title>
      <link>https://modzero.com/en/blog/no-leak-no-problem/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a modern networked surveillance camera that exposes a web-based user interface for configuration and live view. Without the firmware we’re stuck with blind fuzzing of the network interface. In the documentation it looked like it’s possible to boot right into a root shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933497"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://modzero.com/en/blog/no-leak-no-problem/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://modzero.com/en/blog/no-leak-no-problem/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 23:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933497</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing impossible happens</title>
      <link>https://www.oxonianreview.com/articles/nothing-impossible-happens</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.oxonianreview.com/articles/nothing-impossible-happens</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:39:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933960</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go's Sweet 16</title>
      <link>https://go.dev/blog/16years</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the only boost the testing package got over the past year. 25 launched container-aware scheduling, making this pairing even stronger. Under-the-hood improvements In addition to user-visible changes, Go has made significant improvements under the hood over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932962"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://go.dev/blog/16years'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bobjordan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I tried to use go in a project 6-7 years ago and was kind of  shocked by needing to fetch packages directly from source control with a real absence of built in versioning. That turned me off and I went back to python. I gather that now there’s a new system with go modules. I should probably revisit it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;threemux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use Go every day at work and it&amp;#x27;s still the first thing I reach for when completing personal projects. It gets better every year. Keep up the good work Go team!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ashishb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Contributing to a new Go codebase is easy.&lt;p&gt;The Go codebases look all alike.
Not only the language has really few primitives but also the code conventions enforced by standard library, gofmt, and golangci-lint implies that the structure of code bases are very similar.&lt;p&gt;Many language communities can&amp;#x27;t even agree on the build tooling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p2detar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I recently finished my first ever side gig in Go - a web platform that organizes business processes between multiple actors. Got paid and more feature requests are coming in. Fronted with Caddy, the whole thing runs flawlessly on a $5 VPS. I love Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sedatk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I remember when Go was born, then, it turned out there was already another programming language called &amp;quot;Go!&amp;quot;, but nobody cared, and everybody forgot about that other Go!. So, happy birthday, Go, and rest in peace, Go!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Go!_(programming_language)#Conflict_with_Google" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Go!_(programming_language)#Con...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;srameshc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Go is my favorite programming language. I remember when I first found Go and it was because I was using Java back then and learnign Akka framework for concurrent programming . I realized Go was so much less code compared to Java and I could understand it effortlessly. Since then I have been using it very regularly but still I don&amp;#x27;t feel I am good at this language. But it helps me get the work done. Cheers to the 16th anniversary of Go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tail_exchange:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was very skeptical of Go when I started learning it, but it quickly became my favourite language. I like how simple but powerful it is.&lt;p&gt;If I had a magic wand, the only things I would add is better nulability checks, add stack traces by default for errors, and exhaustive checks for sum types. Other than that, it does everything I want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MichaelNolan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Go would probably be my favorite language if it just had a few more features around functional programming. Specifically around immutability and nullness, and maybe exhaustive switch statements. Then it just might be perfect.&lt;p&gt;At work we use Uber’s NillAway, so that helps bit. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;uber-go&amp;#x2F;nilaway" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;uber-go&amp;#x2F;nilaway&lt;/a&gt; Though actually having the type system handle it would be nicer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jryio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Glad to see that the bowling development team is focusing on deterministic tooling like language server protocol in gopls and using static analysis for automatically restoring code with go fix.&lt;p&gt;Recently I made the same assertions as to Go&amp;#x27;s advantage for LLM&amp;#x2F;AI orchestration.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45895897"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45895897&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would not surprise me that Google (being the massive services company that it is) would have sent an internal memo instructing teams not to use the Python tool chain to produce production agents or tooling and use Golang.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;weakfish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like Go. Coming from Python, I appreciate having most things be explicit in nature vs. magical, and having concurrency not feel like a bolted on nightmare.&lt;p&gt;Writing microservices at $DAYJOB feels far easier and less guess-work, even if it requires more upfront code, because it’s clear what each piece does and why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xeoncross:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know they say that your programming language isn&amp;#x27;t the bottleneck, but I remember sitting there being frustrated as a young dev that I couldn&amp;#x27;t parse faster in the languages I was using when I learned about Go.&lt;p&gt;It took a few more years before I actually got around to learning it and I have to say I&amp;#x27;ve never picked up a language so quickly. (Which makes sense, it&amp;#x27;s got the smallest language spec of any of them)&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure there are plenty of reasons this is wrong, but it feels like Go gets me 80% of the way to Rust with 20% of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tschellenbach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10 week onboarding program we use here for go backend devs: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;golang&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1eiea6q&amp;#x2F;10_week_plan_to_master_go_getstreams_onboarding&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;golang&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1eiea6q&amp;#x2F;10_week_pla...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;go is amazing. switches from python to go 7 years ago. It&amp;#x27;s the reason our startup did well&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://go.dev/blog/16years</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932962</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genergo: Propellantless space-propulsion system</title>
      <link>https://www.satcom.digital/news/genergo-an-italian-company-builds-the-worlds-first-known-propellantless-space-propulsion-system-flight-tested-and-validated-on-orbit</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genergo: an Italian Company Builds the World’s First Known Propellantless Space-propulsion System, Flight-tested and Validated On Orbit 11 Nov Written By Jaime Farr Genergo, an Italian deep-tech company based in Como, comes out of stealth and unveils an innovative electromagnetic space-propulsion system that uses no propellant, successfully flight-tested and validated across three space missions and protected by a portfolio of granted international patents. Genergo’s system generates thrust without using any propellant and without expelling reaction mass, by directly converting electrical energy into thrust through controlled electromagnetic impulses. Genergo’s technology opens new perspectives for space missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931224"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.satcom.digital/news/genergo-an-italian-company-builds-the-worlds-first-known-propellantless-space-propulsion-system-flight-tested-and-validated-on-orbit'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 22 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;discoutdynamite:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Skimmed the patent. Its 99% a pedantic and exhaustive explanation of a linear motor. The only interesting thing they mention, is this:&lt;p&gt;The inertial mass of an object varies with the variation of its magnetic field and therefore a variation of inertia can be created&lt;p&gt;But they provide no explanation whatsoever for how a glorified linear motor is relativistically (or otherwise) affecting inertial mass. This could be operating under a novel application of ECE Theory, wherein they are using magnetism to affect gravity, but I doubt it. They would have claimed so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anonymousiam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Torque rods are not a new thing.  Lots of LEO spacecraft use them.  They don&amp;#x27;t work for MEO&amp;#x2F;GEO because Earth&amp;#x27;s magnetic field decreases 1&amp;#x2F;R^3.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Magnetorquer" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Magnetorquer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jiggawatts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Scientifically tested!&amp;quot; is the marketing term for &amp;quot;The tests showed it didn&amp;#x27;t work, but we won&amp;#x27;t mention that second part!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;E.g.:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;successfully flight-tested&amp;quot; -- didn&amp;#x27;t break or leak anything when launched into space. A brick also has these properties.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;validated across three space missions&amp;quot; -- a brick could be flown multiple times too, this proves nothing except that this thing is space-rated.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;protected by a portfolio of granted international patents&amp;quot; -- we&amp;#x27;ve got more lawyers than engineers!&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;accumulated more than 700 hours of on-orbit operation&amp;quot; -- I could say the same thing about a brick left in orbit for a month.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;multiple on-orbit activation cycles have continued alongside data analysis and characterization activities&amp;quot; -- we kept turning it on and off in a futile attempt to work out why nothing was happening.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;confirmed system functionality in real space conditions&amp;quot; -- It definitely was &amp;quot;on&amp;quot;, drawing power and everything!&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;several long-duration tests were conducted in which it was observed, objectively and repeatedly, that motor activation produced a measurable acceleration or deceleration of the host spacecraft.&amp;quot; -- we got confused by atmospheric drag, IMU drift, vibrations, and other confounding factors and called the experiment a success despite a string of failures for short-duration tests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lichtso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For everybody claiming that locomotion without the impulse of a reaction mass is impossible: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2112.09740v2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2112.09740v2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;and before anybody only reads &amp;quot;spacetime curvature&amp;quot; and thinks the paper is talking about a warp drive, it is not.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this Genergo thingy seems to be nonsense IMO, or they would have actually explained how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hinkley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The JPL had a project called M2P2 that explored using magnetic field lines and plasma to create a solar sail out of ionized gas. The idea being that it can be regenerated in the face of micrometeoroids and other space debris.&lt;p&gt;Tethers.inc wanted to, among other things, used cables as a drag line to either lower satellites in orbit by absorbing electrical flux from passing through the magnetosphere, or pulse the cable to push against it to raise the orbit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;octaane:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not possible according to the laws of physics. The closest you can get is a solar sail, but that&amp;#x27;s not &amp;quot;propellant-less&amp;quot; - photons are the propellant.&lt;p&gt;If a company thinks they&amp;#x27;ve broken one of the most fundamental laws of physics (momentum transfer), they need to provide some serious evidence, and publish in full so their results can be replicated. A press release on an obscure website isn&amp;#x27;t how you do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cjameskeller:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Link to relevant patent: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.google.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;US11462985B2&amp;#x2F;en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.google.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;US11462985B2&amp;#x2F;en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;colechristensen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is very likely either nonsense or something very mundane explained poorly.&lt;p&gt;Reactionless drives are probably impossible and inventing them would be an earthshattering breakthrough.&lt;p&gt;Drives &amp;quot;powered&amp;quot; by photon reactions are possible but to get a meaningful amount of thrust you have to produce just an absurd amount of light. (using one in orbit would be a weapon of mass destruction, brighter than the sun, etc)&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I don&amp;#x27;t know, maybe this is something mundane with a little bit of thrust interacting with sparse upper atmosphere gas or something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;visviva:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Impossible claim with no evidence offered - curious why this is on the front page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;beloch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Satellites once used propellant for attitude control.  When the propellant was used up, the satellite lost the ability to maintain or change orientation.  Very much as this article describes, control moment gyroscopes took over because they didn&amp;#x27;t require propellant. They operate on the same principles that let a cat land on it&amp;#x27;s feet by twisting about as it falls.&lt;p&gt;However, there&amp;#x27;s a key difference between attitude control and movement.  Changing your orientation doesn&amp;#x27;t involve changes in net kinetic energy, momentum, etc..  Changing speed (i.e. What a propulsion system does) does involve changes in these quantities, so Newtonian conservation laws come into play.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Genergo’s system generates thrust without using any propellant and without expelling reaction mass, by directly converting electrical energy into thrust through controlled electromagnetic impulses.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If this isn&amp;#x27;t hogwash, it might be something similar to an ion engine.  i.e. It &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; operate by expelling propellant, but what it uses as propellant is background dust and ions, accelerated to a high velocity by electric fields and expelled.&lt;p&gt;If, as the site claims, this technology is currently working and produces non-negligible thrust, it could be very useful.  They need to be very clear about what this is though, since vague and unscientific sounding claims will not attract clients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanzig:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am &lt;i&gt;highly&lt;/i&gt; skeptical. A reactionless thruster is the holy grail of propulsion systems, but there are no known physics which permit it to work. A photon rocket would allow momentum exchange without mass consumption, but a quick look at the math shows it would be infeasible (hundreds of megawatts per newton).&lt;p&gt;My guess is this works at all, it is inadvertently expelling reaction mass somehow, such as ablating off small amounts of volatiles from polymer parts (like an inefficient version of a pulsed plasma thruster).&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d love to be wrong, but this very much falls into the &amp;quot;extraordinary claims&amp;quot; category for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terr_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My money&amp;#x27;s on fake woo-woo.&lt;p&gt;At first—like many others here—I thought it might just be a terribly-written explanation for a device that uses Earth&amp;#x27;s magnetic field, so that the planet itself is the &amp;quot;reaction mass&amp;quot; being pushed around... but I&amp;#x27;m not seeing that in a quick patent search for the company.&lt;p&gt;Instead, there&amp;#x27;s a bunch of stuff that seems like perpetual-motion-machine crankery, where their &amp;quot;motor&amp;quot; depends on a oscillating some mass back and forth inside a chamber using special frequencies and &amp;quot;waveforms&amp;quot;, which &lt;i&gt;somehow&lt;/i&gt; imparts some acceleration which they explain as &amp;quot;generating mass.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; use Earth&amp;#x27;s magnetic field through pure experimental error, and they either haven&amp;#x27;t realized it or think they can bilk investors by presenting it as something new.&lt;p&gt;_________&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.google.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;US11462985B2&amp;#x2F;en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.google.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;US11462985B2&amp;#x2F;en&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The inertial mass of an object varies with the variation of its magnetic field and therefore a variation of inertia can be created which leads to the generation of mass by varying the magnetization of the motor and its constituent elements (at given times, as explained above).&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; [...] the variation of “mass” is generated by the overmagnetization or undermagnetization of the motor itself in conjunction with given “shocks” or interactions between the magnetic piston and the two buffer magnets [...]&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.justia.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;11462985" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;patents.justia.com&amp;#x2F;patent&amp;#x2F;11462985&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; [In] general the motor or the moving system according to the present invention consists of an electromagnetically charged body which moves within a delimited volume of space being accelerated and decelerated electromagnetically in controlled manner during its movement within said volume of space.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Such accelerations&amp;#x2F;decelerations generate a force on the volume inside which the mass moves and allow the volume of space to move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drillsteps5:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I remember in the 80s, after mostly having given up on perpetuuum mobile, bunch of people were trying to invent something like this, using vibration etc which worked on Earth but would not in a vacuum... Looks like a new generation took the baton. Like this guy:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.popularmechanics.com&amp;#x2F;space&amp;#x2F;rockets&amp;#x2F;a65924333&amp;#x2F;engineer-overcoming-earths-gravity&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.popularmechanics.com&amp;#x2F;space&amp;#x2F;rockets&amp;#x2F;a65924333&amp;#x2F;eng...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Engineer Says He’s Found a Way to Overcome Earth’s Gravity&lt;p&gt;This new propulsion system could rewrite the rules of spaceflight—not to mention completely defy conventional physics.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In 2001, British Electrical Engineer Roger Shawyer first introduced the “impossible drive,” known as the EmDrive. It was called “impossible” because its creator purported that the drive was reactionless, meaning no propellant required—in other words, it defied the known laws of physics (specifically, the conservation of momentum).&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fudged71:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Extraordinary claims need extraordinary evidence&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hbrav:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article is quite frustrating, since all that it really tells me is that their system &amp;quot;generates thrust without using any propellant and without expelling reaction mass, by directly converting electrical energy into thrust through controlled electromagnetic impulses&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s rather non-specific. My first thought was that they&amp;#x27;re using photon momentum, but thinking about that a little harder rules it out. The ratio of energy to momentum doesn&amp;#x27;t change with any properties of the photon (they&amp;#x27;re both proportional to frequency) so there&amp;#x27;s nothing to really develop there: so long as you waste very little power as heat, you might as well be shining a well-collimated flashlight.&lt;p&gt;Options 3 and 4 from [this paper](&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;2510.21743" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;2510.21743&lt;/a&gt;), _magnetic sails_ and _solar sails_, seem more promising. Is that what Genergo are doing? I have no idea. The article doesn&amp;#x27;t tell me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wat10000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;1. No info given about how this system works.&lt;p&gt;2. No info about how it supposedly produces thrust.&lt;p&gt;3. No numbers given except for number of hours tested in orbit. No thrust or power consumption figures.&lt;p&gt;4. Violates pretty widely accepted law of physics.&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I&amp;#x27;m ever so slightly skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BurningFrog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Genergo’s system generates thrust without using any propellant and without expelling reaction mass, by directly converting  electrical energy into thrust through controlled electromagnetic impulses.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone have a clue how this might work?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phpnode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;is this EmDrive v2.0? [0]&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;EmDrive" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;EmDrive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snow_mac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is amazing. I wonder how it works. I would be cool if they published it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;frankfrank13:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a layman I have no idea which part of this to be skeptical of, but, cool!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mlyle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not possible under standard physics.&lt;p&gt;I mean, there are propellant-free ways to change trajectory-- gravitational assists, aerobraking, solar sails, etc.&lt;p&gt;You can even boost with something like an electrodynamic tether in theory (a magnetic field gradient lets you apply a net force).  But field gradients out at LEO are low, and I don&amp;#x27;t think that&amp;#x27;s what&amp;#x27;s being claimed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a-priori:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They say it works &amp;quot;by directly converting electrical energy into thrust through controlled electromagnetic impulses&amp;quot;, so I assume it&amp;#x27;s reacting against the Earth&amp;#x27;s magnetic field using the Lorentz force?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.satcom.digital/news/genergo-an-italian-company-builds-the-worlds-first-known-propellantless-space-propulsion-system-flight-tested-and-validated-on-orbit</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931224</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
