<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:37:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone Germany is killing the open internet – one peering connection at a time</title>
      <link>https://coffee.link/vodafone-germany-is-killing-the-open-internet-one-peering-connection-at-a-time/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vodafone Germany is about to blow that system up. By the end of 2025, Vodafone will have completely withdrawn from every public internet exchange in Germany, including DE-CIX Frankfurt, the largest internet exchange on the planet. And it's exactly what Vodafone is abandoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848484"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://coffee.link/vodafone-germany-is-killing-the-open-internet-one-peering-connection-at-a-time/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hylaride:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bell Canada also has had a long-standing policy of refusing to peer with internet exchanges.  They&amp;#x27;ll only truly peer with other direct backbone providers and a handful of one-off peer with other large networks (google, cloud flare, etc), but their historical position as Canada&amp;#x27;s base backbone (not so much anymore, but it was definitely a think pre-2005) has meant their policy is most people should pay them to peer.  I&amp;#x27;m not sure if it&amp;#x27;s still the case, but IIRC for awhile they also refused to peer with any other domestic backbone providers.&lt;p&gt;The result has been some funny routes sometimes.  I live in Toronto and have seen trace routes bounce over to Chicago to connect to stuff colocated here in Toronto.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s frustrating as their fibre is my only real high speed option; also their lack of IPv6 on anything but their mobile network is annoying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phineyes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t unique to Vodafone. Google has also been slowly withdrawing from IXes globally in favor of PNIs and &amp;quot;VPPs&amp;quot; (verified peering providers). This only makes it harder for smaller networks to establish presence on the internet and feels pretty anti-competitive.&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, IXes are becoming harder and less desirable to participate in: port fees are going up, useful networks are withdrawing, low quality network participants are joining and widening blast radius. I&amp;#x27;m not sure what the answer to this is, but this has not been a great year for the &amp;quot;open&amp;quot; internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tracker1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hate this line of thinking.. Netflix isn&amp;#x27;t just sending data to random users, it&amp;#x27;s data Vodafone users request and want to receive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoredPositron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fucking around with peering is the specialty of German ISPs. Telekom (our biggest provider) is sometimes unusable for YouTube&amp;#x2F;Netflix&amp;#x2F;Cloudflare&amp;#x2F;Steam in big cities because of similar shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fuzzy2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s important to keep in mind that Deutsche Telekom is basically doing the same, and has been… forever?&lt;p&gt;I disagree with this move, but it is not without precedent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mystraline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The play by major content providers is &amp;quot;not to pay&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;block inter.link&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Sure, you lose Vodafone germany. Then you explain clearly why to every major media.&lt;p&gt;This coukd be stopped fairly quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there anything that Vodafone customers can do legally to punish Vodafone or not delivering on their broadband contracts?&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re paying for a 1Gbps connection and Netflix is only able to stream to you at 0.93 Mbps because Vodafone or Inter.link are choking off the supply, surely that&amp;#x27;s breach of contract on Vodafone&amp;#x27;s part?&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure Cory Doctorow has a word for what&amp;#x27;s happening here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liftyee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;New selling point for all the VPN sponsored segments... &amp;quot;if you&amp;#x27;re on Vodafone Germany, make your connection speeds faster with YetAnotherVPN!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;benced:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Rare comparative W for American ISPs?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wil421:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I worked with Vodafone years ago to do an integration with ticketing systems. It seems like no one actually worked for Vodafone it was all contractors or contractors of contractors of contractors.&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing peering to a 3rd party seems like their playbook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://coffee.link/vodafone-germany-is-killing-the-open-internet-one-peering-connection-at-a-time/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848484</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Love OCaml</title>
      <link>https://mccd.space/posts/ocaml-the-worlds-best/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good performance Good documentation And then, enter OCaml. With Dune, OCaml compiles extremely fast. I’m left feeling that the authors of OCaml have good taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846517"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://mccd.space/posts/ocaml-the-worlds-best/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 23 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timhh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; why isn’t OCaml more popular&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve used OCaml a bit and found various issues with it:&lt;p&gt;* Terrible Windows support. With OCaml 5 it&amp;#x27;s upgraded to &amp;quot;pretty bad&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;* The syntax is hard to parse for humans. Often it turns into a word soup, without any helpful punctuation to tell you what things are. It&amp;#x27;s like reading a book with no paragraphs, capitalisation or punctuation.&lt;p&gt;* The syntax isn&amp;#x27;t recoverable. Sometimes you can add a single character and the error message is essentially &amp;quot;syntax error in these 1000 lines&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;* Ocamlfmt is pretty bad. It thinks it is writing prose. It will even put complex `match`es on one line if they fit. Really hurts readability.&lt;p&gt;* The documentation is super terse. Very few examples.&lt;p&gt;* OPAM. In theory... I feel like it should be great. But in practice I find it to be incomprehensible, full of surprising behaviours, and also surprisingly buggy. I still can&amp;#x27;t believe the bug where it can&amp;#x27;t find `curl` if you&amp;#x27;re in more than 32 Unix groups.&lt;p&gt;* Optional type annotation for function signatures throws away a significant benefit of static typing - documentation&amp;#x2F;understanding and nice error messages.&lt;p&gt;* Tiny ecosystem. Rust gets flak for its small standard library, but OCaml doesn&amp;#x27;t even have a built in function to copy files.&lt;p&gt;* Like all FP languages it has a weird obsession with singly linked lists, which are actually a pretty awful data structure.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not all bad though, and I&amp;#x27;d definitely take it over C and Python. Definitely wouldn&amp;#x27;t pick it over Rust though, unless I was &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; worried about compile times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArnavAgrawal03:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Came here to say I love Ocaml too&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ilaksh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why isn&amp;#x27;t it more popular if it&amp;#x27;s so good? Because popularity and merit are not the same thing. People confuse them all the time though.&lt;p&gt;Check out the most popular music today. Like the top ten songs currently. Do you think those are really the best songs out there?&lt;p&gt;Popularity is mostly driven by either trends or momentum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fermigier:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Little known fact: OCaml was at one point called &amp;quot;Zinc&amp;quot; (&amp;quot;Zinc is not Caml&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phplovesong:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I kind of wish (like the OP mentioned) there was a ML (ocaml) like language that compiled to Go source. You would get the best of both worlds and access to a huge ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yujzgzc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I loved Ocaml but now I love TypeScript more. It&amp;#x27;s got about the same amount of type safety, the ergonomics are better to me, and the packaging and ecosystem tooling are leaps and bounds above anything else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a-dub:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;fun fact: the secret sauce that makes fftw fast is a code generator written in ocaml: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;FFTW&amp;#x2F;fftw3&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;genfft" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;FFTW&amp;#x2F;fftw3&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;genfft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;japhib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Elixir is the closest thing to OCaml that has a chance at semi-mainstream usage IMO.&lt;p&gt;It has basically all of the stuff about functional programming that makes it easier to reason about your code &amp;amp; get work done - immutability, pattern matching, actors, etc. But without monads or a complicated type system that would give it a higher barrier to entry. And of course it&amp;#x27;s built on top of the Erlang BEAM runtime, which has a great track record as a foundation for backend systems. It doesn&amp;#x27;t have static typing, although the type system is a lot stronger than most other dynamic languages like JS or Python, and the language devs are currently adding gradual type checking into the compiler.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One of the best P2P clients ever created is written in OCaml: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;ygrek&amp;#x2F;mldonkey" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;ygrek&amp;#x2F;mldonkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m still surprised it can do so many things so well, so fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;efficax:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;OCaml is fantastic, but I avoided it and went with Rust for many projects because it had no multicore story and no green threads for a very long time. But it has that now, and I wish I could go back and start everything over in OCaml.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pasxizeis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a Rust newbie and seasoned Go dev, I&amp;#x27;m pretty interested to knownwhere would people experienced in both OCaml and Haskell, would put it in the spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ModernMech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;why isn’t OCaml more popular?&lt;p&gt;OCaml did become popular, but via Rust, which took the best parts of OCaml and made the language more imperative feeling. That&amp;#x27;s what OCaml was missing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p0nce:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well I need both float and double, so cannot even start using it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;karmakaze:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve dabbled in F# &lt;i&gt;(and aside from the rough setup with little coherent information at the time)&lt;/i&gt; had a pretty good time. Actor-based concurrency was easy to grok. The one gotcha was whenever those mutable Arrays entered the picture.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d like to hear some practical reasons for preferring OCaml over F#. &lt;i&gt;[Hoping I don&amp;#x27;t get a lot about MS &amp;amp; .NET which are valid concerns but not what I&amp;#x27;m curious about.]&lt;/i&gt; I want to know more about day to day usage pros&amp;#x2F;cons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pulkas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;darklang team loved ocaml too. in the end they ended up using f#.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ufko_org:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes, in every ML&amp;#x2F;OCaml tutorial, sooner or later the words object, class, and type inference appear and that’s when a once–minimalist language turns into an academic Frankenstein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pkilgore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s some other stuff, but I personally believe if the tooling was closer to Rust&amp;#x2F;Go than C, it would be a lot, lot more popular.&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants to effectively learn a lisp to configure a build system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sanufar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;OCaml’s REPL is lovely, but I found myself having some friction with initial startup. The build&amp;#x2F;package system was pretty convoluted, and I ended up choosing JS’s Core stdlib for my needs (a simple compiler). With the new multicore release it’d be cool to see OCaml in some more practical projects!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeathArrow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For something a bit more modern but still related to OCaml, one can try F#.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fmbb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; It is an old language, and there are a few features that could probably be left out like the OOP-related features, and some libraries in the ecosystem over-complicate things like in Haskell.&lt;p&gt;If one can stand a language that is just a little bit older, there is always Standard ML. It is like OCaml, but perfect!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wslh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Offtopic HTML issue to the author: there is a trailing &amp;lt;&amp;#x2F;head&amp;gt; tag at the end of your generated HTML after the &amp;lt;&amp;#x2F;body&amp;gt; (instead of &amp;lt;&amp;#x2F;html&amp;gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pohl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To this day, whenever I see Machine Learning abbreviated, my heart skips a beat, then I become crestfallen as I realize I&amp;#x27;m not about to read something about Meta Language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmpk2k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;OCaml has been one of those &amp;quot;almost there&amp;quot; languages since at least 2002. Most of the worthwhile ideas in OCaml will be absorbed into more popular languages by the time existing friction is sorted out.  :&amp;#x2F;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mccd.space/posts/ocaml-the-worlds-best/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846517</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gmail AI gets more intrusive</title>
      <link>https://daveverse.org/2025/11/07/gmail-ai-gets-even-more-intrusive/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gmail doesn't just offer to write your emails for you, they actually do it, and it's up to you to delete the text it wrote. Hard to make a screen shot to demo without revealing personal info. That's how awful this thing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848504"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://daveverse.org/2025/11/07/gmail-ai-gets-even-more-intrusive/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;renewiltord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yeah, you gotta watch out for this stuff. The other day I was using Gmail when it just gave me a million dollars. I gave it to charity under an assumed name.&lt;p&gt;Can’t screenshot without revealing the name but I think it’s actually super cool of Google to do this. Just distributed charity. With no benefit to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pflenker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tangentially related, the AI integrated in Google Chat is hilariously bad. Find a thread which starts with „Bug: (…)“ that has 90+ answers. Hey, an AI could be useful here! Click summarize. Wait. Without fail the result will be along the lines of „X, Y and Z discuss a bug.“&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cpursley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve found the email thread summary pretty useful ymmv.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NelsonMinar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could use a more reliable source for this report.&lt;p&gt;I paid for and tried Google AI for Gmail and was appalled at how bad it is. The product team there is really not executing well. I&amp;#x27;ve switched now to Shortwave. It works very well and having LLM+RAG queries for 20+ years of email archives has been very helpful to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;charlieyu1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A client emailed me for a meeting at Monday 2pm. The Gmail AI immediately marked Monday 2am on my calendar and it cannot even be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;merelysounds:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anecdotally, I don’t see any of this. I have all “smart” features in gmail turned off; there is an option like this in the settings.&lt;p&gt;Google’s Help: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;support.google.com&amp;#x2F;mail&amp;#x2F;answer&amp;#x2F;15604322" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;support.google.com&amp;#x2F;mail&amp;#x2F;answer&amp;#x2F;15604322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also relevant:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; By default, smart feature settings are off if you live in: The European Economic Area, Japan, Switzerland, United Kingdom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IncreasePosts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Did the user accidentally keep hitting Alt+H? Or are they part of some experiment? Gmail writes nothing for me unless I click the &amp;quot;help me write&amp;quot; link. I also don&amp;#x27;t know why it is so hard to record a screenshot of the behavior, you can write it to example@example.com, and the draft email UI can be clipped from where it shows your email address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;verdverm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;100% Google has been making their AI more intrusive and in your face across all their portfolio. It&amp;#x27;s not just Google, Atlassian is doing the same&lt;p&gt;With search in gcloud, the drop-down top 2&amp;#x2F;3 is ai calls to action. Completely useless because their suggestions are so bad and for such basic tasks that I never do.&lt;p&gt;It feels like in platform advertising.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve left them feedback, and since they&amp;#x27;ve only doubled down, am now reducing my spend&lt;p&gt;Moving to Cloudflare, if you&amp;#x27;re curious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://daveverse.org/2025/11/07/gmail-ai-gets-even-more-intrusive/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848504</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Denmark's government aims to ban access to social media for children under 15</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/denmark-social-media-ban-children-7862d2a8cc590b4969c8931a01adc7f4</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Her ministry said pressure from tech giants’ business models was “too massive. ” Aiming to shield kids from harmful content onlineMany governments have been grappling with ways of limiting harmful fallout from online technologies, without overly squelching their promise. Stage said Denmark’s legislative push was “not about excluding children from everything digital” — but keeping them away from harmful content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848083"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://apnews.com/article/denmark-social-media-ban-children-7862d2a8cc590b4969c8931a01adc7f4'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;super256:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[delayed]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;awillen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The one thing I don&amp;#x27;t see and always wonder about with these sorts of things is how they define &amp;quot;social media&amp;quot;. Seems like a tough thing to do - if you cast too broad a definition you&amp;#x27;ll end up with just about anywhere one can communicate on the internet, including email. If you take the very narrow approach of naming FB, IG, TikTok, etc., you almost certainly miss out on whatever the next platform is that&amp;#x27;s relevant to kids.&lt;p&gt;Remember YikYak? IIRC that was worse for kids than most of the big social media sites, but how do you write a law that anticipates the next YikYak without banning everything?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notepad0x90:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It sounds extreme, but I support banning usage of anything that runs software for children under 13. Under 13, children are still developing their minds, it is important for their welfare that they learn how to function without technological dependencies.&lt;p&gt;You know how in school they used to tell us we can&amp;#x27;t use calculators to solve math problems? Same thing. It can&amp;#x27;t be done by individual parents either, because then kids would get envious and that in itself would cause more problems than it would solve.&lt;p&gt;It is important for kids to get bored, to socialize in person, to solve problems the hard way, and develop the mental-muscles they need to not only function, but to make best use of modern technology.&lt;p&gt;It is also important that parents don&amp;#x27;t use technology to raise their children (includes TV). Most parents just give their kids a tablet with youtube these days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;postepowanieadm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m a bit suspicious: it was Denmark&amp;#x27;s government that pushed for chat control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;poly2it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A reason to be cautious about propositions like these isn&amp;#x27;t just the inherent belittling of children&amp;#x27;s right to information, which can be argued for or against in certain cases, but the aspect of giving any proceeding government the ability to ban a form of media from children due to their perception of toxicity, derangement, danger, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ceayo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;here we go again...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;umanwizard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good, IMO it should be 18 if not even higher, but 15 is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;worldfoodgood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great. Please raise the age to 115.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telaneo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;ll be interesting to see what they can cook up at home. Chat Control was pushed in large part by Denmark, and Minister of Justice Peter Hummelgaard is on record saying some pretty disturbing things regarding the right to privacy online.[1] Now for this, they don&amp;#x27;t need the entire EU to go along, and any laws already on the books might prove ineffective to protect against means that end up achieving similar goals to Chat Control.&lt;p&gt;Denmark&amp;#x27;s constitution does have a privacy paragraph, but it explicitly mentions telephone and telegraph, as well as letters.[2] Turns out online messaging doesn&amp;#x27;t count. It&amp;#x27;d be a funny one to get to whatever court, because hopefully someone there will have a brain and use it, but it wouldn&amp;#x27;t be the first time someone didn&amp;#x27;t.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;boingboing.net&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;15&amp;#x2F;danish-justice-minister-we-must-break-perception-of-right-to-private-messaging.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;boingboing.net&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;15&amp;#x2F;danish-justice-minister-we...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.grundloven.dk&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.grundloven.dk&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;casesarplus1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How will they achieve that without introducing a requirement to identify yourself on every online platform, which some would say is probably the whole reason for introducing something promoted as being &amp;quot;for the children&amp;quot;™.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aldipower:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Our current form of asocial media is nothing else like drug abuse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://apnews.com/article/denmark-social-media-ban-children-7862d2a8cc590b4969c8931a01adc7f4</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848083</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxic Salton Sea dust triggers changes in lung microbiome after just one week</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-toxic-salton-sea-triggers-lung.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;00209-25 Dust from California's drying Salton Sea doesn't just smell bad. "The dust also just doesn't smell good," said Emma Aronson, UCR environmental microbiologist and study author. " Some dust samples were especially potent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848341"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://phys.org/news/2025-10-toxic-salton-sea-triggers-lung.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;broof:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This makes me incredibly concerned for the great salt lake&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yabones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No wonder the lake is drying up with so much irrigation for agriculture, and an absurd number of golf courses in a very small area.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.google.ca&amp;#x2F;maps&amp;#x2F;@33.6867973,-116.2608676,25994m" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.google.ca&amp;#x2F;maps&amp;#x2F;@33.6867973,-116.2608676,25994m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s clear to me as an outsider that California has serious water sustainability problems. I mean, how long can this last?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jorts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not surprising.  I have a friend who grew up in El Centro and had asthma his whole childhood.  Shortly after moving, he never had respiratory issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://phys.org/news/2025-10-toxic-salton-sea-triggers-lung.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848341</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A.I. and Social Media Contribute to 'Brain Rot'</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/06/technology/personaltech/ai-social-media-brain-rot.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/11/06/technology/personaltech/ai-social-media-brain-rot.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:34:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847465</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nasdaq 100 set for worst week since April meltdown</title>
      <link>https://fortune.com/2025/11/07/nasdaq-100-worst-week-since-april-bear-market-correction/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Investors should prioritize good risk/reward setups, potentially after a healthy pullback within this bull market. Bitcoin extended this week’s slide to 9%. said citing citing EPFR Global data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848428"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://fortune.com/2025/11/07/nasdaq-100-worst-week-since-april-bear-market-correction/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eddy_Viscosity2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Whenever the stock market goes down there is a default, likely algorithmically produced headline that says &amp;quot;This is the worst its been since the last time it was this bad which was X ago&amp;quot;. Meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thriftwy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;paulgraham.com&amp;#x2F;yahoo.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;paulgraham.com&amp;#x2F;yahoo.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;By 1998, Yahoo was the beneficiary of a de facto Ponzi scheme. Investors were excited about the Internet. One reason they were excited was Yahoo&amp;#x27;s revenue growth. So they invested in new Internet startups. The startups then used the money to buy ads on Yahoo to get traffic. Which caused yet more revenue growth for Yahoo, and further convinced investors the Internet was worth investing in. When I realized this one day, sitting in my cubicle, I jumped up like Archimedes in his bathtub, except instead of &amp;quot;Eureka!&amp;quot; I was shouting &amp;quot;Sell!&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Это к вопросу о эпицикле Оракла-Нвидии.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fleventynine:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s still above where it was a few weeks ago. I don&amp;#x27;t see why this is news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fred_is_fred:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It will go back up when Meta borrows from Amazon to buy capacity from Oracle who buys silicon from Broadcom to fund GPUs from nVidia to let OpenAI enhance their app to make Facebook posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jauntywundrkind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Still, up +25% since 6mo ago. Sooo...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fortune.com/2025/11/07/nasdaq-100-worst-week-since-april-bear-market-correction/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45848428</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Making a Small RPG and I Need Feeback Regarding Performance</title>
      <link>https://jslegenddev.substack.com/p/im-making-a-small-rpg-and-i-need</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jslegenddev.substack.com/p/im-making-a-small-rpg-and-i-need</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846360</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
