<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:42:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Ask HN: How would u setup a child's first Linux computer?</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864732</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By comparison on Linux if they search the local “app store” they’ll find stacks and stacks of free, useful, open licensed software. My kids loved the power, freedom and later unexpected community this bought them. Linux with free and open software is the goal and focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864732"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864732'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GTP:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The second hand desktop idea is good. But, if her parents are a bit on the nerd side as well, think how much fun they could have together with a Raspberry pi! It could be the evolution of playing Lego together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;haunter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;An immutable distro, probably Fedora Kinoite &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.fedoraproject.org&amp;#x2F;atomic-desktops&amp;#x2F;kinoite&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.fedoraproject.org&amp;#x2F;atomic-desktops&amp;#x2F;kinoite&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;In windows when a child goes searching the web for a “movie maker for windows” they are going to be in a world of hurt either finding expensive commercial options or super scammy sites promising the world.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s funny that you use that example because the state of video editors on Windows have never been better from industry standard free options (DaVinci Resolve) to FOSS options (KDEnlive, Openshot, Shotcut, Avidemux etc). And tbh 99% of the time for a kid Canva or Adobe Express would be more than enough which are also free to use.&lt;p&gt;What you describe is a Google &amp;#x2F; web &amp;#x2F; browser problem not an OS one&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;microtonal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;My kids loved the power, freedom and later unexpected community this bought them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it is also important to realize&amp;#x2F;point out that we do a lot of projecting and our child may have very different interests. Not saying that applies to you &lt;i&gt;evolve2k&lt;/i&gt;, just wanted to make the general point.&lt;p&gt;I set up a Linux machine with our daughter and while it was initially ok, she did not have much interest in the power&amp;#x2F;freedom and it only became a nuisance for her. Her school&amp;#x2F;friends use PowerPoint - there is a lot of friction trying work with them in LibreOffice. She wanted to do DTP-like things several times and the Linux options are not exactly... user-friendly. Etc.&lt;p&gt;In the end we got her a Mac Mini. She can still open a terminal, use Homebrew, etc. if she ever develops an interest. Heck, she can use most free software. However, she can also do the stuff she is currently interested in much more easily. E.g., she uses Swift Publisher, which is a very simple&amp;#x2F;user-friendly DTP program, can collaborate on PowerPoint presentations when needed, etc.&lt;p&gt;First and foremost listen to what &lt;i&gt;your child&lt;/i&gt; is interested in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nurettin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just give them a raspberry pi and show them gcompris and luanti.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nickserv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I went with LDE Neon for both my kids. It&amp;#x27;s also what I use, I really like the KDE ecosystem, very polished experience overall.&lt;p&gt;Also it&amp;#x27;s similar enough to Windows that they don&amp;#x27;t feel completely out of touch on the school computers.&lt;p&gt;Killer app is Krita for the older one, even got him a cheap Wacom later on.&lt;p&gt;Otherwise school work, native Linux games, and YouTube. That last one with the younger one I have to keep an eye on. Honestly thinking about blocking access, we&amp;#x27;ll see.&lt;p&gt;Both like gaming, so I set up wine for them on my machine with separate accounts. Learning about email, downloads, files and folders by installing Skyrim mods (using kid friendly settings on Nexus), also an exercise in managing frustration...&lt;p&gt;Anyway everyone will be different, just set up something they&amp;#x27;ll enjoy. Already for a kid to know Linux exists is a head start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;croisillon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Windows Movie Maker used to be such a gem, pity it has been discontinued! Nowadays I use Openshot on Windows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xrd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They probably will want to play games. It&amp;#x27;s a slippery slope. But if you go that route:&lt;p&gt;Steam works amazingly well. And you can set up family controls.&lt;p&gt;Roblox works great using &amp;quot;Sober&amp;quot; I don&amp;#x27;t recommend letting them play Roblox but I&amp;#x27;m stuck with it.&lt;p&gt;Minecraft and Curseforge work well, too.&lt;p&gt;Time Keeper Next is a great time limiting control system. If you have a little awareness of docker you can run it in a container and even access it on your phone through an admin gui. If you need help on that get my email from my profile and I&amp;#x27;ll happily share my details.&lt;p&gt;My kids 8,10,12 know how to use the command line. I&amp;#x27;m really proud of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shantara:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fedora Atomic, maybe? I would have probably found it a bit too restrictive as a teen, but I think it’s a good choice for preventing a younger child from accidentally breaking the system, while still providing enough ability to experiment and learn stuff using distrobox&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My kids (pre-teen) have Pi400s. It  lets them play around with basic graphics apps, write stories, write and print letters to family, play simple games without the kid-hostile world of modern “mainstream” gaming, watch movies from the NAS, etc.&lt;p&gt;More than enough to keep them entertained and teach them the basics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;austin-cheney:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would put your entire house behind a custom DNS relay you control, like a PiHole. Use that to eliminate access to advertisements, pornography, some walware, and social media.&lt;p&gt;I would also consider use of Gentoo as your Linux distribution to force learning about building packages and command line. I would avoid Arch as that might be too much of a challenge.&lt;p&gt;For me the goal would be forcing them to learn how this stuff works. I would emphasize scripting in the shell like bash scripts, JavaScript via node, Python, and possibly even Perl. This will take a lot of guidance to get this started because they will need some real world use cases about why they immediately benefit.&lt;p&gt;Once you get the OS finally set up create an ISO of it and put it on both a thumb drive and home file server. Give the kiddo root access to their own computer and let them really break stuff because you can restore from backup&lt;p&gt;Edit:&lt;p&gt;Immediately downvoted. This comment apparently caused a nerd god to shed a tear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drlobster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d give them a stack of Slackware floppies and half the manual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ta12653421:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Im also interested in this, so happy to hear any experience!&lt;p&gt;In my situation i need some type of &amp;quot;remote admin capability&amp;quot;, since we are separated :-(&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bbbhltz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We were gifted our old work laptops. My partner and I work for the same place. She gave hers to the mother in law after I wiped Windows and put Linux on it.&lt;p&gt;I gave mine to my son. I figured that my son might want to use the touch screen I went with Gnome because it seemed a little more touch friendly. I told myself it doesn&amp;#x27;t matter because he is 8 and I can always reinstall.&lt;p&gt;I chose Debian (Stable) so I wouldn&amp;#x27;t have to deal with keeping it updated, put a root password to prevent them from going crazy with installing stuff.&lt;p&gt;I will have to put Scratch on it someday, for the moment he cares about the following:&lt;p&gt;- the LEGO website to look at instructions
- the music player to listen to soundtracks from his favourite games
- MyPaint for making drawings&lt;p&gt;He is starting to figure out the idea of folders, deleting things, undo, etc., but hasn&amp;#x27;t asked for any other software or even games yet.&lt;p&gt;I am a professor and would like for my son to learn about word processors, spreadsheets, programming, etc.. If he ever asks, I will give him the root password and let him browse the repos. Right now, I&amp;#x27;m just happy to see him enjoy it without doing what lots of his friends do: sit in front of YouTube all afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;d3Xt3r:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would recommend installing Scratch[1] - it&amp;#x27;s a programming language designed for kids from 8yrs old onwards. I would recommend pairing it with a Raspberry Pi, as you can do fun real-world physical stuff with using Scratch, and I think kids can find that very interesting. Eg, start with a simple program to turn LED lights on and off, programming buttons, playing sounds etc. Eventually this could lead to making simple games or other programs. Regardless, would highly recommend getting a Raspberry Pi as its just so much fun using it to interact with the physical world and getting to learn actual electronics.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;scratch.mit.edu&amp;#x2F;parents&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;scratch.mit.edu&amp;#x2F;parents&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;al_borland:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I got my nephews a raspberry pi for their first computer. I tried gifting an old laptop, but that was rejected my the parents as “too much”, so I went the Pi route… first with a Kano Kit (which I think is no defunct) and later with a Pi 400.&lt;p&gt;The Kano was nice, because it was built for kids and had some guided stuff to help get them into it with various software and hardware to play around with.&lt;p&gt;With the Pi 400 it was stock Raspbian. The kid wasn’t sure where to begin. While it came with a book geared toward kids, I don’t know that he read it. I was trying to find a way to show him around to stuff he might think is fun, without it seeming boring over overwhelming, but I didn’t feel it went that well. I was also living 6 hours away at the time, so there weren’t regular visits for questions or to help things along, and the parents didn’t know anything about Linux.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I don’t think it inspired them as much as I was hoping. All they actually wanted was something to play Minecraft on, and the Pi edition was a very compromised experience for Minecraft. The Kano did have a mode to let people use Scratch type programming to automate aspects of building, which I thought was really cool, but it didn’t totally seem to click… though I did see some limited use after a couple years.&lt;p&gt;I think not having someone in the house who can guide and field questions really hindered the ability for them to really thrive on Linux. It would probably be worth including a series of lessons to ramp up their skills and knowledge. Doing something like that was difficult for me due to the distance and also not so much parental support on the idea of kids on computers. I was swimming against the current a little with those gifts, because I thought it was important they get access to the main tool they are likely to use throughout their life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;theothertimcook:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Endless OS on a ex corporate box&amp;#x2F;laptop could be a good option.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;distrowatch.com&amp;#x2F;table-mobile.php?distribution=endless" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;distrowatch.com&amp;#x2F;table-mobile.php?distribution=endles...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864732</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864732</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
