<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:21:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Making Democracy Work: Fixing and Simplifying Egalitarian Paxos</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02743</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854862"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02743'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02743</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854862</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple's "notarisation" – blocking software freedom of developers and users</title>
      <link>https://fsfe.org/news/2025/news-20251105-01.en.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NewsLegal Corner: Apple’s “notarisation” – blocking software freedom of developers and users. The implications of Apple’s notarisation for software freedomFor Free Software developers, the implications are even more severe. This breaks users’ rights when it comes to Free Software freedoms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854441"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://fsfe.org/news/2025/news-20251105-01.en.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kkfx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mandatory FLOSS and open hardware is SERIOUSLY the sole way we can evolve positively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fmajid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can see it in action. I have a M1 Ultra Mac Studio, an insanely powerful machine, and when building open source software, actual compilation flies but the autonomy step crawls because IIT has to build test binaries to test OS features and notarization slows that down dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;invaliduser:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The same thing exists on Windows, developers have to code sign their binaries. It&amp;#x27;s even worse in my experience because you have to use a token (usb key with cryptographic signing keys in it) and that&amp;#x27;s impractical if you want your ci&amp;#x2F;cd to run in a datacenter. At my company we had a mac mini with a windows VM and a code signing token plugged in just for the purpose of signing our macos and windows binaries.&lt;p&gt;Another solution that is not mentioned in the article is that users of both macos and windows should be able to easily integrate the certificate of a third-party editor, with a process integrated in their OS explaining the risks, but also making it a process that can be understood and trusted, so that editors can self-sign their own binaries at no cost without needing the approval of the OS editor. Such a tool should ideally be integrated in the OS, but ultimately it could also be provided by a trusted third-party.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;charcircuit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;DMA is about increasing competition of app stores. It is not about giving &amp;quot;freedom&amp;quot; to people. Notorization is an independent process from running an app store on Apple&amp;#x27;s platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moi2388:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still don’t see why you would want your parents to run untrusted software on their devices, but you do you I guess.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fsfe.org/news/2025/news-20251105-01.en.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854441</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
