<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:39:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>The Baumol Effect and Jevons paradox are related</title>
      <link>https://www.a16z.news/p/why-ac-is-cheap-but-ac-repair-is</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each of these phenomena have a name: there’s Jevons Paradox, which means, “We’ll spend more on what gets more productive”, and there’s the Baumol Effect, which means, “We’ll spend more on what doesn’t get more productive. Other goods and services, where AI has relatively less impact, will become more expensive - and we’ll consume more of them anyway. It’s with the blue lines: where are things getting cheaper, in ways that create more jobs, more opportunity, and more spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955879"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.a16z.news/p/why-ac-is-cheap-but-ac-repair-is'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ar-Curunir:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[delayed]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wonnage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s not like people are piling into AI at the expense of other jobs, tech hiring and wages on general seem down relative to a couple of years ago. Hard to see the link between either effect and AI&lt;p&gt;Also weird that Dutch disease wasn’t mentioned at all, it actually seems more relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;parpfish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;that example of the radiologist review cases touches on one worry i have about automation with human-in-the-loop for safety. specifically that a human in the loop wont work as a safeguard unless they are meaningfully engaged beyond being a simple reviewer.&lt;p&gt;how do you sustain attention and thoughtfully review radiological scans when 99% of the time you agree with the automated assessment? i&amp;#x27;m pretty sure that no matter how well trained the doctor is they will end up just spamming &amp;quot;LGTM&amp;quot; after a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;biophysboy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;If you live in the United States today, and you accidentally knock a hole in your wall, it’s probably cheaper to buy a flatscreen TV and stick it in front of the hole, compared to hiring a handyman to fix your drywall.&lt;p&gt;Is it cheaper than buying a TV, and then having someone come install it on your wall? More meaningless drivel from Marc Andreesen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01HNNWZ0MV43FF:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; it’s probably cheaper to buy a flatscreen TV and stick it in front of the hole&lt;p&gt;Says a lot about American politics, figuratively speaking&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; If you can make $30 an hour as a digital freelance marketer (a job that did not exist a generation ago), then you won’t accept less than that from working in food service. And if you can make $150 an hour installing HVAC for data centers, you’re not going to accept less from doing home AC service.&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people work jobs for less money because they enjoy the work more. I’m not sure if it’s worth reading what follows if most of the argument is predicated on this claim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lkey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think any &amp;#x27;interesting thought&amp;#x27; that serves as a conclusion to an article should begin like so:&lt;p&gt;| &amp;#x27;With radiologists, I’m totally speculating and I have no idea what the actual workflow of a radiologist involves...&amp;#x27;&lt;p&gt;Speculation from a place of ignorance is suitable for bar-side musings, not an article that wants us to take it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TekMol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    you accidentally knock a hole in your wall,
    it’s probably cheaper to buy a flatscreen TV
    and stick it in front of the hole
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
What I recently did is that I 3D-printed an object with PLA that exactly fit the whole and just glued that in with assembly glue.&lt;p&gt;What does the HN panel say? Is it a solution? Or does it have any downside?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;josefritzishere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The basic premise here is that productivity growth in one sector, increaes wages in other sectors. But we already know that productivity and wage growth are increasingly disconnected. Thsi si not to say the affect doesnt exist but that it must therefore be small or limited in scope.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.epi.org&amp;#x2F;productivity-pay-gap&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.epi.org&amp;#x2F;productivity-pay-gap&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;littlestymaar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Dupe: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45807542"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45807542&lt;/a&gt; (two weeks ago: 134 points, 184 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.a16z.news/p/why-ac-is-cheap-but-ac-repair-is</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955879</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new book recovers the origins of Effective Altruism</title>
      <link>https://newrepublic.com/article/202433/happened-effective-altruism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the landscape that inspired his famous thought experiment. Peter Singer asks, “Should you worry about that. ” Then Peter Singer makes this very contentious cl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955889"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://newrepublic.com/article/202433/happened-effective-altruism'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TimorousBestie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; . . . but also what’s called long-termism, which is worrying about the future of the planet and existential risks like pandemics, nuclear war, AI, or being hit by comets. When it made that shift, it began to attract a lot of Silicon Valley types, who may not have been so dedicated to the development part of the effective altruism program.&lt;p&gt;The rationalists thought they understood time discounting and thought they could correct for it. They were wrong. Then the internal contradictions of long-termism allowed EA to get suckered by the Silicon Valley crew.&lt;p&gt;Alas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmount:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Effective Altruism and Utilitarianism are just a couple of the presentations authoritarians sometimes make for convenience. To me the code simply as &amp;quot;if I had everything now, that would eventually be good for everybody.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The arguments always feel to me too similar &amp;quot;it is good Carnegie called in the Pinkerton&amp;#x27;s to suppress labor, as it allowed him to build libraries.&amp;quot; Yes it is good what Carnegie did later, but it doesn&amp;#x27;t completely paper over what he did earlier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note sure why you call generosity and giving as some deep philosophy or effective altruism etc. Also generosity, like sugar, if applied in excess, could cause problems like what Europe is facing today with asylum seekers etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;philipallstar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In the past, there was nothing we could do about people in another country. Peter Singer says that’s just an evolutionary hangover, a moral error.&lt;p&gt;This is sadly still true, given the percentage of money that goes to getting someone some help vs the amount dedicated to actually helping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://newrepublic.com/article/202433/happened-effective-altruism</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955889</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to escape the Linux networking stack</title>
      <link>https://blog.cloudflare.com/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish-how-to-escape-the-linux-networking-stack/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This service’s sole responsibility is to proxy IP packets using soft-unicast address space and manage the lease of those addresses. Collision avoidance Suppose we have a soft-unicast address slice, 198. Unlike when binding a socket, Netfilter will simply pick the first free space in the conntrack table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954638"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.cloudflare.com/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish-how-to-escape-the-linux-networking-stack/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.cloudflare.com/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish-how-to-escape-the-linux-networking-stack/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954638</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WBlock: A New Ad-Blocker for Safari</title>
      <link>https://github.com/0xCUB3/wBlock</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Safari content blocker for macOS, iOS, and iPadOS utilizing declarative content blocking rules. wBlock supports any AdGuard-compatible filter list. Does wBlock slow down Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954626"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/0xCUB3/wBlock'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WD-42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The readme proudly proclaims: “ The end of Safari ad-blocking B.S.”&lt;p&gt;Except that it’s just another declarative blocker spread across 4+ extensions. This seems like the same old B.S to me. Better off sticking with Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imagetic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;apps.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;app&amp;#x2F;ublock-origin-lite&amp;#x2F;id6745342698"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;apps.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;app&amp;#x2F;ublock-origin-lite&amp;#x2F;id674534269...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those looking for the iOS &amp;#x2F; safari option for Ublock origin lite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;froddd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just installed it to see if it might be better than AdGuard on memory usage, and now I’m getting constant “Pssst! You forgot to apply some settings” notifications as soon as I leave the app. Clicking it takes me back to the app, where it does an update of everything, and… That’s it. Leave the app again, and the notification reappears. Quite annoying!&lt;p&gt;Edit: it appears it doesn’t remove ad content blocks like AdGuard, and doesn’t let me pick and choose elements to add. I might revisit in a few months, but for now I’m back to AdGuard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hendersoon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s just another declarative adblocker, as that is all Safari (and now Chrome) allows. There&amp;#x27;s vanishingly little room for differentiation in this space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vlovich123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; uBlock Origin Lite: Chromium-only Manifest V3 extension. Not available for Safari.&lt;p&gt;How did I install it as a safari extension on iOS from the App Store?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rocketvole:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just downloaded this and it seems to be everything I&amp;#x27;ve wanted on an ios safari adblocker. I was using ublock origin lite before. Its completely free like ublock but you can use your own filter lists. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dewey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been using &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;1blocker.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;1blocker.com&lt;/a&gt; for many years now without issues. It isn&amp;#x27;t in their comparison list, but looks pretty similar design wise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nozzlegear:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m interested in trying this, but not really interested in signing up for the whole Testflight rigamarole. I&amp;#x27;ve had uBlock Origin Lite installed ever since it was released, but I prefer Safari&amp;#x27;s Content Blocker approach which uBlock doesn&amp;#x27;t use. (uBlock uses manifest v3, and it sometimes it leaves those small &amp;quot;empty image&amp;quot; boxes where an ad would be; I&amp;#x27;m not sure if those two things are related.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InfiniteVortex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;wBlock is a new ad-blocker for Safari. It supports (in general) everything Wipr, AdGuard for Safari&amp;#x2F;iOS, uBlock Origin Lite can do except for maybe multi-device sync&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/0xCUB3/wBlock</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954626</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WeatherNext 2: Our most advanced weather forecasting model</title>
      <link>https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/weathernext-2/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This model surpasses the previous WeatherNext model on 99. By incorporating WeatherNext technology, we’ve now upgraded weather forecasts in Search, Gemini, Pixel Weather and Google Maps Platform’s Weather API. Overall, WeatherNext 2 surpasses our previous state-of-the-art WeatherNext model on 99.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954210"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/weathernext-2/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timenotwasted:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It feels like real weather AI|Forecast|whatever_you_want_to_call_it is still far, far away. Maybe it&amp;#x27;s just the consumer aspect of weather apps but I don&amp;#x27;t feel as if I get any more accurate data now than I did back when my parents turned to the daily weather channel for the forecast. Still a lot of clear days when rain was predicted or the even more dreaded torrential downpour when it was supposed to be sunny and clear.&lt;p&gt;Obviously all I have is anecdata for what I&amp;#x27;m mentioning here but from a consumer perspective I don&amp;#x27;t feel like these model enhancements are really making average folks feel as if weather is any more understood than it was decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakewins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is anyone aware of good sources of higher resolution models? Hourly resolution like this model provides doesn’t help much now that energy markets have moved to 15-min and 5-min resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;binsquare:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I find it interesting that they quantify the improvement on speed and number of forecast-ed scenarios but lack details on how it results in improved accuracy of the forecast per:&lt;p&gt;```
WeatherNext 2 can generate forecasts 8x faster and with resolution up to 1-hour. This breakthrough is enabled by a new model that can provide hundreds of possible scenarios.
```&lt;p&gt;As an end user, all I care is that there&amp;#x27;s one accurate forecasted scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LogicFailsMe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This year, the wild variance in hourly weather reports on my phone has really been something. I attributed it to likely budget cuts as a result of DOGE, but if those forecasts came from Google itself the whole time, all is clear now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xd1936:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pricing, I think?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developers.google.com&amp;#x2F;maps&amp;#x2F;billing-and-pricing&amp;#x2F;pricing#environment-pricing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developers.google.com&amp;#x2F;maps&amp;#x2F;billing-and-pricing&amp;#x2F;prici...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/weathernext-2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954210</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Gemini</title>
      <link>https://geminiprotocol.net/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Project Gemini Gemini in 100 words Gemini is a new internet technology supporting an electronic library of interconnected text documents. Gemini isn't about innovation or disruption, it's about providing some respite for those who feel the internet has been disrupted enough already. If you'd like to know more, read our FAQ Or, if you'd prefer, here's a video overview Official resources Project Gemini news Project Gemini documentation Project Gemini history Known Gemini software All content at geminiprotocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954640"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://geminiprotocol.net/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 17 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aeternum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Too many things are named Gemini&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;debo_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My main blog is now an &amp;quot;anonymous&amp;quot; gemlog. I use the kineto http proxy to provide a website version as well. I wrote a little deploy script that scrapes my posts and creates an atom XML feed (static doc) that kineto serves for those few people who want to stay up-to-date.&lt;p&gt;Once a quarter, I batch up the recent posts and bcc a bunch of folks I like to keep in touch with. Some of them respond. This is what I do in place of social media now; outside of email, Discord and WhatsApp are all I use to keep in touch with folks.&lt;p&gt;I also like to poke around different gemlogs with Lagrange, which is a nice desktop-oriented Gemini client. It&amp;#x27;s good fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;graypegg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really enjoyed messing around with Gemini a while ago! But after the &amp;quot;messing around&amp;quot; stage with the protocol itself, the restrictions inherent to gemtext sapped my excitement around it.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a mark up language squarely focused on those that write text, but arduous to use if you want to share things you&amp;#x27;ve illustrated, which is most of what I share online that isn&amp;#x27;t tech related. There&amp;#x27;s of course the argument that inline images&amp;#x2F;a spec&amp;#x27;d way to expose an image directory listing with thumbnails&amp;#x2F;etc would only serve to distract or exploit you... but that also ignores the fact that people make art for your eyeballs too. Text is certainly the first class citizen, where images&amp;#x2F;music&amp;#x2F;video are all tied for second class, accessible only by downloading them 1 by 1.&lt;p&gt;That does mean it&amp;#x27;s perfectly fit for purpose! I wouldn&amp;#x27;t say it&amp;#x27;s bad just because I don&amp;#x27;t get my specific needs met. Someone who&amp;#x27;s needs are met by Gemini will love it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;myaccountonhn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d love a minimal protocol like this that was also somehow scraping resistant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Recently:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Six Years of Gemini&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44578143"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44578143&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RealCodingOtaku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have got only two annoyance on Gemini, lack of inline links and _font styling_, and they are by design (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;geminiprotocol.net&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;faq.gmi#44-questions-about-textgemini" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;geminiprotocol.net&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;faq.gmi#44-questions-about-t...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fine for something like HN, but I heavily rely on named links and emphasis on all my blogs and is a dealbreaker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dexwiz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I looked at this a few years ago and it seemed to be a graveyard of toy implementations and personal blogs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TuringTest:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Honest question, how do you discover interesting content over this protocol?&lt;p&gt;Is there people building the equivalent to web directories and web rings? Or search engines? What are the cultural expectations on navigating other people&amp;#x27;s published resources?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;denysvitali:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not the Gemini I was hoping to see in the front page today :D&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pianoben:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Gemini was so much fun during lockdown - I loved the distraction of a new simple protocol, and the challenge of writing a gui client for it.&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;#x27;t say I&amp;#x27;m surprised that it hasn&amp;#x27;t taken the world by storm, but it&amp;#x27;s still a cozy part of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;karmakaze:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If this is being developed, it should have a more modern description. Comparing it to Gopher is fine as a historical point, but comparing it to http&amp;#x2F;html is more useful today. I read the faq for geeks and didn&amp;#x27;t learn much:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; 1.1.1 The dense, jargony answer for geeks in a hurry&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Gemini is an application-level client-server internet protocol for the distribution of arbitrary files, with some special consideration for serving a lightweight hypertext format which facilitates linking between hosted files. Both the protocol and the format are deliberately limited in capabilities and scope, and the protocol is technically conservative, being built on mature, standardised, familiar, &amp;quot;off-the-shelf&amp;quot; technologies like URIs, MIME media types and TLS. Simplicity and finite scope are very intentional design decisions motivated by placing a high priority on user autonomy, user privacy, ease of implementation in diverse computing environments, and defensive non-extensibility. In short, it is something like a radically stripped down web stack. See section 4 of this FAQ document for questions relating to the design of Gemini.&lt;p&gt;Annoyed that for a system about plain text links, there&amp;#x27;s no link to &amp;quot;section 4&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;The transport sounds like http without saying so. It doesn&amp;#x27;t go into why it doesn&amp;#x27;t use http. I&amp;#x27;d probably be fine with HTTP and Markdown + image&amp;#x2F;video links. Maybe the Gemini document capabilities&amp;#x2F;scope is better but they&amp;#x27;re not described.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Edit: they are in &amp;quot;4.1.2&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;[0] &lt;i&gt;Be warned, there&amp;#x27;s still a lot of beating-around-the-bush.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; 4.1.2 I&amp;#x27;m familiar with HTTP and HTML. How is Gemini different?&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;geminiprotocol.net&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;faq.gmi#412-im-familiar-with-http-and-html-how-is-gemini-different" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;geminiprotocol.net&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;faq.gmi#412-im-familiar-with...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Edit 2: Seems opinionated in many stupid-by-todays-needs ways. It feels like text-web made by some group of deniers.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ecliptik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From what I remember about the name, it&amp;#x27;s derived from NASA space programs. Where Gopher is Mercury, Web is Apollo and Gemini is in between.&lt;p&gt;Gemini is a new internet protocol which:&lt;p&gt;- Is heavier than gopher&lt;p&gt;- Is lighter than the web&lt;p&gt;- Will not replace either&lt;p&gt;- Strives for maximum power to weight ratio&lt;p&gt;- Takes user privacy very seriously&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agiacalone:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve had a Gemini Capsule (what Gemini calls a &amp;#x27;website&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x27; since about 2021. It gets very little traffic, but it&amp;#x27;s fun to have. Browsing the smallweb is nice in the evenings when I want a high signal-to-noise ratio of interesting content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;netdevphoenix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why do programmers have so little imagination when it comes to names? It should almost never be the case that project names conflict&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bnchrch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If we maintain this trajectory Gemini is going to have as many dual meanings in the software world as Map.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blcknight:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So Gopher?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rappatic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why is everything named Gemini these days?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://geminiprotocol.net/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954640</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cities Panic over Having to Release Mass Surveillance Recordings</title>
      <link>https://www.nakedcapitalism.com/2025/11/cities-panic-over-having-to-release-mass-surveillance-recordings.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;” Flock cameras are designed to watch cars. Flock captures everything it sees. Everything means everything for these everywhere cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955745"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.nakedcapitalism.com/2025/11/cities-panic-over-having-to-release-mass-surveillance-recordings.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;belorn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here in Sweden, the use of license plate scanners has become the norm for basically all parking houses, bridge tolls and road tolls. Even if you don&amp;#x27;t install the app or become a &amp;quot;member&amp;quot; of whatever system they are using, the license plate scanners is still used to detect when you enter or leave, and in some cases they automatically look up your home address to send you the bill with zero interaction with the driver. Even if they offer alternative ways to pay, by for example sms, it still uses the license plate scanner when you leave.&lt;p&gt;The only political party to even mention this as a problem was the pirate party back 15 years ago, and even then it never became a major issue that got discussed. Like paying with credit cards rather than physical cash, people see it as convenience or just as the way things now work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AdamJacobMuller:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand the correlation here, why does having to release the footage mean that the cities are shutting down the systems?&lt;p&gt;It seems like they could simply comply with the requirement that footage is public and they can&amp;#x2F;must share that footage as part of the FOIA process, I don&amp;#x27;t see much of a downside there and it seems like something which most police departments and municipalities are already doing with footage from other scenarios like body cameras?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dedup-com:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It must be said that &amp;quot;cities&amp;quot;, as used in this piece, is a rather generous term. Sedro-Woolley has 13K residents. Stanwood has 9K. They probably don&amp;#x27;t have enough people on payroll to handle FOA requests, hence &amp;quot;panic&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Panopticams&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tptacek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They&amp;#x27;re not panicking about this in Illinois, because Illinois exempts raw ALPR footage from FOIA.&lt;p&gt;This page is blogspam, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bell-cot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m hearing some new lyrics for &lt;i&gt;Behind Blue Eyes&lt;/i&gt; from this...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nakedcapitalism.com/2025/11/cities-panic-over-having-to-release-mass-surveillance-recordings.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955745</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An official atlas of North Korea</title>
      <link>https://www.cartographerstale.com/p/an-official-atlas-of-north-korea</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An official atlas of North KoreaA North Korean atlas that shows the world from the perspective of one of the most isolated countries on the planet. And maps, lots of maps. First, the maps dedicated to enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956176"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cartographerstale.com/p/an-official-atlas-of-north-korea'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cartographerstale.com/p/an-official-atlas-of-north-korea</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956176</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google is killing the open web, part 2</title>
      <link>https://wok.oblomov.eu/tecnologia/google-killing-open-web-2/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compare and contrast with their Pocket integration that they force-installed everywhere before ultimately killing the service Actions, as they say, speak louder than words. And the best defense against that is to attack, and push the use of that feature even harder. Instead, flood their issue tracker with requests to bring back in-browser XSLT support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954560"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://wok.oblomov.eu/tecnologia/google-killing-open-web-2/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1vuio0pswjnm7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;The WHATWG aim is to turn the Web into an application delivery platform, a profit-making machine for corporations where the computer (and the browser through it) are a means for them to make money off you rather than for you to gain access to services you may be interested in.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Such vision is in direct contrast with that of the Web as a repository of knowledge, a vast vault of interconnected documents whose value emerges from organic connections, personalization, variety, curation and user control. But who in the WHATWG today would defend such vision?&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Maybe what we need is a new browser war. Not one of corporation versus corporation -doubly more so when all currently involved parties are allied in their efforts to enclose the Web than in fostering an open and independent one- but one of users versus corporations, a war to take back control of the Web and its tools.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It should be up to the www user not the web developer to determine how they prefer the documents to appear on their screen&lt;p&gt;Contrast this with one or a few software programs, i.e, essentially a predetermined selection (no choice), that purport to offer all possible preferences to all www users, i.e., the so-called &amp;quot;modern&amp;quot; browser.  These programs are distributed by companies that sell ad services and their business partners (Mozilla)&lt;p&gt;Documents can be published in a &amp;quot;neutral&amp;quot; format, JSON or whatever, and users can choose to convert this, if desired, to whatever format they prefer.  This is more or less the direction the web has taken however at present the conversion is generally being performed by web developers using (frequently obfuscated) Javascript, outside the control of the user&lt;p&gt;Although from a technical standpoint, there is nothing that requires (a) document retrieval and (b) document display to be performed by the same program, commercial interests have tried to force users toward using one program for everything (a &amp;quot;do everything program&amp;quot;)^1&lt;p&gt;When users run &amp;quot;do everything programs&amp;quot; from companies selling ad services and their business partners to perform both (a) and (b), they end up receiving &amp;quot;documents&amp;quot; they never requested (ads) and getting tracked&lt;p&gt;If users want such &amp;quot;do everything&amp;quot; corporate browsers, if they prefer &amp;quot;do everything programs&amp;quot;, then they are free to choose them, but there should be other choices and it should be illegal to discriminate against other software as long as rules of &amp;quot;netiquette&amp;quot; are followed.  A requirement to use some &amp;quot;do everything program&amp;quot; is not a valid rule&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;There&amp;#x27;s more to the Internet than the World Wide Web built around the HTTP protocol and the HTML file format. There used to be a lot of the Internet beyond the Web, and while much of it still remains as little more than a shadow of the past, largely eclipsed by the Web and what has been built on top of it (not all of it good) outside of some modest revivals, there&amp;#x27;s also new parts of it that have tried to learn from the past, and build towards something different.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Internet subscribers pay a relatively high price for access in many countries&lt;p&gt;According to one RFC author the www became the &amp;quot;the new waist&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;But to use expensive internet access only for &amp;quot;the web&amp;quot;, especially a 100% commercial, obsessively surveilled one filled with ads, is also a &amp;quot;waste&amp;quot;, IMHO&lt;p&gt;1. Perhaps the opposite of &amp;quot;do one thing well&amp;quot;.  America&amp;#x27;s top billionaire wants to create another of these &amp;quot;do everything programs&amp;quot;, one to rule them all.  These &amp;quot;do everything programs&amp;quot; will always exist but they should never be the only viable options.  They should never be &amp;quot;required&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Prequel:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Google is killing the open web&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44949857"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44949857&lt;/a&gt; - Aug 2025 (181 comments)&lt;p&gt;Also related. Others?&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;XSLT RIP&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45873434"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45873434&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 2025 (459 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Removing XSLT for a more secure browser&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45823059"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45823059&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 2025 (337 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Intent to Deprecate and Remove XSLT&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45779261"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45779261&lt;/a&gt; - Nov 2025 (149 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;XSLT removal will break multiple government and regulatory sites&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44987346"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44987346&lt;/a&gt; - Aug 2025 (146 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Google did not unilaterally decide to kill XSLT&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44987239"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44987239&lt;/a&gt; - Aug 2025 (128 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;Remove mentions of XSLT from the html spec&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44952185"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44952185&lt;/a&gt; - Aug 2025 (535 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Should we remove XSLT from the web platform?&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44909599"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=44909599&lt;/a&gt; - Aug 2025 (96 comments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shadowgovt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Okay, I was entertaining the author&amp;#x27;s position to a point, but I have to get off the train where they sing the praises of NPAPI.&lt;p&gt;Hey fam. I remember NPAPI. I wrote a very large NPAPI plugin.&lt;p&gt;The problem with NPAPI is that it lets people run arbitrary code as your browser. it was barely sandboxed. At &lt;i&gt;best&lt;/i&gt;, it let any plugin do its level best to crash your browser session. At worst, it&amp;#x27;s a third-party binary blob you can&amp;#x27;t inspect running in the same thing you use to control your bank account.&lt;p&gt;NPAPI died for a good reason, and it has little to do with someone wanting to control your experience and everything to do with protecting you, the user, from bad actors. I think the author tips their hand a little too far here; the world they&amp;#x27;re envisioning is one where the elite hackers among us get to keep using the web and everyone else just gets owned by mechanisms they can&amp;#x27;t understand, and that&amp;#x27;s fine because it lets us be &amp;quot;wild&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;free&amp;quot; like we were in the nineties and early aughts again. Coupled with the author&amp;#x27;s downplaying of the security concerns in the XSLT lib, the author seems comfortable with the notion that security is less important than features, and I think there&amp;#x27;s a good reason that the major browser creators and maintainers disagree.&lt;p&gt;The author&amp;#x27;s dream, at the bottom, &amp;quot;a mesh of building blocks,&amp;quot; is asking dozens upon dozens &lt;i&gt;upon dozens&lt;/i&gt; of independent operators to put binary blobs in your browser &lt;i&gt;outside the security sandbox.&lt;/i&gt; We stopped doing that for very, &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shadowgovt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think I&amp;#x27;m plugged into the side of the Internet that considers XML &amp;quot;the backbone of an independent web.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I think XML has some good features, but in general infatuation with it as either a key representation or key transmission protocol has waned over the years. Everything I see on the wire these days is JSON or some flavor of binary RPC like protobuffer; I hardly ever see XML on the wire anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gwbas1c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the past 10-15 years, every time I look at web standards, it always feels like someone is trying to make browsers support their specific niche use case.&lt;p&gt;Seems like getting XSLT (and offering a polyfill replacement) is just a move in the direction of stopping applications from pushing their complexity into the browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dpark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This has nothing to do with the “open web”. I don’t know if the people saying this just don’t have a meaningful definition of what open means or what. “Open” doesn’t mean “supports everything anyone has ever shipped in a browser”. (Chrome should support Gopher, really? Gopher was literally never part of the World Wide Web.)&lt;p&gt;What’s happening is that Google (along when Mozilla and Safari) are changing the html spec to drop support for xslt. If you want to argue that this is bad because it “breaks the web”, that’s fine, but it has nothing at all to do with whether the web is “open”. The open web means anyone can run a web server. Anyone can build their own compatible browser (hypothetically; this has become prohibitively expensive). &lt;i&gt;It means anyone can use the tech, not that the tech includes everything possible.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to complain about Google harming the open web, there are some real examples out there. Google Reader deprecation probably hurt RSS more than anything else. AMP was&amp;#x2F;is an attempt to give Google tighter control over more web traffic. Chrome extension changes were pushed through seemingly to give Google tighter control over ad blockers. Gemini is an attempt to keep Google users from ever actually clicking through to web sites for information.&lt;p&gt;XSLT in the browser has been dead for years. The reality is that &lt;i&gt;no browser developer has cared about xslt since 1.0&lt;/i&gt;. Don’t blame Google for the death of xslt when xslt 2.0 was standardized before Chrome was even released and no one else cared enough to implement it. The removal of xslt doesn’t change the openness of the web and the reality is that it breaks very little while eliminating a source of real security errors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffbee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Nobody wants my nerd bullshit, part 42&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiffanyh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t Google one of the few (if not only), major tech company that would want to &lt;i&gt;keep&lt;/i&gt; alive the open web ... given their business model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kellengreen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Today I Learned: There&amp;#x27;s a built-in class called XSLTProcessor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;et1337:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m no Google fan, but deprecating XSLT is a rare opportunity to shrink the surface area of the web’s “API” without upsetting too many people. It would be one less thing for independent browsers like Ladybird to worry about. Thus actually weakening Google’s chokehold on the browser market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koakuma-chan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I didn&amp;#x27;t know XSLT existed before this drama.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;charcircuit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;Mozilla bent over to Google&amp;#x27;s pressure to kill off RSS by removing the “Live Bookmarks” features from the browser&lt;p&gt;They both were just responding to similar market demands because end users didn&amp;#x27;t want to use RSS. Users want to use social media instead.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;This is a trillion-dollar ad company who has been actively destroying the open web for over a decade&lt;p&gt;Google has both done more for and invested more into progressing the open web than anyone else.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;The WHATWG aim is to turn the Web into an application delivery platform&lt;p&gt;This is what web developers want and browsers our reacting to the natural demands of developers, who are reacting to demands of users. It was an evolutionary process that got it to that state.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;but with their dependency on the Blink rendering engine, controlled by Google, they won&amp;#x27;t be able to do anything but cave&lt;p&gt;Blink is open source and modular. Maintaining a fork is much less effort than the alternative of maintaining a different browser engine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related large discussion:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;XSLT RIP&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45873434"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45873434&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thayne:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t disagree that Google is killing the open web. But XSLT is a pretty weak argument for showing that. It is an extremely complicated feature that is very seldom used. I am very doubtful dropping support is some evil political decision. It is much more likely they just don&amp;#x27;t want to sink resources into maintaining something that is almost never used.&lt;p&gt;For the specific use case of showing RSS and Atom feeds in the browser, it seems like a better solution would be to have built-in support in the browser, rather than relying on the use of XSLT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spankalee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This page makes some wild claims, like Google wants to deprecate MathML, even though it basically just landed. Yeah, the Chrome team wasn&amp;#x27;t prioritizing the work and it came through Igalia, but the best time for Chrome to kill MathML would have been before it was actually usable on the web.&lt;p&gt;The post also fails to mention that all browsers want to remove XSLT. The topic was brought up in several meetings by Firefox reps. It&amp;#x27;s not a Google conspiracy.&lt;p&gt;I also see that the site is written in XHTML and think the author must just really love XML, and doesn&amp;#x27;t realize that most browser maintainers think that XHTML is a mistake and failure. Being strict on input in failing to render anything on an error is antithetical to the &amp;quot;user agent&amp;quot; philosophy that says the browser should try to render something useful to the user anyway. Forgiving HTML is just better suited for the messy web. I bet this fuels some of their anger here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;apeters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The day will come when DRM is used to protect the whole http body.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dfabulich:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In part 1 of this article, the author wrote, &amp;quot;XSLT is an &lt;i&gt;essential&lt;/i&gt; companion to RSS, as it allows the feed itself to be perused in the browser&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Actually, you can make an RSS feed user-browsable by using JavaScript instead. You can even run XSLT in JavaScript, which is what Google&amp;#x27;s polyfill does.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve written thousands of lines of XSLT. JavaScript is better than XSLT in &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; way, which is why JavaScript has thrived and XSLT has dwindled.&lt;p&gt;This is why XSLT has got to go: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.offensivecon.org&amp;#x2F;speakers&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;ivan-fratric.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.offensivecon.org&amp;#x2F;speakers&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;ivan-fratric.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yegle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t the decision made by all the browser vendors (including Apple and Mozilla)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nwellnhof:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Removing XSLT from browsers was long overdue and I&amp;#x27;m saying that as ex-maintainer of libxslt who probably triggered (not caused) this removal. What&amp;#x27;s more interesting is that Chromium plans to switch to a Rust-based XML parser. Currently, they seem to favor xml-rs which only implements a subset of XML. So apparently, Google is willing to remove standards-compliant XML support as well. This is a lot more concerning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jll29:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Let&amp;#x27;s all move to Ladybird next August.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurornis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have yet to read an article complaining about XSLT deprecation from someone who can explain why they actually used it and why it’s important to them.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;  I will keep using XSLT, and in fact will look for new opportunities to rely on it.&lt;p&gt;This is the closest I’ve seen, but it’s not an explanation of why it was important before the deprecation. It’s a declaration that they’re using it as an act of rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jamesbelchamber:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do the up-and-coming new browsers&amp;#x2F;engines (Servo, Ladybird.. others?) plan to support XSLT? If they do already, do they want to remove it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;altmind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do you remember that chrome lost FTP support recently? The protocol was widely used and simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is Chrome OS Platform nowadays, powered by Chrome market share, and helped by everyone shipping Electron garbage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wryoak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think imma convert my blog to XML&amp;#x2F;XSLT. Nobody reads it anyway, but now I’ll be able to blame my lack of audience on chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andsoitis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t know. The author makes some arguments I could get entertain and get behind, but they also enumerate the immense complexity that they want web browsers to support (incl. Gopher).&lt;p&gt;Whether or not Google deprecating XSLT is a “political” decision (in authors words), I don’t know that I know for sure, but I can imagine running the Chrome project and steering for more simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://wok.oblomov.eu/tecnologia/google-killing-open-web-2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954560</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are you stuck in movie logic?</title>
      <link>https://usefulfictions.substack.com/p/are-you-stuck-in-movie-logic</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://usefulfictions.substack.com/p/are-you-stuck-in-movie-logic</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45952890</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When AWS was down, we were not</title>
      <link>https://authress.io/knowledge-base/articles/2025/11/01/how-we-prevent-aws-downtime-impacts</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think that's so extraordinary that the question I want you to keep in mind through this article is: is that actually possible. When I say five nines, I mean that 99. That is, an architecture that just focuses on the features, how might you build this out as simple as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955565"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://authress.io/knowledge-base/articles/2025/11/01/how-we-prevent-aws-downtime-impacts'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://authress.io/knowledge-base/articles/2025/11/01/how-we-prevent-aws-downtime-impacts</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955565</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living my best Sun Microsystems ecosystem life in 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143570/living-my-best-sun-microsystems-ecosystem-life-in-2025/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note that absolutely zero generative “AI” was used in the writing of this article. During these tumultuous times, the various commercial UNIX vendors all pushed out systems that would become the final hurrahs of their respective UNIX workstation lines. – of their enclosures with their x86 brethren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955077"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.osnews.com/story/143570/living-my-best-sun-microsystems-ecosystem-life-in-2025/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WarcrimeActual:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; No “AI” writing aids, no “AI” summaries, no ChatGPT, no Gemini search nonsense, nothing. I take pride in doing research and writing properly, without the “aid” of digital parrots with brain damage, and if there’s any errors, they’re mine and mine alone. Take pride in your work and reject “AI”.&lt;p&gt;This guy better not be using spell check with a tantrum like that tagged to his opening line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;azalemeth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I sold an old Ultra45 from my lab on eBay rather than letting the university people scrap it.&lt;p&gt;It went for the equivalent of $2000 (which I later donated to a charity) and attracted quite a bidding war. Apparently at least one major airport (I won&amp;#x27;t say where or in which bit of the world) used one to control its landing light system and were, through a weird network of contractors, looking to buy more hardware for redundancy...&lt;p&gt;I have also put an IndyO2 SGI machine on eBay that similarly found a repurposed fate. We are now finally at the point where the machines I held on to as a teenager much to my mum&amp;#x27;s chagrin are now becoming highly valuable again!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cameron_b:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would love to hear counterpoints -- The Sun Ray thin client experience seems interesting, but the modern version of that seems to be the web&amp;#x2F;app&amp;#x2F;cloud ecosystem we have now (where the load and storage of your interaction are resident on some other system, &lt;i&gt;potentially&lt;/i&gt; freeing up your local device from resource needs). Specifically, a self-hosted collaborative model with Nextcloud + Collabora or similar. I do wonder what workloads or designs would be fit for a more &amp;quot;time-sharing&amp;quot; approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buildbot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love my ultra 45, it’s certainly the best looking of the early 2000s unix workstations!&lt;p&gt;I lucked out and got a system with 16GB And 2x procs, added in the XVR-2500 and PcPro to play with. It’s also ex-Lockheed Martin which is fun&amp;#x2F;mildly alarming!&lt;p&gt;Since this thread is likely to draw knowledgable sparc people, there’s a totally unrelated question I have - I have a sun blade 150, and was looking around on the motherboard. There are few jumpers that say things like “x86 debug” or x86 rom something - and the socket is technically 378… and from what I can research, the chipset worked with x86… Was there a point at which the sun blade motherboard was setup to work with either sparc or x86?! ( not so crazy given ev6 alpha chipset works on x86&amp;#x2F;the zx1 chipset worked on itanium and hp-parisc? )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dboreham:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note that the rise of Linux was &lt;i&gt;caused&lt;/i&gt; by the rise of low cost, high performance x86 CPUs. There was a period of time when it was obvious you could get much more bang for the buck from x86, but there wasn&amp;#x27;t a viable OS to use (for servers). Yes NT existed, and we shipped binaries for NT but it was always an awkward fit to run server software on NT. So Linux, which at the time was kind of crappy (unreliable, didn&amp;#x27;t have threading) was improved by various vendors&amp;#x27; efforts to the point where they could re-target their server products into PC-class hardware. Sun was sunk by the people who were downstream in the value chain leading back to Sun&amp;#x27;s revenue working hard to design Sun out of the loop, by means of PC-class hardware and the Linux OS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throw0101c:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;Solaris, meanwhile, which had long been available on x86, saw its “own” ISA SPARC live on in the server space until roughly 2017 or so, and was even briefly available as open source until Oracle did its thing.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe worth noting that SPARC was (is?) licensable:&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;sparc.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;sparc.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;OpenSPARC is under GPL2.&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=12578083"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=12578083&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulHoule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(200x) &amp;quot;Never bet against x86&amp;quot; -&amp;gt; (202x) &amp;quot;Never bet against ARM&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.osnews.com/story/143570/living-my-best-sun-microsystems-ecosystem-life-in-2025/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955077</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reselling tickets for profit to be outlawed in UK government crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2025/nov/17/reselling-tickets-for-profit-to-be-outlawed-in-uk-government-crackdown</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;However, the Guardian understands that touts – and ordinary consumers – will no longer be able to charge anything more than the price at which they purchased the ticket in the first place. Resale platforms will be allowed to charge fees on top of that price. Anyone reselling a ticket will also be prohibited from offering more tickets than they could have procured under limits set by the original box office company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956173"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theguardian.com/money/2025/nov/17/reselling-tickets-for-profit-to-be-outlawed-in-uk-government-crackdown'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_dain_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;idiotic populist move. resellers exist because the listed price is much lower than the price people are willing to pay. banning them doesn&amp;#x27;t make the demand go away. this will just create a black market in resold tickets, with no legal recourse against fraud etc.&lt;p&gt;yookay government&amp;#x27;s crusade to outlaw all useful economic activity continues apace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WalterBright:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Arbitrage is a normal free market process that finds the optimal prices for things. Trying to regulate prices always results in gluts, shortages, and black markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/money/2025/nov/17/reselling-tickets-for-profit-to-be-outlawed-in-uk-government-crackdown</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956173</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
