<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:04:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Brain-IT: Image Reconstruction from fMRI via Brain-Interaction Transformer</title>
      <link>https://AmitZalcher.github.io/Brain-IT/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIT’s design enables direct flow of information from brain-voxel clusters to localized image features. The BIT model predicts image features from voxel activations (fMRI). Reconstructions with 1 hour of subject-specific data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830808"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://AmitZalcher.github.io/Brain-IT/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://AmitZalcher.github.io/Brain-IT/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 02:46:23</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830808</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I may have found a way to spot U.S. at-sea strikes before they're announced</title>
      <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/OSINT/comments/1opjjyv/i_may_have_found_a_way_to_spot_us_atsea_strikes/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://old.reddit.com/r/OSINT/comments/1opjjyv/i_may_have_found_a_way_to_spot_us_atsea_strikes/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 04:37:45</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831541</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rust's TUI Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;bottomSection titled “bottom” A customizable cross-platform graphical process/system monitor for the terminal crosswordSection titled “crossword” Play crossword puzzles in your terminal. joshutoSection titled “joshuto” Ranger-like terminal file manager written in Rust materialSection titled “material” A material design color palette for the terminal. View OpenAPI documentations in your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830829"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dkdcio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;the title of this post is odd? it’s a showcase of TUI applications built with this Rust crate — which I am hearing about for the first time, and am interested in. I was expecting a blog post on why Rust is experiencing a TUI revolution or something&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ratatui.rs/showcase/apps/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 02:50:31</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830829</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAA to cut flights by 10% at 40 major airports due to government shutdown</title>
      <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Key PointsTransportation Secretary Sean Duffy announced Wednesday afternoon that he will be reducing flight capacity by 10% at 40 major airports. Transportation Secretary Sean P. "This is proactive," Duffy said in a news conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830797"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mmaunder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Watching officials describe how the NTSB is working hard to investigate the recent air disaster, knowing that many at NTSB aren&amp;#x27;t getting paid...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;runako:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Has anybody modeled what this does to the overall system?&lt;p&gt;My impression is the system doesn&amp;#x27;t have all that much slack to begin with. And then to reduce all the major airports at the same time? And with the (current) expectation that next week will be worse?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;komali2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Even if flights aren&amp;#x27;t cut, TSA and related staff are. I&amp;#x27;ve heard rumors of 4 hour security lines at IAH.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NewsGotHacked:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone figure out yet which 40 airports these are?!? All articles I have seen say 40 airports but don&amp;#x27;t mention which ones&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wnevets:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this the greatness I&amp;#x27;ve been promised?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;defrost:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Earlier: &lt;i&gt;US may cut air traffic 10% by Friday without shutdown deal, sources say&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;(reuters.com) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45828203"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45828203&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;istillwritecode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;No doubt flights between blue cities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CursedSilicon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Kind of glad I picked Amtrak to go down and visit family for Thanksgiving&lt;p&gt;Gonna be rough if the shutdown lasts to the end of November. Shame the usual suspects didn&amp;#x27;t get the memo about how badly their party was just decimated across the country. Should&amp;#x27;ve been a canary in the coal mine moment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JKCalhoun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wild times. I guess I&amp;#x27;m just at a loss for words—what&amp;#x27;s going on in this country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnbc.com/2025/11/05/faa-cuts-flight-capacity-shutdown.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 02:44:05</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830797</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longtime Mozilla Support Japanese Community Shuts Down over AI Translation Usage</title>
      <link>https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Client Challenge JavaScript is disabled in your browser. Please enable JavaScript to proceed. This may be due to a browser extension, network issues, or browser settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830770"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shusaku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s a shame because “improve an off the shelf llm ti translate in line with this large dataset we prepared” is precisely the kind of project people love to work on. It could have been a chance to immortalize the hard work they did up until now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getnormality:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sorry for how you feel about us kicking you in the balls.&lt;p&gt;Would you like to hop on a quick call to chat about this further?&lt;p&gt;Just a quick lil call.&lt;p&gt;Quick lil ol&amp;#x27; callerino.&lt;p&gt;We can hoppity hip hop right on there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thwarted:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the logic behind adding machine translation for content that already had a seemingly robust, enthusiastic, and motivated (volunteer?) community maintaining the translations?  The &amp;quot;saves money&amp;quot; rationale to deploy LLM&amp;#x2F;MT automation doesn&amp;#x27;t make sense when its volunteers are contributing because they want to.  This is kind of community and participation destruction wrought by the introduction of LLMs&amp;#x2F;MT has a serious impact because it undermines the people who are actually willing to do the work. It was presumably costing nothing (or very little) to have the community maintain this content, but the change has cost a significant amount of goodwill.  If the Japanese SUMO community wanted to use MT, it should be their sole decision, baring any issues with their stewardship in general.  This is someone else saying &amp;quot;look, with this great new automation, you don&amp;#x27;t need to spend time anymore doing «thing you &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to do»&amp;quot;. Huh? How does that make any sense to force on anyone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gyomu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a multilingual&amp;#x2F;multicultural human it’s been pretty weird witnessing what AI translation has been doing to regional languages &amp;amp; cultures on the internet in the last few years.&lt;p&gt;Sure we had machine translation before, but it was still a little off. Now the latest language models get us 99.9% there, so they are judged good enough to deploy at scale. What results is a weird twilight zone where everything is in your language, except it feels kind of wrong and doesn’t really communicate in ways specific to the culture from which the language is.&lt;p&gt;You’re in France, you search for something, a thread pops up with everyone interacting in French - seems reasonable enough, but it just reads kind of weird? Then a message is entirely out of place, and you realize that you’re reading an English language thread translated to French.&lt;p&gt;Or your mom sends you a screenshot of a Facebook thread in her native language that has her worked up - and reading it, you realize it’s an LLM translation of something that should have no bearing on her.&lt;p&gt;Same with various support pages on websites - it all reads mostly fine until you hit a weird sentence where the LLM messed up and then you’re transported back to the reality that what you’re reading was not authored by anyone who can actually operate in that language&amp;#x2F;culture.&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of nuance in language beyond the words - how you express disagreement in English is not how you express disagreement in Japanese, how you address the reader in French is not the same as in Korean, etc. Machine translation flattens all modes of expression into a weird culturally en-US biased soup (because that’s where the companies are headquartered and where the language models are trained).&lt;p&gt;I have no illusions that this trend will reverse - high quality translation work is skill and time consuming, and thanks to LLMs anyone on Earth can now localize anything they want in any language they want for ~free in ~0 time.&lt;p&gt;The weirdest part is seeing this bubble up to the real world. I’ve been hearing young people use turns of phrases&amp;#x2F;expressions that I recognize as distinctly American, except not in English.&lt;p&gt;The classic linguist response to this, which I subscribe to, is “no language is fixed, language is ever evolving in response to various external cultural pressures“. Which is true. But it doesn’t make our post-LLM language landscape any less weird.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kaveh_h:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some people do these type of contribution or charity work not just to do some good but also to feel some autonomy and mastery in a world were much of the regular top down driven  drudgery work does not provide much of that feeling. 
 These people are canaries in the coal mine. I expect more people feel a loss of purpose and rise of anxiety and depression in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jahsome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not really able to understand the finer details but I think I picked up enough to get the broad strokes.&lt;p&gt;Really though, all I needed to see was the phrase &amp;quot;jump on a quick call&amp;quot; to form an irrationally strong opinion. That phrase instantly warms my entire body with rage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ants_everywhere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I prohibit to use all my translation as learning data for SUMO bot and AIs.
&amp;gt; I request to remove all my translation from learned data of SUMO AIs.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s Mozilla&amp;#x27;s data...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; explicit violation to the Mozilla mission&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure what this is referring to. I don&amp;#x27;t see any explicit violation of Mozilla.org&amp;#x27;s mission. If anything it seems consistent with that mission to provide universal translation with quick turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adeptima:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10+ years in Japan. The message here is much deeper from my perspective. “Let’s jump on the call” is not the solution. The guy was stripped off of his face. I love Japan for being human. Small business bar or restaurant with 3 tables. Not everything should be streamlined for a quick call solution… the process was pushed on his head. Google nemawashi decision making process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ares623:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is rich&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; We want to make sure we trully understand what you&amp;#x27;re struggling with.&lt;p&gt;The post literally starts with a list of grievances. Maybe ask the AI for an executive summary and the key points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;barbazoo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; They are all happened on the product server, not on staging server. I understand that this is mass destruction of our work and explicit violation to the Mozilla mission, allowed officially.&lt;p&gt;Could this have been a mistake rather than a malicious act?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/forums/contributors/717446</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 02:38:53</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830770</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recursive macros in C, demystified (once the ugly crying stops)</title>
      <link>https://h4x0r.org/big-mac-ro-attack/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And you want to have some insight into how that might be possible. Wait, did I really just say that. We’re going to build a macro that counts the number of variable arguments in a function-like macro that accepts variable arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830223"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://h4x0r.org/big-mac-ro-attack/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://h4x0r.org/big-mac-ro-attack/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-06 01:09:18</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830223</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft and Google overstate job creation at Chile data centers</title>
      <link>https://restofworld.org/2025/data-centers-jobs-microsoft-google-chile/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data centers like this are touted as engines of growth. In June, President Gabriel Boric announced that Microsoft’s hyperscale data center cluster would generate over 81,000 jobs. Construction workers inside Google’s data center in Quilicura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://restofworld.org/2025/data-centers-jobs-microsoft-google-chile/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://restofworld.org/2025/data-centers-jobs-microsoft-google-chile/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 22:06:54</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828742</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lost IBM PC/at Model? Analyzing a Newfound Old Bios</title>
      <link>https://int10h.org/blog/2025/11/lost-ibm-at-model-bios-analysis/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enigmatic IBM EPROMs They came with no further identi­fication, and no hints about their origins, or what machines they may have come from. PC/AT BIOS revision Rev. 3 Date (US format) 01/10/84 06/10/85 11/15/85 P/N (internal/mask ROM) U27, even: 6181028U47, odd: 6181029 U27, even: 6480090U47, odd: 6480091 U27, even: 62X0820U47, odd: 62X0821 P/N (EPROM label) U17/U27, even: 6181024/5U37/U47, odd: 6181026/7 U27, even: 6448896U47, odd: 6448897 U27, even: 61X9266U47, odd: 61X9265 ID bytes: Model, Submodel, Revision level FCh, N/A, N/A a FCh, 00h, 01h FCh, 01h, 00h Technical Reference (with source code listing) March 1984 September 1985 March 1986 PC/AT model and main­board type 068, 099 (Type 1) 239 (Type 2) 319, 339 (Type 3) CPU clock supported 6 MHz (not tested in POST) 6 MHz (tested in POST) 8 MHz (tested in POST) Keyboards supported 84-key AT 84-key AT b 84-key AT101/102-key Enhanced Floppy drive types supported 360 KB1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://int10h.org/blog/2025/11/lost-ibm-at-model-bios-analysis/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://int10h.org/blog/2025/11/lost-ibm-at-model-bios-analysis/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 20:40:39</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827661</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Basic Laws of Human Stupidity (1987) [pdf]</title>
      <link>https://gandalf.fee.urv.cat/professors/AntonioQuesada/Curs1920/Cipolla_laws.pdf</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#��t�czb�Qx{�"���UA�{�)������H=�Y{�������5w^�zǼȾ���ő}+�֏��ǃ)�}d�Ykrog���w $� endstream endobj 321 0 obj &lt;&gt;stream H�l��n�0E��. =cb&gt;&amp;Ãi� D��4��J�xb �ȟo�8��R�S�� 0�m� endstream endobj 322 0 obj &lt;&gt;stream H�t��j. � endstream endobj 328 0 obj &lt;&gt;stream H��SKK�@��W�qWȚM6�)h+X�&lt;��&gt;m�͆j(����̊/&gt;stream H�dS=o�0 ��+8R,H�d�� M�N�Ptp�|q��m8����Hٺ�&amp;�C�# ������pg�1����j~���i[����&gt;,g�v��E��.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://gandalf.fee.urv.cat/professors/AntonioQuesada/Curs1920/Cipolla_laws.pdf'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gandalf.fee.urv.cat/professors/AntonioQuesada/Curs1920/Cipolla_laws.pdf</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 22:58:38</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829210</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos: New Phoenix Microcenter is a 'tech-heaven' for geeks</title>
      <link>https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/arts-culture/micro-center-in-phoenix-a-look-inside-the-new-tech-heaven-40618548/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a look inside the new Micro Center Phoenix store. Benjamin Leatherman Giant-sized mouse pads at Micro Center’s new Phoenix store. Benjamin Leatherman The gaming section at Micro Center Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/arts-culture/micro-center-in-phoenix-a-look-inside-the-new-tech-heaven-40618548/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.phoenixnewtimes.com/arts-culture/micro-center-in-phoenix-a-look-inside-the-new-tech-heaven-40618548/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 23:43:43</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829594</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Stopped Being a Climate Catastrophist</title>
      <link>https://www.breakthroughjournal.org/p/why-i-stopped-being-a-climate-catastrophist</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A future with low rates of technological change is not one that is consistent with high economic growth. Climate advocates have arguably become more catastrophic about climate change in recent years, not less. ShareWhen Is Weather Climate Change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.breakthroughjournal.org/p/why-i-stopped-being-a-climate-catastrophist'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.breakthroughjournal.org/p/why-i-stopped-being-a-climate-catastrophist</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 20:13:37</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827352</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Archive's legal fights are over, but its founder mourns what was lost</title>
      <link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/11/the-internet-archive-survived-major-copyright-losses-whats-next/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;” “We survived,” Internet Archive founder Brewster Kahle told Ars. At the time, law professor Lawrence Lessig predicted that the Internet Archive would face copyright battles, but he also believed that the Wayback Machine would change the way the public understood copyright fights. The Internet Archive also began archiving—and then lending—e-books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/11/the-internet-archive-survived-major-copyright-losses-whats-next/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/11/the-internet-archive-survived-major-copyright-losses-whats-next/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 18:59:39</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45826500</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why aren't smart people happier?</title>
      <link>https://www.theseedsofscience.pub/p/why-arent-smart-people-happier</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intelligence sounds pretty great. Naturally, people with more of this mental horsepower must live happier lives. This large, nationally-representative study from the UK finds that people who score the lowest on an intelligence test are a little less happy than everyone else, but that’s pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theseedsofscience.pub/p/why-arent-smart-people-happier'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theseedsofscience.pub/p/why-arent-smart-people-happier</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 16:32:43</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824864</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT terms disallow its use in providing legal and medical advice to others</title>
      <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/sci-tech/article/openai-updates-policies-so-chatgpt-wont-provide-medical-or-legal-advice/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;couple trying to ‘make good decisions’ after $500K lottery win Eby, coastal First Nations call on Ottawa to maintain oil tanker banAlberta’s nursing industry votes in favour of strike Eby, coastal First Nations call on Ottawa to maintain oil tanker banVideoUnions warn federal government ‘gutting’ public service with plans to cut 28,000 jobs 10-15 mm of rain for Ottawa today, with snow expected tonightVideoAriane 6 rocket launch causes incredible light spiral in Quebec skiesVideoWakefield doctor says she was fired from ministry role for speaking outManslaughter charge laid in fatal assault in central EdmontonSheriffs board up west Edmonton drug house that saw 40 police visits since JuneVideoNext low-pressure system brings rain, flurries, high winds to the MaritimesN. survivor of open-heart surgery writes children’s bookVideo‘It’s exhilarating’: Childhood friends reconnect after 40 years by tossing football in parkBailey says Ottawa must support B. could shape the COP30 climate summit without even being thereSci-TechChatGPT users can’t use service for tailored legal and medic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ctvnews.ca/sci-tech/article/openai-updates-policies-so-chatgpt-wont-provide-medical-or-legal-advice/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ctvnews.ca/sci-tech/article/openai-updates-policies-so-chatgpt-wont-provide-medical-or-legal-advice/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 18:11:16</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45825965</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New gel restores dental enamel and could revolutionise tooth repair</title>
      <link>https://www.nottingham.ac.uk/news/new-gel-restores-dental-enamel-and-could-revolutionise-tooth-repair</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nottingham.ac.uk/news/new-gel-restores-dental-enamel-and-could-revolutionise-tooth-repair</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 19:44:49</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45826995</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The state of SIMD in Rust in 2025</title>
      <link>https://shnatsel.medium.com/the-state-of-simd-in-rust-in-2025-32c263e5f53d</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does this CPU have that instruction. (Floats are cursed even without SIMD. par_iter(), there have been attempts to do the same for SIMD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://shnatsel.medium.com/the-state-of-simd-in-rust-in-2025-32c263e5f53d'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://shnatsel.medium.com/the-state-of-simd-in-rust-in-2025-32c263e5f53d</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 18:45:57</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45826348</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dillo, a multi-platform graphical web browser</title>
      <link>https://github.com/dillo-browser/dillo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Screenshot of the Dillo Website rendered in Dillo: To install Dillo follow the installation guide. This repository contains mostly the original code of Dillo with some minor patches. WarningAs of December 2023, the host dillo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/dillo-browser/dillo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/dillo-browser/dillo</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 18:40:32</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45826266</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solarpunk is already happening in Africa</title>
      <link>https://climatedrift.substack.com/p/why-solarpunk-is-already-happening</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://climatedrift.substack.com/p/why-solarpunk-is-already-happening</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 20:00:40</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827190</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Can't Keep EU Data Safe from US Authorities</title>
      <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/emmawoollacott/2025/07/22/microsoft-cant-keep-eu-data-safe-from-us-authorities/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;However, the admission raises serious concerns around European data sovereignty. Senate members said they couldn't be sure that the two platforms were sufficiently separated, and that sensitive health data wouldn't be shared. "We’re already seeing a shift towards building homegrown solutions that support true data sovereignty rather than data residency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.forbes.com/sites/emmawoollacott/2025/07/22/microsoft-cant-keep-eu-data-safe-from-us-authorities/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.forbes.com/sites/emmawoollacott/2025/07/22/microsoft-cant-keep-eu-data-safe-from-us-authorities/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:00:41</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822902</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask HN: My family business runs on a 1993-era text-based-UI (TUI). Anybody else?</title>
      <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823234</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is anybody still using TUI applications for business. I had a blast and still love this application. This got me thinking: Are other companies still using this type of interface to drive their core operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823234'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823234</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:29:49</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823234</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Norway reviews cybersecurity after remote-access feature found in Chinese buses</title>
      <link>https://scandasia.com/norway-reviews-cybersecurity-after-hidden-remote-access-feature-found-in-chinese-buses/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Yutong electric bus in Norway. Authorities are tightening cybersecurity controls after hidden SIM cards were discovered during internal tests. Norway has launched a cybersecurity review after public transport operator Ruter discovered that electric buses supplied by Chinese manufacturer Yutong contained hidden SIM cards enabling potential remote access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://scandasia.com/norway-reviews-cybersecurity-after-hidden-remote-access-feature-found-in-chinese-buses/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://scandasia.com/norway-reviews-cybersecurity-after-hidden-remote-access-feature-found-in-chinese-buses/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 16:18:01</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824658</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruby and Its Neighbors: Smalltalk</title>
      <link>https://noelrappin.com/blog/2025/11/ruby-and-its-neighbors-smalltalk/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The major player was ParcPlace, which was a spinoff of Xerox that provided Smalltalk tools. I taught an undergrad OO class in Smalltalk in 1997 and 1998 to students that wanted to be learning C++, and I remember telling them that Smalltalk programmers were paid more. Your main interfaces to the smalltalk system are a.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://noelrappin.com/blog/2025/11/ruby-and-its-neighbors-smalltalk/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://noelrappin.com/blog/2025/11/ruby-and-its-neighbors-smalltalk/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 15:24:35</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823831</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gnome Mutter Now "Completely Drops the Whole X11 Back End"</title>
      <link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Mutter-Drops-X11</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GNOME Mutter Now "Completely Drops The Whole X11 Backend" Written by Michael Larabel in GNOME on 5 November 2025 at 08:15 AM EST. 25 Comments The merge to GNOME Mutter has finally happened that "completely drops" the X11 back-end to make GNOME strictly focused on Wayland-based environments. GNOME 50 will continue supporting XWayland clients (apps / games) but moving forward strictly for Wayland-based desktop sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Mutter-Drops-X11'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.phoronix.com/news/GNOME-Mutter-Drops-X11</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:24:15</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823162</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimism Associated with Exceptional Longevity</title>
      <link>https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.1900712116</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.1900712116</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 13:16:58</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822513</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kosmos: An AI Scientist for Autonomous Discovery</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02824</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02824'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.02824</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:43:26</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823358</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NY Smartphone Ban Has Made Lunch Loud Again</title>
      <link>https://gothamist.com/news/ny-smartphone-ban-has-made-lunch-loud-again</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Students said they’ve also seen their classmates reading physical books more. ”Tripathi said it’s good that people are reading more and classroom discussions have become more lively. Students said they have found other ways to push boundaries, like passing old-fashioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://gothamist.com/news/ny-smartphone-ban-has-made-lunch-loud-again'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gothamist.com/news/ny-smartphone-ban-has-made-lunch-loud-again</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 13:20:16</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822539</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UPS plane crashes near Louisville airport</title>
      <link>https://avherald.com/h?article=52f5748f&amp;opt=0</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crash: UPS MD11 at Louisville on Nov 4th 2025, burst into flames on takeoff The Aviation Herald Last Update: Wednesday, Nov 5th 2025 14:28Z32135 Articles availableEvents from Mar 23rd 1994 to Nov 4th 2025 www. 4, after departing from Louisville Muhammad Ali International Airport in Kentucky. SDF 11/077 SDF RWY 17L/35R CLSD 2511050624-2511080300Metars:KSDF 050056Z 15005KT 10SM SCT026 SCT250 13/05 A3020 RMK AO2 SLP227 FU SCT026 T01280050=KSDF 050028Z 15005KT 10SM SCT026 BKN250 13/05 A3020 RMK AO2 FU SCT026 T01330050=KSDF 042356Z 14004KT 10SM FEW022 BKN026 BKN250 14/06 A3021 RMK AO2 SLP229 FU BKN026 T01390056 10183 20133 56007=KSDF 042303Z 16008KT 10SM FEW021 BKN028 BKN032 BKN250 16/05 A3021 RMK AO2 FU BKN028 T01560050=KSDF 042256Z 17006KT 10SM SCT032 BKN250 16/05 A3021 RMK AO2 SLP230 FU SCT032 T01560050=KSDF 042156Z 12006KT 10SM SCT200 BKN250 17/05 A3022 RMK AO2 SLP233 T01670050=KSDF 042056Z 15006KT 10SM FEW200 BKN250 17/04 A3023 RMK AO2 SLP237 T01720044 56028=KSDF 041956Z 14006KT 10SM FEW200 BKN250 18/04 A3025 RMK AO2 SLP241 T01780044=KSDF 041856Z 15007KT 10SM FEW200 BKN250 18/02 A3028 RMK AO2 SLP253 T01780022=KSDF 041756Z 17008KT 10SM FEW200 BKN250 17/02 A3031 RMK AO2 SLP264 T01670022 10167 20033 58028=CCTV recording of initial impact:https://www.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://avherald.com/h?article=52f5748f&amp;opt=0'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://avherald.com/h?article=52f5748f&amp;opt=0</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-04 23:10:53</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45816963</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael Burry is back with two bets against Nvidia and Palantir</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/11/05/business/nvidia-palantir-michael-burry-stock</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tech and AI stocks have carried the market in recent months. He said Burry’s comments likely exacerbated concerns. Burry has made public calls about the market in the years since “The Big Short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cnn.com/2025/11/05/business/nvidia-palantir-michael-burry-stock'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cnn.com/2025/11/05/business/nvidia-palantir-michael-burry-stock</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:38:27</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823313</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The grim truth behind the Pied Piper (2020)</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/travel/article/20200902-the-grim-truth-behind-the-pied-piper</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The grim truth behind the Pied Piper3 September 2020ShareSaveRaphael KadushinFeatures correspondentShareSaveKate Greenawayduncan1890/Getty ImagesEntranced by his flute, the transfixed children of Hamelin followed the Piper out of town (Credit: Kate Greenawayduncan1890/Getty Images)Writers like the Grimm Brothers and Robert Browning may have shaped the Pied Piper legend into art, but it turns out the story is likely based on an actual historical incident. The Hameln Museum offers a sound and light Pied Piper re-enactment; local actors put on an open-air Pied Piper play during summer; and the souvenir shops hawk their own rat-inspired memorabilia. You can go home, if you wish, loaded down with Pied Piper T-shirts, fridge magnets, mugs and flutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bbc.com/travel/article/20200902-the-grim-truth-behind-the-pied-piper'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/travel/article/20200902-the-grim-truth-behind-the-pied-piper</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 12:21:39</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822071</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carice TC2 – An fully analog electric car</title>
      <link>https://www.caricecars.com/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.caricecars.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-05 14:25:36</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45823186</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
