<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 21:24:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>62 chapter open-source Zig book</title>
      <link>https://www.zigbook.net</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning Zig is not just about adding a language to your resume. It is about fundamentally changing how you think about software. netWelcome to Zigbook 🦎Ready to transform how you think about software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947810"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.zigbook.net'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p2detar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hmm, the explanation of Allocators is much more detailed in the book, but I feel although more compact, it seems much more reasonable in the language reference. [0]&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll keep exploring this book though, it does look very impressive.&lt;p&gt;0 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ziglang.org&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;#Memory" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ziglang.org&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;#Memory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;serial_dev:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It was very hard to find a link to the table of contents… then I tried opening it and the link didn’t work. I’m on iOS. I’d have loved to take a look quickly what’s in the book…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gooodvibes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How do people find the time time and energy to spend on a 62-chapter book about a language that nobody uses in the real world yet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wosined:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some text is unreadable because it is so small.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gigatexal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;there&amp;#x27;s no way someone made this for free, where do I donate? im gonna get so much value from this this feels like stealing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amitav1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It looks cool! No experience with Zig so can&amp;#x27;t comment on the accuracy, but I will take a look at it this week. Also a bit annoying that there is no PDF version that I could download as the website is pretty slow. After taking a look at the repository (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;zigbook&amp;#x2F;zigbook&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;zigbook&amp;#x2F;zigbook&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main&lt;/a&gt;), each page seems to be written in AsciiDoc, so I&amp;#x27;ll take a look about compiling a PDF version later today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulRobinson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This looks fantastic. Pedagogically it makes sense to me, and I love this approach of not just teaching a language, but a paradigm (in this case, low-level systems programming), in a single text.&lt;p&gt;Zig got me excited when I stumbled into it about a year ago, but life got busy and then the io changes came along and I thought about holding off until things settled down - it&amp;#x27;s still a very young language.&lt;p&gt;But reading the first couple of chapters has piqued my interest in a language and the people who are working with it in a way I&amp;#x27;ve not run into since I encountered Ruby in ~2006 (before Rails hit v1.0), I just hope the quality stays this high all the way through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jasonjmcghee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So despite this...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The Zigbook intentionally contains no AI-generated content—it is hand-written, carefully curated, and continuously updated to reflect the latest language features and best practices.&lt;p&gt;I just don&amp;#x27;t buy it. I&amp;#x27;m 99% sure this is written by an LLM.&lt;p&gt;Can the author... Convince me otherwise?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; This journey begins with simplicity—the kind you encounter on the first day. By the end, you will discover a different kind of simplicity: the kind you earn by climbing through complexity and emerging with complete understanding on the other side.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Welcome to the Zigbook. Your transformation starts now.&lt;p&gt;...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; You will know where every byte lives in memory, when the compiler executes your code, and what machine instructions your abstractions compile to. No hidden allocations. No mystery overhead. No surprises.&lt;p&gt;...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; This is not about memorizing syntax. This is about earning mastery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.zigbook.net</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947810</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fate of "small" open source</title>
      <link>https://nolanlawson.com/2025/11/16/the-fate-of-small-open-source/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although it’s much more verbose, unnecessarily checking if readAsArrayBuffer actually gives you an ArrayBuffer (although this does make TypeScript happy). (Is this even documentation anymore. This does mean that there’s less opportunity to use these libraries as a springboard for user education (Underscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947639"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://nolanlawson.com/2025/11/16/the-fate-of-small-open-source/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Claude’s version is pretty close to the blob-util version (unsurprising, since it was probably trained on it!).&lt;p&gt;AI are thieves!&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I don’t know which direction we’re going in with AI (well, ~80% of us; to the remaining holdouts, I salute you and wish you godspeed!), but I do think it’s a future where we prize instant answers over teaching and understanding.&lt;p&gt;Google ruined its search engine years ago before AI already.&lt;p&gt;The big problem I see is that we have become WAY too dependent on these mega-corporations. Which browser are people using? Typically chrome. An evil company writes the code. And soon it will fire the remaining devs and replace them with AI. Which is kind of fitting.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Even now there’s a movement toward putting documentation in an llms.txt file, so you can just point an agent at it and save your brain cells the effort of deciphering English prose. (Is this even documentation anymore? What is documentation?)&lt;p&gt;Documentation in general sucks. But documentation is also a hard problem.&lt;p&gt;I love examples. Small snippets. FAQs. Well, many projects barely have these.&lt;p&gt;Look at ruby webassembly&amp;#x2F;wasm or ruby opal. Their documentation is about 99% useless. Or, even worse - rack in ruby. And I did not notice this in the past, in part because e. g. StackOverflow still worked, there were many blogs which helped fill up missing information too. Well all of that is largely gone now or has been slurped up by AI spam.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; the era of small, low-value libraries like blob-util is over. They were already on their way out thanks to Node.js and the browser taking on more and more of their functionality (see node:glob, structuredClone, etc.), but LLMs are the final nail in the coffin.&lt;p&gt;I still think they have value, but looking at organisations such as rubygems.org disrupt the ecosystem and bleeding it dry by kicking out small hobbyists, I think there is indeed a trend towards eliminating the silly solo devs who think their unpaid spare time is not worthy of anything at all, yet the big organisations eagerly throw down more and more restrictions onto them (my favourite example is the arbitrary 100k download limit for gems hosted at rubygems.org, but look at the new shiny corporate rules on rubygems.org - this is when corporations take over the infrastructure and control it. Ironically this also happened to pypi and they admit this indirectly: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.pypi.org&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;2023-05-25-securing-pypi-with-2fa&amp;#x2F;#isnt-supply-chain-security-a-corporate-concern" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.pypi.org&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;2023-05-25-securing-pypi-with-2f...&lt;/a&gt; - of course they deny that corporations control pypi now, but by claiming otherwise they admit it, because this is how hobbyists get eliminated. Just throw more and more restrictions at them without paying them. Sooner or later they decide to do something better with their time.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smcameron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the U.S., anything machine generated is uncopyrightable.&lt;p&gt;Why would you put uncopyrightable code into your codebase?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrenBarn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Sure, you could use blob-util, but then you’d be taking on an extra dependency, with unknown performance, maintenance, and supply-chain risks.&lt;p&gt;Use of an AI to write your code is also a form of dependency.  When the LLM spits out code and you just dump it in your project with limited vetting, that&amp;#x27;s not really that different from vendoring a dependency.  It has a different set of risks, but it still has risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hnlmorg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;More likely, what we will see is the decline of low effort projects. The JavaScript&amp;#x2F; Typescript ecosystem has been plagued with such packages. But that’s more anomalous to the JS community than it is a systemic problem with open source in general.&lt;p&gt;So if fewer people are including silly dependencies like isEven or leftPad, then I see that as a positive outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aperocky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; the era of small, low-value libraries like blob-util is over.&lt;p&gt;Thankfully (not against blob-util specifically because I&amp;#x27;ve never &lt;i&gt;intentionally&lt;/i&gt; used it), I wouldn&amp;#x27;t completely blame llms either since languages like Go never had this dependency hell.&lt;p&gt;npm is a security nightmare not just because of npm the package manager, because the culture of the language rewards behavior such as &amp;quot;left-pad&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Instead of writing endless utilities for other project to re-use, write actual working things instead - that&amp;#x27;s where the value&amp;#x2F;fun is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cactusfrog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This author assumes that open sourcing a package only delivers value if is added as a dependency. Publicly sharing code with a permissive license is still useful and a radical idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;levkk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Several issues:&lt;p&gt;1. Reducing dependencies is a wrong success metric. You just end up doing more work yourself, except you can&amp;#x27;t be an expert in everything, so your code is often strictly worse.&lt;p&gt;2. Regenerating the same solutions with a probabilistic machine will produce bugs a certain percentage of the time. Dependencies are always the same code (when versioned).&lt;p&gt;3. Cognitive overhead for human review is higher with LLM-generated libs, for no additional benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Open source exists because coding was a significant effort and code was a thing of high value. Unsurprisingly companies hesitated to make the code public and free. All of this is changing now as coding has suddenly become trivial. So, yes, the mission of open source, in general, will be challenged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mccoyb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t think open source is going anywhere. It’s posed to get significantly stronger — as the devs which care about it learn how to leverage AI tools to make things that corporate greasemonkeys never had the inspiration to. Low quality code spammers are just marketing themselves for jobs where they can be themselves: soulless and devoid of creative impulse.&lt;p&gt;That’s the thing: open source is the only place where the true value (or lack of value) of these tools can be established — the only place where one can test mettle against metal in a completely unconstrained way.&lt;p&gt;Did you ever want to build a compiler (or an equally complex artifact) but got stuck on various details? Try now. It’s going to stand up something half-baked, and as you refine it, you will learn those details — but you’ll also learn that you can productively use AI to reach past the limits of your knowledge, to make what’s beyond a little more palatable.&lt;p&gt;All the things people say about AI is true to some degree: my take is that some people are rolling the slots to win a CRUD app, and others are trying to use it to do things that they could only imagine before —- and open source tends to be the home of the latter group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CuriouslyC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Small open source is still valuable, but the bar is higher. If your project is something that&amp;#x27;s trivial and nobody just thought to do it before you and bothered to do it after, that&amp;#x27;s probably not going to survive, but if your project is a small focused tool that handles something difficult really well, it&amp;#x27;s 100% got a future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cynicalsecurity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He almost got it right. It&amp;#x27;s not just the fate of small open source. It&amp;#x27;s the fate of all programmers now. Why hire a programmer when an LLM costs less, works faster and makes less mistakes (OP compliments better error handling, read the article).&lt;p&gt;Unless you are a product owner, you have paying clients that love you and your product and won&amp;#x27;t simply ditch it in favour of a new clone, you are really screwed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RyanHamilton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Less incentive to write small libraries. Less incentive to write small tutorials on your own website. Unless you are a hacker or a spammer where your incentives have probably increased.  We are entering the era of cheap spam of everything with little incentive for quality. All this for the best case outcome of most people being made unemployed and rolling the dice on society reorganising to that reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nolanlawson.com/2025/11/16/the-fate-of-small-open-source/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947639</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking users with favicons, even in incognito mode</title>
      <link>https://github.com/jonasstrehle/supercookie</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;js Clone repository git clone https://github. If this tag does exist, the browser requests the icon from the predefined source and if the server response contains an valid icon file that can be properly rendered this icon is displayed by the browser. A web server can draw conclusions about whether a browser has already loaded a favicon or not: So when the browser requests a web page, if the favicon is not in the local F-cache, another request for the favicon is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947770"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/jonasstrehle/supercookie'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HelloUsername:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related discussion?&lt;p&gt;Tales of Favicons and Caches: Persistent Tracking in Modern Browsers [pdf]&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=25868742"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=25868742&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;53 comments on 22-jan-2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sjdonado:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The demo didn&amp;#x27;t work for me. Safari latest ios&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vanschelven:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a shame that the actual attack mechanism doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be detailed on the github repo, and the link to the article is dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;soulofmischief:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I got different IDs in regular browsing vs incognito mode in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zzo38computer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does it work if you disable favicons? (I disabled favicons when I set up the computer, but for a different reason; it is a feature that I don&amp;#x27;t use.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gitmagic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the live demo supposed to do? I just get stuck in an endless redirect loop with a counter going from 1 to 18 and then restarting. I’m using Safari on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;breppp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was sure this has been a thing for a while, either that or safari has a UI bug since forever.&lt;p&gt;I regularly get the wrong favicon in specific sites, for example ars technica favicon in reddit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/jonasstrehle/supercookie</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947770</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Z3 API in Python: From Sudoku to N-Queens in Under 20 Lines</title>
      <link>https://ericpony.github.io/z3py-tutorial/guide-examples.htm</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Z3 can solve nonlinear polynomial constraints. The following example uses a combination of polynomial and Boolean constraints. The following example shows an example that Z3 cannot solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947301"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ericpony.github.io/z3py-tutorial/guide-examples.htm'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ericpony.github.io/z3py-tutorial/guide-examples.htm</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947301</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Pattern Games</title>
      <link>https://www.darkpattern.games</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A game review website devoted to helping you find games that don't use psychological tricks to manipulate you into becoming an addicted gamer. Learn about the dark patterns that game designers use to waste your precious time and money. Social dark patterns use your relationships with friends and family to benefit the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947761"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.darkpattern.games'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mzajc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like the idea, but their ratings seem.. dubious at best. For example: Hyperrogue, which hit the frontpage a few times and which I can confidently say does not feature any dark patterns, is rated just 1.19 [0] on a 5 (best) to -5 (worst) scale.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.darkpattern.games&amp;#x2F;game&amp;#x2F;18554&amp;#x2F;0&amp;#x2F;hyperrogue.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.darkpattern.games&amp;#x2F;game&amp;#x2F;18554&amp;#x2F;0&amp;#x2F;hyperrogue.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.darkpattern.games</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947761</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux mode setting, from the comfort of OCaml</title>
      <link>https://roscidus.com/blog/blog/2025/11/16/libdrm-ocaml/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;com/talex5/libdrm-ocaml cd libdrm-ocaml nix develop dune utop You should see a utop # prompt, where you can enter OCaml expressions. 1 2 utop # 1+1;; - : int = 2 Alternatively, you can install things using opam (OCaml's package manager): opam install libdrm utop utop Then, at the utop prompt enter #require "libdrm";; (including the leading #). Connectors correspond to physical connectors (e.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947822"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://roscidus.com/blog/blog/2025/11/16/libdrm-ocaml/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dlcarrier:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is OCaml an especially comfortable environment to work in?&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite programs, an ncurses-based RPN calculator called Orpie, is written in OCaml, but I&amp;#x27;ve never messed around with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://roscidus.com/blog/blog/2025/11/16/libdrm-ocaml/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947822</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I have recordings proving Coinbase knew about breach months before disclosure</title>
      <link>https://jonathanclark.com/posts/coinbase-breach-timeline.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For four months, I had concrete evidence that attackers possessed detailed Coinbase customer data. And when did Coinbase first become aware that something was wrong. com DKIM signature analysis: Documentation that while the email passed DKIM validation for both coinbase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948058"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://jonathanclark.com/posts/coinbase-breach-timeline.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paulbjensen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I got rung in the UK I think a month ago from someone claiming to be from Coinbase. I told them I only had about £5 of Bitcoin cash in my account (which was true), and they immediately lost interest and said a forthcoming email would handle the matter.&lt;p&gt;They also asked if I had cold storage. I told them I had a fridge (also true).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anonym29:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Has anyone demonstrated that agentic AI systems can be bribed with money, or is that vulnerability still strictly relegated to unrealiable, untrustworthy biological intelligence?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tchalla:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Founder mode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrenBarn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m shocked, shocked to find that a cryptocurrency company did something shady.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chaps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Once did some programming&amp;#x2F;networking work for a company that did the networking of a office sharing building that Coinbase was running out of. Early in my work there I noticed that the company had its admin passwords written on a whiteboard -- visible from the hallway because they had glass for walls. So I sent them an email to ask that they remove it (I billed them for it).&lt;p&gt;Their fix was to put a piece of paper over the passwords.&lt;p&gt;What a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AlexErrant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s a Reuters report from June 2, which includes a link to a May 14 SEC filing:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase knew as far back as January about a customer data leak at an outsourcing company connected to a larger breach estimated to cost up to $400 million, six people familiar with the matter told Reuters.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reuters.com&amp;#x2F;sustainability&amp;#x2F;boards-policy-regulation&amp;#x2F;coinbase-breach-linked-customer-data-leak-india-sources-say-2025-06-02&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reuters.com&amp;#x2F;sustainability&amp;#x2F;boards-policy-regulat...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; On May 11, 2025, Coinbase, Inc., a subsidiary of Coinbase Global, Inc. (“Coinbase” or the “Company”), received an email communication from an unknown threat actor claiming to have obtained information about certain Coinbase customer accounts, as well as internal Coinbase documentation, including materials relating to customer-service and account-management systems.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.sec.gov&amp;#x2F;Archives&amp;#x2F;edgar&amp;#x2F;data&amp;#x2F;1679788&amp;#x2F;000167978825000094&amp;#x2F;coin-20250514.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.sec.gov&amp;#x2F;Archives&amp;#x2F;edgar&amp;#x2F;data&amp;#x2F;1679788&amp;#x2F;000167978825...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;divvvyy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wild tale, but very annoying that he wrote it with an AI. It&amp;#x27;s horribly jarring to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmclnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t there a new law from the Biden era that forces a company disclose breaches to their customers and the SEC  within a few weeks ?&lt;p&gt;If so and if the US had a sane administration maybe, this would be acted upon, but these days, anything goes as long as you &amp;#x27;donate&amp;#x27; to the ballroom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jclarkcom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In January 2025, I was targeted by scammers who knew my exact Bitcoin balance, SSN, DL, and other private Coinbase account details. I immediately reported this to Coinbase&amp;#x27;s Head of Trust &amp;amp; Safety with recordings and technical evidence. Despite repeated follow-ups asking how attackers had my data, Coinbase went silent for 4 months. They only disclosed the breach in May after attackers demanded $20M ransom. The breach involved overseas contractors at TaskUs being bribed for customer data. This article documents the timeline with emails, recordings, and evidence showing Coinbase was aware of the breach months before their official &amp;quot;discovery&amp;quot; date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jonathanclark.com/posts/coinbase-breach-timeline.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 20:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948058</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I finally understand Cloudflare Zero Trust tunnels</title>
      <link>https://david.coffee/cloudflare-zero-trust-tunnels</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a full-on Cloudflare Zero Trust with Warp convert, and while I still have Tailscale running in parallel, almost everything I do now is going through Zero Trust tunnels. This is the thing that you configure to add clients into your Zero Trust network and enforces policies. Can also create one-time-use tunnels that aren’t connected to the Zero Trust network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946865"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://david.coffee/cloudflare-zero-trust-tunnels'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qudat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice article. For easily exposing private services to the internet I’ve been using &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tuns.sh" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tuns.sh&lt;/a&gt; which lets you run ssh tunnels. It’s nice for a zero install solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yuvadam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tailscale now has the awesome feature of peer relays and now there&amp;#x27;s no more excuses why you can&amp;#x27;t traverse that NAT and you can forget about all those DERP servers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jchw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One thing that makes Cloudflare worse for home usage is it acts as a termination point for TLS, whereas Tailscale does not. If you use a Tailscale Funnel, you get the TLS certificate on your endpoint. With Cloudflare, they get a TLS certificate for you, and then strip and optionally re-add TLS as traffic passes through them.&lt;p&gt;I actually have no idea how private networks with WARP are here, but that&amp;#x27;s a pretty big privacy downgrade for tunneling from the Internet.&lt;p&gt;I also consider P2P with relay fallback to be highly desirable over always relaying traffic through a third party, too. Firstly, less middlemen. Secondly, it continues working even if the coordination service is unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hexbin010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This seems like an excellent guide. I love these &amp;quot;how the pieces fit together&amp;quot; kind of guides.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps CF could license it and slap it in their docs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;plantinthebok:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s the actual win here? Avoiding relay latency in the rare cases Tailscale can&amp;#x27;t punch through NAT? If that&amp;#x27;s it, a $3 VPS running Headscale seems simpler. The complexity feels like you&amp;#x27;re optimizing for the 5% case while adding permanent vendor lock in. What am I missing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://david.coffee/cloudflare-zero-trust-tunnels</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946865</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Leibniz Notation (2024)</title>
      <link>https://www.spakhm.com/leibniz</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote this for myself to understand the Leibniz notation. This is called the Leibniz notation. Then it follows that the second derivative in Leibniz notation is dg(x)dx=g′=f′′=g’=f’′dxdg(x)=g′=f′′.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947374"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.spakhm.com/leibniz'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.spakhm.com/leibniz</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947374</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if you don't need MCP at all?</title>
      <link>https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-02-what-if-you-dont-need-mcp/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That many tools will confuse your agent, especially when combined with other MCP servers and built-in tools. ## Start Chrome \`\`\`bash. ts --profile # Start with your Chro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947444"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-02-what-if-you-dont-need-mcp/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jsight:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yeah, I&amp;#x27;m still confused as to why so many people in &amp;quot;AI engineering&amp;quot; seem to think that MCPs are the key to everything.&lt;p&gt;They are great if you have a UI that you want and it needs a plugin system, obviously.&lt;p&gt;But the benefits become much more marginal for a developer of enterprise AI systems with predefined tool selections. They are actually getting overused in this space, if anything, sometimes with security as a primary casualty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bobaso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Moderne Ai agent tool have have a setting where you can trimm down the numbers of tools from an MCP server. Usefull to avoid overwhelming the LLM with 80 tools description when you only need 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lemming:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mario has some fantastic content, and has really shaped how I think about my interface to coding tools. I use a modified version of his LLM-as-crappy-state-machine model (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;badlogic&amp;#x2F;claude-commands" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;badlogic&amp;#x2F;claude-commands&lt;/a&gt;) for nearly all my coding work now. It seems pretty clear these days that progressive discovery is the way forward (e.g. skills), and using CLI tools rather than MCP really facilitates that. I&amp;#x27;ve gone pretty far down the road of writing complex LLM tooling, and the more I do that the more the simplicity and composability is appealing. He has a coding agent designed along the same principles, which I&amp;#x27;m planning to try out (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;badlogic&amp;#x2F;pi-mono&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;packages&amp;#x2F;coding-agent" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;badlogic&amp;#x2F;pi-mono&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;packages&amp;#x2F;codin...&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dennisy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is incredibly simple and neat! Love it!&lt;p&gt;Will have a think about how this can extended to other types of uses.&lt;p&gt;I have personally been trying to replace all tools&amp;#x2F;MCPs with a single “write code” tool which is a bit harder to get to work reliably in large projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emilsedgh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oh you&amp;#x27;re misunderstanding MCP here.&lt;p&gt;MCP was created so llm companies can have a plugin system. So instead of them being the API provider, they can become the platform that we build apps&amp;#x2F;plugins for, and they become the user interface to end consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mariozechner.at/posts/2025-11-02-what-if-you-dont-need-mcp/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947444</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pragmatic Programmer: 20th Anniversary Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.ahalbert.com/technology/2023/12/19/the_pragmatic_programmer.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I appreciate about the book is that they talk about applying the principles not only to software engineering but to writing the book as well. Perhaps the best thing about the book is that the authors summarize their points into short tips highlighted throughout the book. Your software does not nee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948254"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ahalbert.com/technology/2023/12/19/the_pragmatic_programmer.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ahalbert.com/technology/2023/12/19/the_pragmatic_programmer.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 20:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948254</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Man Who Keeps Predicting the Web's Death</title>
      <link>https://tedium.co/2025/10/25/web-dead-predictions-george-colony/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tedium.co/2025/10/25/web-dead-predictions-george-colony/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946937</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding an imaginary unit to a finite field</title>
      <link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/16/finite-field-i/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Then the integers mod p form a finite field. This works for a field with 49 elements, but not for a field of 25 elements. the field Fp, with an element i adjoined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947827"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/16/finite-field-i/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Syzygies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My gut, reading the HN title, was &amp;quot;half the time&amp;quot;. I had to read the article, to see how many words piled up before he said that.&lt;p&gt;Of course, considering finite fields of prime power order, one might leap to the conclusion &amp;quot;a quarter of the time&amp;quot;. One can adjoin &amp;quot;i&amp;quot; for prime powers p^n for half the primes and odd n.&lt;p&gt;Alas, this be wrong, for an amusing reason.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/16/finite-field-i/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45947827</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
