<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>My private information is worth $30</title>
      <link>https://blog.melashri.net/micro/privacy-price/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They do not care about the damage they caused to our personal information. They do not care about the trust they have broken. They have shown that they don't care about their alumni or their students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013816"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.melashri.net/micro/privacy-price/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sapphirebreeze:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;my dog ate my homework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mattmaroon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The settlement you get from a class action lawsuit has no relation to the value of the underlying tort. It is not, as an investor would say, a pricing event.&lt;p&gt;Everybody’s private information would be worth a different amount if you were talking sheer economic value. A poor persons would be very little, a rich person would be worth very much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constantcrying:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe my perspective on Universities is quite different, but I don&amp;#x27;t understand the complaints of the author.&lt;p&gt;This is a public University, they likely outsource some of their IT and somewhere a data breach happened. This data breach apparently affected all employees and students&amp;#x2F;former students. The faceless &amp;quot;they&amp;quot; the author is blaming in all likelihood was effected &lt;i&gt;more drastically&lt;/i&gt; than him.&lt;p&gt;The 30 dollars is not a payment for the data. It is a compensation for the damages, something which the author admits are likely zero, as previous data breaches already impacted him more drastically.&lt;p&gt;What should the university have done? 30 dollars seem reasonable for the damage caused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cpfohl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Class actions like this are opt in; by accepting the settlement you accepted the terms and lost your right to sue for a different (more appropriate to you) value.&lt;p&gt;Planet money did a a great segment on how these work and why America is set up this way. I learned a lot about it. You should definitely take a listen[1]. If you aren’t on Apple then search “What to do when you’re in a class action?” And find the podcast (not the summary article).&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;planet-money&amp;#x2F;id290783428?i=1000664159537" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;planet-money&amp;#x2F;id2907834...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recursivedoubts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think if you look at what it costs to purchase your personal information you will find it is worth far less.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baiac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The author thinks that $30 is an inappropriate amount, but does not suggest what he thinks the correct sum should be.&lt;p&gt;It is my opinion that, as with anything that can be copied infinitely for free, his (and my) personal information is worth $0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bmitch3020:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder how much more organizations would value PII if we could legally demand all of the PII of the executive officers for that same price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hollow-moe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Rembered that time when Ford estimated human life to not be worth enough in case of lawsuit to add a $5 piece to prevent their cars from exploding on rear impact. I love faceless capitalism.&lt;p&gt;Edit: iirc that was about $750&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArcHound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The issue is, that your personal info is valuable to only you. It also doesn&amp;#x27;t reflect character worth or personal worth.&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s how people gave their privacy away to apps - they&amp;#x27;ve realized this is the best deal they can get for it. Conversely, when the court tries to estimate what is the financial impact of such a leak, there&amp;#x27;s not much to base it off.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve just finished The Age of Surveillance Capitalism and it&amp;#x27;s ridiculous how Google et Al were able to profit from these scraps we gave them. So maybe the value could be higher?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eviks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; They will not take responsibility for their actions, and they will not compensate you for the damage they caused. They will just offer you a small amount of money and hope that you will forget about it.&lt;p&gt;Paying for a wrongful action is taking reponsibility and compensating. But also &amp;quot;for the damage they caused&amp;quot; - what&amp;#x27;s the damage if the info is already out there?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The basic problem is that they do not care about us.&lt;p&gt;True, of course, but the basic problem is different - &amp;quot;apology&amp;quot; costs more due to the way the legal system is set up, &amp;quot;nothing more&amp;quot;. Otherwise you&amp;#x27;d get your empty apologies left and right, though strang that you value that more than compensation. Empty words cost even less than $30 (unless, of course, there is a system to make them legally potentially cost more)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It would be interesting to see what calculations went into arriving at the number. They must have started with a large number that should be distributed to all students. Where did that large number come from? Some fund allocated for this kind of purpose? Some ransom that was demanded by the attackers, putting a value on the data? Some psychological tests that determined $30 is enough to keep the young folks from rebellion while not affecting future prospects for the university?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raesan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What I thought was most interesting was the statement at the very end: &amp;quot;The poetic nature of writing in grievance in Arabic is much more effective than in English.&amp;quot; Differences between languages are so interesting to me. Anyone here know Arabic and feel the same way as the author? What makes Arabic different in that sense?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kotaKat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reading investor reports is interesting as well, to see what companies think you&amp;#x27;re worth to them. Check out Roku&amp;#x27;s ARPU - it&amp;#x27;s something like $40 a year now per user in marketing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;knightscoop:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This same university which promised a life access to email address which they did not honor, ...&lt;p&gt;A tangent, but I had the same thing with my university. I wonder how common this is, and if google is the common thread...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.melashri.net/micro/privacy-price/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 11:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013816</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADHD and Monotropism (2023)</title>
      <link>https://monotropism.org/adhd/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://monotropism.org/adhd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013960</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jack Ma's family shifted wealth to UK after years-long 'disappearance'</title>
      <link>https://www.source-material.org/jack-ma-bought-uk-home-after-years-long-disappearance/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Billionaire’s wife bought London mansion as he reconciled with Chinese authorities The family of Chinese billionaire Jack Ma bought a £19. 5 million London mansion amid a rapprochement with Chinese authorities after years of scrutiny and political exile. Many have left China altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013633"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.source-material.org/jack-ma-bought-uk-home-after-years-long-disappearance/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;roenxi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The treatment of Ma compared to his equivalent in the US (probably Bezos or Musk?) might be one of the neatest illustrations of genuine ideological difference between the two countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comrade1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Something that&amp;#x27;s common for wealthy Chinese that live in the USA is to get a USA green card but not citizenship because china does not allow dual citizenship.  The ceo of a company my wife worked for does this - although that didn&amp;#x27;t stop him from being arrested (basically just disappeared) by the Chinese government for about a year a bit after the same happened with Ma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kiba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Real estate(the land, not the mansion) is a really good long term storage of wealth as it is fixed, finite, and doesn&amp;#x27;t depreciate in value except through market trend and it basically only go up as long as the economy itself grow.&lt;p&gt;However, this causes land speculation which drives the price of land up, and people do not want to develop properties because it would means investing in buildings which costs money to build and maintain and entails risk and ongoing effort.&lt;p&gt;The correct solution to this is a land value tax, which if implemented correctly, should drive down the price of land down to zero and force Jack Ma&amp;#x27;s family to either commit to actually investing in UK&amp;#x27;s economy or park their wealth elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.source-material.org/jack-ma-bought-uk-home-after-years-long-disappearance/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013633</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libpng 1.6.51: Four buffer overflow vulnerabilities fixed</title>
      <link>https://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2025/11/22/1</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Powered by blists - more mailing lists Please check out the Open Source Software Security Wiki, which is counterpart to this mailing list. Confused about mailing lists and their use. Read about mailing lists on Wikipedia and check out these guidelines on proper formatting of your messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013579"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2025/11/22/1'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lousken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;rust rewrite when?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;applied_heat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Affects back to version 1.6.0 released Feb 14, 2013&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2025/11/22/1</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46013579</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
