<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:22:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Valve to power up Steam devices</title>
      <link>https://www.igalia.com/2025/11/helpingvalve.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doing so requires a rock-solid Vulkan driver that can ensure correctness, eliminating major rendering bugs, while maintaining high performance. This is a very difficult combination to achieve, and yet that’s exactly what we’ve done for Valve with Mesa3D Turnip, a FOSS Vulkan driver for Qualcomm Adreno GPUs. “We implemented many Vulkan extensions and reviewed numerous others,” said Danylo Piliaiev, an engineer on the Graphics Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006616"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.igalia.com/2025/11/helpingvalve.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uejfiweun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The Steam Frame shows a lot of promise in terms of letting people play games on a massive virtual screen. But with the hardware, even more is possible. I hope they are working on a compatibility layer that allows 2D games to be rendered in 3D, like the 3D TV of the 2010s. In my opinion that would be a killer app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rpmisms:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s incredibly obvious that they&amp;#x27;re trying to make Steam Deck 2 ARM-based. That&amp;#x27;s the generational change Valve is waiting for.&lt;p&gt;This is gonna be fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jorvi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Really cool stuff! Especially nice to see the groundwork being laid for what could become very efficient handhelds, considering how much performance Apple&amp;#x27;s M-series and Qualcomm&amp;#x27;s Elite series with relatively few watts. Much better than AMD, Intel or Nvidia.&lt;p&gt;One nit: it&amp;#x27;s too bad Valve &amp;#x2F; Igalia choose to completely ignore the lessons from Bazzite.&lt;p&gt;Bazzite already runs a scheduler like LAVD, called BORE[0]. It would have saved them a lot of work to extend and improve that rather than invent the wheel again. I&amp;#x27;m not sure if Valve and Igalia are unaware of Bazzite and BORE or if this is a case of NIH.&lt;p&gt;[0]&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;firelzrd&amp;#x2F;bore-scheduler" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;firelzrd&amp;#x2F;bore-scheduler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dcdc123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nothing to contribute other than to say that article was an awesome read and now I wish I had the specific skills needed to work at Igalia. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;troupo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Igalia is a superhero company doing a lot of great work with surprisingly little fanfare.&lt;p&gt;Everytime their name pops up it&amp;#x27;s inevitably &amp;quot;oh some thankless extremely technical low level work leading to impressive&amp;#x2F;long-awaited features&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stavros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t play games almost ever, but I&amp;#x27;m going to buy all the products Valve releases soon, just to support their OSS efforts. They seem to be the only vendor that&amp;#x27;s opening stuff up, rather than locking it down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fidotron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This is a very difficult combination to achieve, and yet that’s exactly what we’ve done for Valve with Mesa3D Turnip, a FOSS Vulkan driver for Qualcomm Adreno GPUs.&lt;p&gt;Look at that. Something Qualcomm should have been doing.&lt;p&gt;Much credit to Valve for pushing that out as FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.igalia.com/2025/11/helpingvalve.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006616</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Remain Alive Also in a Dead Internet</title>
      <link>https://slavoj.substack.com/p/why-we-remain-alive-also-in-a-dead-954</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://slavoj.substack.com/p/why-we-remain-alive-also-in-a-dead-954</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008788</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How/why to sweep async tasks under a Postgres table</title>
      <link>https://taylor.town/pg-task</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just tell your customer they can continue with their goddamn day. Delight your customers with clear feedback. Remember, all your retry-loops have to happen somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007267"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://taylor.town/pg-task'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;morshu9001:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Never do RPCs during an xact like this! Fastest way to lock up your DB. I don&amp;#x27;t even mean at large scale. I&amp;#x27;ve been forced many times to set up two-phase commit. That way you also get more flexibility and visibility into what it&amp;#x27;s doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rgbrgb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re in TS&amp;#x2F;JS land, I like to use an open source version of this called graphile-worker [0].&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;worker.graphile.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;worker.graphile.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rictic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Missing from the article: how to communicate progress and failure to the user?&lt;p&gt;This is much more complicated with task queues. Doable still! But often skipped, because it&amp;#x27;s tempting to imagine that the backend will just handle the failure by retrying. But there are lots of kinds of failure that can happen.&lt;p&gt;The recipient&amp;#x27;s server doesn&amp;#x27;t accept the email. The recipient&amp;#x27;s domain name expired. Actually, we don&amp;#x27;t have an email address for that recipient at all.&lt;p&gt;The user has seen &amp;quot;got it, will do, don&amp;#x27;t worry about it&amp;quot; but if that email is time sensitive, they might want to know that it hasn&amp;#x27;t been sent yet, and maybe they should place a phone call instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stack_framer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I like slim and stupid servers, where each endpoint wraps a very dumb DB query.&lt;p&gt;I thought I was alone in this, but I build all my personal projects this way! I wish I could use this approach at work, but too many colleagues crave &amp;quot;engineering.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koolba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article says:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Never Handroll Your Own Two-Phase Commit&lt;p&gt;And then buried at the end:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; A few notable features of this snippet:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Limiting number of retries makes the code more complicated, but definitely worth it for user-facing side-effects like emails.&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t two-phase commit. This is lock the DB indefinitely while remote system is processing and pray we don&amp;#x27;t crash saving the transaction after it completes. That locked also eats up a database connection so your concurrency is limited by the size of your DB pool.&lt;p&gt;More importantly, if the email sends but the transaction to update the task status fails, it will try again. And again. Forever. If you&amp;#x27;re going to track retries it would have to be before you start the attempt. Otherwise the &amp;quot;update the attempts count&amp;quot; logic itself could fail and lead to more retries.&lt;p&gt;The real answer to all this is to use a provider that supports idempotency keys. Then when you can retry the action repeatedly without it actually happening again. My favorite article on this subject: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;brandur.org&amp;#x2F;idempotency-keys" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;brandur.org&amp;#x2F;idempotency-keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://taylor.town/pg-task</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007267</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brazil charges 31 people in major carbon credit fraud investigation</title>
      <link>https://news.mongabay.com/short-article/2025/11/brazil-charges-31-people-in-major-carbon-credit-fraud-investigation/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The police investigation confirmed that two REDD+ project areas were generating carbon credits at the same time they were being used to launder timber taken from other illegally deforested areas. Brazil police found that the Unitor and Fortaleza Ituxi REDD+ projects were being used to launder illegal timber while selling carbon credits. The Federal Police told Folha that three interconnected groups were involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007294"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://news.mongabay.com/short-article/2025/11/brazil-charges-31-people-in-major-carbon-credit-fraud-investigation/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cheschire:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Remember how people used to talk about the environment and stuff, back before AI made everyone turn a hard 180?&lt;p&gt;What place do carbon credits even have anymore in this economy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;worik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I get very frustrated by &amp;quot;carbon credits&amp;quot;. This is an example of criminal fraud.  But the whole idea is begging for fraud. It is a fraudulent concept from start to finish&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of the Catholic&amp;#x27;s concept of &amp;quot;indulgences&amp;quot;. Sin the sins, pay a fee, and go to heaven.&lt;p&gt;In this case the &amp;quot;sins&amp;quot;, and the sinners, are burning the world for profit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shrubble:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s laden with fraud everywhere, sadly. US regulators like SEC have no interest in auditing, from what I’ve seen.  “Spice must flow” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nebezb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People have been buying fake carbon credits for a long time. There’s very little incentive to validate the authenticity of the credit&amp;#x2F;offset. The press release is usually all the value they’re looking for.&lt;p&gt;I’ve only just now heard of someone getting in trouble for selling them. It’s about time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;staplers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Will they line these people up in the street and kill them like they did to 100+ people for a low-level drug dealer &amp;quot;sweep&amp;quot;?&lt;p&gt;Something tells me not. The global push toward hyper-violent policing feels one sided class wise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vkou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The police investigation confirmed that two REDD+ project areas were generating carbon credits at the same time they were being used to launder timber taken from other illegally deforested areas.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Both projects, which cover more than 140,000 hectares (around 350,000 acres), are located in the municipality of Lábrea in the south of Amazonas state. The area has been identified as one of the newest and most aggressive deforestation frontiers in the Brazilian Amazon.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; ...led by Élcio Aparecido Moço and José Luiz Capelasso.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; In 2017, Moço had been sentenced for timber laundering, but in 2019, another court overruled his sentencing. In 2019, he was also indicted for allegedly bribing two public officials.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s strange that a conman doesn&amp;#x27;t seem to be able to change his spots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.mongabay.com/short-article/2025/11/brazil-charges-31-people-in-major-carbon-credit-fraud-investigation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007294</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
