<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 01:54:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>I can build enterprise software but I can't charge for it</title>
      <link>https://gist.github.com/EchenD/8b211ebfa4941d2c5df7b526790b31aa</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent 18 months building an enterprise AI avatar platform that competes with Soul Machines ($70M funded, $50k+ setup fees for enterprise clients). This isn't the market for enterprise AI. Soul Machines has 100+ enterprise clients (Mercedes-Benz, Vodafone).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894569"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://gist.github.com/EchenD/8b211ebfa4941d2c5df7b526790b31aa'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;didip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone can build anything, it’s the selling that is hard. You need runways for momentum to even begin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SanjayMehta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;OP should try to move to another country. Maybe Dubai.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;renewiltord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tough. But I suppose it means the sanctions are working.&lt;p&gt;The shortest way out is island nation golden passport plus renunciation of Iranian citizenship plus incorporation in Dubai and then get going. Rough because startup cost is $250k. Well, you have a story to tell a VC. It&amp;#x27;ll be tough, though. None of the A listers will risk this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;g-b-r:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Off topic, but I&amp;#x27;ve been wondering for years about people pricing things with a 7 in the end (497$, 597$, 197$...)&lt;p&gt;Every &amp;quot;web marketing&amp;quot; person I ran into does it, it comes from that environment?&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s something considered to result in more sales, or maybe a way to signal that you&amp;#x27;re connected to some web marketing guru?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;petesergeant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could you move to UAE and incorporate there? Your wife’s medical qualifications are likely valid, you’ll be close to home, and there are places there it’s possible to live cheaply. As long as it’s a genuine Emirati company rather than a front for an Iranian one, you should be fine?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gverrilla:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hello friend,&lt;p&gt;Considering this all to be truthful, it seems you have fallen for the startup mythology - I know because I have been there too.&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can make it work, who knows, but the chances are slim - even more because of your nationality.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t all-in in this, protect yourself and your family.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t believe those hard-working startup stories, most of them in reality are really luck or contacts, nothing to do with hardwork, quality, strategy, etc. And there&amp;#x27;s people profiteering over believers like you...&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;#x27;t even comment on the irony of an iranian citizen asking for help from the Silicon Valley - when did these people help you or your country, ever????????&lt;p&gt;Best of luck&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cameldrv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Flagged.  Based on the ask (launder money for me to evade sanctions on Iran), and the ChatGPT generated comment replies from the OP, this appears to be some sort of scam.  There are a few different possible scams it could be, but it&amp;#x27;s using sympathy to become #1 on Hacker News and find marks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mhitza:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From some brief research.&lt;p&gt;The EU seem to have less strict sanctions against Iran, specifically for specific entities, people, and services. Telecommunication is one of those services.&lt;p&gt;In theory you could get hired in an EU company that doesn&amp;#x27;t deal with an US company (for example an EU-only payment provider. If such a thing exists. (One can only hope GNU Taler will be it some day)). Though the compliance requirements might not be easy and cost you a bit to get some layers involved and fill out paperwork together with someone you&amp;#x27;d convenie as your partner.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d pursue this avenue of research further if I&amp;#x27;d where you, or another country wherein the US sanctions aren&amp;#x27;t a real factor. Best of all would be if you&amp;#x27;d be able to emigrate and become a resident of a non sanctioned country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nrhrjrjrjtntbt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wonder if that is enough to get you a visa to a country where you can then launch?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kazinator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The AI scene is oversaturated. Every last huckster and shill is all AI this and AI that. Just standing out and getting noticed is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;move to canada; drop the iranian citizenship, and become active in anti-IRG groups.&lt;p&gt;youll be all set&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wseqyrku:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For starters, don&amp;#x27;t generate your pitch, brother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paxys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Go ahead. Talk to the avatar for 2 minutes. Ask it anything in English. Watch how it responds in real-time with synchronized lip movements and natural conversation. I&amp;#x27;ll be here when you get back.&lt;p&gt;Okay, but you linked to a generic landing page with a &amp;quot;Book a private demo&amp;quot; button. So what exactly does your product do? And why should anyone here be interested if you can&amp;#x27;t as much as post a video of it working?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iambateman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks for sharing this. I can’t legally help you either but your story was meaningful for me.&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of respect for Iranian folks and I hope the relations between our two countries can get better. Best of luck to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ankit_mishra:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;OP&amp;#x27;s account was made an hour ago and comments from it are suspiciously fast (and unnecessarily verbose).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;threads?id=echend"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;threads?id=echend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an obvious scam, I don&amp;#x27;t know why I wasted this time double checking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moomoo11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;scam. weaponized empathy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zacksiri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel for this guy, I really do.&lt;p&gt;I see comments like &amp;quot;is this a request to bypass sanctions&amp;quot; OR &amp;quot;he&amp;#x27;s iranian&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#x27;s remind ourselves of the following:&lt;p&gt;- First understand that he didn&amp;#x27;t choose to be born and raised in Iran.&lt;p&gt;- Second people grow up have families become attached to where they&amp;#x27;re born it&amp;#x27;s not easy to just &amp;#x27;pick up and leave&amp;#x27; moving to a new country is expensive and extremely difficult especially from countries like Iran.&lt;p&gt;- Third he&amp;#x27;s building something he believes in which is probably better than most people who live in privileged countries who sit around and do nothing.&lt;p&gt;To me this reads like a plea for help.&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#x27;s built something and showing it to the world, if someone likes it and wants to fund him &amp;#x2F; get him out of Iran, so he can pursue his dreams AND have the people who help him benefit along with him. I&amp;#x27;m sure he&amp;#x27;ll be all for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cantalopes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Man thats a lot of hard work and an impressive peoduct that is in my opinion very competitive in b2b. I wish it works out with the difficult situation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tomr75:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;use USD denominated stablecoins on a permissionless blockchain (any layer 2 ethereum network like arbritrum) or a ZK L2 ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurornis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Test it first: neoclerks.com&amp;#x2F;en&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Go ahead. Talk to the avatar for 2 minutes. Ask it anything in English. Watch how it responds in real-time with synchronized lip movements and natural conversation.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I&amp;#x27;ll be here when you get back.&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, there is no live demo. There is a button to &amp;quot;book a private demo&amp;quot;, but I can&amp;#x27;t find anything to try.&lt;p&gt;Second: Unfortunately, this is a request to partner with someone who will violate sanctions for this person. Anyone considering entertaining this offer should be very clear on that fact. Acting as a proxy to monetize a business in a sanctioned country is not a position you want to be in. You take the legal risk, the other party gets the proceeds (until sanctions catch up). Any investors looking at this arrangement would nope right out of the conversation as soon as any of this was discovered. Thoughts and feelings about sanctions aside, this is not a position you want to put yourself in.&lt;p&gt;If this is real then I feel sorry for the person, but given that this entire post is a direct ask for someone to violate international sanctions and the content of the website doesn&amp;#x27;t even match the description (no live demo) I think it&amp;#x27;s best to flag it. Would be sad if someone on HN felt guilty and got tricked into violating international sanctions over this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KomoD:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Go ahead. Talk to the avatar for 2 minutes. Ask it anything in English. Watch how it responds in real-time with synchronized lip movements and natural conversation.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s nothing.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The product works. You just tested it.&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#x27;t, there&amp;#x27;s nothing to try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ivraatiems:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am not a lawyer or diplomat or expert on trade, but I can make some general observations from an American&amp;#x2F;Western perspective:&lt;p&gt;First, the sanctions on Iran are such that any partnership with an Iranian person for business reasons is effectively impossible in the West, without the resources of a multi-million or billion-dollar company to circumvent them. The author says &amp;quot;I am not looking for anyone to bypass sanctions&amp;quot; but that is very obviously exactly what they are asking for.&lt;p&gt;Second, circumventing sanctions is illegal, and people regularly go to prison or are given massive monetary fines for this. OP, I don&amp;#x27;t question your motives, but you need to understand that people have literally gone to prison and lost their whole livelihoods for doing exactly what you are asking.&lt;p&gt;Therefore, posting this on a Western platform (Github) and advertising it on a Western message board (HN) is unlikely to help. I don&amp;#x27;t think the author&amp;#x27;s intentions are poor; I think they may simply not understand the intensity of the legal regime that makes working with them impossible.&lt;p&gt;There is also the matter of Westerners&amp;#x27; general opinions on Iran, which - general attitudes of multiculturalism and tolerance nonwithstanding - is typically quite negative. The sanctions didn&amp;#x27;t come from nowhere.&lt;p&gt;I would recommend the author look into partnerships with persons from countries that are more sympathetic to their situation. The ones with strong tech industries would be Russia, China, and India. Vietnam is another example of a country with some tech industry which also has mostly positive relationships with Western countries, these days. I realize this is not as attractive as the West, but there are good people even in places whose governments I may as a Westerner may not particularly like, and English is a lingua franca the world over. I&amp;#x27;d strongly recommend those places as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nickphx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do people actually want such a service? What part of interacting with a touch screen displaying an animated character, high end or luxury?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ravenical:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting definition of &amp;quot;photorealistic&amp;quot;. Link to the site in question: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;neoclerks.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;neoclerks.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;poly2it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this the best idea you could&amp;#x27;ve put your time on? Maybe I don&amp;#x27;t see the vision, but I have no idea who would by this or for what. AI&amp;#x2F;slop is cheap and luxury brands will only lean further away from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;avandekleut:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a technical founder I empathize with the authors situation and approach, but honestly spending that much time and energy on a product before even getting one sign up is a known failure mode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DiabloD3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He&amp;#x27;s Iranian. Github is most likely going to delete his account due to sanctions.&lt;p&gt;Weird to just announce that publicly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syspec:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Me: I built this insane 3D multilingual AI avatar platform with real-time conversation, full enterprise stack, 47 languages, and Unreal Engine&lt;p&gt;You: Can bypass US Treasury sanctions and open a Stripe account&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kevmo314:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t get it. I clicked the demo link but there’s nothing to try, only a home page with some AI generated images?&lt;p&gt;Even if this were legal it feels like a pitch for a scam…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lykahb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this a request to bypass the sanctions?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://gist.github.com/EchenD/8b211ebfa4941d2c5df7b526790b31aa</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894569</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X5.1 solar flare, G4 geomagnetic storm watch</title>
      <link>https://www.spaceweatherlive.com/en/news/view/593/20251111-x5-1-solar-flare-g4-geomagnetic-storm-watch.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 (R3-strong) solar flare peaked this morning at 10:04 UTC. More about that below. Thank you for reading this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893004"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.spaceweatherlive.com/en/news/view/593/20251111-x5-1-solar-flare-g4-geomagnetic-storm-watch.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drmpeg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A severe geomagnetic storm is starting now (November 12 0000Z). But it&amp;#x27;s from the previous X-flares (X1.7 and X1.2), not the X5.1 flare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sigmaprimus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;what effect if any will the solar flare emissions have on the new ish constellation style satellite networks? and or vice versa? EG would a shielded group or constellation provide a pathway for charge particles around the Earth?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aussieguy1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;looks like i&amp;#x27;ll be going out tonight&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nreilly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This has a pretty good view of the aurora now: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=hfF9bhaBuvw" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=hfF9bhaBuvw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meindnoch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Carrington event 2.0?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;superkuh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We won&amp;#x27;t know any actionable detail till about 1 hour before it arrives at Earth. That&amp;#x27;s when interplanetary coronal mass ejections actually have their magnetic field orientation and intensity measured by ACE and other satellites far out at the L1 lagrange point: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;services.swpc.noaa.gov&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;ace-mag-swepam-24-hour.gif" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;services.swpc.noaa.gov&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;ace-mag-swepam-24-hour...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you see the red line on this plot^, the interplanetary magnetic field, be more than -10 nanotesla for about 4 hours then there&amp;#x27;s a good chance of lower than normal latitude aurora. Negative means the magnetic field is pointing downwards out of the ecliptic plane of the solar system and this is the most energetically favorable orientation for reconnecting CME magnetic field lines with Earth&amp;#x27;s magnetic field lines and letting solar particles&amp;#x2F;energy in.&lt;p&gt;It can be 20nT positive (upwards) magnetic field with intense density and high velocity but still be a non-event aurora-wise just because energy is delivered to the Earth&amp;#x27;s ring currents at 10x slower rate than if it&amp;#x27;s pointing downwards.&lt;p&gt;None of the WSA-ENLIL or related predictive models take into consideration the magnetic field orientation of iCMEs because it&amp;#x27;s really hard to know from remote observations. They can be thought of as warnings to pay attention to the ACE L1 measurements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rpcope1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can see the real time magnetic field change when it hits: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dasi.barlow.cpi.com&amp;#x2F;dashboard" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dasi.barlow.cpi.com&amp;#x2F;dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snitzr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Are we doomed by the next Carrington Event?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fghorow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[1] is a real-time forecast for the auroral oval. See if you are in with a chance. Clear Skies!&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.spaceweatherlive.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;auroral-activity&amp;#x2F;auroral-oval.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.spaceweatherlive.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;auroral-activity&amp;#x2F;auroral...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brcmthrowaway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could this destroy the ISS?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arainach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; could impact our planet as early as 16 UTC on 12 November&lt;p&gt;Is that 16:00 or 00:16?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abujazar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Also: 100 % cloud cover in basically all of Northern Europe :&amp;#x2F; Iceland is probably the place to be for the aurora show!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.spaceweatherlive.com/en/news/view/593/20251111-x5-1-solar-flare-g4-geomagnetic-storm-watch.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893004</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I didn't reverse-engineer the protocol for my blood pressure monitor in 24 hours</title>
      <link>https://james.belchamber.com/articles/blood-pressure-monitor-reverse-engineering/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;"Oh, no, that will just stress you out. My blood pressure seems to be encoded in this packet. that looks like a blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893095"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://james.belchamber.com/articles/blood-pressure-monitor-reverse-engineering/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deevus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The reason Bottles&amp;#x2F;WINE doesn&amp;#x27;t work with USB devices like that is likely because WINE isn&amp;#x27;t supposed to support kernel level device access. It&amp;#x27;s for running programs and just fakes enough for that to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;broken-kebab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;I&amp;#x27;m pretty sure that reverse-engineering this will be good for my blood pressure.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I feel healthier after reading this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;devinvs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;my best shot at it:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  year:   bits 0-6 reversed
  month:  bits 6-10 reversed
  hour:   bits 13-18
  minute: bits 18-24
  day:    bits 24-29 (maybe reversed)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
unsatisfyingly I don&amp;#x27;t have any idea what the gaps are or why parts need to be reversed, so i could be wrong. With the data from the post:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  y  mo d  h  mi
  25 11 10 11 3
  25 11 10 11 31
  25 11 10 12 1
  25 11 10 12 35
  25 11 10 13 0
  25 11 10 13 31
  25 11 10 13 31
  25 11 10 14 0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;khannn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Turns out that when you check someone&amp;#x27;s blood pressure after giving them an injection, it&amp;#x27;s higher than normal.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Nick-Cage-You-Dont-Say.png&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;supportengineer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not a single comment in here about Bottles - what exactly is it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pinkmuffinere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I tried feeding a lot of this into various Als (Kagi gives you access to a few with a nice interface) and I found that they mostly were stupid in ways that made me think&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;stupid in ways that made me think&amp;quot; is (IMO) a really good summary of how AI is useful, as well as its pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ck2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have three blood pressure cuffs&lt;p&gt;They all give me different numbers, by a lot sometimes&lt;p&gt;btw you think they ever clean those devices?&lt;p&gt;you think healthy people go to pharmacies?&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;#x27;t even touch the signature pen, imagine what&amp;#x27;s on that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arch-TK:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Would be fun to see the traffic dumps, I would love to try to figure out the protocol offline with them.&lt;p&gt;Just spent half a day reverse engineering a Windows virtual printer driver (for work) and had to force myself to stop spending the rest of the day doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arainach:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Testing blood pressure &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; a shot seems weird.&lt;p&gt;I have high blood pressure, managed with a low dose of medication.  I&amp;#x27;ve had plenty of advice from my PCP and other actual doctors on how to take blood pressure - how to sit, how long to sit still, how to position your arm, etc.&lt;p&gt;It is remarkable how many medically-adjacent professionals are bad at this.  My dentist starts my sessions with a blood pressure reading - theoretically in case they have to numb me or something, probably because it&amp;#x27;s billable or whatever.  What always seems to happen is that I get in for my appointment (driving, which can be stressful even if I&amp;#x27;m not running late), they take me to the chair within 2 minutes max, immediately put some sort of wrist cuff on me, hold my arm at an angle that is not what most actual doctors have recommended to me and take a reading that is often high enough to surprise both the hygenist and myself.&lt;p&gt;The thing is that I have two sufficiently-calibrated Omron units, one at home and one at the office.  I take my blood pressure often enough to know what it usually is (and my real doctor takes it at least twice a year).  That is to say that no, it&amp;#x27;s not 200&amp;#x2F;160 or whatever nonsense the dentist thinks it is and you&amp;#x27;d think that with a very small amount of reading they&amp;#x27;d know better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lifeisstillgood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So I did something similar (well less cool), but as old Software devs start finding our bodies don’t work as well after a while we will see more and more of this sort of “taking control”&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mikado-aktiia.readthedocs.io&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mikado-aktiia.readthedocs.io&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;latest&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cestith:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Regarding white coat hypertension, the shot isn’t always necessary. Some people’s blood pressure just goes up from the stress of the clinical setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://james.belchamber.com/articles/blood-pressure-monitor-reverse-engineering/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893095</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four strange places to see London's Roman Wall</title>
      <link>https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/11/odd-places-to-see-londons-roman-wall.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The plaque confirms that the stones here are a continuation of the wall seen (much more clearly) outside. Perhaps the best thing about this bit of wall is that you can walk through it. Stuff that, there's an actual Roman Wall back here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893795"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/11/odd-places-to-see-londons-roman-wall.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zeristor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I worked for Lloyd’s Register for a spell, and their cafeteria was where the Vine Street building is, just got used to eating lunch there by the bits of wall everyday for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trenchpilgrim:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Note this is about the City of London, an entity much smaller and older than the modern city known as London. It&amp;#x27;s land area is about 3 km^2.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;City_of_London" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;City_of_London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Title should probably read &amp;quot;the City of London&amp;quot; rather than &amp;quot;London&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hodgesrm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For another interesting mix of new and ancient, check out the Serdica metro station in Sofia, Bulgaria. [0] It&amp;#x27;s fully inside an excavated Roman-era ruin. Very cool!&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Serdika_Metro_Station" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Serdika_Metro_Station&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jen729w:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For more of this &lt;i&gt;sort&lt;/i&gt; of thing, check out the Old Structures Engineering blog. Don does a post a day, day in, day out -- so obviously some are more detailed than others. I enjoy having it in my feed.&lt;p&gt;Recent examples:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;oldstructures.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;24&amp;#x2F;not-quite-a-tunnel&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;oldstructures.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;24&amp;#x2F;not-quite-a-tunnel&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;oldstructures.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;21&amp;#x2F;relieved&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;oldstructures.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;21&amp;#x2F;relieved&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tom_alexander:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; ground level then was a few metres lower than now&lt;p&gt;What?! That&amp;#x27;s huge. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ipnon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not bad engineering to make it through a handful of civil wars, a Blitz, and a couple thousand V-1 rockets mostly intact. You have to wonder how long all the steel and concrete that&amp;#x27;s been laid around the Thames from our civilization will last.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Architectural Digest has a good video of the Roman Wall and other Ancient Roman history in london: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=j_-JnvuAeVI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=j_-JnvuAeVI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulRobinson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The Museum of London site (now closed as they prepare to move to their new site, coincidentally near the AWS HQ), and there was a window you could look down on part of the wall, which you can also see from the other side of the road near Barbican. I won&amp;#x27;t give directions, as that seems futile anywhere near Barbican, but I had only just thought about how weird it is that there is wall at Tower Hill, and wall at Barbican - they can&amp;#x27;t be the same run of wall as it was built, can they? That&amp;#x27;d be immense...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/11/odd-places-to-see-londons-roman-wall.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893795</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>.NET MAUI Is Coming to Linux and the Browser, Powered by Avalonia</title>
      <link>https://avaloniaui.net/blog/net-maui-is-coming-to-linux-and-the-browser-powered-by-avalonia</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is the Avalonia MAUI Backend. At its core, the Avalonia MAUI Backend enables you to keep your MAUI codebase while replacing the rendering layer with Avalonia. Why Is Avalonia Building a Backend for MAUI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893986"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://avaloniaui.net/blog/net-maui-is-coming-to-linux-and-the-browser-powered-by-avalonia'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 18 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9cb14c1ec0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ok, finally catching up to Kotlin Multiplatform Compose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;textlapse:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is awesome… but:
On the Web, is Avalonia using Skia to render inside a Skia Canvas?&lt;p&gt;**insert inception meme here**&lt;p&gt;Joking aside: this points to MSFT moving away from the whole Mono&amp;#x2F;Maui investments and into Aspire or whatever they call it. Without MSFT backing this I am not sure if there is much more future left for MAUI (or dotnet on mobile in general).&lt;p&gt;Avalonia is great though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;binary132:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why does everything need to have a soulless mascot now?  It’s offputting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tylerchilds:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If React is what’s powering the start menu now, I’m more curious about why Maui doesn’t power the start menu.&lt;p&gt;.NET Maui running on windows seems like a more logical first step to prove the organization buys their own dogfood.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhyNotHugo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A toolkit announcing “Linux support” is pretty ambiguous. Does it mean Xorg support? Wayland support? Framebuffer support? The announcement provides no clue about this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;maxrmk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Took more than a minute to load on my macbook. Ouch!&lt;p&gt;I really love C# and the .net ecosystem, but they just haven&amp;#x27;t made it work for web.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mattfrommars:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the .NET ecosystem, I have noticed people to shame .NET MAUI because Microsoft themselves don&amp;#x27;t use this framework - Microsoft Team is built on Electron and not MAUI.&lt;p&gt;Why build a product on MAUI when Microsoft aren&amp;#x27;t too sure about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skrig:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know if it has since improved, but .NET MAUI was really, really rough when I created a mobile app for my employer last year. I&amp;#x27;m talking basic things - changing basic colors on the toolbar (1), putting non-text content inside a button (2), basic trigger behavior (3), to list a few. Not to mention that .NET UI has been years behind on hot-reload and developer tooling. Additionally, It was a fight to keep our app performant. The XAML compiler is a step in the right direction, but we had relatively simple views (in the dozens of components) absolutely tanking our FPS. I know there is probably some of my skill issue in there, but when I find basic things taking hours to optimize that I wouldn&amp;#x27;t even think about in React, I start to wonder about the framework. I spent a lot of time creating PRs on .NET MAUI but their team appears quite small and overloaded. I wish them the best - they&amp;#x27;re some talented folks, but I don&amp;#x27;t envy their job.&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t help but think of Joel Spolsky&amp;#x27;s Things You Should Never Do (5) - the transition from Xamarin to .NET MAUI feels like a very similar mistake to Netscape. All of the battle tested Xamarin code, documentation, community examples, packages, etc. is now dead and has to be converted over to .NET MAUI.&lt;p&gt;On top of that, XAML just doesn&amp;#x27;t do it for me - having to deal with code-behind, MVVM view models, custom converters, and the actual XAML files themselves is insane for what is usually just a a single file in JS. The fact that you need to write a &amp;quot;InvertedBoolConverter&amp;quot; (4) just to flip a boolean is the most Microsoft thing ever. MAUI feels like it&amp;#x27;s designed just to keep a large development team busy. I&amp;#x27;m not joking, we have a 42 line file that&amp;#x27;s only purpose is to flip booleans for XAML views.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re a C# shop so it was nice to share our common C# with our desktop application, but I don&amp;#x27;t think it was worth it in the end. Sure JS has its problems, but I&amp;#x27;ll take those problems any day over MAUI.&lt;p&gt;I hope Avalonia can fix .NET MAUI - it&amp;#x27;d be a massive kudos to them if they can smooth it over, but I can&amp;#x27;t say I&amp;#x27;d willingly rely on this project long term.&lt;p&gt;1 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;15612" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;15612&lt;/a&gt;
2 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;8191" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;8191&lt;/a&gt;
3 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;15655" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;15655&lt;/a&gt;
4 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;learn.microsoft.com&amp;#x2F;en-us&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;communitytoolkit&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;converters&amp;#x2F;inverted-bool-converter" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;learn.microsoft.com&amp;#x2F;en-us&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;communitytoolkit&amp;#x2F;ma...&lt;/a&gt;
5 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.joelonsoftware.com&amp;#x2F;2000&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;06&amp;#x2F;things-you-should-never-do-part-i&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.joelonsoftware.com&amp;#x2F;2000&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;06&amp;#x2F;things-you-should-...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;16965" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;pull&amp;#x2F;16965&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OsrsNeedsf2P:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not to be confused with the MauiKit[0], the cross platform UI toolkit that had the name first[1]&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mauikit.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mauikit.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;
[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;35" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dotnet&amp;#x2F;maui&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;35&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arkensaw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In case anyone is confused&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Using .NET MAUI, you can develop apps that can run on Android, iOS, macOS, and Windows from a single shared code-base.&lt;p&gt;This new development adds Linux and Browser to that list.&lt;p&gt;I recently tried out .NET MAUI to see how easy it was to build a hello world app. It was quite messy getting it setup on Mac but eventually I got a simple hello world app working. Nice to use XAML again after all these years. I always liked it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coffeeaddict1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; We are collaborating with the Flutter team at Google to bring Impeller, their GPU first renderer, to .NET. That work is already in progress and as it lands, the MAUI backend will inherit those gains.&lt;p&gt;Interesting, I wonder how good Impeller is and if it&amp;#x27;s actually better than the new Graphite backend of Skia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;labrador:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Three apprecitions:&lt;p&gt;1) In today&amp;#x27;s American political climate I think it&amp;#x27;s appropriate to express appreciation for immigrants to like Miguel de Icaza who dragged Microsoft kicking and screaming into cross platform .NET and is the godfather of .NET Maui&lt;p&gt;2) As someone who came up developing desktop apps for Windows and Mac, I never liked developing web applications. There was so much lacking, but now developing web apps is becoming like developing desktop apps. Now you get&amp;#x2F;put your data from HTTP calls instead of file system and database calls or with Blazor and SignalR you don&amp;#x27;t even have to think about those. This may seem obvious to younger programmers today, but it would have seemed like magic back in 2004 when Dymanic HTML and Ajax (both Microsoft) were being invented.&lt;p&gt;3) I&amp;#x27;m grateful Microsoft has changed their old ways to be a forward thinking company. They still have problems that any GIANT, Inc. organization has, but let&amp;#x27;s not forget how far they&amp;#x27;ve come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imcritic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there anything we can do to stop it? Or will it come anyway?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;judah:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is interesting for sure. Kudos for bringing this capability to the web!&lt;p&gt;One issue the demos reveal is, it doesn&amp;#x27;t _feel_ like the web. That is, I can&amp;#x27;t hit Ctrl+F to find text on a page. I can&amp;#x27;t select text with my cursor. I can&amp;#x27;t copy the address of a hyperlink. On my phone, I can&amp;#x27;t hard press on an image and share it to others. Screen readers can&amp;#x27;t handle it. I can&amp;#x27;t press a shortcut key to make everything larger.&lt;p&gt;These all may seem pedantic, but they contribute to the feeling &amp;quot;this is not the real web.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This is the same problem with Java applets in the late &amp;#x27;90s, Flash and Silverlight in the early 2000s. They are islands of richness within a web page, but those islands are, well, opaque to browsers, search engines, and virtually all web tooling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sylens:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;MAUI has felt like a barebones project for years. Forgive me if I don&amp;#x27;t believe this is the beginning of more robust support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;js4ever:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Too little, too late. Desktop apps are mostly dead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SigmundA:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Avalonia is also working towards using the new Flutter rendering backend Impeller which is being used to replace Skia, which is used by Chrome for rendering, turtles all the way down:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;avaloniaui.net&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;avalonia-partners-with-google-s-flutter-t-eam-to-bring-impeller-rendering-to-net" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;avaloniaui.net&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;avalonia-partners-with-google-s-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mwkaufma:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My kingdom for a UI toolkit that can be used to make real CAD programs, and not yet-more things that just look like webviews and could just be a webpage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://avaloniaui.net/blog/net-maui-is-coming-to-linux-and-the-browser-powered-by-avalonia</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893986</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heroku Support for .NET 10</title>
      <link>https://www.heroku.com/blog/support-for-dotnet-10-lts-what-developers-need-know/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NET 10 apps on Heroku, with buildpack support for new SDK features like file-based apps,. slnx solution files, and more. Zero-config deployment with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893646"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.heroku.com/blog/support-for-dotnet-10-lts-what-developers-need-know/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mythz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How does running on expensive clouds become newsworthy?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bastawhiz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I suppose congrats to Salesforce for inventing the most expensive way to run .Net 10?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cultofmetatron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I lament what could have been with heroku. I did some back of the envelope calculations for what it would have cost for my own startup to run on it and it came out to significantly more than what it costs us on aws INCLUDING our dedicated devops guy. They really killed its utility for anything bigger than a hobby project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.heroku.com/blog/support-for-dotnet-10-lts-what-developers-need-know/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 22:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893646</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Nietzsche Matters in the Age of Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://cacm.acm.org/blogcacm/why-nietzsche-matters-in-the-age-of-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cacm.acm.org/blogcacm/why-nietzsche-matters-in-the-age-of-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894588</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Department of War just shot the accountants and opted for speed</title>
      <link>https://steveblank.com/2025/11/11/the-department-of-war-just-shot-the-accountants-and-opted-for-speed/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But the DoW acquisition system was impenetrable to startups. We needed an acquisition system that could deliver needed things faster. Reminder: What Did Our Acquisition System Look Like Until Last Week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887699"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://steveblank.com/2025/11/11/the-department-of-war-just-shot-the-accountants-and-opted-for-speed/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 24 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celloductor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;‘Two organizations ought to be very concerned – China and the defense prime contractors.’&lt;p&gt;the department was not built with a single country as their focus, and their target will come and go with the times. would have read the whole article the blatant bias is off putting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rpmisms:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Prima Facie: probably good. The existing system is pure and simple money laundering, the legendary $900 toilet seat is absurd and this seems to be a step away from the supply-chain-for-everything system in place currently. I believe the defense budget could be cut in half with &lt;i&gt;increased&lt;/i&gt; capability, at least in theory. There&amp;#x27;s that much cruft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;parsimo2010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I skimmed this and want everyone to be aware of the danger in articles like this- it sounds like the author is knowledgeable but there are some real conceptual problems.  I’ll list a few so that maybe you won’t read this and think that it’s time to jump into defense contracting. Before I start I’ll state that I’m a statistics professor but also  worked in acquisitions for the USAF for 10 years, which is apparently 10 years more experience than the author has. Not to denigrate the author’s service in Vietnam, but it looks like he got out and jumped into Silicon Valley and never actually worked in government acquisitions, all his experience seems to be from the side of the contractor. If you’re looking for a tl;dr (or a BLUF), it’s that nothing has actually changed.&lt;p&gt;Issue 1: “using fast-track acquisition processes, rather than the cumbersome existing Federal Acquisition Regulations.” This is just plain wrong. The FAR always applies. It has special considerations for buying COTS products, but you’re still required to follow the FAR.&lt;p&gt;Issue 2: “Instead of buying custom-designed weapons, the DoW will prioritize buying off-the-shelf things that already exist” this isn’t something that Hegseth thought up, it has been a priority since at least the late 2000s, it’s in my FAM training material. The issue is that there are no COTS fighter jets or tanks. So we might prioritize COTS but the big ticket items are going to be custom.&lt;p&gt;Issue 3: (paraphrasing) “We’ve created PAEs, and there so much different than the clunky PEOs!” They actually sound like almost the exact same thing to me. The General Officer, whatever you call him, might notice a few different people showing up to his meetings. He’s still calling the shots. There is a slight difference that we seem to be trimming the number of portfolios, which means that each GO will have a few more programs to be responsible for.&lt;p&gt;Issue 4: (paraphrasing) “The PAEs will be able to trade cost, schedule, and performance!” This has literally always been the only job of acquisition. This isn’t new.&lt;p&gt;Issue 5: “Companies selling to the DoW previously had to comply with the impenetrable DFAR and FAR – the Defense and Federal Acquisition Regulations – with over 5,000 pages of complex rules. … 
Now the DoW is telling PAEs to toss those and use Non-FAR regulations like OTAs (Other Transaction Authorities).” I researched options for OTAs for my program director during the Biden administration. They are a great way to do research and possibly even get a prototype made with significant participation by a non-traditional contractor. Unfortunately you can’t get anything mass produced under an OTA, so it allows you to speed by without a contract until you actually need to order a production run, and then the FAR applies. So any contractor that hopes to get a big order has to be planning for FAR compliance during development anyway. The profit isn’t in the prototype.&lt;p&gt;“Weapons Will Be Able to Talk to Each Other” Yup, we’ve had that one since at least the late 2000s. This is just rewording the “Net-ready KPP” that all major systems have to meet. Modular open systems aren’t new. (Okay, a few years ago this was downgraded from a KPP, but literally all modern weapons systems are still networked on common standards).&lt;p&gt;“To retrain&amp;#x2F;reeducate contracting and acquisition officers, the “Defense Acquisition University” will become the “Warfighting Acquisition University.” Fine.  I’ll start using the word sex instead of gender and I’ll start sprinkling the word “merit” in my reports. It doesn’t change the end product.&lt;p&gt;“In JCIDS’ place the Secretary of War created three new organizations…” Holy shit, I thought we were streamlining this process! You cut off one dysfunctional organization and three grew in its place! Is this Hegseth or the Hydra?&lt;p&gt;Anyway, nothing has actually changed until Congress changes the laws that we have to follow. Until then it’s all window dressing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Havoc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;DoW will prioritize buying off-the-shelf things that already exist&lt;p&gt;Hey Hegseth. You could use SAP - that&amp;#x27;s off the shelf &amp;amp; I&amp;#x27;m reliably informed by an army of consultants that they can customize it to fit the exacting needs of the department of war!&lt;p&gt;(psst China - if I pull this off you better slide me a couple billion as thanks)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tehjoker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We don’t need more weapons. We also don’t have real adversaries, that’s war propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dgoodell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think we use the same PPBE process at NASA. Many of the systems and procedures that NASA uses are are defense-derived. If it&amp;#x27;s anything like what we do, then it&amp;#x27;s a total mess and we mostly just go through the motions with it, knowing it doesn&amp;#x27;t actually reflect reality and it&amp;#x27;s kind of a waste of time for everybody.&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;#x27;s risky to assume that scrapping a crappy system will result in things being better. The current shitty system was almost certainly the result of scrapping and replacing something else that had some problems.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, hopefully this works well, because we&amp;#x27;ll probably end up copying it at NASA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aussieguy1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Get ready for the Department Of Corruption&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;homeonthemtn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This reads like a propaganda piece. (Cautiously) Great that we&amp;#x27;re attempting modernization, but maybe don&amp;#x27;t huff the press release like a stick of finely aged glue&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hizonner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The United States does not have a &amp;quot;Department of War&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stackskipton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone who has some familiarity with this process, just like safety regulations are written in blood, Federal Acquisition rules are written in misuse of money, sometimes criminally.&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have swung too much towards the bureaucrats but I&amp;#x27;m not sure throwing out everything is solution to the issue.&lt;p&gt;Move fast works great when it&amp;#x27;s B2B software and failures means stock price does not go up. It&amp;#x27;s not so great when brand new jet acts up and results in crashes.&lt;p&gt;Oh yea, F-35 was built with move fast, they rolled models off the production line quickly, so Lockheed could get more money, but it looks like whole &amp;quot;We will fix busted models later&amp;quot; might have been more expensive. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;henning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The Pentagon is a giant grifting and fraud machine, that&amp;#x27;s why they can&amp;#x27;t ever pass a financial audit. New changes to how the grifting works from the pedophile rapist grifter-in-chief who is hoping we forget the files showing how he is a child rapist will change nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;awwaiid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was very confused until I realized the author was Steve Blank not Steve Klabnik.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chiph:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Design For Rapid Scale In a Crisis&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I think Anduril (Palmer Luckey and other founders) is doing right is designing for manufacturability. The invasion of Ukraine has shown that future conflicts will use up weapons at a very high pace. And that the US capability to build them at the rate needed to sustain conflict isn&amp;#x27;t there anymore. But that one thing that could help is making them easier to build. (the decline of US manufacturing is a related but separate topic)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M95D:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Remember Fat Leonard? This time there&amp;#x27;s going to be more than one.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Fat_Leonard_scandal" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Fat_Leonard_scandal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mcphage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The DoW is being redesigned to now operate at the speed of Silicon Valley, delivering more, better, and faster. Our warfighters will benefit from the innovation and lower cost of commercial technology, and the nation will once again get a military second to none.&lt;p&gt;So move fast and break things, and now the thing we’re breaking is our national defense?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pragmatic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So fast forward five years and 50% of our war materials are produced in foreign countries?&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#x27;t help but believe this is going to weaken our war footing because the dumbest people in the room are behind it. Thirsty Pete does not inspire confidence in the Department of War Thunder.&lt;p&gt;I mean on the surface it sounds good, but LEAN is why we had no PPE on hand during covid.&lt;p&gt;In order to have off the shelf supplies we are going have an active international arms market by definition. Is this what we want?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;troelsSteegin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A big assumption with this change is that the &amp;quot;Modular Open Systems Approach&amp;quot; (MOSA) [0] [1] will be adequate for integrating new systems developed and acquired under this &amp;quot;fast track&amp;quot;. MOSA appears to be about 6 years old as a mandate [2] and is something that big contractors - SAIC, BAI, Palantir [3] - talk about. But, 6 years seems brand new in this sector. I&amp;#x27;d be curious to see if LLM&amp;#x27;s have leverage for MOSA software system integrations.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;breakingdefense.com&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;modular-open-systems-architecture&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;breakingdefense.com&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;modular-open-systems-archite...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.dsp.dla.mil&amp;#x2F;Programs&amp;#x2F;MOSA&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.dsp.dla.mil&amp;#x2F;Programs&amp;#x2F;MOSA&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.govinfo.gov&amp;#x2F;app&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;USCODE-2016-title10&amp;#x2F;USCODE-2016-title10-subtitleA-partIV-chap144B-subchapI-sec2446a" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.govinfo.gov&amp;#x2F;app&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;USCODE-2016-title10&amp;#x2F;USCO...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.palantir.com&amp;#x2F;implementing-mosa-with-software-defined-systems-integration-4882b12f74ce" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.palantir.com&amp;#x2F;implementing-mosa-with-software-de...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thatguymike:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Based on this article alone, I can believe this is a good thing. The US military suffers incredibly from its monopsony position and without a doubt will get a heavy wakeup call (read: dead young people) next time it has to fight a real war. In addition the army should be the most accountable and results oriented branch of government, since it’s the only one that’s actively oppositional. If we can’t fix procurement there then what hope do we have for the rest of government?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fnord77:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel uneasy about the govt taking the &amp;quot;move fast and break things&amp;quot; approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SirFatty:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Department of Defense... unless Congress changes the name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zzless:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Army PIT? Ah, this is not a good name...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giraffe_lady:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Embarrassing regurgitation of propaganda. This is basically the military DOGE. Are these systems dysfunctional in some ways, could well-intended sweeping reforms improve them? Sure, maybe, I don&amp;#x27;t know much about it.&lt;p&gt;Is that what&amp;#x27;s happening here? No, this a way to get the existing functions out from under the oversight and constraints of acquisition laws to reduce friction for corruption and war profiteering.&lt;p&gt;If you fell for DOGE don&amp;#x27;t fall for this too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sebmellen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Out of all of the hires of this new administration, Hegseth is the most surprisingly competent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sd9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;More weapons more quickly. This is what I want.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure they will be used for good.&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2F;s&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure there are good reasons for this, and the approach doesn&amp;#x27;t seem totally unreasonable, to be fair. I&amp;#x27;m just personally woefully unequipped to understand how to deploy weapons humanely and morally, and naively think less weapons is better. Thankfully there are adults in the room making these decisions for me...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://steveblank.com/2025/11/11/the-department-of-war-just-shot-the-accountants-and-opted-for-speed/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:34:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887699</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
