<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:29:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>OpenMW 0.50.0 Released – open-source Morrowind reimplementation</title>
      <link>https://openmw.org/2025/openmw-0-50-0-released/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openmw.org/2025/openmw-0-50-0-released/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846090</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta projected 10% of 2024 revenue came from scams</title>
      <link>https://sherwood.news/tech/meta-projected-10-of-2024-revenue-came-from-scams-and-banned-goods-reuters/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Per the report, Meta internal projections from late last year said that 10% of the company’s total 2024 revenue would come from scammy ads and sales of banned goods — which works out to $16 billion. The cost of lost revenue from clamping down on the scams was weighed against the cost of fines from regulators. Meta spokesperson Andy Stone told Reuters the documents were a “selective view” of internal enforcement: “We aggressively fight fraud and scams because people on our platforms don’t want this content, legitimate advertisers don’t want it, and we don’t want it either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845772"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://sherwood.news/tech/meta-projected-10-of-2024-revenue-came-from-scams-and-banned-goods-reuters/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 24 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;podgorniy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What a business&amp;#x2F;ethical dilemma ~not~ to solve&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stusmall:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Once I got an Instagram ad for buying ketamine that just linked to a telegram channel.  They didn&amp;#x27;t even bother being coy or using mispelling or slang.  A simple keyword search to flag for more review would have caught it.  I can&amp;#x27;t even wrap my head around what internal controls exist when something like that makes it out to users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[dupe] Earlier on source: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45834840"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45834840&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dkdcio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;ban digital advertisement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffbee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10% scams is bush league rookie stats. They gotta pump that up to play in the same league as Nextdoor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noaidi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder if the government and lawmakers would care if 10% of my income came from selling heroin...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pessimizer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That&amp;#x27;s a quarter to a third of its entire margin. And that&amp;#x27;s what it admits to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samlinnfer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A new car built by my company leaves somewhere travelling at 60 mph. The rear differential locks up. The car crashes and burns with everyone trapped inside. Now, should we initiate a recall? Take the number of vehicles in the field, A, multiply by the probable rate of failure, B, multiply by the average out-of-court settlement, C. A times B times C equals X. If X is less than the cost of a recall, we don&amp;#x27;t do one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Havoc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Meta is cooked. It&amp;#x27;s not just scam portion - their entire strategy is in trouble&lt;p&gt;FB - nobody I know actively uses it anymore.&lt;p&gt;Insta - is being overrun with AI slop and given meta&amp;#x27;s stated goal of adding more AI interactions on their platforms I doubt they&amp;#x27;ll even try to get a grip on it let alone succeed&lt;p&gt;Whatsapp &amp;amp; FB messenger - some use but has zero moat over other messengers. It&amp;#x27;s a completely fungible service in a space that has fractured across many providers.&lt;p&gt;VR&amp;#x2F;meta&amp;#x2F;AI&amp;#x2F;etc - they keep trying. Maybe one day&lt;p&gt;...that leaves their adtech which only works due to their invasive tracking...that is directly dependent on their other properties succeeding: Their targeting edge comes directly from front row seats tracking users behaviour on their platforms. No users, no insights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jm4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If my company inadvertently made money from scams, I would try to make the victims whole or donate that money. It&amp;#x27;s so scummy that they sit around waiting to be fined. It&amp;#x27;s just plain stupid management to document this in emails and not also document a good faith attempt to make it right. I always assume my emails could be made public after my entire mailbox was subpoenaed in a lawsuit my employer was involved in and I was deposed to answer questions about email threads and source code comments from years ago. (I didn&amp;#x27;t do anything wrong personally, but my employer most likely did.) If I&amp;#x27;m going to discuss something that could make me or the company look bad, I&amp;#x27;m sure as hell going to write it in a way that&amp;#x27;s defensible when it gets out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IronyMan100:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If i Look at all the finfluences and &amp;quot;get thin in 30h with my cale diet eBook&amp;quot;-influencer, i though it was substantially more than 10%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bjourne:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; “We aggressively fight fraud and scams because people on our platforms don’t want this content, legitimate advertisers don’t want it, and we don’t want it either.”&lt;p&gt;I wonder if those who market illegal Israeli settlements counts as &amp;quot;legitimate advertisers&amp;quot;: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aljazeera.com&amp;#x2F;features&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;3&amp;#x2F;31&amp;#x2F;meta-profits-as-ads-promote-illegal-israeli-settlements-in-west-bank" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aljazeera.com&amp;#x2F;features&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;3&amp;#x2F;31&amp;#x2F;meta-profits-as...&lt;/a&gt; I have a hunch that &amp;quot;legitimacy&amp;quot; is directly proportional to the dollar amount of the ad bid...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mk89:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Imagine going in the streets as a normal human being and advertising these companies (the scammers, I mean).&lt;p&gt;You would never see the light again, after fighting countless battles with lawyers (rightly so!), ending up in prison.&lt;p&gt;But these guys just can exploit it, because that&amp;#x27;s what they do, and literally never be accountable for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;igleria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;X&amp;#x27;s scam originated revenue is probably a bigger percent, but 10% is too much... Shame on Meta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macNchz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Alongside a password manager and keeping things up to date, using an ad blocker is truly a foundational security practice these days. The big advertising players simply have all of the wrong incentives to control this problem. They &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; massively reduce the volume of scams advertised on their networks, but it’d be worse for them on two fronts: they’d have to pay for more moderation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they’d lose billions in revenue in the process. Shoulder surfing while a non-savvy user browses Facebook or YouTube without an ad blocker and engages with obviously fraudulent ads is painful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notahacker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Certainly puts the £3m lawsuit settlement with Martin Lewis (UK consumer  financial advice guru who sued because he&amp;#x27;s the go-to fake endorsement of any scam product targeting Britons using Facebook ads) into perspective.&lt;p&gt;No wonder scammers are still spamming his likeness all over Facebook paid ads even though it&amp;#x27;s technically &lt;i&gt;trivial&lt;/i&gt; for them to algorithmically flag it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baggachipz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would posit that nearly 100% of their revenue comes from scams of one sort or another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2OEH8eoCRo0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Scam ads and the sale of banned goods. They don&amp;#x27;t do anything about it because they aren&amp;#x27;t liable.&lt;p&gt;Repeal section 230&lt;p&gt;If you place these ads you should be held accountable. Meta has a duty to know who they&amp;#x27;re taking money from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;getnormality:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As my children become old enough to have more unfettered internet access, I plan to tell them the lessons of my experience: that all online ads are for products that range from disappointing to fraudulent, so do your best to completely ignore them. I would hope that every parent does the same and we end up with a generation that dries up the revenue for this sick racket.&lt;p&gt;I suppose the next move by advertisers will be corrupting all the other metrics of quality that I rely on. At that point, paywalled services like Consumer Reports (which has its own massive limitations) may be the only relatively authentic signals of quality left in the digital world.&lt;p&gt;A convergence to that equilibrium can be predicted based on it having already happened in the financial advice industry. The dictum that &amp;quot;if it&amp;#x27;s free, you&amp;#x27;re the product&amp;quot; is just as true of old-school in-person finance as it is of the digital world, except in finance the exploitative free system has been carefully carved out by decades of industry-honed regulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cjonas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;At least 50% of the YouTube promoted videos I get are crypto currency scams where some paid actor walks you though deploying an eth contract that empties your wallet. I report every one and nothing changes :(&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;balderdash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder what their definition of scammy is? I bet it’s pretty narrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrweasel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That probably depends on your definition of a scam, but it seems fairly low. Many products and services advertised online just skirts the border of being scams or fraud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;miyuru:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Original Reuters article: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reuters.com&amp;#x2F;investigations&amp;#x2F;meta-is-earning-fortune-deluge-fraudulent-ads-documents-show-2025-11-06&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reuters.com&amp;#x2F;investigations&amp;#x2F;meta-is-earning-fortu...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cyanydeez:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seems low, they need to pump those numbers up if they want to compete with the trp administration, russia or twittee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sherwood.news/tech/meta-projected-10-of-2024-revenue-came-from-scams-and-banned-goods-reuters/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845772</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Memorization to Reasoning in the Spectrum of Loss Curvature</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24256</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845800"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24256'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kingstnap:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A very similar idea is presented here in the first 5 minutes of this recent talk. But more from observing a kink in loss curves.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;UyK3DgWY7yw?si=NN3f9Erik8o_Nfbs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;UyK3DgWY7yw?si=NN3f9Erik8o_Nfbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andy12_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very concise summary of the procedure described in this paper:&lt;p&gt;1. Run the model once across a dataset to estimate loss curvature per MLP weight matrix via K-FAC (activation&amp;#x2F;gradient covariances).&lt;p&gt;2. Decompose each weight matrix into curvature-ordered components; low-curvature directions correspond most to verbatim memorization, higher curvature to shared&amp;#x2F;general mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;3. Edit by dropping the low-curvature subspace and keep only the top directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.24256</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845800</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Majority of teens hold negative views of news media, says report</title>
      <link>https://www.niemanlab.org/2025/11/biased-boring-chaotic-and-bad-a-majority-of-teens-hold-negative-views-of-news-media-report-finds/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 way that Americans get news for the first time. Breitbart or Fox News. Naturally, the researchers from News Literacy Project believe that news literacy is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845147"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.niemanlab.org/2025/11/biased-boring-chaotic-and-bad-a-majority-of-teens-hold-negative-views-of-news-media-report-finds/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bdangubic:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;kids do their own research :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yalogin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How journalism and media evolve is key to democracy over the long run. Its inability to change and adapt to the times has already caused grave damage, but the damage it will cause going forward could be greater. Social media and the supposed advantage to having a camera in every hand did not pan out at all and in fact became a negative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workaccount2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the surface this feels right, &amp;quot;Oh look, the kids can see through the bullshit&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;But this assumes that the kids have a stable honest reference point, and from there are calling out the bullshit.&lt;p&gt;That is almost &lt;i&gt;certainly&lt;/i&gt; not the case. What is far more likely, is that kids are getting their news from random tiktoks that are farming views with credible bullshit, and from that totally deranged reference point, the kids are calling the news bullshit.&lt;p&gt;You will find few people more hostile towards contemporary journalism than me, and you will find no one more hostile towards &amp;quot;self proclaimed social media news producer&amp;quot; than me. I could write essays about the people in my life who left behind journalism produced news to go &lt;i&gt;completely&lt;/i&gt; off the deep end getting &amp;quot;the truth&amp;quot; from tiktok.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pkphilip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am not sure if this scepticism is exclusive to the teens. I think a lot of people are more and more sceptical about news media and the close ties it has with the establishment - especially the way we have seen different platforms &amp;quot;manage&amp;quot; the news on behalf of the establishment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dwa3592:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think ground news is doing good work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mensetmanusman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Everyone complains about the media, but few offer solutions.&lt;p&gt;My favorite type of solution is something along the lines of taxing organizations whose viewers are more disconnected from statistics on the ground (by a bipartisan independent board choosing the types of knowledge sets that a well informed population should have). We could also subsidize organizations that are doing well informing people.&lt;p&gt;This is a way of dealing with the externalities brought about by people having so much misinformation in their day-to-day decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CuriouslyC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Traditional media is basically dead, YouTube is in the process of killing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adolph:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there an irony in this? The negativity cognitive bias often used by news media to increase the salience of their output now affects the perception of their product.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mensetmanusman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is good. Too many have slept walk into trusting narratives with dubious outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cbondurant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think the biggest thing that makes me distrust the news as it stands is that I feel like news reporting is far too prone to overly leveling debates. And by that I mean making both sides come across as equally credible, even when that could not be further from the truth.&lt;p&gt;The most common way I see it happen is like this:
you have a situation some group says that some totally safe thing is actually super dangerous.
There&amp;#x27;s a large body of scientific literature that really clearly shows its totally safe.
the news reports on it as such:
&amp;quot;While many within the scientific community state that there is no harm with X, anti-X proponents respond that the current studies are not substantial enough, and that they are simply asking questions.&amp;quot;
This framing, does not point out that the anti-X proponents are just a group of 10 people, nor does it describe how much evidence there exists in the scientific literature showing the thing is safe. Both sides are made to sound equally reasonable, which in my mind is practically a lie by omission. Because they &lt;i&gt;aren&amp;#x27;t&lt;/i&gt; equally reasonable.&lt;p&gt;Edit: One additional thought. I still will read news articles if they get shared to me, and I try to evaluate based off of what the source is. but another reason I don&amp;#x27;t actively keep a news subscription is because news orgs love reporting on tragedy. Because its more noteworthy. I&amp;#x27;m just not interested in reading yet another article about how crime is on the rise. Or about the most recent fatal car crash. Etc.&lt;p&gt;I stare into the void enough as it is. I don&amp;#x27;t want another.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nixpulvis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We need more public funding in independent accredited digital media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spicyusername:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I mean, the heyday of print news was almost a century ago and televised news decades ago.&lt;p&gt;Basically all digital news outlets, outside of just a few notable outliers, have no money to produce anything but low effort articles that are just a vehicle to show ads. And some of those are active propaganda outlets for basically nothing but evil interest groups.&lt;p&gt;What is there to have a positive view about...?&lt;p&gt;Society stopped paying for journalism and we got what we paid for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffrallen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My teen son loves The Onion.&lt;p&gt;Is this a data point? I have no idea, but he&amp;#x27;s cool and so is The Onion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mbfg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;maybe the kids will save us, afterall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.niemanlab.org/2025/11/biased-boring-chaotic-and-bad-a-majority-of-teens-hold-negative-views-of-news-media-report-finds/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845147</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We chose OCaml to write Stategraph</title>
      <link>https://stategraph.dev/blog/why-we-chose-ocaml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State corruption can't be "rare. Stategraph stores Terraform state as a dependency graph in PostgreSQL with resource-level locking. Every Terraform resource type, every state transition, and every database record is strongly typed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845958"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://stategraph.dev/blog/why-we-chose-ocaml'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a-french-anon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sorry for the large aside, but anyone knows the whereabouts of the Flambda2 project? Can&amp;#x27;t find the GH repo anymore, only this fork I didn&amp;#x27;t know about: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;oxcaml&amp;#x2F;oxcaml&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;oxcaml&amp;#x2F;oxcaml&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;markstos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My concern for a team language choice is &amp;quot;How hard is going to be be hire people to write in this language effectively and how much will &amp;#x2F;they&amp;#x2F; enjoy it?&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s one thing to pick a language that I like and am productive in, it&amp;#x27;s another to choose a language for a larger team.&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x27;ve found an full team of motivated and capable OCaml coders, great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;churlin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have worked with Haskell, Scala, and OCaml; they all bring the joy of programming into daily tasks, and OCaml has a fast compiler and a great module system. This makes it a really fun and effective language to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sgarland:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TIL (via a rabbit hole after reading this) that a good type system removes an absurd amount of boilerplate validation code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iLoveOncall:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Everyone makes mistakes, it&amp;#x27;s good to admit them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celpgoescheeew:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hope for the team to settle with a FLOSS license, so it becomes feasible to evaluate for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keyle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are many languages that fit these requirements. I don&amp;#x27;t get the purpose of writing these posts besides a reason to go viral and get clicks talking about your product.&lt;p&gt;I write OCaml myself, but not for $paid job, it&amp;#x27;s okay, it&amp;#x27;s a fine language although with cruft, but it&amp;#x27;s not the panacea described here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hardwaregeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like OCaml and have written the &amp;quot;why we chose XYZ language&amp;quot; posts. Most of the time the real answer is &amp;quot;we like it and it makes us feel good to use it&amp;quot;. Like the answers aren&amp;#x27;t &lt;i&gt;wrong&lt;/i&gt; per se but they&amp;#x27;re more post-facto justifications. And that&amp;#x27;s perfectly fine! I think we should normalize saying that tech stack choices are subjective and preference-based. We&amp;#x27;re not robots. The social and aesthetic parts of a stack matter to people&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;laszlojamf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t really get what&amp;#x27;s special about OCaml with these points they raise? Wouldn&amp;#x27;t almost any strongly typed language do? Wouldn&amp;#x27;t TypeScript also tick all these boxes?&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I wouldn&amp;#x27;t choose TypeScript either for this type of use case, but not for the reasons they state, that&amp;#x27;s my point&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koakuma-chan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is any of this OCaml specific? You can check all boxes with TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cyberpunk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Most systems handle this defensively with locks and runtime validation.&lt;p&gt;So i work at an org with 1000s of terraform repos, we use the enterprise version which locks workspaces during runs etc.&lt;p&gt;everywhere else i’ve worked, we either just use some lock mechanism or only do applies from a specific branch and CI enforces they run one at a time.&lt;p&gt;My question is: who is this aimed at and what problem is it actually solving? Running terraform isn’t difficult - thousands of orgs handle it no problem - the issues I have with it with it have never been around lock contention and race conditions..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://stategraph.dev/blog/why-we-chose-ocaml</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845958</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Software the UFOlogy of Engineering Disciplines?</title>
      <link>https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2025/11/07/is-software-the-ufology-of-engineering-disciplines/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But that doesn’t make it real. But that doesn’t mean aliens. His central claim was that “the evidence is overwhelming that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845948"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2025/11/07/is-software-the-ufology-of-engineering-disciplines/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 28 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shagie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m going to refer to Philosophy of Computer Science ( &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=20912718"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=20912718&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10388603"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=10388603&lt;/a&gt; ) and say &amp;quot;its not an easy or decided problem&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Section 3 has about 100 pages (in the pdf - I&amp;#x27;d have to dig around to find the hard copy) that tries to look into what computer science is.  Section 3.10 starts comparing it with engineering... and noting that it&amp;#x27;s looking at &lt;i&gt;computer science&lt;/i&gt; rather than programing aspect of it.  Part of the questions being asked is &amp;quot;is computer science a science?&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m going to highly recommend the book for those interested in these questions.  I&amp;#x27;ll also point out that across its thousand(!) pages, this book is in large part a survey of the literature of tens of thousands of &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; pages on the subjects.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t believe that most people are approaching software development (be it called computer science or software engineering) with either the mindset of a scientist or an engineer (there are times when one of those mindsets is necessary)  Rather, I agree with a later section in it...&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    3.14.7 Is CS Magic?

    The great science-fiction author Arthur C. Clarke famously said that “Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic” (http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Clarke’s_three_laws). Could it be that the advanced technology of CS is not only indistinguishable from magic, but really is magic? Not magic as in tricks, but magic as in Merlin or Harry Potter? As one CS student put it,
    Computer science is very empowering. It’s kind of like knowing magic: you learn the right stuff and how to say it, and out comes an answer that solves a real problem. That’s so cool. —Euakarn (Som) Liengtiraphan, quoted in Hauser 2017, p. 16
    Brooks makes an even stronger claim than Clarke:
    The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure thought-stuff. He [sic] builds castles in the air, creating by the exertion of the imagination . . . . Yet the program construct, unlike the poet’s words [or the magician’s spells?], is real in the sense that it moves and works, producing visible outputs separate from the construct itself. . . . *The magic of myth and legend has come true in our time. One types the correct incantation on a keyboard, and a display screen comes to life, showing things that never were nor could be.* (Brooks, 1975, pp. 7–8, my emphases).

    ...

    Clearly, programming involves exactly that kind of use of symbols. Or, as Abelson &amp;amp; Sussman put it in their introductory CS text (which we discussed in §3.14.4): A computational process is indeed much like a sorcerer’s idea of a spirit. It cannot be seen or touched. It is not composed of matter at all. However, it is very real. It can perform intellectual work. It can answer questions. It can affect the world by disbursing money at a bank or by controlling a robot arm in a factory. *The programs we use to conjure processes are like a sorcerer’s spells.* They are carefully composed from symbolic expressions in arcane and esoteric programming languages that prescribe the tasks we want our processes to perform. (Abelson et al., 1996, my italics)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jpmens.net&amp;#x2F;2021&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;the-unix-magic-poster&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jpmens.net&amp;#x2F;2021&amp;#x2F;04&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;the-unix-magic-poster&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=27029196"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=27029196&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;analog31:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder if there&amp;#x27;s a danger of comparing the real activity of programming with an idealized picture of engineering.&lt;p&gt;Most time spent by people with engineering degrees and job titles, is involved in things like organizing and arranging things, fitting things together, troubleshooting, documentation, meetings. Doing &amp;quot;hard&amp;quot; quantitative engineering is rare, and a lot of the calculations have been rolled into the CAD software. Unless designs are really critical, it&amp;#x27;s possible to solve problems by the rule of &amp;quot;when in doubt, make it stout.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Is this OK? I think it&amp;#x27;s an outgrowth of the rising complexity of products. As the number of pieces rises by O(n), the number of interactions goes as O(n*2), so at some point the dominant effort is managing interactions between pieces, rather than engineering the pieces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finnucane:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a little bit of irony that the example of the author points to architects relying on a CAD system, a system that was presumably built by programmers. Who had to understand that the results their software produced had to have a high level of reliability--if it produced a wrong result, buildings could collapse, people could be hurt or killed. Errors would be extremely costly. So it&amp;#x27;s not impossible, just most software isn&amp;#x27;t held to that standard, because there&amp;#x27;s less incentive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hate the idea of having one &amp;quot;Software Discipline&amp;quot;. Something is lost when people are constrained by OOP or TDD or &amp;quot;Clean Code&amp;quot;. Obviously, as with the example of TDD in the article, a lot of these terms mean different things to different people. Hence whenever &amp;quot;Clean Code&amp;quot; is criticized, people who think their code is &amp;quot;clean&amp;quot; take up arms.&lt;p&gt;I tend to disagree with most of these rulesets that are meaningless to &amp;quot;engineering&amp;quot;. The idea that a function should only be 40 lines long is offensive to me. Personally, I would rather have one 400 line function than ten 40 line functions. I&amp;#x27;m a Ziguana. I care about handling edge cases and I think my programming language should be a domain specific language to produce optimal assembly.&lt;p&gt;I would not constrain other people who feel differently. I read an article where some project transitioned from Rust to Zig, even though the people on the team were all Rustaceans. Obviously their Rust people hated this and left! To me, that&amp;#x27;s not a step in the right direction just because I prefer Zig to Rust! That&amp;#x27;s a disaster because you&amp;#x27;re taking away the way your team wants to build software.&lt;p&gt;I think hardly any of the things we disagree on actually have much to do with &amp;quot;Engineering&amp;quot;. We mostly aren&amp;#x27;t proving our code correct, nor defining all the bounds in which it should work. I personally tend to think in those terms and certain self-contained pieces of my software have these limits documented, but I&amp;#x27;m not using tools that do this automatically yet. I&amp;#x27;d love to build such tools in the coming years though. But there&amp;#x27;s always the problem that people build tools that don&amp;#x27;t notice common use-cases that are correct, and then people have to stop doing correct things that the tool can&amp;#x27;t understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;okaleniuk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is software an engineering discipline at all?&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of activities that are essential for engineering but not a sort of engineering themselves. Like writing documentation, or communicating requirements to your colleagues. Making instructions and operational procedures. Management. Accounting. Marketing. What makes making software an engineering discipline and making coffee not? Where is the line and why we presume we should be behind that line?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WillAdams:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sturgeon&amp;#x27;s Law.&lt;p&gt;For counter-examples see:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu&amp;#x2F;~knuth&amp;#x2F;taocp.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu&amp;#x2F;~knuth&amp;#x2F;taocp.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;and&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=bmSAYlu0NcY" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=bmSAYlu0NcY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;which is about the wonderful book:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.goodreads.com&amp;#x2F;book&amp;#x2F;show&amp;#x2F;39996759-a-philosophy-of-software-design" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.goodreads.com&amp;#x2F;book&amp;#x2F;show&amp;#x2F;39996759-a-philosophy-of...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sota_pop:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Engineer is to scientist as builder is to engineer.&lt;p&gt;Scientists take reality observations and make theories&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;principles.
Engineers take scientific principles and make technological designs.
Builders take available technologies and make a product&amp;#x2F;object&amp;#x2F;_thing_.&lt;p&gt;In each level, understanding how your inputs work defines the minimum criteria of success, but those who take the time to understand the “why” are largely considered “the good ones”.&lt;p&gt;And the rest is turtles all the way down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoppreH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think this eternal discussion persists because we conflate two different aspects of software engineering: the technical and the social.&lt;p&gt;Technically, we&amp;#x27;re a mature discipline. The author laments our lack of tools as advanced as architectural CAD systems, but I&amp;#x27;m unconvinced. We have static types, tests, linters, version control, benchmarks, standard data formats and protocols, deployment orchestration, debuggers. It&amp;#x27;s pretty nice.&lt;p&gt;Socially, our discipline feels immature. As mentioned, we don&amp;#x27;t know how well TDD works, how best to write documentation, or how to pick a flavor of agile. But these are meta-problems that plague every discipline! I challenge you to find a high quality study comparing imperial vs metric units in architecture, or the ideal number of architects for a given project size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One big caveat to this is formal methods. If we did formal methods for all production code, it would meet the highest definition for rigor and rest safely as a true engineering discipline.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Formal_methods" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Formal_methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IlikeKitties:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is as much about UFOlogy as it&amp;#x27;s about SE. But there&amp;#x27;s also Science in Ufology, for example statistical analysis of reported UFO sightings or video analysis of UFO Videos. I think this applies to software engineering as well.&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s an example I found enlightening: It&amp;#x27;s about the HTTP3&amp;amp; the QUIC protocol: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=4rYPXgCKamM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=4rYPXgCKamM&lt;/a&gt;
So much real engineering went into that, from fossilized infrastructure that doesn&amp;#x27;t allow certain ipv6 extension headers, to assumptions about the great firewall of china and it&amp;#x27;s inner workings and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devasta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Real engineers can face personal liability and even jail time for negligence.&lt;p&gt;How much of modern software practices would exist today if the senior engineer needed to sign off on a project?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uvaursi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Software development isn’t engineering and it has never been. Software developers aren’t engineers.&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why this keeps coming up, maybe slow news day. It’s okay to be passionate about a craft or a job and for that job to be very technical and demanding. Many people feel that way about what they do, and they are perfectly okay not being engineers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve always wondered why UFOs are only a USA phenomenon. Why doesn&amp;#x27;t China have these extraterrestrial biological remains? What about Russia? North Korea? Japan? Because it&amp;#x27;s a form of mass-hysteria. Just like the flat Earth crowd, they will continue to shovel the narrative and ignore scientific evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TedDallas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ask this question in the 1940s and they would tell you it’s math. We are making machines that do math to kill Nazis. Now take this vacuum tube and plug it in over there and then go get me a cigarette.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;z3t4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The thing with software is that you need to feel the pain in order to learn something. For example, when you lose all your work due to a bad HDD, you learn the importance of backups. But we also learn from others telling you that you need backups. So you make a copy of your data, but on the same hdd. Because you really haven&amp;#x27;t learned the lesson. Same with test driven development, you can have an entire career without software regression bugs, so you have no reason to use TDD. No pain no gain!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imglorp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is closely related to why Sussman and Abelson stopped teaching SICP: it is not possible to engineer software any more because systems are too complicated to completely understand and abstractions hide too many behaviors. So now we do &amp;quot;programming by poking&amp;quot; to understand what the system does instead of making it correct by construction.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lambda-the-ultimate.org&amp;#x2F;node&amp;#x2F;5335" rel="nofollow"&gt;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;lambda-the-ultimate.org&amp;#x2F;node&amp;#x2F;5335&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;We just tinker. That&amp;#x27;s all we can do to get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sampo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; More than 20 years ago, I corresponded with famous UFO researcher Stanton T. Friedman. His central claim was that “the evidence is overwhelming that some UFOs are extraterrestrial spacecraft”.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t believe in UFOs. But if I had to believe in UFOs, this would be my position:&lt;p&gt;We have had modern humans for 500 000 years [1]. If it takes 10 000 years to make it from stone age to space age, we have theoretically had time to make that 50 times over. Maybe there was a previous version of a human civilization [2], then wiped out by ice ages or something, but a small number of highly advanced humans have survived and keep hiding from us. I think this could be somewhat more plausible than interstellar travel.&lt;p&gt;[1] Or maybe 1 million &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45510582"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45510582&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Silurian_hypothesis" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Silurian_hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;efitz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Building software is usually a craftsmanship task.&lt;p&gt;Software can be engineered, but It’s rare and expensive so it’s only built that way when the cost is justified, as when building life critical systems (manned aircraft&amp;#x2F;spacecraft flight controllers) or security critical components like ssl stacks, cryptographic algorithm implementations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;apalmer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This again? In general, Software Engineering is not engineering.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not a technical issue, it&amp;#x27;s a &amp;#x27;software doesn&amp;#x27;t really kill people so government doesn&amp;#x27;t intervene in it&amp;#x27;. In the case where the software is life and death it&amp;#x27;s generally developed in ways similar to &amp;#x27;real&amp;#x27; engineering&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally folks built building&amp;#x2F;structures without engineering, just so consistently caused death and destruction that govt stepped in and started requiring licensed trained folks, approval trails etc. without this real world intervention regular physical &amp;#x27;engineering&amp;#x27; the same crap shoot as software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;karaterobot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Some programmers are engineers, but not all programmers are engineers. A lot of us are plumbers, basically. We connect together things other people have engineered. There&amp;#x27;s nothing wrong with plumbing; it&amp;#x27;s an important, honorable profession. It&amp;#x27;s just a different thing than engineering. And I&amp;#x27;m not saying that a really good programmer transforms into an engineer by virtue of being really productive, or smart, or whatever—I&amp;#x27;m saying engineering is a specific activity that most of us don&amp;#x27;t do every day as part of our jobs. So, to the point of this article, I&amp;#x27;d like evidence to be gathered from engineers, specifically, and not programmers like me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hatsuseno:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How many centuries did it take for civil engineering, for example, to become the codified, standardized, and respected calling it is now? While I&amp;#x27;m sure &amp;quot;software development&amp;quot; will leapfrog that span of time, but it&amp;#x27;s only been 75 years since the discipline was invented to begin with (Lovelace&amp;#x27;s work was more applied math than anything else, but the starting point is arguably between then and, let&amp;#x27;s say, FORTRAN?).&lt;p&gt;That is to say, as a programmer, I feel like we&amp;#x27;re wading in an ocean of unknown  size and depth. As we learn, by trial and error, the confines of that space will fuel the standardization and codification of the craft will only increase as a function of time until it isn&amp;#x27;t craft, but applied science.&lt;p&gt;Edit: s&amp;#x2F;applied science&amp;#x2F;engineering&amp;#x2F;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jerf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This isn&amp;#x27;t an uncommon lament, despite what the author thinks.&lt;p&gt;The problem is that running &amp;quot;studies&amp;quot; on what the author and others are asking for is effectively impossible. You can&amp;#x27;t get 25 teams of suitably-random professionals to build a non-trivial program one way, and 25 to build it another, and then do statistically-significant analysis of them, because that would be a staggeringly expensive study... and that is just for &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; such study, which would then be, you know, wrong, incorrectly analyzed, controversial, biased, etc. The expense of getting a representative &lt;i&gt;set&lt;/i&gt; of such studies, independently conducted, enough to actually settle a question, beggars the imagination.&lt;p&gt;Even such studies as have been performed are almost all invalidated by virtue of being run on inexperienced students. I&amp;#x27;m not really that interested in whether inexperienced students do or do not do well with some methodology for the most part. What happens with professionals?&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, all we&amp;#x27;ve got is experiences. Contrary to popular belief, science does not mandate that we therefore curl up into a ball and cry ourselves to sleep at night. We just have to do our best. Berating other people for not pouring billions of dollars into the simplest of studies won&amp;#x27;t help much. They&amp;#x27;re still not going to, and you still have to go to work, sit down, and figure out how you&amp;#x27;re going to accomplish some task, even it you don&amp;#x27;t have double-blinded meta-analyses from decades of studies to pull from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kykat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I always thought of myself as someone closer to a craftsman than an engineer, it&amp;#x27;s true that there&amp;#x27;s more &amp;quot;I think&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;I believe&amp;quot; than verified working processes, their limits, etc.&lt;p&gt;But I also think that the software development process is maybe too flexible to be regulated, and tested like the other disciplines, a building is always a building, a material is always the same material.&lt;p&gt;But in software, who is going to test and verify the &amp;quot;materials&amp;quot; if they change constantly and evolve? It seems to me that any attempt at standardizing software development could slow down development so much that most won&amp;#x27;t find it to be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giantg2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most of software isn&amp;#x27;t engineering, it&amp;#x27;s just building.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s like a lot of these custom car&amp;#x2F;motorcycle builders vs actual engineers designing for a major manufacturer. You are both building a product but one places a lot more rigor on the science, data, and testing behind the decisions. That doesn’t mean the custom builders don&amp;#x27;t build good stuff, just that you won&amp;#x27;t get answers to things like how much force a particular part can take or how much energy it will absorb in a crash.&lt;p&gt;In software, you might have some people still doing real software engineering, but they are in sectors that take documentation and testing more seriously. Not that every player takes this dedicated approach, but potentially parts of auto, aviation and defense fall into this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almondsetat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What I believe makes the distinction between engineer and non-engineer in the software world so difficult to pin down is that software is so powerful that most non-engineers can end up easily doing engineer-level work.&lt;p&gt;For example, a mechanical engineer is someone that designs mechanical systems. In order to do that, they will need specialized and very expensive equipment, and the end result will be produced with machines costing hundreds of thousands or even millions of dollars. Designing a system and producing a single one-off artifact are two very different things, and that&amp;#x27;s why a lone craftsman in their shed cannot do actual engineering (outside of pen and paper mockups).&lt;p&gt;With software, otoh, it takes nothing to go from default nginx for serving your static personal website to an orchestrated cluster of containers and load balancers. The problem is that, for the latter, if you haven&amp;#x27;t got an engineer-like training, you will not be able to reason about the system, because you didn&amp;#x27;t really design it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marshferm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The binary was always a kind of hallucination from real events. It&amp;#x27;s a toy model that uniquely (and mostly poorly) fits in our reality as simula. This article demonstrates Baudrillard was more accurate than The Matrix, ie the simula becomes seamless and transparent in our reality. It&amp;#x27;s not separate.&lt;p&gt;Software is neither engineering nor science, so the terms Software Engineering and Computer Science are mislabels at best and extinction propaganda at worst.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pbarry25:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Many governments do not recognize software development as an engineering discipline, and do not treat it (i.e. licensing, regulation) as such.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zigurd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s craft. But what about the math, you say. All kinds of craft demand understanding of the related math.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2025/11/07/is-software-the-ufology-of-engineering-disciplines/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845948</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: OSS implementation of Test Time Diffusion that runs on a 24gb GPU</title>
      <link>https://github.com/eamag/MMU-RAG-competition</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This file will store your API keys. docker compose up --build This command will: Build the Docker image from the Dockerfile. py --base-url http://localhost:5053 # Test only the dynamic /run endpoint python local_test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845575"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/eamag/MMU-RAG-competition'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/eamag/MMU-RAG-competition</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845575</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
