<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:23:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Spec-Driven Development: The Waterfall Strikes Back</title>
      <link>https://marmelab.com/blog/2025/11/12/spec-driven-development-waterfall-strikes-back.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Double Code Review: The technical specification already contains code. Most coding agents already have a plan mode and a task list. ” It does so by replacing developers with coding agents and guarding those agents with meticulous planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935763"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://marmelab.com/blog/2025/11/12/spec-driven-development-waterfall-strikes-back.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 17 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phyzix5761:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Replace the product people with LLMs and keep the engineers. You&amp;#x27;ll get better results that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;perma_junior:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m still not convinced there&amp;#x27;s anything wrong with waterfall for some projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constantcrying:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Much of the hype around SDD is really about developers never having experienced a real waterfall project.&lt;p&gt;Of course SDD&amp;#x2F;Waterfall helps the LLM&amp;#x2F;Outsourced labor to implement software in a predictable way. Waterfall was always a method to please &lt;i&gt;Managers&lt;/i&gt; and in the case of SDD the manager is the user promoting the coding agent.&lt;p&gt;The problem with SDD&amp;#x2F;Waterfall is not the first part of the project. The problems come when you are deep into the project, your spec is a total mess and the tiniest feature you want to add requires extremely complex manipulation of the spec.&lt;p&gt;The success people are experiencing is the success managers have experienced at the &lt;i&gt;beginning&lt;/i&gt; of their software projects. SDD will fail for the same reason Waterfall has failed. The constant increasing of complexity in the project, required to keep code and spec consistent can not be managed by LLM or human.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CraigJPerry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; You can see my instructions in the coding session logs&lt;p&gt;such a rare (but valued!) occurrence in these posts. Thanks for sharing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nkmnz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There’s nothing keeping you from scoping the spec to an agile package of work. To the contrary: even if you start with a full spec for a multi-day-AI-coding-session, you are free to instruct it to follow agile principles. Just ask it to add checkpoints at which you want to be able to let users test a prototype, or where you want to revisit and discuss the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chance-Device:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a weird article. How many times in your career have you been handed a grossly under-specified feature and had to muddle your way through, asking relevant people along the way and still being told at the end that it’s wrong?&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the same thing but for AIs. The user might think that the AI got it wrong, except the spec was under-specified and it had to make choices to fill in the gaps, just like a human would.&lt;p&gt;It’s all well and good if you don’t actually know what you want and you’re using the AI to explore possibilities, but if you already have a firm idea of what you want, just tell it in detail.&lt;p&gt;Maybe the article is actually about bad specs? It does seem to venture into that territory, but that isn’t the main thrust.&lt;p&gt;Overall I think this is just a part of the cottage industry that’s sprung up around agile, and an argument for that industry to stay relevant in the age of AI coding, without being well supported by anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tamimio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I, for one, welcome the fact that agile&amp;#x2F;scrum&amp;#x2F;daily standup&amp;#x2F;etc. rituals will be outdated. While they might be somehow useful in some software development projects, in the past 10 years it turned out to be a cult of lunatics who want to apply it to any engineering work, not just software, and think any other approach than that will result in bad outcomes and less productivity. Can&amp;#x27;t wait for the &amp;quot;open office&amp;quot; BS to die next too, literally a boomer mindset that came from government offices back in the day, and they think it&amp;#x27;s more productive that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hereme888:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think I&amp;#x27;ve seen enough of a trend: all these LLM ideas eventually get absorbed by the LLM provider and integrated. The OSS projects or companies with products eventually become irrelevant.&lt;p&gt;So they&amp;#x27;re more like 3rd party innovations to lobby LLM providers to integrate functionalities.&lt;p&gt;X prompting method&amp;#x2F;coding behaviors? Integrated. Media? Integrated. RAG? Integrated. Coding environment? Integrated. Agents? Integrated.  Spec-driven development? It&amp;#x27;s definitely present, perhaps not as formal yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jillesvangurp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A point I like to make in discussions like this is that software and hardware specifications are very different. We think of software as the thing we&amp;#x27;re building. But it&amp;#x27;s really just a spec that gets turned into the thing we actually run. It&amp;#x27;s just that the building process is fully automated. What we do when we create software is creating a specification in source code form.&lt;p&gt;Compared to what an architect does when they create a blueprint for a building, creating blueprints for software source code is not a thing.&lt;p&gt;What in waterfall is considered the design phase is the equivalent of an architect doing sketches, prototypes, and other stuff very early in the project. It&amp;#x27;s not creating the actual blue print. The building blue print is the equivalent of source code here. It&amp;#x27;s a complete plan for actually constructing the building down to every nut and bolt.&lt;p&gt;The big difference here is that building construction is not automated, costly, and risky. So architects try to get their blueprint to a level where they can minimize all of that cost and risk. And you only build the bridge once. So iterating is not really a thing either.&lt;p&gt;Software is very different; compiling and deploying is relatively cheap and risk free. And typically fully automated. All the effort and risk is contained in the specification process itself. Which is why iteration works.&lt;p&gt;Architects abandon their sketches and drafts after they&amp;#x27;ve served their purpose. The same is true in waterfall development. The early designs (whiteboard, napking, UML, brainfart on a wiki, etc.) don&amp;#x27;t matter once the development kicks off. As iterations happen, they fall behind and they just don&amp;#x27;t matter. Many projects don&amp;#x27;t have a design phase at all.&lt;p&gt;The fallacy that software is imperfect as an engineering discipline because we are sloppy with our designs doesn&amp;#x27;t hold up once you realize that essentially all the effort goes into creating hyper detailed specifications, i.e. the source code.&lt;p&gt;Having design specifications for your specifications just isn&amp;#x27;t a thing. Not for buildings, not for software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thomascountz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I just tried an experiment using Spec-Kit from GitHub to build a CLI tool. Perhaps the scope of the tool doesn&amp;#x27;t align itself with Spec-Driven Development, but I found the many many hours—tweaking, asking, correcting,  analyzing, adapting, refining, reshaping, etc—before getting to see any code challenging. As would be the case with Waterfall today, the lack of iterative end-to-end feedback is foreign and frustrating to me.&lt;p&gt;After Claude finally produced a significant amount of code, and after realizing it hadn&amp;#x27;t built the right thing, I was back to the drawing board to find out what language in the spec had led it astray. Never mind digging through the code at this point; it would be just as good to start again than to try to onboard myself to the 1000s of lines of code it had built... and I suppose the point is to ignore the code as &amp;quot;implementation detail&amp;quot; anyway.&lt;p&gt;Just to make clear: I love writing code with an LLM, be it for brainstorming, research, or implementation. I often write—and have it output—small markdown notes and plans for it to ground itself. I think I just found this experience with SDD quite heavy-handed and the workflow unwieldy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeathArrow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For myself, I found that having a work methodology similar to spec-driven development is much better than vibe coding. The agent makes less mistakes, it stays on the path and I have less issues to fix.&lt;p&gt;And while at it, I found out that using TDD also helps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zvr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a nice observation that Spec-Driven Development essentially implements the waterfall model.&lt;p&gt;Personally, I tried SDD, consciously trying to like it, but gave up. I find writing specs much harder than writing code, especially when trying to express the finer points of a project. And of course, there is also that personal preference: I &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; writing code, much more than text. Yes, there are times where I shout &amp;quot;Do What I Mean, not what I say!&amp;quot;, but these are mostly learning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Davidbrcz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That&amp;#x27;s Event-B (minus the formal side) with LLM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;podgorniy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article if for those who already made up their mind that &amp;quot;spec-based-development&amp;quot; isn&amp;#x27;t for them.&lt;p&gt;I believe (and practice) that spec-based development is one of the future methodologis for developing projects with LLMs. At least it will be one of the niches.&lt;p&gt;Author thinks about specs as waterfalls. I think about them as a context entrypoint for LLMs. Giving enough info about the project (including user stories, tech design requirements, filesystem structure and meaning, core interfaces&amp;#x2F;models, functions, etc) LLM will be able to build sufficient initial context for the solution to expand it by reading files and grepping text. And the most interesting is that you can make LLM to keep the context&amp;#x2F;spec&amp;#x2F;projetc file updated each time LLM updates the project. Viola: now you are in agile again: just keep iterating on the context&amp;#x2F;spec&amp;#x2F;project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IanCal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;But specs are per feature, it’s just an up front discussion first like you’d have on may things rather than questions-&amp;gt; immediate code writing from a model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;smj-edison:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bit of a tangent, but this reminds me of a video[1] I watched a bit ago where there was someone who interviewed 20 or so people who were both engineers and programmers, and asked them what the two fields could learn from each other. One of the things it mentioned from the perspective of a physically-based engineer is that a little more up-front planning can make a big difference, and that&amp;#x27;s stuck with me ever since.&lt;p&gt;[1] (pretty sure this is the right one): &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;CmIGPGPdxTI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;CmIGPGPdxTI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4ndrewl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And this is absolutely fine, because the problem with waterfall wasn&amp;#x27;t the detailed spec, it was&lt;p&gt;a) the mulyi-year lead time from starting the spec to getting a finished product&lt;p&gt;b) no (cheap) way to iterate or deliver outside the spec&lt;p&gt;Neither of these are a problem with SDD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://marmelab.com/blog/2025/11/12/spec-driven-development-waterfall-strikes-back.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:48:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935763</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Is Cool. Thank You, TCP</title>
      <link>https://cefboud.com/posts/tcp-deep-dive-internals/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember, the network stack goes: Physical –&gt; Data Link (Ethernet/Wi-Fi, etc) –&gt; Network (IP) –&gt; Transport (TCP/UDP). That’s just how the internet works. Flow and Congestion ControlWhen you step back and think about network communication, here’s what we’re really trying to do: machine A sends data to machine B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935503"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://cefboud.com/posts/tcp-deep-dive-internals/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gsliepen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you start with the problem of how to create a reliable stream of data on top of an unreliable datagram layer, then the solution that comes out will look virtually identical to TCP. It just is the right solution for the job.&lt;p&gt;The three drawbacks of the original TCP algorithm were the window size (the maximum value is just too small for today&amp;#x27;s speeds), poor handling of missing packets (addressed by extensions such as selective-ACK), and the fact that it only manages one stream at a time, and some applications want multiple streams that don&amp;#x27;t block each other. You could use multiple TCP connections, but that adds its own overhead, so SCTP and QUIC were designed to address those issues.&lt;p&gt;The congestion control algorithm is not part of the on-the-wire protocol, it&amp;#x27;s just some code on each side of the connection that decides when to (re)send packets to make the best use of the available bandwidth. Anything that implements a reliable stream on top of datagrams needs to implement such an algorithm. The original ones (Reno, Vegas, etc) were very simple but already did a good job, although back then network equipment didn&amp;#x27;t have large buffers. A lot of research is going into making better algorithms that handle large buffers, large roundtrip times, varying bandwidth needs and also being fair when multiple connections share the same bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stavros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wait, &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; you actually just use IP? Can I just make up a packet and send it to a host across the Internet? I&amp;#x27;d think that all the intermediate routers would want to have an opinion about my packet, caring, at the very least, that it&amp;#x27;s either TCP or UDP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hate to think of the future of these nice blog posts, that need to struggle to convince the readers about the &lt;i&gt;organic&lt;/i&gt; level of their content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cefboud.com/posts/tcp-deep-dive-internals/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935503</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So, you want to design your own language? (2017)</title>
      <link>https://cs.lmu.edu/~ray/notes/languagedesignnotes/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Language Design So, you want to design your own language. ) your own programming language. Programming Language Concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935342"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://cs.lmu.edu/~ray/notes/languagedesignnotes/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gf000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Java and C#, for being enterprisey&lt;p&gt;I believe there are far more interesting stuff to learn about these languages, like the whole category of runtimes could have been mentioned, which can directly affect the language design itself (e.g. having GC vs some language feature for managing memory, open vs closed world model, having an async feature in the language or let the runtime handle it, etc)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;procaryote:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think you should probably start by asking yourself if you &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; design a new language. Most new languages fall in the bucket of low value innovation that is instant tech debt for anyone who tries to use it for real&lt;p&gt;Even the successful ones are often pointless variations on a theme. Ruby, perl &amp;amp; python don&amp;#x27;t all need to exist for example, as they essentially do the same thing, about as poorly. Now python has won we should just drop the others&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hongbo_zhang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;forum.rescript-lang.org&amp;#x2F;t&amp;#x2F;introducing-moonbit-and-a-few-reflections-from-building-the-rescript-toolchain&amp;#x2F;7019&amp;#x2F;1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;forum.rescript-lang.org&amp;#x2F;t&amp;#x2F;introducing-moonbit-and-a-...&lt;/a&gt;
I happend to write a post sharing experience in building Rescript and MoonBit language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fjfaase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting page. The latest language I designed is an stack based intermediate language for a C compiler. Not realy intended for human usage, but readable in the sense that you can compare it with the original C code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;didierbreedt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m waiting for a llm focused language. We’re already seeing AI is better with strongly typed languages. If we think about how an agent can ensure correctness as instructed by a human, as the priority, things could get interesting. Question is, will humans actually be able to make sense of it? Do we need to?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;librasteve:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would like to see Raku (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;raku.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;raku.org&lt;/a&gt;) at least mentioned in the list of languages to be aware of. Why?&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Raku has built in Grammars so it is a great place to do early iteration of your parser
  - Raku is objects and type classes all the way down (as explained here https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gist.github.com&amp;#x2F;raiph&amp;#x2F;849a4a9d8875542fb86df2b2eda89296 )
  - RakuAST development is well advanced (use v6.e.PREVIEW) with the Slangify module to accelerate development of sub languages (Slangs)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Here is a Raku implementation of Brainfuck to whet the appetite &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;alabamenhu&amp;#x2F;PolyglotBrainfuck&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;lib&amp;#x2F;Polyglot&amp;#x2F;Brainfuck&amp;#x2F;Grammar.rakumod" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;alabamenhu&amp;#x2F;PolyglotBrainfuck&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;li...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imvetri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This talks about programming language.&lt;p&gt;Right question is to design own linguistic language common between computer and across human.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeathArrow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had some thoughts about designing a new language. However it&amp;#x27;s a huge undertaking and I don&amp;#x27;t know the answers to some questions:&lt;p&gt;1. Is there a need for the programming language?&lt;p&gt;2.If the answer to the previous question is yes, can I find enough people to help and enough resources?&lt;p&gt;3. If the answer to the previous question is yes, can we release a MVPin a reasonable amount of time?&lt;p&gt;4. If the answer to the previous question is yes, what is the chance it will gather a reasonable amount of users?&lt;p&gt;There are literally tons of programming languages that didn&amp;#x27;t make it. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t want to waste my and other people resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What do these languages compile to? What&amp;#x27;s the build pipeline and runtime context?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dash2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is bad and reads like AI slop. Try the &amp;quot;programming language checklist&amp;quot; instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cs.lmu.edu/~ray/notes/languagedesignnotes/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935342</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messing with Scraper Bots</title>
      <link>https://herman.bearblog.dev/messing-with-bots/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post isn't about that. This post is about fighting back. Use this method directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935729"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://herman.bearblog.dev/messing-with-bots/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://herman.bearblog.dev/messing-with-bots/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935729</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ohm Editor</title>
      <link>https://ohmjs.org/editor/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ohm Editor Explain parse Show spaces × Log into GitHub Username: Password: × Save Grammar As Grammar name: Arithmetic { Exp = AddExp AddExp = AddExp "+" MulExp -- plus | AddExp "-" MulExp -- minus | MulExp MulExp = MulExp "*" ExpExp -- times | MulExp "/" ExpExp -- divide | ExpExp ExpExp = PriExp "^" ExpExp -- power | PriExp PriExp = "(" Exp ")" -- paren | "+" PriExp -- pos | "-" PriExp -- neg | ident | number ident (an identifier) = letter alnum* number (a number) = digit* ". " digit+ -- fract | digit+ -- whole } 2 * (42 - 1) / 9 1+2*3 oh no ( 123 ) (2+4)*7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935398"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ohmjs.org/editor/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;foofoo12:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bad landing page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ohmjs.org/editor/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935398</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Reservoir – The World's Smartest Water Heater</title>
      <link>https://www.reservoirhome.com/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Reservoir The world’s smartest water heater. Some people want even more control, especially with visitors. Some people want even more control, especially with visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934912"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.reservoirhome.com/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;itopaloglu83:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Technology Connections have a video about how water heaters work in detail and how much power can be saved by strategically turning them off when not needed.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;Bm7L-2J52GU" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;Bm7L-2J52GU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the website has some weird vibes as well, like why would you say something like below?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; And some just want Dad Mode for when your teenager needs to finish that shower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bob1029:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think hot water should be this smart.&lt;p&gt;The last &amp;quot;intelligent&amp;quot; systems that made sense to me in the home are variable speed HVAC and micro grid &amp;#x2F; solar &amp;#x2F; battery stuff.&lt;p&gt;What is the value add to the customer of making hot water an app that can presumably stop working the next time AWS goes down?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swiftcoder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;... I may be out of touch with US water usage, but just &lt;i&gt;how much&lt;/i&gt; hot water does the average household use?&lt;p&gt;They quote $2,500 10-year savings vs oil. I have my hot water piggybacked on the oil-fired condensing boiler unit that&amp;#x27;s also used for my central heating, and I doubt I burn more than $250&amp;#x2F;year total on the hot water side of the equation (in a 4-bed, 4-bath house).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elcomet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The heat pump will pull heat from inside the house? This sounds terrible for efficiency in winter, as you will need to reheat the room&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firerouge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A heat pump water heater seems like a no brainer way to improve efficiency. 
They&amp;#x27;re not yet common, but there are many more options available over seas than in America.&lt;p&gt;This project seems emblematic of the challenges facing funding manufacturing initiatives in America. 
What&amp;#x27;s funded are the projects that appeal to tech investors, more of a focus on flashy presentation, luxury design, AI, and cloud app features, than the baseline functionality.&lt;p&gt;We get innovation as a side effect of convincing investors that the idea will disrupt industries and create app ecosystems that lock in consumer attention. 
Chasing the 100x unicorns and no longer training workhorses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3eb7988a1663:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The pricing page does not make it clear how much the actual unit costs, just $6500 with installation. Never purchased a water heater, but going to Home Depot, I see traditional options priced $500-$2000.&lt;p&gt;Which says you are putting up a high upfront cost, hoping to recoup on increased efficiency. Which could be worthwhile, but you would have to run some simulations if the price is worthwhile. Seems potentially easier to get a dumb water heater to run extra hot using off-peak electricity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChadNauseam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty cool. Reminds me of Impulse. I think there&amp;#x27;s a big market for home appliances that have more care and attention to detail than we&amp;#x27;re accustomed to. No one I know is overly satisfied with their water heater.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;porphyra:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting but federal tax credits for heat pump water heaters is ending next month [1]. It looks nice though.&lt;p&gt;For people wondering what&amp;#x27;s up with the &amp;quot;150 gal virtual&amp;quot; capacity, it&amp;#x27;s actually a 47 gal water heater but it heats water to a really high temperature (if needed) and mixes it with a thermostatic valve to output the desired temperature. For example if cold water was 15 degrees C and you want the hot water to be 40 degrees C, it can triple its &amp;quot;capacity&amp;quot; by heating it up to 90 degrees C and then mixing one part hot water with 2 parts cold water to give you three times as much hot water. Of course, this comes with a grave penalty to efficiency so you should only do it for &amp;quot;party mode&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.energystar.gov&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;federal-tax-credits" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.energystar.gov&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;federal-tax-credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MrLeap:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not interested until it can also show ads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reservoirhome.com/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 03:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934912</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
