<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:25:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns</title>
      <link>https://apnews.com/article/immigration-border-patrol-surveillance-drivers-ice-trump-9f5d05469ce8c629d6fecf32d32098cd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Border Patrol is using hidden license plate readers to track drivers and flag “suspicious” travel patterns, an AP investigation found, raising concerns over secret surveillance. Texas law enforcement agencies have asked Border Patrol to use facial recognition to identify drivers, documents show. Customs and Border Protection, into something more akin to a domestic intelligence operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996860"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://apnews.com/article/immigration-border-patrol-surveillance-drivers-ice-trump-9f5d05469ce8c629d6fecf32d32098cd'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 23 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pstuart:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s germane to point out the War on Drugs™ is a war on the people and has never been about &amp;quot;keeping people safe&amp;quot;. I know that a lot of people say that cannabis is ok but hard drugs should not be legal to keep people safe. Look at how well that&amp;#x27;s worked out, as well as how the people involved with those drugs are treated (users are treated like dangerous criminals rather than with substance abuse issues).&lt;p&gt;This war along with the War on Terror™ give pretense to all of these abuses of power and need to be undone. The problems they profess to address can be addressed in much simpler, cheaper, and humane ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gosub100:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;just saw this [1] today where the police chief was using license plate readers to stalk and harass &amp;quot;multiple victims&amp;quot;. This is why you don&amp;#x27;t collect the information in the first place. I am sure the lawyers are one step ahead, but I think Flock should pay these victims directly (in addition to the PD) for failing to stop the misuse of their technology.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.fox5atlanta.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;braselton-police-chief-arrested-hours-after-announcing-retirement" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.fox5atlanta.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;braselton-police-chief-arre...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;greenavocado:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Modern cars log their GPS coordinates about every 60 seconds and maintain weeks of records at minimum. Police regularly obtain search warrants to view weeks of GPS logs from your infotainment system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shortrounddev2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the last admin I used to think that &amp;quot;abolish ICE&amp;quot; was hysterical.&lt;p&gt;I now believe we need to not only abolish ICE, but puts the politicians and officers on trial. CBP needs to be purged and rebuilt from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[dupe] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45991257"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45991257&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;russellbeattie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Over the past decade we&amp;#x27;ve seen large numbers of Trump and MAGA supporters on HN.&lt;p&gt;Has their life improved because of ICE and CBP crackdowns? Are they happier now that all those undocumented immigrants have had their lives ruined? Are they proud of the destruction of our democratic norms and the attack on our civil liberties? Do they enjoy watching the rights of American citizens being trampled on a daily basis by a wannabe dictator?&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#x27;ve been very vocal and aggressive here in the past, where are they now? Will they continue to spout misinformation, disinformation and whataboutism with unprecedented presidential power grabs, the economy faltering and the Constitution being ignored?&lt;p&gt;I wonder how they feel now that literally every fear that progressives warned about are coming true? Are they willing to accept that they are and always have been completely wrong?&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to reply and show your full throated support for this administration. I&amp;#x27;d like to see how many HNers are so stubborn as to ignore reality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lbrito:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is what the world&amp;#x27;s most perfect democracy looks like. Peak Freedom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;License plate scanners are one of the most under-appreciated violations of personal privacy that exist today.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not just government use either. There are private companies that scan vast numbers of license plates (sometimes by driving around parking lots with a camera), build a database of what plate was seen where at what time, then sell access to both law enforcement and I believe private investigators.&lt;p&gt;Want to know if your spouse is having an affair? Those databases may well have the answer.&lt;p&gt;Here is a Wired story from 2014 about Vigilant Solutions, founded in 2009: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.wired.com&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;license-plate-tracking&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.wired.com&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;license-plate-tracking&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe Vigilant only provide access to law enforcement, but Digital Recognition Network sell access to others as well: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;drndata.com&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;drndata.com&amp;#x2F;about&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good Vice story about that: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.vice.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;article&amp;#x2F;i-tracked-someone-with-license-plate-readers-drn&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.vice.com&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;article&amp;#x2F;i-tracked-someone-with-licen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hugkdlief:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hey look!&lt;p&gt;The tools of oppression that all of you AI sycophants have been helping to perfect!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;standardUser:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; often for reasons cited such as speeding, failure to signal, the wrong window tint or even a dangling air freshener&lt;p&gt;Police shouldn&amp;#x27;t be able to pull someone over for an air freshener or tinted windows. They can send a fix-it ticket without wasting the time and resources, and without causing the inconvenience or diversions in traffic. And, as a private citizen, I strongly prefer the police have the minimal necessary powers to detain me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;codegeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Suddenly, drivers find themselves pulled over — often for reasons cited such as speeding, failure to signal, the wrong window tint or even a dangling air freshener blocking the view. They are then aggressively questioned and searched, with no inkling that the roads they drove put them on law enforcement’s radar.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Wow, this is incredibly concerning. So they can pull me over, lie about why and then try to manufacture something ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;csours:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;100 Mile Border Zone - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aclu.org&amp;#x2F;know-your-rights&amp;#x2F;border-zone" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aclu.org&amp;#x2F;know-your-rights&amp;#x2F;border-zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your rights are limited in interactions with CBP, or to state the inverse: CBP have claimed more powers than traditional law enforcement. This has been true for quite a while; they have at various times been more and less careful about your rights while exercising those powers. They are being less careful now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hypeatei:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s been fascinating watching the party of &amp;quot;small government&amp;quot; turn into one that supports ever expanding powers of a three letter agency whose job is &lt;i&gt;supposed to be&lt;/i&gt; patrolling the border. It&amp;#x27;s like a new 9&amp;#x2F;11 Patriot act moment, except it&amp;#x27;s only one side supporting it this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ericbarrett:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One of the most striking things about this article were the photos of the disguised cameras, especially the ones dressed up as traffic cones and electrical boxes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wslh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In Saudi Arabia Uber reports all trips to the kingdom [1].&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.careem.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;local-regulatory-data-sharing-requirements-in-saudi-arabia" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.careem.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;local-regulatory-data-sharing-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nabla9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;65% of the US population, 200 million Americans, live within the 100-Mile &amp;quot;Constitution-Free Zone&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Supreme Court  has established that some established constitutional provisions do not apply at the U.S. border, and protections against governmental privacy incursions are significantly reduced.&lt;p&gt;The border search exception applies within 100 miles (160 km) of the border of the United States, including borders with Mexico and Canada but also coastlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bomewish:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wouldn’t it be trivial for serious criminals - like cartels etc - to just use different vehicles?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sahaj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;But the criminals and illegals and the worst of the worst and the drugs.  Think of the children that are being fed illegal drugs thru tubes put in by the trans-national trans gangs.&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2F;s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;franciscator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Use AI to keep your driving pattern non suspicious ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LgWoodenBadger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Suspicious behavior is not a crime, and law enforcement is required to have a reasonable, articulable suspicion of a crime in order to detain people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mothballed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;License plates aren&amp;#x27;t compatible with the 4th amendment, and this only becomes more obvious with time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;duxup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This dragnet style data monitoring is illegal when it comes to phones, it probably should be illegal when it comes to cameras too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;themafia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Drive a rental car with California plates through Arizona on eastward and you&amp;#x27;re likely to find this out first hand.&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#x27;ll of course pretend that they just saw you commit a minor infraction and that&amp;#x27;s why you were pulled over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://apnews.com/article/immigration-border-patrol-surveillance-drivers-ice-trump-9f5d05469ce8c629d6fecf32d32098cd</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996860</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data-at-Rest Encryption in DuckDB</title>
      <link>https://duckdb.org/2025/11/19/encryption-in-duckdb</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4 ships database encryption capabilities. Starting with DuckDB 1. 0, DuckDB supports transparent data encryption of data-at-rest using industry-standard AES encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996585"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://duckdb.org/2025/11/19/encryption-in-duckdb'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;glenjamin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Other than motherduck, is anyone aware of any good models for running multi-user cloud-based duckdb?&lt;p&gt;ie. Running it like a normal database, and getting to take advantage of all of its goodies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kianN:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m just continually amazed by the DuckDB team. We had built out a naive solution with OpenSSL to encrypt duckdb files, but that lead to a 2x runtime cost for first time queries and used up a lot of ram because we were encrypting&amp;#x2F;decrypting the entire file all at once. It seems like because DuckDB is encrypting at the page level and leveraging modern processors native AES operations, they are able to perform read&amp;#x2F;writes at practically no cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://duckdb.org/2025/11/19/encryption-in-duckdb</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996585</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NTSB Preliminary Report – UPS Boeing MD-11F Crash [pdf]</title>
      <link>https://www.ntsb.gov/Documents/Prelimiary%20Report%20DCA26MA024.pdf</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ntsb.gov/Documents/Prelimiary%20Report%20DCA26MA024.pdf</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995834</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are replacing OOP with something worse</title>
      <link>https://blog.jsbarretto.com/post/actors</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All have the goal of attenuation the information that might travel between components by force. In tandem, other bright sparks were discovering that computers could be made to talk to one-another, and that perhaps this might be useful. Now, programs written by people that didn’t even know one-another - let alone trust one-another - could start interacting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997099"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.jsbarretto.com/post/actors'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;epolanski:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Many great design patterns have come from OOP and have found their home in functional languages or libraries.&lt;p&gt;Dependency injection has to be the most successful one, but anything from facade, visitor is there.&lt;p&gt;What has rarely proven to be a good idea instead is inheritance at behavior level. It&amp;#x27;s fine for interfaces, but that&amp;#x27;s it.&lt;p&gt;You can even have classes in functional programming word, it&amp;#x27;s irrelevant, it&amp;#x27;s an implementation detail, what matters is that your computations are pure, and side effects are implemented in an encoded form that can be combined in a pure way (an IO or Effect data type works, but so can a simple thunk encoding).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CuriouslyC:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Microservices are a bad pattern. Function as a service is better, because that architecture tends to assume vertical integration within the function and you can leverage a shared business logic library across an organization. Having service-to-service communication is the thing that makes microservices suck, if you can give people autonomy while having a shared systems language and keeping computation on one system it works ok.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TZubiri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had a job interview where the guy asked me something along the lines of do I have experience with OOP or Microservices，or both. So I answered how I like both and feel that MS are Objects at the network layer, the dude cut me off and told me to stick to the question. Absolutely gut wrenching, I was being evaluated by who knows who, in a slot of 30 minutes, maybe his entire job was repeating the same set of questions 16 times per day and he was unironically writing down yes&amp;#x2F;no next to &amp;quot;Microservices?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;OOP&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sroerick:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not really qualified to talk about either topic at length, but my impression is that the Microservice crowd is kind of a different group than the anti-OOP crowd.&lt;p&gt;As a total beginner to the functional programming world, something I&amp;#x27;ve never seen mentioned at length is that OOP actually makes a ton of sense for CRUD and database operations.&lt;p&gt;I get not wanting crazy multi tier class inheritance, that seems like a disaster.&lt;p&gt;In my case, I wanted to do CRUD endpoints which were programmatically generated based on database schema. Turns out - it&amp;#x27;s super hard without an ORM or at least some kind of object layer. I got halfway through it before I realized what I was making was actually an ORM.&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to let me know why this is all an awful idea, or why I&amp;#x27;m doing it wrong, I genuinely am just winging it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WCSTombs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TL;DR: OOP is being replaced by microservices (and even more extreme ideas), which is much worse. Yeah, I have to agree with this author.&lt;p&gt;I will say that service-oriented architecture does have some advantages, and thus sometimes it&amp;#x27;s the right choice. Parallelism is pretty free and natural, you can run services on different machines, and that can also give you scalability if you need it. However, in my experience that architecture tends to be used in myriad situations where it clearly isn&amp;#x27;t needed and is a net negative. I have seen it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;colordrops:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nonsense. Network service layer separation solves a different problem than OOP. It doesn&amp;#x27;t replace it.  Services and containers bring features and capabilities that OOP doesn&amp;#x27;t provide. It&amp;#x27;s orthogonal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bloppe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Someone is bound to quote Dijkstra here:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; To put it quite bluntly: as long as there were no machines, programming was no problem at all; when we had a few weak computers, programming became a mild problem, and now we have gigantic computers, programming has become an equally gigantic problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrkeen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Other bright sparks jumped in on the action: what if this separation did not rely on the personal hygiene of the programmers - something that should always be called into question for public health reasons - and was instead enforced by the language? Components might hide their implementation by default and communicate only though a set of public functions, and the language might reject programs that tried to skip around these barricades. How quaint.&lt;p&gt;Sounds like C.&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you did OO against a .h file without even needing access to the .c file?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; And so, the process&amp;#x2F;network boundary naturally became that highest and thickest wall&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve had it both ways.  Probably everyone here has.  It&amp;#x27;s difficult to make changes with microservices.  You gotta open new routes, and wait for people to start using those routes before you close the old ones.  But it&amp;#x27;s impossible to make changes to a monolith: other teams aren&amp;#x27;t using your routes, they&amp;#x27;re using your services and database tables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bauble:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is so much nonsense. Contracts and interfaces have little to do with OOP. If you don&amp;#x27;t like inheritance, then talk about OOP. It&amp;#x27;s fine. Many people, including myself, don&amp;#x27;t like inheritance. On the other hand, if it&amp;#x27;s interfaces and contracts that have you bothered, parse-dont-validate to your heart&amp;#x27;s content. If the domain allows it. Just don&amp;#x27;t drag unrelated concepts into this particular discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the__alchemist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think this is some combination of strawman, and subset of all cases. You can lament complications of OOP. You can also lament the complications of docker, kubernetes, HTTP APIs etc. These aren&amp;#x27;t mutually exclusive, and they don&amp;#x27;t span the breadth of programming techniques. I prefer avoiding all of these.&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, I&amp;#x27;ve replaced OOP with plain data structures and functions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notorious_pgb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think that &amp;quot;OOP&amp;quot; is an incredibly overloaded term which makes it difficult to speak about intelligibly or usefully at this point.&lt;p&gt;Are we talking about using classes at all? Are we arguing about Monoliths vs [Micro]services?&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t really think about &amp;quot;OOP&amp;quot; very often. I also don&amp;#x27;t think about microservices. What some people seem to be talking about when they say they use &amp;quot;OOP&amp;quot; seems strange and foreign to me, and I agree we shouldn&amp;#x27;t do it like that. But what _other_ people mean by &amp;quot;OOP&amp;quot; when they say they don&amp;#x27;t use it seems entirely reasonable and sane to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xnx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Perhaps a sneaky HTTP request to localhost for desert.&lt;p&gt;Typo: dessert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.jsbarretto.com/post/actors</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997099</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Kagi Assistants</title>
      <link>https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-assistants</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kagi Quick Assistant and Research Assistant (documentation here) are Kagi’s flagship research assistants. quick will call Quick Assistant. research calls Research Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997294"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-assistants'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;natemcintosh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As a Kagi subscriber, I find this to be mostly useful. I&amp;#x27;d say I do about 50% standard Kagi searches, 50% Kagi assistant searches&amp;#x2F;conversations. This new ability to change the level of &amp;quot;research&amp;quot; performed can be genuinely useful in certain contexts. That said, I probably expect to use this new &amp;quot;research assistant&amp;quot; once or twice a month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;itomato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m seeing a lot of investment in these things that have a short shelf life.&lt;p&gt;Agents&amp;#x2F;assistants but nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HotGarbage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really wish Kagi would focus on search and not waste time and money on slop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daft_pink:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not for nothing, but I wish there was an anonymized ai built into a kagi that was able to have normal conversation discussion about sexual topics or search for pornographic topics like a safe search off function.&lt;p&gt;I understand the safety needs around things LLM should not build nuclear weapons, but it would be nice to have a frontier model that could write or find porn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jryio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think there&amp;#x27;s a very important nugget here unrelated to agents: Kagi as a search engine is a higher signal source
of information than  Google page rank and ad sense funded model. Primarily because google as it is today includes a massive amount of noise and suffered from blowback&amp;#x2F;cross-contamination as more LLM generated content pollute information truth.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; We found many, many examples of benchmark tasks where the same model using Kagi Search as a backend outperformed other search engines, simply because Kagi Search either returned the relevant Wikipedia page higher, or because the other results were not polluting the model’s context window with more irrelevant data.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; This benchmark unwittingly showed us that Kagi Search is a better backend for LLM-based search than Google&amp;#x2F;Bing because we filter out the noise that confuses other models.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-assistants</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997294</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Says It's Finally Done with Two-Faced Onerep</title>
      <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/mozilla-says-its-finally-done-with-two-faced-onerep/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week, Mozilla announced its partnership with Onerep will officially end next month. Image Mozilla Monitor Plus video on Youtube. In a statement published Tuesday, Mozilla said it will soon discontinue Monitor Plus, which offered data broker site scans and automated personal data removal from Onerep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996433"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/mozilla-says-its-finally-done-with-two-faced-onerep/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ugh123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Onerep’s founder had created dozens of people-search services&lt;p&gt;How in the world was this not considered fraud, or in the very least - breach of contract?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve-Tony:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mozilla ended its partnership with OneRep (used in its Monitor Plus service) after an investigation revealed OneRep’s CEO, Dimitri Shelest, ran multiple people-search and data broker companies. 
Ars Technica
+1&lt;p&gt;Despite this, Mozilla says they haven’t found a values-aligned replacement yet, so OneRep continues to power the backend temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;201984:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;403 Forbidden&amp;quot; error unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slabity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Damn, I apparently missed the memo that the backend service for Mozilla Monitor was shady while I used it.&lt;p&gt;Are there any actual services like this that work properly? I&amp;#x27;ve noticed whenever it indicated that a service has removed my data, that same service would come back online as having my data a few weeks later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shellwizard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish they would let users fund Firefox development directly and not Mozilla&amp;#x27;s own agenda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;netule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good. I really wish Mozilla would rely less on these shady backroom deals and open up to direct user funding. The Mozilla Foundation accepts donations, but they don&amp;#x27;t go toward funding Firefox; instead, they fund advocacy campaigns.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Firefox is maintained by the Mozilla Corporation, a wholly-owned subsidiary of the Mozilla Foundation. While Firefox does produce revenue — chiefly through search partnerships — this earned income is largely reinvested back into the Corporation. The Mozilla Foundation’s education and advocacy efforts, which span several continents and reach millions of people, are supported by philanthropic donations.[1]&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.mozillafoundation.org&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;donate&amp;#x2F;help&amp;#x2F;#frequently-asked-questions" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.mozillafoundation.org&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;donate&amp;#x2F;help&amp;#x2F;#frequently...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/11/mozilla-says-its-finally-done-with-two-faced-onerep/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996433</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Docker containers natively in Proxmox 9.1 (OCI images)</title>
      <link>https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Finally_run_Docker_containers_natively_in_Proxmox_9.1.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Skip to main content Finally, run Docker containers natively in Proxmox 9. They recommend to run docker inside a Proxmox QEMU virtual machine. This means that you can run Docker containers as application containers on Proxmox VE like you would any other LXC container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997722"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Finally_run_Docker_containers_natively_in_Proxmox_9.1.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nirav72:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I played with this a bit today.  Only downside is, no easy way to update containers yet.  But on the other hand, no more dealing with macvlan or custom docker networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://raymii.org/s/tutorials/Finally_run_Docker_containers_natively_in_Proxmox_9.1.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997722</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Coast Guard will no longer classify swastikas, nooses as hate symbols</title>
      <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/11/20/coast-guard-swastika-noose/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/11/20/coast-guard-swastika-noose/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997729</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
