<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:50:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code on the Z-Machine</title>
      <link>https://entropicthoughts.com/advent-of-code-on-z-machine</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead, they used Lisp macros that generated zil. Inform 6 is another language that compiles to Z-machine bytecode. We compile this to Z-machine bytecode with In[4]: $ inform hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886194"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://entropicthoughts.com/advent-of-code-on-z-machine'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meindnoch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oh. From the title I thought it would be the Z machine at Sandia labs: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Z_Pulsed_Power_Facility" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Z_Pulsed_Power_Facility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://entropicthoughts.com/advent-of-code-on-z-machine</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886194</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI may not use lyrics without license, German court rules</title>
      <link>https://www.reuters.com/world/german-court-sides-with-plaintiff-copyright-case-against-openai-2025-11-11/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reuters.com/world/german-court-sides-with-plaintiff-copyright-case-against-openai-2025-11-11/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886131</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Effort Scales Superlinearly with the Perceived Quality of Creative Work</title>
      <link>https://markusstrasser.org/creative-work-landscapes.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verification latency and rate–distortion combine into a precision tax that scales superlinearly with perceived quality. That nested search is where the effort goes. , it demands more precision edits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885242"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://markusstrasser.org/creative-work-landscapes.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stavros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Judging by the comments here, I&amp;#x27;m the only one, but I have no idea what he&amp;#x27;s talking about. Even the abstract:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The act of creation is fractal exploration–exploitation under optimal feedback control. When resolution increases the portion of parameter space that doesn&amp;#x27;t make the artifact worse (acceptance volume) collapses. Verification latency and rate–distortion combine into a precision tax that scales superlinearly with perceived quality.&lt;p&gt;Is this just saying that it&amp;#x27;s ok if doodles aren&amp;#x27;t good, but the closer you get to the finished work, the better it has to be? If your audience can&amp;#x27;t understand what the hell you&amp;#x27;re talking about for simple ideas, you&amp;#x27;ve gone too far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SebFender:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I appreciate this post as I think too many folks focus on the end before understanding what made it there. It&amp;#x27;s kind of asking what&amp;#x27;s the movie about before watching it or especially movie trailers that essentially shows way too much.&lt;p&gt;We should all take some time to better understand what brought us here to be better prepared for general creative work and uniqueness in the future...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xmd5a:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On a related note I wrote a few “poems” using anagrams. The principle is simple: take a short phrase and have each line in the poem be an anagram of it. You can’t do this with just any phrase; the letters need to be reasonably well balanced for the target language so you can still form pronouns, key grammatical verbs (to be, to have, etc.), and some basic structure.&lt;p&gt;It becomes interesting once sentences span multiple lines and you start using little tactical tricks to keep syntax, semantics, and the overall argument coherent while respecting the anagram constraint.&lt;p&gt;Using an anagram generator is of course a first step, but the landscapes it offers are mostly desert: the vast majority of candidates are nonsense, and those that are grammatical are usually thematically off relative to what you’ve already written. And yet, if the repeated anagram phrase is chosen well, it doesn’t feel that hard to build long, meaningful sentences. Subjectively, the difficulty seems to scale roughly proportionally with the length of the poem, rather than quadratically and beyond.&lt;p&gt;There’s a nice connection here to Sample Space Reducing (SSR) processes. The act of picking letters from a fixed multiset to form words, and removing them as you go, is a SSR. So is sentence formation itself: each committed word constrains the space of acceptable continuations (morphology, syntax, discourse, etc.).&lt;p&gt;Understanding scaling through history-dependent processes with collapsing sample
space, &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;1407.2775" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;1407.2775&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Many such stochastic processes, especially those that are associated with complex systems, become more constrained as they unfold, meaning that their sample-space, or their set of possible outcomes, reduces as they age. We demonstrate that these sample-space reducing (SSR) processes necessarily lead to Zipf’s law in the rank distributions of their outcomes.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; We note that SSR processes and nesting are deeply connected to phase-space collapse in statistical physics [21, 30–32], where the number of configurations does not grow exponentially with system size (as in Markovian and ergodic systems), but grows sub-exponentially. Sub-exponential growth can be shown to hold for the phase-space growth of the SSR sequences introduced here. In conclusion we believe that SSR processes provide a new alternative view on the emergence of scaling in many natural, social, and man-made systems.&lt;p&gt;In my case there are at least two coupled SSRs: (1) the anagrammatic constraint at the line level (letters being consumed), and (2) the layered SSRs of natural language that govern what counts as a well-formed and context-appropriate continuation (from morphology and syntax up through discourse and argumentation). In practice I ended up exploiting this coupling: by reserving or spending strategic words (pronouns, conjunctions, or semantically heavy terms established earlier), I could steer both the unfolding sentence and the remaining letter pool, and explore the anagram space far more effectively than a naive generator.&lt;p&gt;Very hand-wavy hypothesis: natural language is a complex, multi-layered SSR engine that happens to couple extremely well to other finite SSR constraints. That makes it unusually good at “solving” certain bounded combinatorial puzzles from the inside—up to and including, say, assembling IKEA furniture.&lt;p&gt;One extra nuance here: in the anagrammatic setting, the coupling between constraints is constitutive rather than merely referential. The same finite multiset of letters simultaneously supports the combinatorial constraint (what strings are formable) and the linguistic constraint (what counts as a syntactically and discursively acceptable move), so every choice is doubly binding. That’s different from cases like following IKEA instructions, where language operates as an external controller that refers to another state space (parts, tools, assembly steps) without sharing its “material” degrees of freedom. This makes the anagram case feel like a toy model where syntax and semantics are not two separate realms but two intertwined SSR layers over one shared substrate—suggesting that what we call “reference” might itself be an emergent pattern in how such nested SSR systems latch onto each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contravariant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just map quality q to e^q or something and it will be sublinear again.&lt;p&gt;Or more directly, if your argument for why effort scales linearly with perceived quality doesn&amp;#x27;t discuss how we perceive quality then something is wrong.&lt;p&gt;A more direct argument would be that it takes roughly an equal amount of effort to halve the distance from a rough work to its ideal. Going from 90% to 99% takes the same as going from 99% to 99.9% but the latter only covers a tenth of the distance. If our perception is more sensitive to the _absolute_ size of the error you get an exponential effort to improve something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anechouapechou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I believe that last-mile edits do not significantly improve the quality of (most) creative work. To produce high-quality work, one must have already &amp;quot;cached&amp;quot; their &amp;quot;motor heuristics,&amp;quot; which, in simpler terms, means having dedicated thousands of hours to deep and deliberate practice in their field.&lt;p&gt;The definition of &amp;#x27;last-mile edits&amp;#x27; is very subjective, though. If you&amp;#x27;re dealing with open systems, it&amp;#x27;s almost unthinkable to design something and not need to iterate on it until the desired outcome is achieved. In other domains, for example, playing an instrument, your skills need to have been honed previously: there&amp;#x27;s nothing that will make you sound better (without resorting to editing it electronically).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nilirl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I liked the post but can someone explain how macro choices change the acceptance volume?&lt;p&gt;Is it their effect on the total number of available choices?&lt;p&gt;Does picking E minor somehow give you fewer options than C major (I&amp;#x27;m not a musician)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;svara:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Perceived quality is relative. It&amp;#x27;s roughly linearly related to rank position along some dimension, but moving up in rank requires exponential effort due to competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dickiedyce:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Also - the speed and quality improvements when having to redo homework lost to an undiscerning canine companion is also a corollary of this.
Perhaps the time it takes to &amp;#x27;redo&amp;#x27; is a better measure than last mile - it&amp;#x27;s the entire effort, minus the initial solution-space exploration?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;qlm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Perhaps a controversial view on this particular forum but I find the tendency of a certain type of person* to write about everything in this overly-technical way regardless of whether it is appropriate to the subject matter to be very tiresome (&amp;quot;executing cached heuristics&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;constrained the search space&amp;quot;).&lt;p&gt;*I associate it with the asinine contemporary &amp;quot;rationalist&amp;quot; movement (LessWrong et al.) but I&amp;#x27;m not making any claims the author is associated with this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exasperaited:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Understanding Poetry, by Dr J. Evans Pritchard, PhD&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;turtleyacht:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How often is a drawing really trashed and restarted?&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s the saying, &amp;quot;Plan to throw one away,&amp;quot; but seems like it varies in practice (for software).&lt;p&gt;There are even books about patching paintings, like &lt;i&gt;Master Disaster: Five Ways to Rescue Desparate Watercolors.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;In architecture, it&amp;#x27;s understood the people, vehicles, and landscape are not as exact as the building or structure, and books encourage reusing magazine clippings, overhead projectors, and copy machines to generally &amp;quot;be quick&amp;quot; on execution.&lt;p&gt;Would like to see thoughts on comparing current process with the &amp;quot;Draw 50&amp;quot; series, where most of the skeleton is on paper by the first step, but the last is really the super-detailed, totally refined, owl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://markusstrasser.org/creative-work-landscapes.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885242</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zig / C++ Interop</title>
      <link>https://tuple.app/blog/zig-cpp-interop</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;const c = @cImport({ @cInclude("cppstuff. shared_ptr_std_string_data(&amp;my_string); const size: usize = c. SharedPtrStdString) void; Notice that we’ve defined any function we need from C++ to move types around or access data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885135"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://tuple.app/blog/zig-cpp-interop'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://tuple.app/blog/zig-cpp-interop</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885135</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop overhyping AI, scientists tell von der Leyen</title>
      <link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/stop-overhyping-ai-scientists-tell-von-der-leyen/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[NurPhoto / Getty Images] A group of scientists has called on Commission President Ursula von der Leyen to retract a statement she made earlier this year when she suggested artificial intelligence would soon reach parity with human intelligence. “Now we expect this to happen already next year. “These are marketing statements driven by profit-motive and ideology rather than empirical evidence and formal proof,” the scientists write in the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886344"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.euractiv.com/news/stop-overhyping-ai-scientists-tell-von-der-leyen/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lysace:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We find the usual types in the signatory list:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Assistant Professor of Sustainability
  Lecturer in Critical Intersectional Perspectives on AI
  Professor of History and Anthropology
  Assistant Professor of Gender and Diversity in AI
  Professor of English Language and Literature
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
(&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.iccl.ie&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;uploads&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;20251110_Scientists-letter-to-the-President-AI-Hype.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.iccl.ie&amp;#x2F;wp-content&amp;#x2F;uploads&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;20251110_Scie...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rmoriz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The dilemma of leaders way behind is to find the right attack vector. Of course, you won&amp;#x27;t be able to become competitive by just &amp;quot;put more effort&amp;quot; into the existing stuff and hence everyone is eager to hope for a &amp;quot;Wunderwaffe&amp;quot; like flying taxis, quantum computing, blockchain, AI moonshots or whatever. In the end they all fail because the existing issues and problems won&amp;#x27;t be fixed, leading to the next failure. This happens over and over again, but voters still believe the promises of politicians.&lt;p&gt;Worse, there is a whole European industry sector hunting for subsidies doing build-to-fail projects, for example &amp;quot;google competitor&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;European cloud&amp;quot; etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AbrahamParangi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is comical because we used to have something called the turing test which we considered our test of human-level intelligence. We never talk about it now because we obviously blew past it years ago.&lt;p&gt;There are some interesting ways in which AI remains inferior to human intelligence but it is also obviously already superior in many ways already.&lt;p&gt;It remains remarkable to me how common denial is when it comes to what AI can or cannot actually do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;978689757846:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Overhyping unscientific marketing claims is on brand for the regime.&lt;p&gt;Btw, where are the messages she sent and received in connection to the backroom deals she made with Pfizer on behalf of 450 million citizens?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.euractiv.com/news/stop-overhyping-ai-scientists-tell-von-der-leyen/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886344</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazel (YC W24) Is Hiring Full Stack Engineers</title>
      <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/hazel-2/jobs/fCdGOZw-full-stack-engineer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hazel builds AI for the public interest. Hazel is transforming government procurement – how government agencies purchase goods and services from commercial vendors. Hazel combines startup speed with the mission focus of public service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886350"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/hazel-2/jobs/fCdGOZw-full-stack-engineer'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/hazel-2/jobs/fCdGOZw-full-stack-engineer</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886350</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The "Dependency Cutout" Workflow Pattern</title>
      <link>https://blog.glyph.im/2025/11/dependency-cutout-workflow-pattern.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FooApp is your job; LibBar is (at best) your hobby. Vendor LibBar into your codebase and fix your vendored version. Monkey-patch LibBar to include your fix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884951"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.glyph.im/2025/11/dependency-cutout-workflow-pattern.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TekMol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am using Git submodules for dependencies. My approach to a situation like this:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    1: Clone gh.com&amp;#x2F;someone&amp;#x2F;LibBar to gh.com&amp;#x2F;me&amp;#x2F;LibBar
    2: Fix the bug
    3: Send pull request to someone
    5: git submodule set-url lib&amp;#x2F;LibBar https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gh.com&amp;#x2F;me&amp;#x2F;LibBar.git
       git submodule sync lib&amp;#x2F;LibBar
       git submodule update --init --remote --recursive lib&amp;#x2F;LibBar
       cd lib&amp;#x2F;LibBar&amp;#x2F;; git checkout main; cd ..&amp;#x2F;..
       git add .; git commit -m &amp;quot;Use my own version of lib&amp;#x2F;LibBar&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
And keep using my fork until upstream accepted my pull request. Then I switch the url of the dependency back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;a_t48:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For me it usually looks like:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    - Fork LibBar on Github, apply patch
     - In docker stage build-bar:
        - RUN git clone gh.com&amp;#x2F;my_org&amp;#x2F;bar
        - WORKDIR bar&amp;#x2F;build
        - RUN cmake .. -DCMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=Release (old habits die hard, need to remember to use -B)
        - RUN make -j
     - in main docker stage: --mount from=bar,src=bar&amp;#x2F;build,target=&amp;#x2F;tmp&amp;#x2F;bar make install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
...and that&amp;#x27;s it. A little bit of wastage if I had to install over the top of some apt install but oh well. If I contributed back to upstream, or they fix independently, gravy - remove the extra build. This doesn&amp;#x27;t work as well for python or js, of course, and doesn&amp;#x27;t &amp;quot;solve&amp;quot; pulling in upstream regularly, but I usually don&amp;#x27;t need to. Benefits of not usually working on internet facing software, I suppose.&lt;p&gt;The python case is thankfully usually not terrible nowadays (clone, `uv build`, push to artifact registry), modulo needing to pass whatever flag to uv to let it take into account both my private registry and public pypi at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.glyph.im/2025/11/dependency-cutout-workflow-pattern.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884951</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
