<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:35:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>A Fond Farewell from Farmers' Almanac</title>
      <link>https://www.farmersalmanac.com/fond-farewell-from-farmers-almanac</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Farmers' Almanac Staffhttps://www. com/author/fa-adminNovember 6, 2025End of an Era: Farmers’ Almanac Announces Final PublicationFarmers' Almanac Staffhttps://www. Farmers' Almanac Staffhttps://www.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843146"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.farmersalmanac.com/fond-farewell-from-farmers-almanac'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waterluvian:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What exactly &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the Farmer’s Almanac? I always thought it was basically a big set of historical data that helped provide a sort of statistical foundation for choices, even if the &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; isn’t explained.&lt;p&gt;Which seems like I can completely understand it as a practical tool in the past but fairly obsolete in modern times.&lt;p&gt;Or did it evolve, too, and was essentially modern science and maths, dressed in the trappings of a beloved cultural relic? Or is it more than ever a collection of stories and advice and other culture, and much less about the actual almanac?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjbeam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Huh, this always seemed like such an institution it never occurred to me that people have to produce Farmers&amp;#x27; Almanac. Which of course they do. Didn&amp;#x27;t have this on my bingo card today, makes me a little sad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lisbbb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know it has a tradition behind it, but you can&amp;#x27;t just make shit up and just expect people in this technical age to be okay with it.  I used to peruse my Grandmother&amp;#x27;s Reader&amp;#x27;s Digest as a kid and never really understood that one, either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thorum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This press release has a bit more explanation:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.farmersalmanac.com&amp;#x2F;end-of-an-era-farmers-almanac-announces-final-publication" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.farmersalmanac.com&amp;#x2F;end-of-an-era-farmers-almanac...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; This decision, though difficult, reflects the growing financial challenges of producing and distributing the Almanac in today’s chaotic media environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mtillman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I skim both almanac products each year. Both have helpful little home tips and quite a bit of gardening advice. Sad to see them go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tylerchilds:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ll put a bowl of water in the moonlight tonight to bring blessings to the generations of authors farming our collective reality framing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yieldcrv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting, I appreciate how they gave no reasons, I’m also curious if there is more details beyond “we don’t want to anymore”&lt;p&gt;Would be pretty cool if it was that simple, that reason needs more representation and is how I run my entrepreneurial endeavors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shervinafshar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not to be confused with Old Farmer&amp;#x27;s Almanac (est. 1792) and yet sad to see a 200 years old periodical closing up shop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.farmersalmanac.com/fond-farewell-from-farmers-almanac</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843146</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Meta and PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://soumith.ch/blog/2025-11-06-leaving-meta-and-pytorch.md.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PyTorch handles exascale training now. Something uncomfortable. It's very hard to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843948"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://soumith.ch/blog/2025-11-06-leaving-meta-and-pytorch.md.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://soumith.ch/blog/2025-11-06-leaving-meta-and-pytorch.md.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843948</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Slides with notes</title>
      <link>https://nbd.neocities.org/slidepresentation/Slide%20presentation%20about%20slides</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And let's define slide notes as a div with a slidenote class. And with that we already have basic slide functionality. Let's pick n for notes Now all we're missing is having notes in a separate window synchronized with the slides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45842777"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://nbd.neocities.org/slidepresentation/Slide%20presentation%20about%20slides'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hecanjog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love it, but it was very disorienting to use `j` to move forward and `k` to move backward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;small_scombrus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is really cute!&lt;p&gt;I have a special spot in my heart for tools that do a good job of explaining themselves using their own outputs.&lt;p&gt;I wonder how hard it would be to add the cute old PowerPoint style transitions using CSS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;asplake:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could add clicker support (which I have done previously). Note however that clickers vary between Up&amp;#x2F;Down and PgUp&amp;#x2F;PgDown. Enabling the former was potentially annoying if you like to use the arrow keys to scroll, so I made that configurable.
Alternatively you configure mappings per device outside the browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://nbd.neocities.org/slidepresentation/Slide%20presentation%20about%20slides</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45842777</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dead Framework Theory</title>
      <link>https://aifoc.us/dead-framework-theory/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;React has become the platform. React usage has stalled at 1. So what has driven the uptick in React sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843220"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://aifoc.us/dead-framework-theory/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contrarian1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not really sure why this focuses so much on React, when it&amp;#x27;s a general &amp;quot;issue&amp;quot;&amp;#x2F;&amp;quot;feature&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;More broadly, obviously there is some pressure to use a framework&amp;#x2F;library&amp;#x2F;programminglang&amp;#x2F;editor that has better LLM training. But even before LLMs.. you&amp;#x27;d want to choose the one that has more SO questions, more blog posts and books published about it. The one where you can hire experienced programmers.&lt;p&gt;New players has a certain activation energy they need to overcome - which is probably good. B&amp;#x2F;c it slows down the churn of new shiny with incrementally improvements. I think a paradigm shift is sufficient though. Programmers like new shiny things - especially the good ones that are passionate about their craft&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;miffy900:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel like there could be a loophole here for the new-framework-author. Stick to using JSX for the view; JSX is just syntax sugar for built in react functions for constructing a tree, which can be easily swappable with your own implementation. I recall years ago using a babel plugin that just emitted static HTML from JSX. I know Vue.js v2 also had JSX support that way.&lt;p&gt;I think LLMs, despite already being trained massively on React, can easily adapt their output to suit a new framework&amp;#x27;s-specific API surface with a simple adjustment to the prompt. Maybe include an abbreviated list of type&amp;#x2F;function signatures that are specific to your new framework and just tell the LLM to use JSX for the views?&lt;p&gt;What I think will definitely be a challenge for new library authors in the age of LLMs is state management. There are already tons of libraries that basically achieve the same thing but have vastly different APIs. In this case, new lib-authors may be forced to just write pluggable re-implementations of existing libraries just to enable LLMs to emit compilable&amp;#x2F;runnable code. Though I dont know of any state management library that dominates the web like React does with the view layer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timinou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t buy it either. I&amp;#x27;ve been building my own backend framework for the past 2.5 years, and even though it&amp;#x27;s a DSL over Python and there&amp;#x27;s no documentation online and barely one in my computer, Claude Code understands it with enough usage examples in my codebase.&lt;p&gt;In front-end as well—I&amp;#x27;ve been able to go much farther for simple projects using alpine than more complex frameworks. For big products I use Elm, which isn&amp;#x27;t exactly the most common front-end choice but it provides a declarative programming style that forces the LLM to write more correct code faster.&lt;p&gt;In general, I think introspectible frameworks have a better case, and whether they&amp;#x27;re present in training data or not becomes more irrelevant as the introspectibility increases. Wiring the Elm compiler to a post-write hook means I basically have not written front-end code in 4 or 5 months. Using web standards and micro frameworks with no build step means the LLM can inspect the behaviour using the chrome dev tools MCP and check its work much more effectively than having to deal with the React loop. The ecosystem is so fragmented there, I&amp;#x27;m not sure about the &amp;quot;quality because of quantity of training data&amp;quot; argument.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The argument here is that React has permanently won because LLMs are so heavily trained on it and default to it in their answers.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t buy this. The big problem with React is that the compilation step is almost required - and that compilation step is a significant and growing piece of friction.&lt;p&gt;Compilation and bundling made a lot more sense before browsers got ES modules and HTTP&amp;#x2F;2. Today you can get a long way without a bundler... and in a world where LLMs are generating code that&amp;#x27;s actually a more productive way to work.&lt;p&gt;Telling any LLM &amp;quot;use Vanilla JS&amp;quot; is enough to break them out of the React cycle, and the resulting code works well and, crucially, doesn&amp;#x27;t require a round-trip through some node.js build mechanism just to start using it.&lt;p&gt;Call me a wild-eyed optimist, but I&amp;#x27;m hoping LLMs can help us break free of React and go back to building things in a simpler way. The problems React solve are mostly around helping developers write less code and avoid having to implement their own annoying state-syncing routines. LLMs can spit out those routines in a split-second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tow21:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the plus side, maybe this means the endless churn of JS libraries will finally slow down and as someone who isn’t a JS developer but occasionally needs to dip their toe into the ecosystem, I can actually get stuff done without having to worry about 6-month old tutorials being wrong and getting caught in endless upgrade hell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;add-sub-mul-div:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That was depressing as shit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gibbitz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is the AI apocalypse. Not AI nuking us, but nuking choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://aifoc.us/dead-framework-theory/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843220</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
