<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 02:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem</title>
      <link>https://blog.cloudflare.com/18-november-2025-outage/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That feature file, in turn, doubled in size. The larger-than-expected feature file was then propagated to all the machines that make up our network. AccessAuthentication failures were widespr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973709"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.cloudflare.com/18-november-2025-outage/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 27 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alhirzel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I worry this is the big botnet flexing.&lt;p&gt;Even worse - the small botnet that controls everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;back_to_basics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While it&amp;#x27;s certainly worthwhile to discuss the Technical and Procedural elements that contributed to this Service Outage, the far more important (and mutually-exclusive aspect) to discuss should be:&lt;p&gt;Why have we built &amp;#x2F; permitted the building of &amp;#x2F; Subscribed to such a Failure-intolerant &amp;quot;Network&amp;quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cvhc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t get why that SQL query was even used in the first place. It seems it fetches feature names at runtime instead of using a static hardcoded schema. Considering this decides the schema of a global config, I don&amp;#x27;t think the dynamicity is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would have been a bit cheeky and opened with &amp;#x27;It wasn&amp;#x27;t DNS.&amp;#x27;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sema4hacker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you deploy a change to your system, and things start to go wrong that same day, the prime suspect (no matter how unlikely it might seem) should be the change you made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wildmXranat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Hold up ,- when I used a C or similar language for accessing a database and wanted to clamp down on memory usage to deterministically control how much I want to allocated, I would explicitly limit the number of rows in the query.&lt;p&gt;There never was an unbound &amp;quot;select all rows from some table&amp;quot; without a &amp;quot;fetch first N rows only&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;limit N&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If you knew that this design is rigid, why not leverage the query to actually do it ?&lt;p&gt;What am I missing ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;avereveard:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Question: customer having issues also couldn&amp;#x27;t switch their dns to bypass the service, why is the control plane updated along the data plane here it seem a lot of use could save business continuity if they could change their dns entry temporarily&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arjie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great post-mortem. Very clear. Surprised that num(panicking threads) didn&amp;#x27;t show up somewhere in telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;habibur:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    On 18 November 2025 at 11:20 UTC (all times in this blog are UTC), Cloudflare&amp;#x27;s network began experiencing significant failures
    As of 17:06 all systems at Cloudflare were functioning as normal
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
6 hours &amp;#x2F; 5 years gives ~99.98% uptime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;testemailfordg2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Customers on our old proxy engine, known as FL, did not see errors, but bot scores were not generated correctly, resulting in all traffic receiving a bot score of zero.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This simply means, the exception handling quality of your new FL2 is non-existent and is not at par &amp;#x2F; code logic wise similar to FL.&lt;p&gt;I hope it was not because of AI driven efficiency gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yoyohello13:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People really like to hate on Rust for some reason. This wasn’t a Rust problem, no language would have saved them from this kind of issue. In fact, the compiler would have warned that this was a possible issue.&lt;p&gt;I get it, don’t pick languages just because they are trendy, but if any company’s use case is a perfect fit for Rust it’s cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slyall:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ironically just now I got a Cloudflare &amp;quot;Error code 524&amp;quot; page because blog.cloudflare.com was down&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RagingCactus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Lots of people here are (perhaps rightfully) pointing to the unwrap() call being an issue. That might be true, but to me the fact that a reasonably &amp;quot;clean&amp;quot; panic at a defined line of code was not quickly picked up in any error monitoring system sounds just as important to investigate.&lt;p&gt;Assuming something similar to Sentry would be in use, it should clearly pick up the many process crashes that start occurring right as the downtime starts. And the well defined clean crashes should in theory also stand out against all the random errors that start occuring all over the system as it begins to go down, precisely because it&amp;#x27;s always failing at the exact same point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nanankcornering:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Matt, Looking forward in regaining Elon&amp;#x27;s and his team trust to use CF again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dzonga:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; thread fl2_worker_thread panicked: called Result::unwrap() on an Err value&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t use Rust, but a lot of Rust people say if it compiles it runs.&lt;p&gt;Well Rust won&amp;#x27;t save you from the usual programming mistake. Not blaming anyone at cloudflare here. I love Cloudflare and the awesome tools they put out.&lt;p&gt;end of day - let&amp;#x27;s pick languages | tech because of what we love to do. if you love Rust - pick it all day. I actually wanna try it for industrial robot stuff or small controllers etc.&lt;p&gt;there&amp;#x27;s no bad language - just occassional hiccups from us users who use those tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ksajadi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;May I just say that Matthew Prince is the CEO of Cloudflare and a lawyer by training (and a very nice guy overall). The quality of this postmortem is great but the fact that it is from him makes one respect the company even more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trengrj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Classic combination of errors:&lt;p&gt;Having the feature table pivoted (with 200 feature1, feature2, etc columns) meant they had to do meta queries to system.columns to get all the feature columns which made the query sensitive to permissioning changes (especially duplicate databases).&lt;p&gt;A Crowdstrike style config update that affects all nodes but obviously isn&amp;#x27;t tested in any QA or staged rollout strategy beforehand (the application panicking straight away with this new file basically proves this).&lt;p&gt;Finally an error with bot management config files should probably disable bot management vs crash the core proxy.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m interested here why they even decided to name Clickhouse as this error could have been caused by any other database. I can see though the replicas updating causing flip &amp;#x2F; flopping of results would have been really frustrating for incident responders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ojosilva:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is the multi-million dollar .unwrap() story. In a critical path of infrastructure serving a significant chunk of the internet, calling .unwrap() on a Result means you&amp;#x27;re saying &amp;quot;this can never fail, and if it does, crash the thread immediately.&amp;quot;The Rust compiler forced them to acknowledge this could fail (that&amp;#x27;s what Result is for), but they explicitly chose to panic instead of handle it gracefully. This is textbook &amp;quot;parse, don&amp;#x27;t validate&amp;quot; anti-pattern.&lt;p&gt;I know, this is &amp;quot;Monday morning quarterbacking&amp;quot;, but that&amp;#x27;s what you get for an outage this big that had me tied up for half a day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sigmar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow. What a post mortem. 
Rather than Monday morning quarterbacking how many ways this could have been prevented, I&amp;#x27;d love to hear people sound-off on things that unexpectedly broke. I, for one, did not realize logging in to porkbun to edit DNS settings would become impossible with a cloudflare meltdown&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ed_mercer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow. 26M&amp;#x2F;s 5xx error HTTP status codes over a span of roughly two hours. That&amp;#x27;s roughly 187 billion HTTP errors that interrupted people (and systems)!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vsgherzi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why does cloudflare allow unwraps in their code? I would&amp;#x27;ve assumed they&amp;#x27;d have clippy lints stopping that sort of thing. Why not just match with { ok(value) =&amp;gt; {}, Err(error) =&amp;gt; {} } the function already has a Result type.&lt;p&gt;At the bare minimum they could&amp;#x27;ve used an expect(&amp;quot;this should never happen, if it does database schema is incorrect&amp;quot;).&lt;p&gt;The whole point of errors as values is preventing this kind of thing....  It wouldn&amp;#x27;t have stopped the outage but it would&amp;#x27;ve made it easy to diagnose.&lt;p&gt;If anyone at cloudflare is here please let me in that codebase :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lukan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Throwing us off and making us believe this might have been an attack was another apparent symptom we observed: Cloudflare’s status page went down. The status page is hosted completely off Cloudflare’s infrastructure with no dependencies on Cloudflare. While it turned out to be a coincidence, it led some of the team diagnosing the issue to believe that an attacker may be targeting both our systems as well as our status page.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately they do not share, what caused the status page to went down as well. (Does this happen often? Otherwise a big coincidence it seems)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;otterley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; work has already begun on how we will harden them against failures like this in the future. In particular we are:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Hardening ingestion of Cloudflare-generated configuration files in the same way we would for user-generated input&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Enabling more global kill switches for features&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Eliminating the ability for core dumps or other error reports to overwhelm system resources&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Reviewing failure modes for error conditions across all core proxy modules&lt;p&gt;Absent from this list are canary deployments and incremental or wave-based deployment of configuration files (which are often as dangerous as code changes) across fault isolation boundaries -- assuming CloudFlare has such boundaries at all. How are they going to contain the blast radius in the future?&lt;p&gt;This is something the industry was supposed to learn from the CrowdStrike incident last year, but it&amp;#x27;s clear that we still have a long way to go.&lt;p&gt;Also, enabling global &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; (i.e., &amp;quot;enabling global kill switches for features&amp;quot;) sounds like an incredibly risky idea. One can imagine a bug in a global switch that transforms disabling a feature into disabling an entire system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tristan-morris:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why call .unwrap() in a function which returns Result&amp;lt;_,_&amp;gt;?&lt;p&gt;For something so critical, why aren&amp;#x27;t you using lints to identify and ideally deny panic inducing code. This is one of the biggest strengths of using Rust in the first place for this problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EvanAnderson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It reads a lot like the Crowdstrike SNAFU. Machine-generated configuration file b0rks-up the software that consumes it.&lt;p&gt;The &amp;quot;...was then propagated to all the machines that make up our network...&amp;quot; followed by &amp;quot;....caused the software to fail.&amp;quot; screams for a phased rollout &amp;#x2F; rollback methodology. I get that &amp;quot;...it’s critical that it is rolled out frequently and rapidly as bad actors change their tactics quickly&amp;quot; but today&amp;#x27;s outage highlights that rapid deployment isn&amp;#x27;t all upside.&lt;p&gt;The remediation section doesn&amp;#x27;t give me any sense that phased deployment, acceptance testing, and rapid rollback are part of the planned remediation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gucci-on-fleek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; This showed up to Internet users trying to access our customers&amp;#x27; sites as an error page indicating a failure within Cloudflare&amp;#x27;s network.&lt;p&gt;As a visitor to random web pages, I definitely appreciated this—much better than their completely false “checking the security of your connection” message.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The issue was not caused, directly or indirectly, by a cyber attack or malicious activity of any kind. Instead, it was triggered by a change to one of our database systems&amp;#x27; permissions&lt;p&gt;Also appreciate the honesty here.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; On 18 November 2025 at 11:20 UTC (all times in this blog are UTC), Cloudflare&amp;#x27;s network began experiencing significant failures to deliver core network traffic. […]&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Core traffic was largely flowing as normal by 14:30. We worked over the next few hours to mitigate increased load on various parts of our network as traffic rushed back online. As of 17:06 all systems at Cloudflare were functioning as normal.&lt;p&gt;Why did this take so long to resolve? I read through the entire article, and I understand &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; the outage happened, but when most of the network goes down, why wasn&amp;#x27;t the first step to revert any recent configuration changes, even ones that seem unrelated to the outage? (Or did I just misread something and this was explained somewhere?)&lt;p&gt;Of course, the correct solution is always obvious in retrospect, and it&amp;#x27;s impressive that it only took 7 minutes between the start of the outage and the incident being investigated, but it taking a further 4 hours to resolve the problem and 8 hours total for everything to be back to normal isn&amp;#x27;t great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SerCe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As always, kudos for releasing a post mortem in less than 24 hours after the outage, very few tech organisations are capable of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.cloudflare.com/18-november-2025-outage/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973709</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Heineman – from homelessness to porting Doom</title>
      <link>https://corecursive.com/doomed-to-fail-with-burger-becky/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction Adam: Hi. ” It’s like, “Didn’t have enough space, didn’t have enough time. Becky: Honestly, there’s truth to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973573"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://corecursive.com/doomed-to-fail-with-burger-becky/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ddasdsasdkjasdj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s a wonderful interview with Rebecca that goes into a lot of detail about her experiences as a trans person in the 80&amp;#x27;s and 90&amp;#x27;s. She said she doesn&amp;#x27;t like to talk about those things too much because she&amp;#x27;d rather be admired than pitied, but the context makes her accomplishments more remarkable considering she played life on hard mode for a while.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=8SyIL6zAmhA" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=8SyIL6zAmhA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QuantumAtom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;May her memory be a blessing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;welcome_dragon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;She passed away. There&amp;#x27;s another story on HN about it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jonny_eh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Rebecca is currently fighting cancer and has a gofundme: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.gofundme.com&amp;#x2F;f&amp;#x2F;help-rebecca-ann-heineman-fight-aggressive-cancer" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.gofundme.com&amp;#x2F;f&amp;#x2F;help-rebecca-ann-heineman-fight-a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;She&amp;#x27;s very close to her goal!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cognitive-sci:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LarsDu88:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Did not realize the cofounder of Interplay also ported Doom for the 3DO. Looking at Fabien Sanglard&amp;#x27;s Doom Blackbook (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fabiensanglard.net&amp;#x2F;b&amp;#x2F;gebbdoom.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fabiensanglard.net&amp;#x2F;b&amp;#x2F;gebbdoom.pdf&lt;/a&gt;), I just now noticed that Heineman actually provided some behind-the-scenes promotional photos to that book!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fud101:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an old episode and from memory it was a good one but this year Corerecursive fell off hard. His most recent episode was the worst one yet - completely awful, somehow worse than that single mono episode of him talking about AI (oh my god a Podcaster talking about AI as if he has something interesting to say about it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://corecursive.com/doomed-to-fail-with-burger-becky/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973573</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blender 5.0</title>
      <link>https://www.blender.org/download/releases/5-0/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.blender.org/download/releases/5-0/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45972519</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The code and open-source tools I used to produce a science fiction anthology</title>
      <link>https://compellingsciencefiction.com/posts/the-code-and-open-source-tools-i-used-to-produce-a-science-fiction-anthology.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;yaml # Central tracking file markets. yaml reactor-magazine/ larson_breathing. 5%) asimovs-magazine: 2 stories (12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968121"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://compellingsciencefiction.com/posts/the-code-and-open-source-tools-i-used-to-produce-a-science-fiction-anthology.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thangalin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I developed my Markdown editor, KeenWrite[0], to replace the shell scripts described in the Typesetting Markdown series[1]. KeenWrite takes in YAML document metadata (for variables), (R) Markdown documents, and generates XHTML. The XHTML is passed to ConTeXt[2] for PDF typesetting.&lt;p&gt;A feature matrix[3] compares various text formats and ecosystems for generating PDF files.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;keenwrite.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;keenwrite.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dave.autonoma.ca&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2019&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;22&amp;#x2F;typesetting-markdown-part-1&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dave.autonoma.ca&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2019&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;22&amp;#x2F;typesetting-markdow...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;wiki.contextgarden.net" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;wiki.contextgarden.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;keenwrite.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;feature-matrix&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;keenwrite.com&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;08&amp;#x2F;feature-matrix&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m-hodges:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very cool! How does licensing work with the included stories? What tools or systems contributed to the success of managing that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A_D_E_P_T:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s quite an achievement.&lt;p&gt;I was once interested in publishing a SF anthology.  Formatting and editing was nbd -- I was going to use Amazon&amp;#x27;s KDP software package for most of it, which can take a .docx and output an ebook in 5 minutes.  I&amp;#x27;ve done it before for non-anthology books I&amp;#x27;ve published, and it couldn&amp;#x27;t be easier, though I understand why people might avoid Amazon in this day and age.&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; trouble was getting the rights to all of the different stories!  Though everybody I was able to get in touch with was great -- in particular, Peter Watts, Alan Dean Foster, David Moles, and Walter Jon Williams -- many authors were totally impossible to reach!  I ended up scrapping the idea after a few stories I was intent on collecting in the anthology were unobtainable.  (And this after I had already paid an initial sum to many of the authors.)  Finding alternates and embarking on more contract negotiations just seemed like too much work.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I bought your anthology, will review when I&amp;#x27;m done reading, and sincerely respect the hard work that went into it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;__mharrison__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I did this 10 or so years ago when I taught an ebook course to elementary students.&lt;p&gt;We learned about ebooks, HTML, and they each write a short story, which was included in an ebook (and a physical book).&lt;p&gt;Pretty amazing the tools we have access to. Of course, now I would use typst instead of latex for the physical book part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://compellingsciencefiction.com/posts/the-code-and-open-source-tools-i-used-to-produce-a-science-fiction-anthology.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968121</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucent 7 R/E 5ESS Telephone Switch Rescue</title>
      <link>http://kev009.com/wp/2024/07/Lucent-5ESS-Rescue/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next step will be to acquire some AC and DC power distribution equipment, which will have to wait for my funds to recover. I will have to reduce the size of the system quite a bit for power and space reasons so will have spare parts to sell or trade. comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973955"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://kev009.com/wp/2024/07/Lucent-5ESS-Rescue/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CaliforniaKarl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(2024), but still a good read!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakedata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Visiting Bletchley Park and seeing step-by-step telephone switching equipment repurposed for computing re-enforced my appreciation for the brilliance of the telecommunication systems we created in the past 150 years. Packet switching was inevitable and IP everything makes sense in today&amp;#x27;s world, but something was lost in that transition too. I am glad to see that enthusiasts with the will and means are working to preserve some of that history. -Posted from SC2025-&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;g-mork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Talk about a gargantuan project.. also awesome to bag such a thing. He&amp;#x27;s lucky to even have the resources to store^W warehouse it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yborg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder how many operating 5ESS are left now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kev009.com/wp/2024/07/Lucent-5ESS-Rescue/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973955</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini 3 Pro Model Card [pdf]</title>
      <link>https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-media/Model-Cards/Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;��K� endstream endobj 4 0 obj &lt;&gt; stream x���1 �Om ���� endstream endobj 6 0 obj &lt;&gt; stream x��ڱ A@���k�ά�j���T0 � ��k`7ޫ�'˰����p;g'@mS|��(m��. ����x_g����Sv�|d@u��(�$�1�D0��:t����N6`о;�sO� endstream endobj 13 0 obj &lt;&gt; stream x��yP���u��3mӦ�N�Lc������3�L;�鴝(�iL4�hsz��ʹ�$F���J&lt;8Q�p#" X�e9��X�e�=�&amp;��}���]$�Z�~K��3;/�}f&gt;�/���&lt;��9�n�4��m1���3��#��v�pP� �3�pt���� £x��p�� X�G9�N�. �����CxJ��hq�p������ �=e|P endstream endobj 14 0 obj &lt;&gt; stream x���sg��G 5�wy��}s�_;�X�%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963670"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-media/Model-Cards/Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ks2048:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why is this linking to a random site? Here is a link hosted by Google:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Ge...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;butlike:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s over. I just don&amp;#x27;t care anymore. I don&amp;#x27;t care what a pro model card is. I don&amp;#x27;t care what a humanity&amp;#x27;s last exam is. I don&amp;#x27;t care if the response makes me feel good about the prompt I made. I don&amp;#x27;t care if it&amp;#x27;s sentient. I don&amp;#x27;t care if it&amp;#x27;s secretly sentient. I don&amp;#x27;t care if it&amp;#x27;s just a machine. I don&amp;#x27;t care if the gov&amp;#x27;t has appropriated a secret model. I don&amp;#x27;t care if this is the precursor to AGI, ASI, AGGI, AGGSISGIGIG....I just. Don&amp;#x27;t. care.&lt;p&gt;And I really don&amp;#x27;t think I&amp;#x27;m alone in this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eric15342335:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Update: it is available at &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aistudio.google.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aistudio.google.com&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aliljet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s wild here is that among every single score they&amp;#x27;ve absolutely killed, somehow, Anthropic and Claude Sonnet 4.5 have won a single victory in the fight: SWE Bench Verified and only by a singular point.&lt;p&gt;I already enjoy Gemini 2.5 pro for planning and if Gemini 3 is priced similarly, I&amp;#x27;ll be incredibly happy to ditch the painfully pricey Claude max subscription. To be fair, I&amp;#x27;ve already got an extremely sour taste in my mouth from the last Anthropic bait and switch on pricing and usage, so happy to see Google take the crown here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;robert-zaremba:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The strategic move to use TPU rather than Nvidia is paying well for Google. They are able to better utilize their existing large infrastructure, but also specialize the processes and pipelines for their own framework that they use to create and train models.&lt;p&gt;I think a specialized hardware for training models is the next big wave in China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koakuma-chan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Gemini 3 Pro was trained using Google’s Tensor Processing Units (TPUs)&lt;p&gt;NVDA is down 3.26%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topfi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Additional context from AI Studio including pricing:&lt;p&gt;Our most intelligent model with SOTA reasoning and multimodal understanding, and powerful agentic and vibe coding capabilities&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;=200K tokens • Input: $2,00 &amp;#x2F; Output: $12,00&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; 200K tokens • Input: $4,00 &amp;#x2F; Output: $18,00&lt;p&gt;Knowledge cut off: Jan. 2025&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One benchmark I would really like to see: instruction adherence.&lt;p&gt;For example, the frontier models of early-to-mid 2024 could reliably follow what seemed to be 20-30 instructions. As you gave more instructions than that in your prompt, the LLMs started missing some and your outputs became inconsistent and difficult to control.&lt;p&gt;The latest set of models (2.5 Pro, GPT-5, etc) seem to top out somewhere in the 100 range? They are clearly much better at following a laundry list of instructions, but they also clearly have a limit and once your prompt is too large and too specific you lose coherence again.&lt;p&gt;If I had to guess, Gemini 3 Pro has once again pushed the bar, and maybe we&amp;#x27;re up near 250 (haven&amp;#x27;t used it, I&amp;#x27;m just blindly projecting &amp;#x2F; hoping). And that&amp;#x27;s a huge deal! I actually think it would be more helpful to have a model that could consistently follow 1000 custom instructions than it would be to have a model that had 20 more IQ points.&lt;p&gt;I have to imagine you could make some fairly objective benchmarks around this idea, and it would be very helpful from an engineering perspective to see how each model stacked up against the others in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ethmarks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; TPUs are specifically designed to handle the massive computations involved in training LLMs and can speed up training considerably compared to CPUs.&lt;p&gt;That seems like a low bar. Who&amp;#x27;s training frontier LLMs on CPUs? Surely they meant to compare TPUs to GPUs. If &amp;quot;this is faster than a CPU for massively parallel AI training&amp;quot; is the best you can say about it, that&amp;#x27;s not very impressive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fraboniface:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Developments to the model architecture contribute to the significantly improved performance from previous model families.&lt;p&gt;I wonder how significant this is. DeepMind was always more research-oriented that OpenAI, which mostly scaled things up. They may have come up with a significantly better architecture (Transformer MoE still leaves a lot of room).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bemmu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I saw this on Reddit earlier today. Over there the source of this file was given as: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.g...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bucket name &amp;quot;deepmind-media&amp;quot; has been used in the past on the deepmind official site, so it seems legit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mynti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is interesting that the Gemini 3 beats every other model on these benchmarks, mostly by a wide margin, but not on SWE Bench. Sonnet is still king here and all three look to be basically on the same level. Kind of wild to see them hit such a wall when it comes to agentic coding&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mohsen1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     This model is not a modification or a fine-tune of a prior model

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Is that common to mention that? Feels like they built something from scratch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bobaso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting to see on page 2 the reference to ML pathways [1]. Looks like a multi layer mixture of experts. 
Is this common ?&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.google&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;ai&amp;#x2F;introducing-pathways-next-generation-ai-architecture&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.google&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;ai&amp;#x2F;introducing-pathways-next-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;denysvitali:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Title of the document is &amp;quot;[Gemini 3 Pro] External Model Card - November 18, 2025 - v2&amp;quot;, in case you needed further confirmation that the model will be released today.&lt;p&gt;Also interesting to know that Google Antigravity (antigravity.google &amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;Google-Antigravity" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;Google-Antigravity&lt;/a&gt; ?) leaked. I remember seeing this subdomain recently. Probably Gemini 3 related as well.&lt;p&gt;Org was created on 2025-11-04T19:28:13Z (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;api.github.com&amp;#x2F;orgs&amp;#x2F;Google-Antigravity" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;api.github.com&amp;#x2F;orgs&amp;#x2F;Google-Antigravity&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palmik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Archive link: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.g...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lxdlam:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What does the &amp;quot;Google Antigravity&amp;quot; mean? The link is &lt;a href="http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;antigravity.google&amp;#x2F;docs" rel="nofollow"&gt;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;antigravity.google&amp;#x2F;docs&lt;/a&gt;, seemingly a new product but now routing to the Google main page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;transcriptase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There needs to be a sycophancy benchmark in these comparisons. More baseless praise and false agreement = lower score.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;embedding-shape:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Curiously, this website seems to be blocked in Spain for whatever reason, and the website&amp;#x27;s certificate is served by `allot.com&amp;#x2F;emailAddress=info@allot.com` which obviously fails...&lt;p&gt;Anyone happen to know why? Is this website by any change sharing information on safe medical abortions or women&amp;#x27;s rights, something which has gotten websites blocked here before?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oalessandr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Trying to open this link from Italy leads to a CSAM warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scrlk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Benchmarks from page 4 of the model card:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    | Benchmark             | 3 Pro     | 2.5 Pro | Sonnet 4.5 | GPT-5.1   |
    |-----------------------|-----------|---------|------------|-----------|
    | Humanity&amp;#x27;s Last Exam  | 37.5%     | 21.6%   | 13.7%      | 26.5%     |
    | ARC-AGI-2             | 31.1%     | 4.9%    | 13.6%      | 17.6%     |
    | GPQA Diamond          | 91.9%     | 86.4%   | 83.4%      | 88.1%     |
    | AIME 2025             |           |         |            |           |
    |   (no tools)          | 95.0%     | 88.0%   | 87.0%      | 94.0%     |
    |   (code execution)    | 100%      | -       | 100%       | -         |
    | MathArena Apex        | 23.4%     | 0.5%    | 1.6%       | 1.0%      |
    | MMMU-Pro              | 81.0%     | 68.0%   | 68.0%      | 80.8%     |
    | ScreenSpot-Pro        | 72.7%     | 11.4%   | 36.2%      | 3.5%      |
    | CharXiv Reasoning     | 81.4%     | 69.6%   | 68.5%      | 69.5%     |
    | OmniDocBench 1.5      | 0.115     | 0.145   | 0.145      | 0.147     |
    | Video-MMMU            | 87.6%     | 83.6%   | 77.8%      | 80.4%     |
    | LiveCodeBench Pro     | 2,439     | 1,775   | 1,418      | 2,243     |
    | Terminal-Bench 2.0    | 54.2%     | 32.6%   | 42.8%      | 47.6%     |
    | SWE-Bench Verified    | 76.2%     | 59.6%   | 77.2%      | 76.3%     |
    | t2-bench              | 85.4%     | 54.9%   | 84.7%      | 80.2%     |
    | Vending-Bench 2       | $5,478.16 | $573.64 | $3,838.74  | $1,473.43 |
    | FACTS Benchmark Suite | 70.5%     | 63.4%   | 50.4%      | 50.8%     |
    | SimpleQA Verified     | 72.1%     | 54.5%   | 29.3%      | 34.9%     |
    | MMLU                  | 91.8%     | 89.5%   | 89.1%      | 91.0%     |
    | Global PIQA           | 93.4%     | 91.5%   | 90.1%      | 90.9%     |
    | MRCR v2 (8-needle)    |           |         |            |           |
    |   (128k avg)          | 77.0%     | 58.0%   | 47.1%      | 61.6%     |
    |   (1M pointwise)      | 26.3%     | 16.4%   | n&amp;#x2F;s        | n&amp;#x2F;s       |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
n&amp;#x2F;s = not supported&lt;p&gt;EDIT: formatting, hopefully a bit more mobile friendly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;laborcontract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s hilarious that the release of Gemini 3 is getting eclipsed by this cloudflare outage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;patates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It says it&amp;#x27;s been trained from scratch. I wonder if it will have the same undescribable magic that makes me spend an hour every day with 2.5. I really love the results I can get with 2.5 pro. Google eventually limiting aistudio will be a sad day.&lt;p&gt;Also I really hoped for a 2M+ context. I&amp;#x27;m living on the context edge even with 1M.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TheAceOfHearts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They scored a 31.1% on ARC AGI 2 which puts them in first place.&lt;p&gt;Also notable which models they include for comparison: Gemini 2.5 Pro, Claude Sonnet 4.5, and GPT-5.1. That seems like a minor snub against Grok 4 &amp;#x2F; Grok 4.1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meetpateltech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;it was accidentally pushed a little early, and now it has been taken down.&lt;p&gt;here’s the archived pdf:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;Model-Cards&amp;#x2F;Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20251118111103&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.g...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lifthrasiir:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For the veracity of the link itself: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;*" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;storage.googleapis.com&amp;#x2F;deepmind-media&amp;#x2F;*&lt;/a&gt; has been used by DeepMind itself (e.g. &amp;quot;View tech report&amp;quot; in &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;deepmind.google&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;gemini&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) so it is a genuine leak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storage.googleapis.com/deepmind-media/Model-Cards/Gemini-3-Pro-Model-Card.pdf</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963670</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub: Git operation failures</title>
      <link>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/5q7nmlxz30sk</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Resend OTP By subscribing you agree to our Privacy Policy. This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply. By subscribing you agree to our Privacy Policy, the Atlassian Terms of Service, and the Atlassian Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971726"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/5q7nmlxz30sk'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 29 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h4kunamata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;With Microsoft (Behind GitHub) going full AI mode, expected things to get worse.&lt;p&gt;I worked for one of the largest company in my country, they had &amp;quot;catch-up&amp;quot; with GitHub and it is not longer about GitHub as you folks are used to but AI aka CoPilot.&lt;p&gt;We are seeing major techs such as but not limited to Google, AWS and Azure going under after making public that their code is 30% AI generated (Google).&lt;p&gt;Even Xbox(Microsoft) and its gaming studio got destroyed (COD BO7) for heavily dependency on AI.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t you find it coincidence all of these system outage worldwide happening right after they proudly shared heavily dependency on AI??&lt;p&gt;Companies aren&amp;#x27;t using AI&amp;#x2F;ML to improve processes but to replace people, full stop.
The AI stock market is having a massive meltdown as we speak with indications that the AI bubble went live.&lt;p&gt;If you as a company wanna keep your productivity at 99.99% from now on:&lt;p&gt;* GitLab: Self-hosted GitLab&amp;#x2F;runners
* Datacenter: AWS&amp;#x2F;GCP&amp;#x2F;Azure is no longer a safe option or cheaper, we have data center companies such as Equinix which have a massive backup plan in place. 
I have visited one, they are prepared for a nuclear war and I am not even being dramatic.
If I was starting a new company in 2025, I would go back to datacenter over AWS&amp;#x2F;GCP&amp;#x2F;Azure
* Self-host everything you can, and no, it does not require 5 days in the office to manage all of that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grepfru_it:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There was a comment on another GitHub thread that I replied to. I got a response saying it’s absurd how unreliable Gh is when people depend on it for CI&amp;#x2F;CD. And I think this is the problem. At GitHub the developers think it’s only a problem because &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; ci&amp;#x2F;cd is failing. Oh no, we broke GitHub actions, the actions runners team is going to be mad at us! Instead of, oh no, we broke GitHub actions, half the world is down!&lt;p&gt;That larger view held only by a small sliver of employees is likely why reliability is not a concern. That leads to the every team for themselves mentality. “It’s not our problem, and we won’t make it our problem so we don’t get dinged at review time” (ok that is Microsoft attitude leaking)&lt;p&gt;Then there’s their entrenched status. Real talk, no one is leaving GitHub. So customers will suck it up and live with it while angry employees grumble on an online forum. I saw this same attitude in major companies like Verio and Verisign in the early 2000s. “Yeah we’re down but who else are you going to go to? Have a 20% discount since you complained. We will only be 1% less profitable this quarter due to it” The kang and kodos argument personified.&lt;p&gt;These views are my own and not related to my employer or anyone associated with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JonChesterfield:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What&amp;#x27;s the local workaround for this?&lt;p&gt;Git is distributed, it should be possible to put something between our servers and github which pulls from github when it&amp;#x27;s running and otherwise serves whatever it used to have. A cache of some sort. I&amp;#x27;ve found the five year old &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;jonasmalacofilho&amp;#x2F;git-cache-http-server" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;jonasmalacofilho&amp;#x2F;git-cache-http-server&lt;/a&gt; which is the same sort of idea.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve run a git instance on a local machine which I pull from, where a cron job fetches from upstream into it, which solved the problem of cloning llvm over a slow connection, so it&amp;#x27;s doable on a per-repo basis.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d like to replace it globally though because CI looks like &amp;quot;pull from loads of different git repos&amp;quot; and setting it up once per-repo seems dreadful. Once per github&amp;#x2F;gitlab would be a big step forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;captainkrtek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reflecting on the last decade, with my career spanning big tech and startups, I&amp;#x27;ve seen a common arch:&lt;p&gt;Small and scrappy startup -&amp;gt; taking on bigger customers for greater profits &amp;#x2F; ARR -&amp;gt; re-architecting for &amp;quot;enterprise&amp;quot; customers and resiliency &amp;#x2F; scale -&amp;gt; more idealism in engineering -&amp;gt; profit chasing -&amp;gt; product bloat -&amp;gt; good engineers leave -&amp;gt; replaced by other engineers -&amp;gt; failures expand.&lt;p&gt;This may be an acceptable lifecycle for individual companies as they each follow the destiny of chasing profits ultimately. Now picture it though for all the companies we&amp;#x27;ve architected on top of (AWS, CloudFlare, GCP, etc.) Even within these larger organizations, they are comprised of multiple little businesses (eg: EC2 is its own business effectively - people wise, money wise)&lt;p&gt;Having worked at a $big_cloud_provider for 7 yrs, I saw this internally on a service level. What started as a foundational service, grew in scale, complexity, and architected for resiliency, slowly eroded its engineering culture to chase profits. Fundamental services becoming skeletons of their former selves, all while holding up the internet.&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;#x27;t a singular cause here, and I can&amp;#x27;t say I know what&amp;#x27;s best, but it&amp;#x27;s concerning as the internet becomes more centralized into a handful of players.&lt;p&gt;tldr: how much of one&amp;#x27;s architecture and resiliency is built on the trust of &amp;quot;well (AWS|GCP|CloudFlare) is too big to fail&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;they must be doing things really well&amp;quot;? The various providers are not all that different from other tech companies on the inside. Politics, pressure, profit seeking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agnishom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(epistemic status: frustrated, irrational)&lt;p&gt;This is what happens when they decide that all the budget should be spent on AI stuff rather than solid infra and devops&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aeldidi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m becoming concerned with the rate at which major software systems seem to be failing as of late. For context, last year I only logged four outages that actually disrupted my work; this quarter alone I&amp;#x27;m already on my fourth, all within the past few weeks. This is, of course, just an anecdote and not evidence of any wider trend (not to mention that I might not have even logged everything last year), but it was enough to nudge me into writing this today (helped by the fact that I suddenly had some downtime). Keep in mind, this isn&amp;#x27;t necessarily specific to this outage, just something that&amp;#x27;s been on my mind enough to warrant writing about it.&lt;p&gt;It feels like resiliency is becoming a bit of a lost art in networked software. I&amp;#x27;ve spent a good chunk of this year chasing down intermittent failures at work, and I really underestimated how much work goes into shrinking the &amp;quot;blast radius&amp;quot;, so to speak, of any bug or outage. Even though we mostly run a monolith, we still depend on a bunch of external pieces like daemons, databases, Redis, S3, monitoring, and third-party integrations, and we generally assume that these things are present and working in most places, which wasn&amp;#x27;t always the case. My response was to better document the failure conditions, and once I did, realize that there was many more than we initially thought. Since then we&amp;#x27;ve done things like: move some things to a VPS instead of cloud services, automate deployment more than we already had, greatly improve the test suite and docs to include these newly considered failure conditions, and generally cut down on moving parts. It was a ton of effort, but the payoff has finally shown up: our records show fewer surprises which means fewer distractions and a much calmer system overall. Without that unglamorous work, things would&amp;#x27;ve only grown more fragile as complexity crept in. And I worry that, more broadly, we&amp;#x27;re slowly un-learning how to build systems that stay up even when the inevitable bug or failure shows up.&lt;p&gt;For completeness, here are the outages that prompted this: the AWS us-east-1 outage in October (took down the Lightspeed R series API), the Azure Front Door outage (prevented Playwright from downloading browsers for tests), today’s Cloudflare outage (took down Lightspeed’s website, which some of our clients rely on), and the Github outage affecting basically everyone who uses it as their git host.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whinvik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Haha I don&amp;#x27;t know if its a good test or not but I could not figure out why git pull was failing and Claude just went crazy trying so many random things.&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Pro after 3 random things announced Github was the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bstsb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;side effect that isn&amp;#x27;t immediately obvious: all raw.githubusercontent.com content responds with a &amp;quot;404: Not Found&amp;quot; response.&lt;p&gt;this has broken a few pipeline jobs for me, seems like they&amp;#x27;re underplaying this incident&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;netsharc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I remember a colleague setting up a CI&amp;#x2F;CD system (on an aaS obviously) depending on Docker, npm, and who knows what else... I thought &amp;quot;I wonder what % of time all those systems are actually up at the same time&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;consumer451:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We live in a house of cards. I hope that eventually people in power realize this. However, their incentive structures do not seem to be a forcing function for that eventuality.&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about this a lot lately. What would be a tweak that might improve this situation?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OptionOfT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is insane how many failures we&amp;#x27;ve been getting lately, especially related to actions.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * jobs not being picked up
    * jobs not being able to be cancelled
    * jobs running but showing up as failed
    * jobs showing up as failed but not running
    * jobs showing containers as pushed successfully to GitHub&amp;#x27;s registry, but then we get errors while pulling them
    * ID token failures (E_FAIL) and timeouts. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I don&amp;#x27;t know if this is related to GitHub moving to Azure, or because they&amp;#x27;re allowing more AI generated code to pass through without proper reviews, or something else, but as a paying customer I am not happy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mendyberger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;After restarting my computer, reinstalling git, almost ready to reinstall my os, I find out it&amp;#x27;s not even my fault&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mandus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good thing git was designed as a decentralized revision control system, so you don’t really need GitHub. It’s just a nice convenience&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keepamovin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s weird to think all of our data lives on physical servers (not &amp;quot;in the cloud&amp;quot;) that are falliable and made and maintained by falliable humans, and could fail at any moment. So long to all the data! Good ol&amp;#x27; byzantine backups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SteveNuts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have a serious question, not trying to start a flame war.&lt;p&gt;A. Are these major issues with cloud&amp;#x2F;SaaS tools becoming more common, or is it just that they get a lot more coverage now? It seems like we see major issues across AWS, GCP, Azure, Github, etc. at least monthly now and I don&amp;#x27;t remember that being the case in the past.&lt;p&gt;B. If it&amp;#x27;s becoming more common, what are the reasons? I can think of a few, but I don&amp;#x27;t know the answer, so if anyone in-the-know has insight I&amp;#x27;d appreciate it.&lt;p&gt;Operations budget cuts&amp;#x2F;layoffs?
Replacing critical components&amp;#x2F;workflows with AI?
Just overall growing pains, where a service has outgrown what it was engineered for?&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;silverwind:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not only http, also ssh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lol768:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; We are seeing failures for some git http operations and are investigating&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not just HTTPS, I can&amp;#x27;t push via SSH either.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not convinced it&amp;#x27;s just &amp;quot;some&amp;quot; operations either; every single one I&amp;#x27;ve tried fails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dadof4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Same for me, fatal: unable to access &amp;#x27;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;repository_example.git&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;repository_example.git&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x27;: The requested URL returned error: 500&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_jab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;GitHub is pretty easily the most unreliable service I&amp;#x27;ve used in the past five years. Is GitLab better in this regard? At this point my trust in GitHub is essentially zero - they don&amp;#x27;t deserve my money any longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chrsstrm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I thought I was going crazy when I couldn&amp;#x27;t push changes but now it seems it&amp;#x27;s time to just call it for the day. Back at it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;laurentiurad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A lot of failures lately during the aI ReVoLuTiOn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;personjerry:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks like Gemini 3 figured out the best way to save costs on its compute time was to shut down github!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kennysmoothx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;FYI in an emergency you can edit files directly on Github without the need to use git.&lt;p&gt;Edit: ugh... if you rely on GH Actions for workflows though actions&amp;#x2F;checkout@v4 is also currently experiencing the git issues, so no dice if you depend on that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sgreene570:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;github has had a few of these as of late, starting to get old&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cjonas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I didn&amp;#x27;t really want to work today anyways.  First cloudflare, now this... Seems like a sign to get some fresh air&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JLCarveth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The last outage was a whole 5 days ago &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45915731"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45915731&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arbol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m also getting this. Cannot pull or push but can authenticate with SSH&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    myrepo git:(fix&amp;#x2F;context-types-settings) gp
    ERROR: user:1234567:user
    fatal: Could not read from remote repository.

    myrepo git:(fix&amp;#x2F;context-types-settings) ssh -o ProxyCommand=none git@github.com
    PTY allocation request failed on channel 0
    Hi user! You&amp;#x27;ve successfully authenticated, but GitHub does not provide shell access.
    Connection to github.com closed.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bhouston:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I cannot push&amp;#x2F;pull to any repos.  Scared me for a second, but of course I then checked here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shooker435:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.githubstatus.com&amp;#x2F;incidents&amp;#x2F;5q7nmlxz30sk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.githubstatus.com&amp;#x2F;incidents&amp;#x2F;5q7nmlxz30sk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;it&amp;#x27;s up now (the incident, not the outage)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/5q7nmlxz30sk</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971726</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues</title>
      <link>https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/8gmgl950y3h7</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Posted Nov 18, 2025 - 19:28 UTC Update Cloudflare services are currently operating normally. Posted Nov 18, 2025 - 13:04 UTC Update We are continuing to investigate this issue. Posted Nov 18, 2025 - 12:53 UTC Update We are continuing to investigate this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963780"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/8gmgl950y3h7'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tethys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This incident has been resolved.
Posted 4 minutes ago. Nov 18, 2025 - 19:28 UTC&lt;p&gt;Better link for chroniclers, since the incident is now buried pretty far down on the status page: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cloudflarestatus.com&amp;#x2F;incidents&amp;#x2F;8gmgl950y3h7" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cloudflarestatus.com&amp;#x2F;incidents&amp;#x2F;8gmgl950y3h7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aavshr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; In short, a latent bug in a service underpinning our bot mitigation capability started to crash after a routine configuration change we made. That cascaded into a broad degradation to our network and other services. This was not an attack.&lt;p&gt;From the CTO, Source: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;dok2001&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1990791419653484646" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;dok2001&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1990791419653484646&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;r721:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Quote from The Guardian&amp;#x27;s story:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;A spokesperson for Cloudflare said: “We saw a spike in unusual traffic to one of Cloudflare’s services beginning at 11.20am. That caused some traffic passing through Cloudflare’s network to experience errors. While most traffic for most services continued to flow as normal, there were elevated errors across multiple Cloudflare services.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;“We do not yet know the cause of the spike in unusual traffic. We are all hands on deck to make sure all traffic is served without errors. After that, we will turn our attention to investigating the cause of the unusual spike in traffic.”&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theguardian.com&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;nov&amp;#x2F;18&amp;#x2F;cloudflare-outage-causes-error-messages-across-the-internet" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theguardian.com&amp;#x2F;technology&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;nov&amp;#x2F;18&amp;#x2F;cloudflar...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;djfobbz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’d rather mitigate a DDoS attack on my own servers than deal with Cloudflare. Having to prove you’re human is the second-worst thing on my list, right after accepting cookies. Those two things alone have made browsing the web a worse experience than it was in the late 90s or early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abelanger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If anyone needs commands for turning off the CF proxy for their domains and happens to have a Cloudflare API token.&lt;p&gt;First you can grab the zone ID via:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET &amp;quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;api.cloudflare.com&amp;#x2F;client&amp;#x2F;v4&amp;#x2F;zones&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application&amp;#x2F;json&amp;quot; | jq -r &amp;#x27;.result[] | &amp;quot;\(.id) \(.name)&amp;quot;&amp;#x27;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
And a list of DNS records using:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET &amp;quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;api.cloudflare.com&amp;#x2F;client&amp;#x2F;v4&amp;#x2F;zones&amp;#x2F;$ZONE_ID&amp;#x2F;dns_records&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application&amp;#x2F;json&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Each DNS record will have an ID associated. Finally patch the relevant records:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X PATCH &amp;quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;api.cloudflare.com&amp;#x2F;client&amp;#x2F;v4&amp;#x2F;zones&amp;#x2F;$ZONE_ID&amp;#x2F;dns_records&amp;#x2F;$RECORD_ID&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN&amp;quot; -H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application&amp;#x2F;json&amp;quot; --data &amp;#x27;{&amp;quot;proxied&amp;quot;:false}&amp;#x27;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Copying from a sibling comment - some warnings:&lt;p&gt;- SSL&amp;#x2F;TLS: You will likely lose your Cloudflare-provided SSL certificate. Your site will only work if your origin server has its own valid certificate.&lt;p&gt;- Security &amp;amp; Performance: You will lose the performance benefits (caching, minification, global edge network) and security protections (DDoS mitigation, WAF) that Cloudflare provides.&lt;p&gt;- This will also reveal your backend internal IP addresses. Anyone can find permanent logs of public IP addresses used by even obscure domain names, so potential adversaries don&amp;#x27;t necessarily have to be paying attention at the exact right time to find it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mulhoon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I know this is bad, and some people&amp;#x27;s livelihood and lives rely on critical infrastructure, but when these things happen, I sometimes think GOOD!, let&amp;#x27;s all just take a breather for a minute yeh? Go outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rzerowan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One  of the things that i didnt like about cloudflare MITM as a service is their requirement if you want SSL&amp;#x2F;CDN that you must use their DNS.
Overconcentration of infra within one single pint of disruption with no easy outs when the stack tips over.
Sadly i dont see any changes or rethink to be more decentralised  even after this outage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rgilton:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What would the Internet&amp;#x27;s architecture have to look like for DDOS&amp;#x27;ing to be a thing of the past, and therefore Cloudflare to not be needed?&lt;p&gt;I know there are solutions like IPFS out there for doing distributed&amp;#x2F;decentralised static content distribution, but that seems like only part of the problem.  There are obviously more types of operation that occur via the network -- e.g. transactions with single remote pieces of equipment etc, which by their nature cannot be decentralised.&lt;p&gt;Anyone know of research out there into changing the way that packet-routing&amp;#x2F;switching works so that &amp;#x27;DDOS&amp;#x27; just isn&amp;#x27;t a thing?  Of course I appreciate there are a lot of things to get right in that!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dvcoolarun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There was an article on HN a few days back about how companies like this are influencing the overall freedom of the web (I missed the source) and their own way of doing things. Other examples of influence I see similarly are of Vercel, like with enterprise. Even a few days back, we saw AWS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shuddown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wanted to check if it was DNS again but &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;isitdns.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;isitdns.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; is also down…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neop1x:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Your origin servers are protected now as no one can access them. Thanks for choosing CloudFlare&amp;#x27;s MITM &amp;quot;protection&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DASD:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting(unnerving?) to see a number of domain registrars that offer their own DNS services utilize at least some kind of Cloudflare service for at least their own web fronts.  Did a check on 6 registrar sites I currently interact with and half were down(Namecheap&amp;#x2F;Spaceship, Name, Dynadot) and up(Porkbun, Gandi, GoDaddy).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ropable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s something maliciously satisfying about seeing your own self-hosted stuff working while things behind Cloudflare or AWS are broken. Sure, they have like four more nines that me, but right now I&amp;#x27;m sitting pretty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lordofgibbons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How did we get to a place where either Cloudflare or AWS having an outage means a large part of the web going down? This centralization is very worrying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wiradikusuma:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used to say, &amp;quot;Don&amp;#x27;t worry, we host it on Cloudflare. If it&amp;#x27;s down, then 30% internet is down. It&amp;#x27;s highly unlikely.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Well...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;misswaterfairy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; During our attempts to remediate, we have disabled WARP [their VPN service] access in London.  Users in London trying to access the Internet via WARP will see a failure to connect.
Posted 4 minutes ago. Nov 18, 2025 - 13:04 UTC&lt;p&gt;Is Cloudflare being attacked...?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;madjam002:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Can&amp;#x27;t even change my nameservers away from Cloudflare as Namecheap use Cloudflare!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrouteMinou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do you remember when the Internet was redundant and resilient?&lt;p&gt;It seems 20% of the Internet is down every two weeks now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rco8786:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it me or has there been a very noticeable uptick in large scale infra-level outages lately? AWS, Cloudflare, etc have all been way under whatever SLA they publish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rollulus:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Classic. I see issues. Vendor’s status page is all green. Go to HN to find the confirmation. Applies to AWS, GH, everyone.&lt;p&gt;Edit: beautiful, this decentralised design of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virajk_31:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was shouting at network guy&amp;#x2F;colleague, how come challenges.cloudflare.com got blocked!! damn, I must apologise to him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;djsjajah:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I went to check how many services are being impacted on down detector, but it was down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;farhadhf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Pretty much everything is down (checking from the Netherlands). The Cloudflare dashboard itself is experiencing an outage as well.&lt;p&gt;Not-so-funny thing is that the Betterstack dashboard is down but our status page hosted by Betterstack is up, and we can&amp;#x27;t access the dashboard to create an incident and let our customers know what&amp;#x27;s going on.&lt;p&gt;Edit: wording.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jamesnorden:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And no lesson about single point of failure and centralization was learned that day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vinishbhaskar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tried checking Cloudflare’s status on Downdetector, but Downdetector was also behind Cloudflare. Internet checkmate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gwd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I do appreciate the visual &amp;quot;mea culpa&amp;quot;:&lt;p&gt;Your browser: Working&lt;p&gt;Host:  Working&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare: Error&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mojah:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interestingly, also noticing that websites that use Cloudflare Challenge (aka &amp;quot;I&amp;#x27;m not a Robot&amp;quot;) are also throwing exceptions with a message as &amp;quot;Please unblock challenges.cloudflare.com to proceed&amp;quot; - even though it&amp;#x27;s just responding with an HTTP&amp;#x2F;500.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bratao:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The danger of Internet centralization in Cloudflare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;itzjacki:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A colleague of mine just came bursting through my office door in a panic, thinking he brought our site down since this happened just as he made some changes to our Cloudflare config. He was pretty relieved to see this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;its_notjack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ironically, DownDetector seems to be down because it protects its site with Cloudflare Turnstile... which is also down!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cloudflarestatus.com/incidents/8gmgl950y3h7</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963780</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am stepping down as the CEO of Mastodon</title>
      <link>https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2025/11/my-next-chapter-with-mastodon/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;But it would be uncouth for me to pretend that there isn’t some self-interest involved. Some things chip faster. But I’m also aware that my aversion to public appearances cost Mastodon some opportunities in publicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969909"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2025/11/my-next-chapter-with-mastodon/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 24 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;metabagel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would love to love Mastodon, but discoverability was so incredibly difficult that I just gave up. I can find people and topics so much more easily on Bluesky. The starter packs are nice too.&lt;p&gt;Does Mastodon have starter packs (lists of people to follow posting on a particular subject area, which ideally you could just click once and follow everyone)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;glenstein:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is an indescribably devastating loss for a project that, whatever its imperfections, can fairly lay claim to the most intellectually consistent and sincere adherence to FOSS, privacy, and decentralization of any major social media project. Eugene has proven a spectacular and indispensable developer, and I don&amp;#x27;t know that Mastodon has the ability to move on without him. I want to praise Eugen but the uncomfortable truth is I think Mastodon as a project may not recover from losing him. Though I hope to be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;swaggerist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does Jeff Bezos even dress well?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10 years leading. I would have fatigued.&lt;p&gt;Mastodon needs to push for more activity and users though. I kind of know what it is, but I am not really using it. We could need, say, some replacement of Twitter-owned-by-billionaires.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thih9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; and transferring my ownership of the trademark and other assets to the Mastodon non-profit&lt;p&gt;This is refreshing and exemplary; especially in the light of recent wordpress, rubygems, or similar power struggle dramas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rmoriz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My mastodon account on mastodon.social (the official instance of Mastodon gGmbH) was deleted without a reason after I criticized the former GDR. Not going to donate another €100 this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keybored:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; I have so much passion for Mastodon and the fediverse. The fediverse is an island within an increasingly dystopian capitalist hellscape. And from my perspective, Mastodon is our best shot at bringing this vision of a better future to the masses. This is why I’m sticking around, albeit in a more advisory, and less public, role.&lt;p&gt;Wait ’til the masses hear about this one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ants_everywhere:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mastodon seems pretty unhealthy to me.&lt;p&gt;I logged in for the first time in months a few days ago and it was mostly angry memes, a surprising number of which were celebrating violence and murder. This is despite me aggressively muting people who post that sort of thing.&lt;p&gt;I hope they find a niche, but the cultural damage may already be done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arjie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;I steer clear of showing vulnerability online, but there was a particularly bad interaction with a user last summer that made me realise that I need to take a step back and find a healthier relationship with the project, ultimately serving as the impetus to begin this restructuring process.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of these microblogging sites seem to be populated by people with extreme views. One of the pleasant things about old Internet forums is that they were like a local bar: there&amp;#x27;s some kind of community with some local code there. Reddit etc. function like forum aggregators and get halfway there, but the microblogging sites seem like a completely flat layer. There isn&amp;#x27;t really a community sense there.&lt;p&gt;Twitter used to have SimClusters[0] but either they decided against that or the tech as it was no longer functions to prevent context escape.&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;#x27;ve found that I end up being &amp;#x27;infected&amp;#x27; by these angry people and I also post outrageous nonsense in response - so there&amp;#x27;s some sort of virality to this behaviour. I stopped using Twitter around the time of the Charlie Kirk killing because I figured that everything was going to get twice as inflamed as it already was and it was honestly worse than I actually wanted anyway.&lt;p&gt;The other day I went to the For You tab and I was struck by how insane it seemed to me. A few days away and suddenly everything looks ridiculous. I have noticed that I do have these interactions on Hacker News as well, so I wrote up a quick server and Chrome extension to filter out people who comment things that infuriate me and HN has gotten so much better (and consequently I am better too).&lt;p&gt;I do like microblogging. It scratches a different itch. But I haven&amp;#x27;t figured out whether I should run my own Mastodon server or my own ATProto PDS and, to be honest, when I browse those sites the front page makes me not feel like I want to be part of those communities.&lt;p&gt;Mastodon has [1][2][3] as the top few posts. Blue Sky is better but among the top five are these [4][5] and I really am not that interested in all this outrage-mongering.&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.x.com&amp;#x2F;engineering&amp;#x2F;en_us&amp;#x2F;topics&amp;#x2F;open-source&amp;#x2F;2023&amp;#x2F;twitter-recommendation-algorithm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.x.com&amp;#x2F;engineering&amp;#x2F;en_us&amp;#x2F;topics&amp;#x2F;open-source&amp;#x2F;2023...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;infosec.exchange&amp;#x2F;@0xabad1dea&amp;#x2F;115572086526058545" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;infosec.exchange&amp;#x2F;@0xabad1dea&amp;#x2F;115572086526058545&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tech.lgbt&amp;#x2F;@Natasha_Jay&amp;#x2F;115572233358693165" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tech.lgbt&amp;#x2F;@Natasha_Jay&amp;#x2F;115572233358693165&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;universeodon.com&amp;#x2F;@georgetakei&amp;#x2F;115572239317649349" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;universeodon.com&amp;#x2F;@georgetakei&amp;#x2F;115572239317649349&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;4: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bsky.app&amp;#x2F;profile&amp;#x2F;wendyjfox.bsky.social&amp;#x2F;post&amp;#x2F;3m5tz3fafpk2n" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bsky.app&amp;#x2F;profile&amp;#x2F;wendyjfox.bsky.social&amp;#x2F;post&amp;#x2F;3m5tz3fa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;5: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bsky.app&amp;#x2F;profile&amp;#x2F;forbes.com&amp;#x2F;post&amp;#x2F;3m5tlsetevz2t" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bsky.app&amp;#x2F;profile&amp;#x2F;forbes.com&amp;#x2F;post&amp;#x2F;3m5tlsetevz2t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kragen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, fuck.  Cue community-destroying drama and infighting, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tannhaeuser:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Found it interesting they&amp;#x27;ve lost status as a non-profit for tax exemption in Germany, and now establish a non-profit in the US for attracting investors while dev and ops remain in a German gGmbH.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amiga386:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Fantastic!&lt;p&gt;Now he&amp;#x27;s not there to block progress [0], can we remove Mastodon&amp;#x27;s intentional DDoS please and just &lt;i&gt;include the link preview in the toot&lt;/i&gt;. Add a disclaimer on the UI saying &amp;quot;link preview comes from toot&amp;quot; if it makes you happy. Then Mastodon can be a good web citizen and not a force for evil.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s only been an open problem for 7 years. Nothing in the grand scheme of things.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;mastodon&amp;#x2F;mastodon&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;4486#issuecomment-396732769" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;mastodon&amp;#x2F;mastodon&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;4486#issuecommen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bhhaskin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mastodon has been great. The platform and generally most users aren&amp;#x27;t trying to constantly sell me something or influence me. It people sharing their lives, hobbies and passion. Influencers don&amp;#x27;t bother because it doesn&amp;#x27;t have the massive following and reach other platforms have, but that&amp;#x27;s part of what makes it special imo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;burningChrome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks like the inmates won again:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Without linking to the posts, Rochko also mentioned that “a particularly bad interaction with a user last summer” led him to realize it was time to “step back and find a healthier relationship with the project.” It also drove the decision to restructure Mastodon.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Related:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Future Is Ours to Build – Together&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.joinmastodon.org&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;the-future-is-ours-to-build-together&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.joinmastodon.org&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;the-future-is-ours-to-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mastodon: Building for the Long Term&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.patreon.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;building-for-137854404" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.patreon.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;building-for-137854404&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ekjhgkejhgk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Mastodon is great. It&amp;#x27;s just unfortunate that the number of people is on the low side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jonathaneunice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;I always want to say to people who want to be rich and famous: &amp;#x27;try being rich first&amp;#x27;. See if that doesn&amp;#x27;t cover most of it. There&amp;#x27;s not much downside to being rich, other than paying taxes and having your relatives ask you for money. But when you become famous, you end up with a 24-hour job.&amp;quot; -- Bill Murray&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;billy99k:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is the problem with a stressful role, with little compensation. Most people wouldn&amp;#x27;t want to be in this position.&lt;p&gt;It sounds like anyone that runs a moderately sized open source project.&lt;p&gt;More money would solve most of these issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xupybd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;The fediverse is an island within an increasingly dystopian capitalist hellscape.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This seems like an extreme view to me. It&amp;#x27;s not so bad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisArchitect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Title is: My next chapter with Mastodon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lapcat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think it&amp;#x27;s good for the future of Mastodon as a decentralized platform to not depend essentially on any one person. After all, the web itself no longer depends on Tim Berners-Lee. That doesn&amp;#x27;t diminish their accomplishments, which were never about king-making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;layer8:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He’s also receiving €1 million as a one-time compensation. Not quite enough to retire on that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m-hodges:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Godspeed, John Mastodon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JadoJodo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What happened last summer? (I couldn&amp;#x27;t find anything on it)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2025/11/my-next-chapter-with-mastodon/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969909</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OrthoRoute – GPU-accelerated autorouting for KiCad</title>
      <link>https://bbenchoff.github.io/pages/OrthoRoute.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hand routing this would take months. This would result in an ugly board. There are serious deficits with this system compared to the new IPC plugin system released with KiCad 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970391"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://bbenchoff.github.io/pages/OrthoRoute.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;morellt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I would love to know the application of this ludicrous PCB, and I&amp;#x27;d be even more interested to see the quote price&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NoiseBert69:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Being that engineer in a   PCB Fab in China who has to punch all the vias by hand&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;heart attack&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bbenchoff.github.io/pages/OrthoRoute.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970391</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bild AI (YC W25) is hiring – Make housing affordable</title>
      <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/bild-ai/jobs/m2ilR5L-founding-engineer-applied-ai</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Puneet and I (Roop) founded Bild AI to tackle the mess that is blueprint reading, cost estimation, and permit applications in construction. It's a tough technical problem that requires the newest CV and AI approaches, and we’re impact-driven to make it more efficient to build more houses, hospitals, and schools. We're building blueprint understanding with a model-garden approach, so there is a lots of ground to break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45972390"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/bild-ai/jobs/m2ilR5L-founding-engineer-applied-ai'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/bild-ai/jobs/m2ilR5L-founding-engineer-applied-ai</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45972390</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monotype font licencing shake-down</title>
      <link>https://www.insanityworks.org/randomtangent/2025/11/14/monotype-font-licencing-shake-down</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So that couldn’t be what this person was talking about. Turns out a couple of people from the digital and design teams had received identical messages from this Monotype “Business Development Representative”. So not long after, I received a message from one of my procurement team colleagues who’d been forwarded that LinkedIn message from their senior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973261"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.insanityworks.org/randomtangent/2025/11/14/monotype-font-licencing-shake-down'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;great_wubwub:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This reminds me of the Blue Jeans Cable &amp;#x2F; Monster Cable shakedown nonsense.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.bluejeanscable.com&amp;#x2F;legal&amp;#x2F;mcp&amp;#x2F;index.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.bluejeanscable.com&amp;#x2F;legal&amp;#x2F;mcp&amp;#x2F;index.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish I could find the original writeup from Blue Jeans, it was frickin&amp;#x27; magnificent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;donatj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do these tactics ever work out for companies in the long term?&lt;p&gt;Over my 20 years in tech, I&amp;#x27;ve seen a couple cases where someone installed something they shouldn&amp;#x27;t have and we got threatening emails from the companies who somehow caught wind.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s always resulted on our side with a total corporate ban on using &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; from that company, even things that are otherwise OK &amp;#x2F; open source.&lt;p&gt;For instance at a previous company I worked, Oracle came calling for &amp;quot;VirtualBox Tools&amp;quot; trying to charge us some asinine amount because like one user had it installed and they wanted us to pay seats for the entire company. This resulted in a swift and decisive total corporate ban on VirtualBox.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve seen this at a couple companies and can&amp;#x27;t imagine we&amp;#x27;re alone in this. You&amp;#x27;re trading long-term business for short-term gains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brohee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is like the old IBM shakedown playbook &amp;quot;we have thousands of patents, if we dig enough we&amp;#x27;ll find one you infringe upon, so better pay for peace of mind&amp;quot;. I do assume that like in the case of IBM, some companies do pay...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hedora:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder if it’s possible to demand vendors send billing agreements before running an audit like this:&lt;p&gt;We’re reasonably sure your report is incorrect, and it doesn’t contain compelling evidence to back up its claims.&lt;p&gt;Our standard auditing fee for requests like this is $10,000, pre-paid to an escrow account and refundable if we find the use of an unlicensed font.&lt;p&gt;Or something.  Not a lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fortran77:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the United States if someone makes a false statement about you, comminicates that statement to a third party, and that statement can or has caused financial harm, you can reocover damages in court. If there are similar laws in your country. it&amp;#x27;s probably worth sending a demand letter to cover the time wasted on investigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;liquidise:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not typically sensitive to AI-sounding text but those image captions leave me understanding others&amp;#x27; issues with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;js4ever:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Paying for fonts is something I will never understand, I have a perfect vision but I&amp;#x27;m nearly blind to fonts it makes nearly no difference to me (except for windings)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ianferrel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It feels like the recipient company did an awful lot of work in response to what was &lt;i&gt;at best&lt;/i&gt; a fishing expedition. A serious complaint about licensing that demanded a real response would have been sent by post. It&amp;#x27;s not clear to me that scattershot LinkedIn messages deserve any response at all. The fact that the initial message lies about trying to contact him another way is another check in the &amp;quot;ignore this completely&amp;quot; column.&lt;p&gt;The same way that I wouldn&amp;#x27;t bother to fact-check a spam phone caller, why give any credence to this kind of thing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rodents:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“But before responding, the digital team would do their own investigation into the fonts we use and the licences we own so we could verify everything was in compliance. […] messaged a dozen or so more people from different parts of the business, hoping to hook just one person who would reply to the scary message they were sending.”&lt;p&gt;Piece of advice for the future: if you receive a message like this, and don’t want the sender to reach out to other people in your organization — acknowledge the message.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.insanityworks.org/randomtangent/2025/11/14/monotype-font-licencing-shake-down</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973261</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: A subtly obvious e-paper room air monitor</title>
      <link>https://www.nicolin-dora.ch/blog/en-epaper-room-air-monitor-part-1/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Health and comfort issues become more frequent. Very rare in normal indoor environments. Effects of indoor humidity on human health and comfort: A systematic review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962266"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.nicolin-dora.ch/blog/en-epaper-room-air-monitor-part-1/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tehjoker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is cool! How does it compare to e.g. an Aranet4? I got one to detect when there is a high risk of COVID-19 aerosols lingering and generally carry it in my bag. That way I can check the reading using my phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;loloquwowndueo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The air gets &amp;quot;stale&amp;quot;: humidity often rises above 60 %,&lt;p&gt;Fun - I have the opposite problem, humidity goes down to almost nothing and we have to use humidifiers to keep it around 40% to avoid horrible nose&amp;#x2F;throat&amp;#x2F;skin dryness.&lt;p&gt;Forced air hvac is probably why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quadrium:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You should find a friend&amp;#x27;s garage, shop or hackerspace with a brake, and metal cutting tools.&lt;p&gt;I have a similar monitor for equipment metrics, and the cardboard design is similar to the stand I made out of metal. I powder coated the metal light beige and it looks professional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dafelst:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Germans sure love their Lüften&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animats:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There are lots of commercial gadgets like that.&lt;p&gt;Most of the affordable CO2 meters are relative, not absolute. They set their 400 PPM level based on the lowest value they ever see. That&amp;#x27;s usually OK, but it&amp;#x27;s not good enough for places with permanent people occupancy, such as nursing homes.
Absolute detectors with NIST calibration are available but around US$500.[1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.forensicsdetectors.com&amp;#x2F;products&amp;#x2F;carbon-dioxide-detector" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.forensicsdetectors.com&amp;#x2F;products&amp;#x2F;carbon-dioxide-d...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ozim:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was looking for cheap co2 sensors that can be deployed on RPi but I guess they all feel expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zucked:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cool project. I&amp;#x27;ve done something similar using defunct crypto Awair AQI sensors tied into Home Assistant. They have an LED panel in the front that can show overall AQI or any of the pollutants they track:
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.getawair.com&amp;#x2F;products&amp;#x2F;element" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.getawair.com&amp;#x2F;products&amp;#x2F;element&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sky is the limit as to what you can do with Home Assistant automations.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s surprising how quickly a room with a closed door and one person can go from ~ambient CO2 levels to 1000ppm+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nicolin-dora.ch/blog/en-epaper-room-air-monitor-part-1/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962266</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: RowboatX – open-source Claude Code for everyday automations</title>
      <link>https://github.com/rowboatlabs/rowboat</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RowboatX - CLI Tool for Background Agents ✨ Create background agents with full shell access E. export OPENAI_API_KEY=your-openai-api-key Install RowboatX npx @rowboatlabs/rowboatx Demo Examples Add and Manage MCP servers $ rowboatx Add MCP: 'Add this MCP server config: &lt;config&gt; ' Explore tools: 'What tools are there in &lt;server-name&gt; ' Create background agents $ rowboatx 'Create agent to do X. Allow the agent to run shell commands including ffmpeg' Schedule and monitor agents $ rowboatx 'Make agent &lt;background-agent-name&gt; run every day at 10 AM' 'What agents do I have scheduled to run and at what times' 'When was &lt;background-agent-name&gt; last run' 'Are any agents waiting for my input or confirmation' Run background agents manually rowboatx --agent=&lt;agent-name&gt; --input="xyz" --no-interactive=true rowboatx --agent=&lt;agent-name&gt; --run_id=&lt;run_id&gt; # resume from a previous run Models support You can configure your models in ~/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970338"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/rowboatlabs/rowboat'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m increasingly seeing code-adjacent people who are using coding agents for non-coding things because the tooling support it better, and the agents work really well.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s an interesting area, and glad to see someone working on this.&lt;p&gt;The other program in the space that I&amp;#x27;m aware of is Block&amp;#x27;s Goose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;divan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One of the main reasons for me for sticking with Claude Code (also for non-coding tasks, I think the name is a misnomer) is the fixed price plan. Pretty much any other open-source alternative requires API key, which means that as soon as I start using it _for real_, I&amp;#x27;ll start overpaying and&amp;#x2F;or hitting limits too fast. At least that was my initial experience with API from OpenAI&amp;#x2F;Claude&amp;#x2F;Gemini.&lt;p&gt;Am I biased&amp;#x2F;wrong here?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jckahn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Can this use local LLMs?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/rowboatlabs/rowboat</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970338</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying out Gemini 3 Pro with audio transcription and a new pelican benchmark</title>
      <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/18/gemini-3/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 has the same underlying characteristics as Gemini 2. 00 Gemini 3 Pro ≤ 200k tokens: $2. ScreenSpot-Pro (Screen understanding) Gemini 3 Pro 72.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970519"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/18/gemini-3/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So Gemini 3 Pro dropped today, which happens to be the day I proofread a historical timeline I&amp;#x27;m assisting a PhD with.  I do one pass and then realize I should try Gemini 3 Pro on it.  I give the same exact prompt to 3 Pro as Claude 4.5 Sonnet.  3 pro finds 25 real errors, no hallucinations. Claude finds 7 errors, but only 2 of those are unique to Claude. (Claude was better at &amp;quot;wait, that reference doesn&amp;#x27;t match the content! It should be $corrected_citation!). But Gemini&amp;#x27;s visual understanding was top notch. It&amp;#x27;s biggest flaw was that it saw words that wrapped as having extra spaces. But it also correctly caught a typo where a wrapped word was misspelled, so something about it seemed to fixate on those line breaks, I think.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vessenes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;d like a long bet on when Simon will add animation to the pelican SVG benchmark. I&amp;#x27;m thinking late 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scosman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If anyone enjoys cheeky mischief targeting LLM benchmark hackers: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scosman&amp;#x2F;pelicans_riding_bicycles" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scosman&amp;#x2F;pelicans_riding_bicycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll need to update for V2!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;razodactyl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was waiting for this post.&lt;p&gt;Love the pivot in pelican generation bench.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wowfunhappy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Aww, I don’t like the new pelican benchmark as much. I liked that the old prompt was vague and we could see how the AI interpreted it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nurumaik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seems like pelican benchmark is finally added to model training process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;leetharris:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I used to work in ASR. Due to the nature of current multimodal architectures, it is unlikely we&amp;#x27;ll ever see accurate timestamps over a longer horizon. You&amp;#x27;re better off using encoder-decoder ASR architectures, then using traditional diarization using embedding clustering, then using a multimodal model to refine it, then use a forced alignment technique (maybe even something pre-NN) to get proper timestamps and reconciling it at the end.&lt;p&gt;These things are getting really good at just regular transcription (as long as you don&amp;#x27;t care about verbatimicity), but every additional dimension you add (timestamps, speaker assignment, etc) will make the others worse. These work much better as independent processes that then get reconciled and refined by a multimodal LLM.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeroConcerns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; so I shrunk the file down to a more manageable 38MB using ffmpeg&lt;p&gt;Without having an LLM figure out the required command line parameters? Mad props!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;londons_explore:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone got a class full of students and able to get a human version of this pelican benchmark?&lt;p&gt;Perhaps half with a web browser to view the results, and half working blind with the numbers alone?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;simonw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The audio transcript exercise here is particularly interesting from a journalism perspective.&lt;p&gt;Summarizing a 3.5 hour council meeting is something of a holy grail of AI-assisted reporting. There are a LOT of meetings like that, and newspapers (especially smaller ones) can no longer afford to have a human reporter sit through them all.&lt;p&gt;I tried this prompt (against audio from &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=qgJ7x7R6gy0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=qgJ7x7R6gy0&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Output a Markdown transcript of this meeting. Include speaker
  names and timestamps. Start with an outline of the key
  meeting sections, each with a title and summary and timestamp
  and list of participating names. Note in bold if anyone
  raised their voices, interrupted each other or had
  disagreements. Then follow with the full transcript.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Here&amp;#x27;s the result: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gist.github.com&amp;#x2F;simonw&amp;#x2F;0b7bc23adb6698f376aebfd700943314" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gist.github.com&amp;#x2F;simonw&amp;#x2F;0b7bc23adb6698f376aebfd700943...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not sure quite how to grade it here, especially since I haven&amp;#x27;t sat through the whole 3.5 hour meeting video myself.&lt;p&gt;It appears to have captured the &lt;i&gt;gist&lt;/i&gt; of the meeting very well, but the fact that the transcript isn&amp;#x27;t close to an exact match to what was said - and the timestamps are incorrect - means it&amp;#x27;s very hard to trust the output. Could it have hallucinated things that didn&amp;#x27;t happen? Those can at least be spotted by digging into the video (or the YouTube transcript) to check that they occurred... but what about if there was a key point that Gemini 3 omitted entirely?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/18/gemini-3/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970519</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google boss says AI investment boom has 'elements of irrationality'</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy7vrd8k4eo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asked whether Google would be immune to the impact of the AI bubble bursting, Mr Pichai said the tech giant could weather that potential storm, but also issued a warning. Mr Pichai said action was needed, including in the UK, to develop new sources of energy and scale up energy infrastructure. "You don't want to constrain an economy based on energy, and I think that will have consequences," he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961886"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy7vrd8k4eo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bryanrasmussen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;isn&amp;#x27;t that basically the definition of a bubble, a boom with elements of irrationality?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;avadodin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;People predicting a crash and pulling back due to a bubble indicates the beginning of the bubble.&lt;p&gt;If I were the gambling man, I would grab my PETS.AI stock and sit tight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;outside1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;About twice a day I think about how I am basically reinforcement learning my replacement.  Thank goodness I am 53.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HardwareLust:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;...says the man guilty of said irrationality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;beanjuiceII:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;will gamers be eatin&amp;#x27; good?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mtrovo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Assuming this is irrational and must come back to reality at some point, I&amp;#x27;m not convinced this is connected to the common man economy as other bubbles in the past were. This round of investment is mostly being funded by exuberant cash flow accumulated over the years that was otherwise used as stock buybacks by a small number of stocks and some private credit deals that are not that accessible to the general public. This is looking more like a crypto crash kind of effect rather than a 2008 one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;guytv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Every cent poured into this boom is building Google’s future competitors.&lt;p&gt;Of course he’s nervous - what else would you expect him to say?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OptionOfT:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interestingly I think if the AI succeed at the level that a lot of these CEOs hope we&amp;#x27;re not much better off either.&lt;p&gt;And the sentiment that goes around is more: reduce the amount of people needed to do the same amount of work:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theregister.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;mckinsey_ai_monetization&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theregister.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;10&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;mckinsey_ai_monetizat...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; McKinsey says, while quoting an HR executive at a Fortune 100 company griping: &amp;quot;All of these copilots are supposed to make work more efficient with fewer people, but my business leaders are also saying they can&amp;#x27;t reduce head count yet.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The problem becomes that eventually all these people who are laid off are not going to find new roles.&lt;p&gt;Who is going to be buying the products and services if no-one has money to throw around?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;binary132:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;if only there were some way for THE ENTIRE MARKET to not have quite so much exposure to hype bubbles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;helterskelter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m curious what HN is doing with their portfolios right about now. I&amp;#x27;d be dumping NVDA and reallocating to more bonds for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;partiallypro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think AI is a bubble, but I don&amp;#x27;t think we&amp;#x27;re close to the peak yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;badgersnake:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Every CEO is reading from the same script right now. It might be a bubble but it’s just like the internet, it’s still going to be relevant and it’s just the crap companies and grifters who will die.&lt;p&gt;I wonder who’s writing the script.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rchaud:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most bubbles occur due to excessive levels of credit offered too cheaply, resulting in a whole bunch of defaults happening at the same time. All the major AI players have borrowed money to buy GPUs and build data centers and have used Special Purpose Vehicles to do it so the debt doesn&amp;#x27;t fall on their own balance sheet, probably using a certain amount of stock as collateral. If the SPV defaults, could that trigger a big sell-off?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scottLobster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Silicon Valley! Unprofitable debt and marketing all the way up until you get bailed out by the taxpayers, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giancarlostoro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think it will pop but not in the way everyone thinks it will pop. There&amp;#x27;s plenty that&amp;#x27;s not going to go away &amp;#x2F; anywhere, but I&amp;#x27;m sure lots of startups will fail and close their doors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmount:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tons of companies survived the dot com bubble pop. Corrections are when the market does some sorting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sgroppino:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s not a bubble until it bursts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viccis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Very cool and healthy for the CEO of a company investing massive amounts into a given technology to casually refer to it as a &amp;quot;bubble&amp;quot; at the same time. I guess he softens the statement a bit by calling it &amp;quot;an AI bubble&amp;quot; instead of the &amp;quot;the AI bubble&amp;quot;, but it&amp;#x27;s still interesting to see everyone involved in this economic mess start to acknowledge it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;burnte:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And there we have the reason for all of these interdependent deals between all these firms, they&amp;#x27;re all hedging with each other they can keep this set of plates spinning.&lt;p&gt;They can&amp;#x27;t, not firever. Bubbles pop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ghostpepper:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does anyone really think it’s “if” and not “when” ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lesuorac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; He told the BBC that the company owns what he called a “full stack” of technologies, from chips to YouTube data to models and frontier science research. This integrated approach, he suggested, would help the company weather any market turbulence better than competitors.&lt;p&gt;I guess but is it better for an investor to own 2 shares of Google or 1 share of OpenAI and 1 share of TSMC?&lt;p&gt;Like I have no doubt that being vertically integrated as a single company has lot of benefits but one can also create a trust that invests vertically as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clickety_clack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like something an extortionist would say in a movie. “We’re all dirty here!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwawayffffas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Obviously, at least in the US the AI bubble is the only thing keeping the economy afloat. If it wasn&amp;#x27;t for the bubble the US would be in a recession.&lt;p&gt;Not sure how the situation is in Europe and Asia, but I would guess about the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nabla9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Google, Meta, Microsoft, and Amazon will get through easily. They don&amp;#x27;t have excessive debt. They can afford to lose their investments into AI.  Their valuations will take a hit. Nvidia will lose revenue and profits,  stock will go down by 60% or more, but it will also survive.&lt;p&gt;Oracle will likely fail. It funded its AI pivot with debt. The Debt-to-Revenue ratio is 1.77, the Debt-to-Equity ratio D&amp;#x2F;E  is 520, and it has  a free cash flow problem.&lt;p&gt;OpenAI, Anthropic, and others will be bought for cents on the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TrackerFF:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like &lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;We&amp;#x27;re too big to fail. If we go down, everyone goes down. It is your choice.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;But unlike 08 crisis, we&amp;#x27;re getting a heads up to bring out the lube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;donkeylazy456:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Now they are talking like Wall Street greedy bankers back in subprime crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yawpitch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It’s not a matter of &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt;, it’s a matter of &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rvz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Most of all of Big Tech, especially Google are doing just fine, making $100B a quarter.&lt;p&gt;Startups and other unprofitable companies however...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aurareturn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it really a bubble about to burst when literally everyone is talking about AI being in a bubble and maybe bursting soon?&lt;p&gt;To me, we&amp;#x27;re clearly not peak AI exuberance. AI agents are just getting started and getting so freaking good. Just the other day, I used Vercel&amp;#x27;s v0 to build a small business website for a relative in 10 minutes. It looked fantastic and very mobile friendly. I fed the website to ChatGPT5.1 and asked it to improve the marketing text. I fed those improvements back to v0. Finished in 15 minutes. Would have taken me at least one week in the past to do a design, code it, test it for desktop&amp;#x2F;mobile, write the copy.&lt;p&gt;The way AI has disrupted software building in 3 short years is astonishing. Yes, code is uniquely great for LLM training due to open source code and documentation but as other industries catch up on LLM training, they will change profoundly too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WarOnPrivacy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m okay with being victim to RAM and NVME prices returning to pre-skyrocket levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy7vrd8k4eo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961886</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
