<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:52:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Checkout.com hacked, refuses ransom payment, donates to security labs</title>
      <link>https://www.checkout.com/blog/protecting-our-merchants-standing-up-to-extortion</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BlogNov 10, 2025What is the difference between a refund and a reversal transaction. Read article BlogNov 6, 2025Deep dive: Tackling friendly fraud this holiday seasonRead article BlogNov 3, 2025The importance of fast refunds during the holiday sales seasonRead article BlogNov 3, 2025Conversion tactics for White Friday 2025: How to win customers at checkoutRead article BlogNov 3, 2025How to boost conversion during the holiday sales seasonRead article BlogNov 3, 2025Optimizing your payments flow for the latest Google Play Store updatesRead article BlogOct 31, 2025Money20/20 Las Vegas 2025: Innovation, trust, and agentic AIRead article BlogOct 30, 2025Visa Compelling Evidence 3. 0: New rules explainedRead article BlogOct 23, 2025How Checkout maintains uptime during peak seasonRead article BlogOct 21, 2025My Path in Payments: Zetti Zahari, Senior Product Owner for Payment at zooplus Read article BlogOct 21, 2025Payment networks explainedRead article BlogOct 17, 2025Reflections from Thrive Venice 2025 Read article Return to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912698"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.checkout.com/blog/protecting-our-merchants-standing-up-to-extortion'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 17 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zetanor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They&amp;#x27;re &amp;quot;sorry&amp;quot;, they want to be &amp;quot;transparent&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;accountable&amp;quot;, they want your &amp;quot;trust&amp;quot;, but not enough to publicly explain what happened or what kind of data got taken (is a full CRM backup from 6 years ago considered &amp;quot;legacy&amp;quot; &amp;quot;internal operational documents&amp;quot;?). There&amp;#x27;s not even a promise to produce more information about their mistake.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Jimmy, where did the cookies go?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Something that was on the counter is gone! I don&amp;#x27;t know how! It might not even be my fault! But I&amp;#x27;m sorry!&lt;p&gt;What kind of an apology is that? It&amp;#x27;s not. It&amp;#x27;s marketing for the public while they contact the &amp;quot;less than 25% of [their] current merchant base&amp;quot; whose (presumably sensitive) information was somehow in &amp;quot;internal operational documents&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Oh but also took some of what they charge their customers and gave that (undisclosed?) sum away to a university. They must be &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; sorry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;betimd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have checkout.me domain, and it is for sale. email me if you want to get it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vntok:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Checkout.com hacked, refuses ransom payment, donates to security labs&lt;p&gt;This submission&amp;#x27;s edited title reads like the &amp;quot;target headline&amp;quot; from The Office (US):&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Scranton Area Paper Company - Dunder Mifflin - &lt;i&gt;Apologizes&lt;/i&gt; - to Valued Client - Some Companies - Still Know - How - Business - is - Done&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nalekberov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;At this point I think we all understand that we will never be able to trust any company in this world with our data.&lt;p&gt;In most cases they can get away with &amp;quot;We are sorry&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Trust me, bro&amp;quot; attitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dizhn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Giving me MBA vibes. Will they close up shop and go when it&amp;#x27;s the remaining 75% of their infrastructure next time?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Isn&amp;#x27;t it illegal in many countries to pay a ransom?&lt;p&gt;(If not, why not?)&lt;p&gt;(Imho, it would make sense if only the state can pay ransoms)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lateforwork:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This should be law. Any company that is hacked should be required by law to make a sizeable investment in a third-party security research company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;globalise83:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;The system was used for internal operational documents and merchant onboarding materials at that time&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;To me it seems most likely that this is data collected during the KYC process during onboarding, meaning company documents, director passport or ID card scans, those kind of things. So the risk here for at least a few more years until all identity documents have expired is identity theft possibilities (e.g. fraudsters registering their company with another PSP using the stolen documents and then processing fraudulent payments until they get shut down, or signing up for bank accounts using their info and tax id).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;saberience:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So, I used to work in the fintech world and it looks to me like what was hacked was merchant KYB documents. I.e. when a merchant signs up for a PSP they have to provide various documentation about the business so the PSP can underwrite the risk of taking on this business. I.e. some PSPs won&amp;#x27;t deal with porn companies or travel companies or companies from certain regions etc.&lt;p&gt;This sort of data is generally treated very differently to the actual PANs and payment information (which are highly encrypted using HSMs).&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;#x27;s obviously shitty to get hacked, but if it was just KYB (or KYC) type information, it&amp;#x27;s not harming any individuals. A lot of KYB information is public (depending on country).&lt;p&gt;Fair play on them for being open about this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nashashmi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sometimes cyber insurance will come to the rescue. That’s why companies Don’t pay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arbll:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; The attackers gained access to a legacy, third-party cloud file storage system.&lt;p&gt;I think the answer is ok but the &amp;quot;third-party&amp;quot; bit reads like trying to deflect part of the blame on the cloud storage provider.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dmoreno:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;When they say &amp;quot;The episode occurred when threat actors gained access to this third party legacy system which was not decommissioned properly. &amp;quot; for me it sounds like a not properly wiped disk that got into the the bad guys hands. It would be interesting to know more to be prepared for proper decommissioning of hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prodigycorp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If i was a customer id be pissed off, but this is as good as a response you can have to an incident like this.&lt;p&gt;- timely response&lt;p&gt;- initial disclosure by company and not third party&lt;p&gt;- actual expression of shame and remorse&lt;p&gt;- a decent explanation of target&amp;#x2F;scope&lt;p&gt;i could imagine being cyclical about the statement, but look at other companies who have gotten breached in the past. very few of them do well on all points&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pm2222:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Could this be aws s3?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lexlambda:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The donation is more or less virtue signaling rather than actual insight.&lt;p&gt;The problem can not be helped by research research against cybercrime. Proper practices for protections are well established and known, they just need to be implemented.&lt;p&gt;The amount donated should&amp;#x27;ve rather be invested into better protections &amp;#x2F; hiring a person responsible in the company.&lt;p&gt;(Context: The hack happened on a not properly decomissioned legacy system.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;throwaway2037:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love this part (no trolling from me):&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;gt; We are sorry. We regret that this incident has caused worry for our partners and people. We have begun the process to identify and contact those impacted and are working closely with law enforcement and the relevant regulators. We are fully committed to maintaining your trust.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I know there will by a bunch of cynics who say that an LLM or a PR crisis team wrote this post... but if they did, hats off.  It is powerful and moving.  This guys really falls on his sword &amp;#x2F; takes it on the chin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;junaru:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; We will be donating the ransom amount to Carnegie Mellon University and the University of Oxford Cyber Security Center (OXCIS) to support their research in the fight against cybercrime.&lt;p&gt;Can this be tax deducted? Because this it sounds like gaslighting to change the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.checkout.com/blog/protecting-our-merchants-standing-up-to-extortion</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912698</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hack Club has been handling children's data for 4 years without a privacy policy</title>
      <link>https://kys.llc/blog/my-hackclub-story</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;you could tell people were actually building things they cared about. that's what got me invested in hack club. but hack club built something different - a space where teenagers actually help each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45913663"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://kys.llc/blog/my-hackclub-story'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jstummbillig:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; so in july 2025, i discovered that neighbourhood was exposing thousands of users&amp;#x27; full legal names through an unprotected API endpoint. literally anyone with a slack ID could access this data. no authentication, no nothing. just a URL parameter and boom, there&amp;#x27;s your real name.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; i sent formal breach notifications to security@hackclub.com and gdpr@hackclub.com on july 9th. radio silence. nothing. not even an automated &amp;quot;we&amp;#x27;ve received your email&amp;quot; response.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; when i tried talking to HQ staff informally, the responses were... well, shocking doesn&amp;#x27;t quite cover it. the first intern told me that since hack club is US-based, they&amp;#x27;re &amp;quot;not held to GDPR,&amp;quot; that if fined &amp;quot;nothing compels us to pay it,&amp;quot; and that EU people &amp;quot;void your EU protections&amp;quot; by coming to the US.&lt;p&gt;What? How did we get from (allegedly) informing them about something, that looks like a security vulnerability to them responding &amp;quot;nothing compels us to pay it&amp;quot;? I feel like the author is not being quite as candid in their account as they should probably be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prodigycorp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m usually the type to be annoyed at hn people who nitpick about articles but.. this is unreadable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tomalaci:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Companies should quickly realize that ChatGPT can go both ways - it can turn a &amp;quot;script-kiddie&amp;quot; into fully fledged hacker if vulnerabilities continue to be this sloppy. I am fairly certain that low-skill hacker sweatshops already heavily rely on LLMs to quickly exploit trivial vulnerabilities like these.&lt;p&gt;Like it or not but I feel like account logins, PII and payment stuff will have to be handled by central big orgs. Ideally, I would like that to be a competent open-source government service. For now it is big companies like Google that can shove its SSO around in accessible manner to other sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1a527dd5:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not sure if it is just me, but the background animation absolutely kill my browser (Chrome) and scrolling is _super_ laggy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rodents:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sounds like Hack Club is doing a great job at preparing teenagers for the real world: nobody cares about the things you care about as much as you do. The most important skill to learn for the real world is to pick your battles. Using ChatGPT for legal advice is dumb, but it’s not your battle to fight.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kys.llc/blog/my-hackclub-story</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45913663</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seed. LINE's Custom Typeface</title>
      <link>https://seed.line.me/index_en.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LINE Seed Licensing All content of LINE Seed is copyrighted material owned by LY Corp. This license is also available with a FAQ at: https://scripts. However, the software font files themselves cannot be sold by the other parties other than LY Corp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912785"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://seed.line.me/index_en.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wartywhoa23:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Sorry, it&amp;#x27;s just yet another faceless and generic font like 100s of others...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eptcyka:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is the license situation here?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hecanjog:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I thought the original LINE had made a typeface, bummer. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.lineimprint.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.lineimprint.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James_K:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve not a clue what Line is, but their front page contains this gem:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Listen, Watch and &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Sing along.&lt;p&gt;How the hell does that happen in the year of our Lord 2025?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semaphor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For those who are wondering what Line is, it’s a Japanese messenger turned super-app [0]&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Line became Japan&amp;#x27;s largest social network in 2013 and is used by over 70% of the population as of 2023; it is also popular mainly in Indonesia, Taiwan and Thailand.&lt;p&gt;The font looks decent, nice of them to have it under the SIL Open Font License.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Line_(software)" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Line_(software)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;benguild:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;is this necessary?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://seed.line.me/index_en.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912785</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Telli (Voice AI – YC F24) is hiring ambitious engineers in [on-site, Berlin]</title>
      <link>https://hi.telli.com/eng</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://hi.telli.com/eng</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912744</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering Yaesu FT-70D Firmware Encryption</title>
      <link>https://landaire.net/reversing-yaesu-firmware-encryption/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article dives into my full methodology for reverse engineering the tool mentioned in this article. What's this last entry, "23". RES_UPDATE_INFO looks like just binary data -- perhaps this is our firmware image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911704"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://landaire.net/reversing-yaesu-firmware-encryption/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jacquesm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Job well done! I tried reverse engineering the encryption on Yamaha&amp;#x27;s midi files. I thought it would be super complex but it turned out to be ridiculously easy. It&amp;#x27;s funny when you&amp;#x27;re preparing mentally for some long slog and turns out to be an hour at best. In case you&amp;#x27;re interested: they used a fixed block of 256 bytes that they xor&amp;#x27;d the data with in a cyclic fashion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiniuclx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ham radio is well worth getting into if you come from a software background but want to get more hands-on with embedded electronics. Radios are ubiquitous in modern technology, and getting a deeper understanding of how they work can have surprising career benefits too!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://landaire.net/reversing-yaesu-firmware-encryption/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911704</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
