<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:33:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>The privacy nightmare of browser fingerprinting</title>
      <link>https://kevinboone.me/fingerprinting.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Browser fingerprinting does not depend on cookies. Canvas fingerprinting works by having the browser run code that draws text (perhaps invisibly), and then retrieving the individual pixel data that it drew. It appears that only about one browser in every thousand share the same canvas fingerprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016249"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://kevinboone.me/fingerprinting.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 17 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;udev4096:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;JavaScript disabling helps a lot, regardless of what author says. It disables most of the tracking attempts, improves security and most of all pages load faster and hardly break if you&amp;#x27;re just browsing anyway.&lt;p&gt;The whole article never mentions the gold standard of anti-fingerprinting, Tor Browser. It just shows how shallow the article is when it mentions Mullvad Browser, a fork of TBB, instead of TBB itself! There&amp;#x27;s also no mention of using an upto-date DNS block list to thwart fingerprinting attempts even more&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;drnick1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Firefox w&amp;#x2F; the Arkenfox user.js is probably as good as it gets in terms of privacy. By default, this config burns cookies on exit, standardizes the time zone to UTC, spoofs the canvas fingerprint, and does other helpful things. Basically, it makes Firefox expose the same information as the Tor browser.&lt;p&gt;In addition, I block most known advertizing&amp;#x2F;tracking domains at the DNS level (I run my own server, and use Hagezi&amp;#x27;s blacklists).&lt;p&gt;Finally, another suggestion would be to block all third party content by default using uBlock Origin and&amp;#x2F;or uMatrix. This will break a lot of websites, but automatically rules out most forms of tracking through things such as fonts hosted by Google, Adobe and others. I manually whitelist required third party domains (CDNs) for websites I frequently visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;btilly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t mind advertisers knowing more about me. If they can display ads that are relevant to me, this is a better experience on both sides.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no way to tell advertisers, &amp;quot;No, I&amp;#x27;m not interested in your product. I never will be. Don&amp;#x27;t waste your money.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;The top offender is Hims. No, I don&amp;#x27;t have hair loss. I don&amp;#x27;t want hair loss supplements. I also don&amp;#x27;t have ED, and I object strongly to ads for that showing up unexpectedly when I&amp;#x27;m showing a YouTube video to someone else.&lt;p&gt;The second top offender is whoever it is (they keep changing their name) who thinks that I need some kind of Christian motivational course to get control of &amp;quot;the P-word&amp;quot;. (Their phrase, not mine.) No, I don&amp;#x27;t have a problem with pornography. I am very rarely interested in it. And when it comes up every few months, I don&amp;#x27;t feel any guilt about it afterwards. Furthermore I&amp;#x27;m an atheist. A Christian motivational course isn&amp;#x27;t going to work well for me regardless.&lt;p&gt;Yes, Google does offer a report function, and a block function, for ads. The report function seems to have gotten rid of the unwanted ED ads. The block really doesn&amp;#x27;t work when the ads are all very similar AI slop that is rotated frequently. Block this ad, and then next unwanted ad from the same source will be coming along soon enough. (The reason why I particularly dislike Hims is that they are more aggressively rotating their ads.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tetha:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It reminds me of a game we played with students of data classification algorithms like ID3: How many yes&amp;#x2F;no questions do we need to uniquely identify everyone in this room?&lt;p&gt;With like 12 students, that&amp;#x27;s 4 bits, and it often ends up with 2-3 questions. It starts off with the obivious ones - man&amp;#x2F;woman&amp;#x2F;diverse, but then a realization comes in: An answer usually contains more information than just that one bit. If you have long hair, you&amp;#x27;re most likely a woman and&amp;#x2F;or a metalhead for example. That part will get shaken out later on.&lt;p&gt;And those thoughts make these browser fingerprinting techniques all the more scary: They contain a lot of information and that quickly cuts the possible amount of people down. Like, I&amp;#x27;m a Linux Firefox user with a screen on the left. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t be suprised if that put me in a 5-6 digit bucket of people already.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daft_pink:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m curious if there is a product like cloudflare’s remote browser isolation that obfuscates it in that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ekjhgkejhgk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The core of the problem is that we&amp;#x27;ve made this behavior of &amp;quot;run javascript that pulls more javascript and then run that too&amp;quot; the default. Stallman was right, as always.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bparsons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Browser fingerprinting has been a thing since at least 2008. Kissmetrics was the first company I heard of that was doing this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rcpt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All this and I still need to click on the cookie pop ups like they&amp;#x27;ll bring the cargo planes to the island.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ekjhgkejhgk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I mean... I don&amp;#x27;t give a fuck about fonts, I don&amp;#x27;t give a fuck about drawing shit to some canvas. Can I not just opt out?&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that&amp;#x27;s ski-mask bla bla bla, but I still don&amp;#x27;t want my browser to be doing this nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lilsoso:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks for the browser recommendations.&lt;p&gt;I switched to the Mullvad browser. The other recommendation, LibreWolf, provides the following warning on install which scared me away: &amp;quot;Warning: librewolf has been deprecated because it does not pass the macOS Gatekeeper check! It will be disabled on 2026-09-01.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prng2021:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How exactly do advertisers take fingerprints and translate that to targeted ads for each user?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abigail95:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To extend the closing remarks from a SIGINT perspective, sure some fingerprints are non unique and short lived, have little data. But hang onto it long enough and sure enough some slower data from another band might eventually correlate it with something else.&lt;p&gt;The last time I looked at this seriously I was trying to find out how much fidelity (if it was possible at all) was necessary to identify someone by their mouse and keyboard input.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not just what you do but how you do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;balamatom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;And even though my personal safety and liberty probably aren’t at stake, I don’t want to give any support to the global advertising behemoth, by allowing advertisers access to better information about me.&lt;p&gt;Giving the surveillance economy access to your habits means making them slightly better informed about &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt;. That won&amp;#x27;t directly endanger you; the SE will just become slightly better informed about how people like you function.&lt;p&gt;This will enable it to increase the amount of risk faced by some other person that you will never hear of (and vice versa) if any of you is even suspected of endangering the SE, in proportion to the risk to the SE which people like you may hypothetically pose, as quantified by the methods of nepotism-powered pseudoscience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;doug_durham:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I agree with the points in the article. Fingerprinting of any kind is a major risk for personal freedom.  At the same time I want to make sure that content creators are compensated for their work.  Ad firms that employ fingerprinting stand between me and the content creator.  That said, I&amp;#x27;m not going to pay $5&amp;#x2F;month for every blog that I occasionally read.  The ad based model provides a more streamlined approach to compensation, but at the unacceptable price of privacy.  I&amp;#x27;m not quite sure what the answer is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neuroelectron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;10 years too late.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dringov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;Worst of all, perhaps, it can extract a canvas fingerprint. Canvas fingerprinting works by having the browser run code that draws text (perhaps invisibly), and then retrieving the individual pixel data that it drew. This pixel data will differ subtly from one system to another, even drawing the same text, because of subtle differences in the graphics hardware and the operating system.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am concerned about the detail here: does this mean per hardware class (e.g. same model of GPU), or per each individual device?&lt;p&gt;Is the implication that there are certain graphical operations that - perhaps unintentionally - end up becoming akin to a physically unclonable function in hardware?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ArcHound:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You missed one of our best guarded secrets: ja3 hashes and their successors.&lt;p&gt;Basically, we can identify browsers based on the supported ciphers in TLS handshake (order matters too AFAIK). Then when your declared identity is not matching the ja3 hash, you&amp;#x27;re automatically suspicious, if not blocked right away. I think that&amp;#x27;s the reason for so many Capchas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kevinboone.me/fingerprinting.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016249</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a U.S. First, New Mexico Opens Doors to Free Child Care for All</title>
      <link>https://www.wsj.com/us-news/in-a-u-s-first-new-mexico-opens-doors-to-free-child-care-for-all-2dfdea96</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wsj.com/us-news/in-a-u-s-first-new-mexico-opens-doors-to-free-child-care-for-all-2dfdea96</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015763</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depot (YC W23) Is Hiring a Staff Infrastructure Engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/depot/jobs/O2iB56E-staff-infrastructure-engineer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We started Depot because we were frustrated with the constant pain of slow build performance. They slow down innovation. We help folks save literal years in build time every single week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016799"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/depot/jobs/O2iB56E-staff-infrastructure-engineer'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/depot/jobs/O2iB56E-staff-infrastructure-engineer</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016799</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'The French people want to save us': help pours in for glassmaker Duralex</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/nov/22/french-people-want-to-save-us-help-pours-glassmaker-duralex</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;View image in fullscreenFrançois Marciano, chief executive of Duralex, holds up a Picardie glass. Photograph: Magali Delporte/The GuardianView image in fullscreenEach glass is carefully inspected. ”View image in fullscreenThe instantly recognisable Picardie glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015379"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/nov/22/french-people-want-to-save-us-help-pours-glassmaker-duralex'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broussebar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As the article said Duralex was the brand use by a large number of school cantinas in France. Inside of each glass there’s a small number used by the brand to identify the mold used for the creation of the glass. For kids that was a way to decide who is going to fetch the water for the table (smaller number or higher number of the table). 
That’s why the CE is holding his glass like that in the guardian article.
Beside the nostalgia i think a lot of people support them because it’s a SCOP (the majority of the capital of the company is owned by the employees) [1] and it’s nice to see that another kind of company is possible.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fr.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Soci%C3%A9t%C3%A9_coop%C3%A9rative_et_participative" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;fr.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Soci%C3%A9t%C3%A9_coop%C3%A9ra...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;constantcrying:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Selling products based on nostalgia does not work. Europe needs to do far more keep it&amp;#x27;s industry afloat and to make locally produced products competitive.&lt;p&gt;Duralex is currently selling products at 10x the costs of what a similar product, made in China, costs on Amazon. This is not sustainable. These enormous differences in prices mean that only very people can afford their products. It is a brand which sells an everyday item at prices, which are legitimately hard to afford for most of the population.&lt;p&gt;Obviously a company like this can not succeed long term. It is totally uncompetitive, except for some brand recognition and positive brand perception. These obviously help, but will do nothing for the long term success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffbee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article doesn&amp;#x27;t even mention that this company already went bankrupt once this century, in 2008. Like some of the other posters, I furnished my cupboards with Duralex decades ago and never needed any more. In the same way, I filled my flatware drawers with Oneida decades before Oneida disappeared, and my plates are all from some long-forgotten Swedish stoneware maker, and I bought all my furniture from a dead Italian brand at a showroom that no longer exists in San Francisco. I have a personal pet theory on this, which is that the astronomical cost of housing has squeezed out all other aspects of home furnishing from people&amp;#x27;s budgets, in a race to the bottom where the last brand standing is Ikea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;variadix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;They make great glassware, very scratch and chip resistant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wkat4242:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Duralex is good quality anyway, very strong against breaking but they do scratch pretty badly&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;erwan577:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The brand suffered from energy price hikes, felt particularly sharply after 2022, and its marketing could clearly be improved. Only now, after more than two or three decades, are new designs finally appearing on the roadmap.&lt;p&gt;These glasses were once ubiquitous in public middle-school cafeterias, so the emotional attachment runs deep across generations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjerem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The article mentions it, but don’t insist on it. Duralex is now quite a special company: they were a renowned and beloved brand that was heading toward bankruptcy, until last year when the company was bought by its own workers and turned into a cooperative.&lt;p&gt;Since then, they have stayed afloat, probably thanks mainly to people wanting to support a worker-owned business by buying their glasses, but still, it works.&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty positive story so far, and I hope they’ll continue to thrive under this new structure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chihuahua:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;While there is no shortage of irrelevant details, the article is very light on relevant details. What prevents the factory from staying in business? Not enough orders? The French people supposedly love this glassware and orders pour in whenever the company is mentioned. They have the factory up and running, they have employees. The workers own the means of production, what could be better than that?&lt;p&gt;Why do they need to expand into new product ranges, if the existing products are in such high demand? I&amp;#x27;m not sure if the proposed pint glasses for British pubs are a sure winner. Why not stick with what already works?&lt;p&gt;None of this is explained in the article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lostlogin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;New products and new markets clearly help finances. Burning that much gas has got to be their major expense. Are there other way to heat the furnaces?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/nov/22/french-people-want-to-save-us-help-pours-glassmaker-duralex</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015379</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Apple Study Shows LLMs Can Tell What You're Doing from Audio and Motion Data</title>
      <link>https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/21/apple-research-llm-study-audio-motion-activity/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple Research New Apple study shows LLMs can tell what you’re doing from audio and motion data Marcus Mendes | Nov 21 2025 - 1:56 pm PT 3 Comments Apple researchers have published a study that looks into how LLMs can analyze audio and motion data to get a better overview of the user’s activities. We show that large language models (LLMs) can be used for late fusion for activity classification from audio and motion time series data. , household activities, sports) from the Ego4D dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015578"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/21/apple-research-llm-study-audio-motion-activity/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;skavi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe the 2026 Apple Watch will be able to auto detect running as reliably as my 2015 Samsung Gear S2. My 2022 Series 8 is certainly not there yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rckt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Why do you need LLM to interpret patterns?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gizajob:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Time to ditch the Apple Watch then&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;palmotea:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AI will finally allow us to bring 1984&amp;#x27;s Telescreens into existence, at scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrewrn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Something to note here that annoys me about the title is that the LLMs aren&amp;#x27;t taking in the raw data (LLM&amp;#x27;s are for text, after all). The raw data is fed through audio and motion models that then produce natural language descriptions, that are then fed to the LLM.&lt;p&gt;Unrelated: yeah, this article is a little creepy, but damn is it interesting technically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chasing0entropy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re interested in this concept, it&amp;#x27;s not new and the alarm has been sounded since the android Facebook app required motion sensor permissions in android 4.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;par.nsf.gov&amp;#x2F;servlets&amp;#x2F;purl&amp;#x2F;10028982" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;par.nsf.gov&amp;#x2F;servlets&amp;#x2F;purl&amp;#x2F;10028982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;2109.13834.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;2109.13834.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/21/apple-research-llm-study-audio-motion-activity/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46015578</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
