<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:52:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>My dad could still be alive, but he's not</title>
      <link>https://www.jenn.site/my-dad-could-still-be-alive-but-hes-not/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the dispatcher responds that don't have visibility on that. mom decides that they should not keep waiting. except of course i understand that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909667"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.jenn.site/my-dad-could-still-be-alive-but-hes-not/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 26 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hitensethiya:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Really sorry for you man! May his soul rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;twodave:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I feel this, but in reverse. My son could be dead, but he’s not. He was born on the floor of a trailer park apartment, not breathing. His birth mother’s partner called 911, who dispatched an ambulance. All rescue units for his zone were already busy. An ambulance returning from the nearby hospital to another zone heard the call over the radio and happened to be passing by. The hospital was expecting a DOA, but the paramedics (HEROES) managed to get him breathing again on the way. He’s 11 now, and he is the source of all kinds of trouble and joy. Our home would be very different without him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;boxerab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Canada has experienced an unprecedented spike in both legal and illegal immigration over the past decade of Liberal rule. Every system has its carrying capacity:  the health care &amp;#x2F; EMS system is overloaded (and underfunded). This no doubt contributed to that ambulance not arriving in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;markus_zhang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’m so sad to see this. For anyone who reads this, get a day, learn CPR, and buy that machine if your parents or whoever has history of heart issues. The machine doesn’t fix every kind of heart diseases but the trainer told me it decreases the possibility of death from a heart attack greatly. I recall that the possibility is lowered by 50% if you do CPR and 80% with the machine.&lt;p&gt;It is not hard to use the machine as it has clear instructions. They probably expect you to still be able to read when in panic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zechariahwhite:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My dad also died of a heart attack at 57. I am so sorry to hear this. Thank you for writing it, theres a powerful message in there I think more people need to think about. Sending love and prayers your way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magi604:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a very tragic story and my heart goes out to the family. It&amp;#x27;s one I&amp;#x27;ve seen a few times now and hear about on a very regular basis from my coworkers.&lt;p&gt;I am a Canadian Paramedic (EMR soon to be PCP in a few months, roughly equivalent to EMT and AEMT respectively). Some things strike out at me:&lt;p&gt;- Here in BC our calltakers can advise patients on some treatments. I&amp;#x27;m sure if that were to happen here, they would have advised the family to administer some ASA (Aspirin) to the patient which would have bought valuable time until professional care could be reached. Even if it was found to be contraindicated, the fact it was not mentioned in the blog post stands out to me.&lt;p&gt;- I&amp;#x27;m not familiar with the geography of Toronto or its normal traffic patterns, but it&amp;#x27;s surprising that a single ambulance was not 30 minutes from the patient driving lights and sirens at that time of night (shortly after dinner).&lt;p&gt;- Fire crews here in BC are dispatched to severe medical incidents (like heart attacks) and most of the time can even beat ambulance crews to a scene. They would have been able to provide CPR if needed, possibly even ASA or Nitro depending on their scope. So again it&amp;#x27;s surprising that there&amp;#x27;s no mention of them. Perhaps they aren&amp;#x27;t dispatched to medical calls in Toronto?&lt;p&gt;- Lastly it&amp;#x27;s surprising that the calltaker had no visibility on where the dispatched crews were at. At the very least they could have radioed the crew to get an ETA. I guess I just take it for granted that over here we are tracked as soon as we sign in to our vehicle (it&amp;#x27;s a safety thing especially in some of our more rural&amp;#x2F;remote stations). If the ambulance was just about to reach the patient right before the family decided to go to the hospital on their own, things might have turned out differently.&lt;p&gt;Also since I&amp;#x27;m assuming that a large percentage of HN readers are older males who are at risk of a heart attack (due to factors like working desk jobs and not keeping up with fitness as much), read up on the signs and symptoms of a heart attack and keep a bottle of aspirin at the ready. Bodies are complicated and weird and you never know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samdoesnothing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Such a tragedy, and I&amp;#x27;m really not surprised it happened in Canada. Our healthcare system here is utter garbage and there isn&amp;#x27;t really any political will to do anything about it because &amp;quot;it&amp;#x27;s better than the Americans at least&amp;quot; (it&amp;#x27;s not). I don&amp;#x27;t buy that it&amp;#x27;s underfunded either, it&amp;#x27;s just sorely mismanaged and nobody wants to build or grow. Even a child could tell you if you increase the population of a country by 10% in ten years, you also need to grow its infrastructure by at least that amount - but our political class are idiots and haven&amp;#x27;t even considered it. After all it&amp;#x27;s not &amp;quot;green&amp;quot; to build more hospitals. And thus we get situations like this where there literally aren&amp;#x27;t enough ambulances to handle the load.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sorry if I&amp;#x27;m ranting under a post about a father&amp;#x27;s passing, but tragedies like this are so &lt;i&gt;avoidable&lt;/i&gt; that it practically sends me into a rage. This person should still be alive, she should still have her father. Fuck sakes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;beyondCritics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is terrible to lose a relative in young age.
But at least 80% percent of all heart diseases are known to be fully avoidable. The risk factors are known for ages and as matter of fact every adult is fully responsible to care for his own health. The right thing to do, is to watch out for a healthy diet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moralestapia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stinkbeetle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; my dad is dead, because his family members were too naive to know that the thing they were instructed to do by the state was a false thing.&lt;p&gt;The primary goal of the state is to ensure the power of the state is perpetuated. It&amp;#x27;s really the only goal of the state, anything it does good for its people is a side effect in its pursuit of maintaining power.&lt;p&gt;The government doesn&amp;#x27;t care about you, doesn&amp;#x27;t care about your health, your children&amp;#x27;s education, your safety, your house, your job, anything else about you except in as far as they provide conditions for people sufficient to avoid large scale civil unrest and threat of government losing authority. If individuals get crushed in the machine, nobody gives a shit, least of all the government.&lt;p&gt;This is the reason vigilantism is viewed so harshly by the state and tends to attract much more attention and harsher punishment than a crime that was not motivated by justice. Not because the outcome for a victim of vigilantism is any different, but because the act threatens to undermine the authority of the state in application of justice.&lt;p&gt;The biggest perpetrators of atrocities and injustice, war, murder, theft, genocide, death and suffering through negligence and incompetence, has been the state and agents of the state. Everybody should be critical of everything the government, politicians, bureaucrats, &amp;quot;experts&amp;quot; tell you at all times. Consider they can and do lie and cover-up as easily as a person drinks water, consider motivations, and explore outcomes and alternatives and consider what is best for you, your family, your community, your society. Use your common sense, don&amp;#x27;t prejudice your ideas with what gets repeated about things. Develop plans accordingly, or at least spend a little time to think about these things.&lt;p&gt;This is not &amp;quot;conspiratorial&amp;quot;. The actual conspiracy theory would that those in government are conspiring to actually help the people foremost. Anybody who puts forward that kind of crazed unfounded conspiracy theory had better come up with air-tight evidence, otherwise they&amp;#x27;d just be peddling far-something ultra-something disinformation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;weddpros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My sincere condolences to the author. Wishing you strength and peace.&lt;p&gt;I once saw a man have a heart attack on the beach, less than a 5 minutes drive from a fire-station and rescue team. A helicopter arrived after 45 minutes, and the man was deceased already. That was in Martinique, french Caribbean.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a need for an app to let patients track the ambulance. It&amp;#x27;s been possible for 10+ years, as seen with Uber. It seems existing products have focused on tracking only for the purpose of managing a fleet, missing the focus on patients needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pugio:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I can speak to this. I recently joined a community first responder association (I&amp;#x27;ve always wanted to know what to do in case of a medical emergency) and was shocked to hear the members&amp;#x27; horror stories of how long it can take an ambulance to arrive. Like the author, I grew up with the narrative &amp;quot;in trouble, call the ambulance, they&amp;#x27;ll scream through the streets to get to you in moments&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;That might still be true where I grew up, in the US, but that&amp;#x27;s certainly not a guarantee in Melbourne, where I now live. On joining the local volunteer organization, I went from thinking &amp;quot;oh this will be a useful bonus for the community&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;wow, we can literally be essential&amp;quot;. Since our org is composed of people living within the community, average response time to ANY call is &amp;lt;5 minutes (lower for cardiac arrest, when people really move). Sometimes one of us is right next door.&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;#x27;t do everything an ambulance paramedic can, but we can give aspirin, GTN, oxygen, CPR, and defibrillation. We can also usually navigate&amp;#x2F;bypass the usual triage system to get the ambulance priority upgraded to Code 1 (highest priority, lights + sirens, etc.) If for some reason the ambulance is far away (it backs up all the time), we can go in the patient&amp;#x27;s car with them to the hospital, with our gear, in case of further issues in transit.&lt;p&gt;I tell everyone now to always call us first (since our dispatcher will also call the ambulance) but while I feel more confident in how I&amp;#x27;d handle an emergency, I feel less safe overall, with the system&amp;#x27;s faults and failings more exposed, and the illusion of security stripped away.&lt;p&gt;My condolences to the author.&lt;p&gt;In terms of updating - consider whether The System is really working. If not, what can you do yourself (or within your larger network) to better prepare...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hermannj314:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What is not excusable is why he was told to wait.  A man dies because a rent-seeking bottleneck of corruption sat between him and his doctor.&lt;p&gt;The same politicians that would say this is a tragedy in one breath will send millions to early grave in the next so long as it could line their own pockets.&lt;p&gt;We live in a world diseased by greed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;michaelhoney:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sorry this happened to you&amp;#x2F;Jenn.&lt;p&gt;I lost my brother to a heart attack aged 50, but he died immediately. In the end it was very quick, but he had warning signs for years. Look after yourselves, people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the_jeremy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thanks to this I looked where my nearest ER is and found that it&amp;#x27;s 7 minutes away, so I can&amp;#x27;t imagine calling an ambulance for my wife unless I was worried about her spine. (I don&amp;#x27;t think she can lift me so the reverse isn&amp;#x27;t true.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrcwinn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There&amp;#x27;s another scenario where someone heads to the hospital and get stuck at a red light or behind and accident or you&amp;#x27;re speeding and kill someone. It&amp;#x27;s just hard to know sometimes which path to pick when you don&amp;#x27;t have a guaranteed outcome on either one.&lt;p&gt;In any case, I&amp;#x27;m sorry for your loss. My dad died too due to a heart attack, except he was alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakebasile:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If the author sees this, I&amp;#x27;m sorry for your loss.&lt;p&gt;Losing family is hard, but losing them suddenly makes it harder. Losing them suddenly because of poor advice or (in)action of people who are supposed to help is yet more difficult. I know from experience.&lt;p&gt;It does get easier to deal with, in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;captainkrtek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My condolences, very sorry for your loss.&lt;p&gt;I work as an EMT (911) and resourcing is certainly a problem. In my small city, our response time is around 5 minutes, and if we need to upgrade to get paramedics, that’s maybe another 5-10.&lt;p&gt;However, if we are out on a call, out of service, or the neighboring city is on a call, now the next closest unit is 15+ minutes away.. sometimes there can just be bad luck in that nearby units are already out on multiple calls that came in around the same time, making the next closest response much further.&lt;p&gt;for a heart attack or unstable angina, the most an EMT will do (for our protocols) is recognize the likely heart attack, call for paramedics to perform an EKG to confirm the MI, administer 4 baby aspirin to be chewed and&amp;#x2F;or nitro (rx only), and monitor closely in case it becomes a cardiac arrest. If medics are far away we will probably head immediately to a hospital with a catheterization lab, or rendezvous with medics for them to takeover transport.&lt;p&gt;The few goals though:&lt;p&gt;- recognition (it could also be something equally bad&amp;#x2F;worse like an aortic aneurysm).&lt;p&gt;- aspirin to break any clots, assist administering nitro if prescribed.&lt;p&gt;- getting to a cath lab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;croes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; my dad is dead, because his family members were too naive to know that the thing they were instructed to do by the state was a false thing.&lt;p&gt;Hindsight is 20&amp;#x2F;20.
There are also cases where people died because they didn’t wait for the ambulance. So without proper statistics that‘s a dangerous conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unnamed76ri:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve been reading Influence by Robert Cialdini and just finished a disturbing section about how we are wired to obey an authority figure even when it causes harm. In this instance, the 911 dispatcher was the authority figure. Sad story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moralestapia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;family members were too naive to know that the thing they were instructed to do by the state was a false thing&lt;p&gt;Would be interesting to see everyone who jumped in here yesterday [1] to comment on this one as well.&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45889297"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45889297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vondur:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is horrible. What is going on in Toronto that ambulances take 30 minutes to respond?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ugh123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;my dad is dead, because his family members were too naive to know that the thing they were instructed to do by the state was a false thing.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re told a lot of things by &amp;quot;officials&amp;quot; not because it&amp;#x27;s correct, but because it holds the least legal liability for official parties involved, &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; anything involving healthcare. These officials also sometimes include doctors, who work to protect themselves and the system first, and then patients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chzblck:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m really sorry about your dad.&lt;p&gt;I bet he&amp;#x27;s proud of you for writing and sharing this to help others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hcknwscommenter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Something similar happened to a friend of mine.  In San Francisco.  I just sort of assumed it was just bad luck.  Bad things happen occasionally even in good systems.  But maybe that assumption is wrong?  Is this a thing?  Are ambulances just unreliable?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rectang:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This story reminds me of how the high schoolers on the Korean ferry MV Sewol obeyed the instructions to stay in their rooms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.jenn.site/my-dad-could-still-be-alive-but-hes-not/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909667</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Fovea Detector</title>
      <link>https://www.shadertoy.com/view/4dsXzM</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.shadertoy.com/view/4dsXzM</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909059</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valve is about to win the console generation</title>
      <link>https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/valve-is-about-to-win-the-console-generation/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/valve-is-about-to-win-the-console-generation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 23:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45908464</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
