<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 01:54:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreaking AI Models to Phish Elderly Victims</title>
      <link>https://simonlermen.substack.com/p/can-ai-models-be-jailbroken-to-phish</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://simonlermen.substack.com/p/can-ai-models-be-jailbroken-to-phish</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987252</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verifying your Matrix devices is becoming mandatory</title>
      <link>https://element.io/blog/verifying-your-devices-is-becoming-mandatory-2/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Device verification mattersDevice verification acts like a hand shake between your devices, proving cryptographically to your contacts that they belong to you. Without this verification step, messages sent from your new devices must be marked as untrusted in your conversations. From April 2026:Unverified devices will no longer be able to send messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987179"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://element.io/blog/verifying-your-devices-is-becoming-mandatory-2/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hedora:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t use Matrix, but if it’s E2EE, then how is it possible in the current design for an unverified device to even exist?&lt;p&gt;It has the keys, or it doesn’t, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jerrythegerbil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As someone whose devices randomly became unverified just a few months ago, signed out, and then tried to use my recovery keys: I was authenticated, but unverified.&lt;p&gt;When attempting to verify iOS, Desktop linux didn’t work. When attempting to verify Desktop Linux, Desktop Windows didn’t work. When verifying Android, iOS didn’t work. Every verified official client for every platform was verified, tried a different verification method than expected, and failed.&lt;p&gt;All of this to say, this isn’t the first time this has happened to myself and others. Forcing verification is otherwise known as unexpected “offboarding”. If some verification methods have problems, publish a blog about their deprecation instead.&lt;p&gt;I love element, but this can’t be done without prior work to address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lousken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;The authenticity of this encrypted message cant be guaranteed on this device&amp;quot;
both sides verified, but this still randomly pops up, what happens then? will i lose those messages in the future?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bfkwlfkjf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is this the ritual of getting together with a person and checking that their fingerprint match what you see on the app?&lt;p&gt;If this is that case what will happen is that people will start verifying everyone (because they might want to text to strangers that they can&amp;#x27;t bother verifying because the stakes are so low) and so verification will lose all meaning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tripdout:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; verification? What does it involve doing? A lot of information on why it&amp;#x27;s useful, but how is it implemented? I hope it&amp;#x27;s not something like the Play Integrity API, but with no information to go on, I can&amp;#x27;t say either way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;olivia-banks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What exactly does this entail? I&amp;#x27;m willing to be charitable in assuming that their use of &amp;quot;verify&amp;quot; isn&amp;#x27;t the modern usage of &amp;quot;give us your ID!&amp;quot; but I&amp;#x27;m not enmeshed enough in the ecosystem anymore to know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://element.io/blog/verifying-your-devices-is-becoming-mandatory-2/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987179</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debunking the Myths of the HBO Chernobyl series (2023)</title>
      <link>https://blog.osm-ai.net/investigation/2023/01/05/hbo-chernobyl-myth.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Legasov indicated the opposite. Legasov made no mention of this. Legasov believed that this work was unnecessary and excessive, but the only positive aspect was that it prov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987289"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.osm-ai.net/investigation/2023/01/05/hbo-chernobyl-myth.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papazsazsa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There is a podcast [1] featuring the showrunner Craig Mazin who is also a very conscientious and prolific podcaster [2] who cares deeply about balancing fact with a compelling narrative.&lt;p&gt;This is the basic difference between historical fiction and documentary. Having worked as a screenwriter myself I can assure you that even if the script had been 100% factual, things would have been changed beyond the creators&amp;#x27; control anyway.&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;the-chernobyl-podcast&amp;#x2F;id1459712981" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;podcasts.apple.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;podcast&amp;#x2F;the-chernobyl-podcast&amp;#x2F;...&lt;/a&gt;
2 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;scriptnotes.net&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;scriptnotes.net&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tptacek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;M. Gessen wrote a much better piece about the accuracy of HBO&amp;#x27;s Chernobyl:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.newyorker.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;our-columnists&amp;#x2F;what-hbos-chernobyl-got-right-and-what-it-got-terribly-wrong" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.newyorker.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;our-columnists&amp;#x2F;what-hbos-cher...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This piece seems a little confused, since Legasov wasn&amp;#x27;t the primary source for the show?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sqrt_1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It really annoys me when fiction is based on real events, takes a lot of liberty with the source material that it enters into the public consciousness.&lt;p&gt;The classic case is the &amp;quot;The Life and Voyages of Christopher Columbus&amp;quot; where it was claimed he was aiming to prove the Earth was not flat. 
My personal peeve is movies like &amp;quot;The Imitation Game&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catapart:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; It’s like we’ve chosen to ignore the truth in favor of a good story or a good feeling.&lt;p&gt;Aww, man. I&amp;#x27;ve got some bad news for you about literally any fact you know that isn&amp;#x27;t derived from math. And even that is still, philosophically, just some stories we&amp;#x27;re telling ourselves about the observations we&amp;#x27;re all seeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cm2012:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nit pick after nit pick&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisMarshallNY:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It was a good show. I&amp;#x27;ve re-watched it a couple of times. The actors are excellent, and it&amp;#x27;s well-done.&lt;p&gt;I take it for granted that a lot of it was amped up for drama, but other sources (several documentaries) seem to agree on a lot of the actions and timelines. The show added motivations, and some fictional characters.&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed &lt;i&gt;Dopesick&lt;/i&gt;, and that&amp;#x27;s a subject that I have direct experience and knowledge of. I have pretty much the same issues with that show.&lt;p&gt;But I still enjoyed both of them as dramas.&lt;p&gt;If I want facts, I&amp;#x27;ll do my own research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tomboden:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m currently writing my own expose on the historical inaccuracies in the Harry Potter series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hodgehog11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;To be honest, I find most of these inconsistencies to be inconsequential for enjoying the film. The ones that really get to me though are the dramatic overestimates on the devastation caused by Chernobyl, and the effects of the radiation itself. Most of the effect of the film comes from this belief that the radiation really is that dangerous. When you know it isn&amp;#x27;t, it takes quite a bit away from the premise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jihadjihad:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a dramatization, of course there are going to be liberties taken and creative license used to further the (TFA might say contrived) story.&lt;p&gt;One thing not mentioned in TFA, though, is how those suffering from radiation sickness (first responders like the firefighter Ignatenko, etc.) are portrayed almost as if they are contagious, and so should not be touched. The Chernobyl series is not the only one to do this, either, and it can lead to viewers thinking radiation sickness is something you can &amp;quot;catch&amp;quot; from someone else.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know why they never make it clear that it&amp;#x27;s &lt;i&gt;for the sake of the sickened themselves&lt;/i&gt; that contact should be minimized (assuming all contaminated clothing etc. has already been discarded), since their immune and other internal systems are totally compromised by radiation poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hkpack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think we need to also debunk the debunking.&lt;p&gt;You know, some of us were already living then and it is not some distant event we have no knowledge of.&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Re: The soviet government did not want to evacuate the town of Pripyat&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Debunking: Legasov indicated the opposite. He said that the decision to evacuate was made quickly, even though the levels of radiation in the town were not considered to be dangerous.&lt;p&gt;WTF? The level of radiation was not considered to be dangerous when your reactor was blown open? Are you fucking kidding?&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Re: The government made an effort to conceal everything regarding the accident and what was happening.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Legasov stated that this was not the case, and that information was not provided at the time because it didn&amp;#x27;t exist. The situation was very confusing, and information was scarce, coming from multiple conflicting sources and estimates, making it difficult to collect, filter, and access the correct information.&lt;p&gt;The accident happened on 26 April 1986, and on the 1st of May, _4 days later_ there was a celebration of Labour Day - a mandatory parade in Kyiv within just 100 km. And no-one knew about the disaster from the official sources. Only people with access to foreign radio knew about the disaster, others were happily marching with red flags on the streets breathing polluted air.&lt;p&gt;And so on, and so forth...&lt;p&gt;He claims that they had all the equipment ready and knew the actual levels, but at the same time were confused and information was scarce, and the level of radiation were not that bad - it this some type of propaganda for the dumb?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mvkel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Legasov commended the swiftness and efficiency of the government response at all levels&lt;p&gt;Sure, but in those times, he would be compelled to say such things. That doesn&amp;#x27;t mean he believed it.&lt;p&gt;It seems the main faults that OP finds in the show are that Legasov had issues with his government, when in &amp;quot;reality&amp;quot; he thought they were great. But is that &amp;quot;reality,&amp;quot; or oppression?&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;#x27;t see the fault in highlighting him as the &amp;quot;main&amp;quot; scientist; it&amp;#x27;s a show.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;unethical_ban:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;At the end of the day, creators want an entertaining show and that usually requires intrigue, interpersonal conflict, character growth, good vs. evil, etc.&lt;p&gt;Biopics&amp;#x2F;dramatizations of events often bring multiple minor characters together into a single person.&lt;p&gt;I would be more bothered by the change of small details irrelevant to the narrative than I am by larger character changes. I would prefer that the mainline details stay the same - chain of events, impact to the town, aftermath - but I am not watching the series in order to write a paper. I appreciate the articles which document the fiction vs. reality of historical dramas, but I do not share in any anger. Then again, I&amp;#x27;m not related to anyone whose character was represented in the series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ggm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This kind of &amp;quot;for the drama&amp;quot; variance is very common. Look at archaeologists reaction to Coogans film about Richard III which went to court.&lt;p&gt;Films, even documentary, don&amp;#x27;t always get it right and often don&amp;#x27;t even try because &amp;quot;based on&amp;quot; admits a lot of change.&lt;p&gt;People often don&amp;#x27;t understand history. &amp;quot;The KGB regiments shot deserters in ww2 Stalingrad&amp;quot; since the KGB was formed in 1954, that&amp;#x27;s a serious mis-statement of history. Should we be surprised the role of soviet structural agencies is misunderstood by an american dramatisation? (This kgb comment is a generalisation for illustration not a dig at anything in the doco)&lt;p&gt;Still. It&amp;#x27;s a pretty egregious list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dylan604:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s funny that this series seems as if it is being confused as a documentary. It was a dramatic telling of a story. Creative licensing was in full effect. The first item in the  &amp;quot;Series VS tapes: point by point&amp;quot; is a very common use of that creative licensing. Trying to follow multiple people in a work like this gets tiring and a bit boring. The details are kept, but it&amp;#x27;s easier to follow when those multiple people are written as one character. It&amp;#x27;s why the term &amp;quot;littleuns&amp;quot; was used in Lord of The Flies as the individuals were not important to the story, just the fact they were there and needed to be considered allowed the story to not get bogged down.&lt;p&gt;The series was also told completely in ~8 hours of content, yet this event clearly took longer than 8 hours to play out. Why no critique on that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.osm-ai.net/investigation/2023/01/05/hbo-chernobyl-myth.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987289</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workday to acquire Pipedream</title>
      <link>https://newsroom.workday.com/2025-11-19-Workday-Signs-Definitive-Agreement-to-Acquire-Pipedream</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;"Joining Workday allows us to bring that simplicity to more than 11,000 organizations around the world, unlocking AI-powered workflows that make work dramatically easier. Orrick is serving as legal advisor to Workday. About Workday Workday is the enterprise AI platform for managing people, money, and agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987220"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://newsroom.workday.com/2025-11-19-Workday-Signs-Definitive-Agreement-to-Acquire-Pipedream'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xgulfie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Pipedream is a platform for building AI agents&lt;p&gt;It is? Last I used it, it was a serverless event-driven pipeline platform&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;haolez:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My company uses Workday. It is integrated with our EntraID SSO. If you leave a tab open for a few minutes, it will close your session automatically, which means logging you out of Microsoft 365 altogether. Simply bizarre. Maybe more AI will help them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dustyharddrive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great news for this site&amp;#x27;s most prolific spammer!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;namegulf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Got confused first reading the title of this post (thought someone joking about a pipedream)&lt;p&gt;This is interesting acquisition, a integration platform to boost their AI offering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pbw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Workday is a disaster, at least the version we have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;afavour:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Workday, Inc. (NASDAQ: WDAY), the enterprise AI platform for managing people, money, and agents, today announced it has entered into a definitive agreement to acquire Pipedream, a leading integration platform for AI agents&lt;p&gt;Pipedream indeed!&lt;p&gt;It blows my mind that every company has decided to call itself an “AI platform” but it blows my mind even more that the stock market apparently believes them when they say it. Workday was an HR platform five years ago. It still an HR platform today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://newsroom.workday.com/2025-11-19-Workday-Signs-Definitive-Agreement-to-Acquire-Pipedream</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987220</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Researchers discover security vulnerability in WhatsApp</title>
      <link>https://www.univie.ac.at/en/news/detail/forscherinnen-entdecken-grosse-sicherheitsluecke-in-whatsapp</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.univie.ac.at/en/news/detail/forscherinnen-entdecken-grosse-sicherheitsluecke-in-whatsapp</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985036</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise geolocation via Wi-Fi Positioning System</title>
      <link>https://www.amoses.dev/blog/wifi-location/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That could be catastrophic. After allowing your browser permission to access your location, a website has access to the getCurrentPosition() function. But how does this translate to your location on a map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985867"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.amoses.dev/blog/wifi-location/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UltraSane:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve had companies send us laptops for VPN access that had LTE modems and GPS specifically for location verification before granting access to the VPN.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bigiain:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I assume that smart comp sci kids already have some sort of proxy running on an Android phone that publishes the current in-classroom WiFi environment, and a browser plugin or Linux hack that their stay-at-home friends can run that intercepts the geolocation calls and spoofs the responses with what the in-classroom android phone is seeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;friedgil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Small digression: did you know that, until May 2000, GPS satellites (which are owned and operated by the United States Space Force) provided the general public a signal with intentional error built into it?&lt;p&gt;What the hell? Why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paxys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;As the article mentions this tech has been in widespread use for over two decades now. You have likely used it on your phone today without knowing it. GPS is accurate but also very fickle (takes time to get a lock, battery hog, doesn&amp;#x27;t work great when surrounded by buildings, doesn&amp;#x27;t work great when inside a building, doesn&amp;#x27;t work in bad weather). Wifi data is plentiful today in every urban setting, and you can get an exact location in under a second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;montroser:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One time I worked at a zoom competitor, and our team got to prototype a &amp;quot;detect if these people are in the same room as each other&amp;quot; feature for dealing with echo cancellation etc, where everyone&amp;#x27;s laptop would emit a unique high frequency, and everyone&amp;#x27;s laptop would listen for other frequencies.  Of course it worked in pristine conditions and fell down in the real world. But it was a fun experiment...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nlawalker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Oh wow, it&amp;#x27;s the modern version of the &lt;i&gt;clicker&lt;/i&gt;, the physical device assigned to you at the beginning of the term used for classroom participation and attendance checking, and which was most definitely defeatable via &amp;quot;the unpatchable strategy of Having Friends&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IshKebab:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TL;DR: location API exists. Wifi-based location exists. American universities apparently use this to take &amp;quot;secure&amp;quot; attendance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;neilv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The root problem is that a lot of higher education is nurturing a culture of cheaters right now.&lt;p&gt;Your future doctors, scientists, government officials, etc...  will have had to compete and gain coveted academic and career opportunities, in an environment that both has been heavily gamified, and is being overrun by cheaters.&lt;p&gt;Insulting measures like this TopHat practically endorses the culture of cheating, by telling students that they can&amp;#x27;t be trusted, and turning into yet another cheating challenge&amp;#x2F;task.&lt;p&gt;Schools with any integrity should be bending over backwards to find, nurture, and support students of integrity.&lt;p&gt;And to save those who only got admitted by being sketchy, but first semester is a chance to unlearn the bad lessons from before.&lt;p&gt;Not by treating them as criminals to be monitored, but by treating them like the respectable people they should aspire to be, and which the school expects and requires that they be.&lt;p&gt;And, for any hopelessly shitty students, who fail to honor this first semester extension of trust, the school should smack them to the curb.  Lost tuition income, lost named buildings&amp;#x2F;chairs, and expensive lawsuits from helicopter parents, be damned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;incompatible:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My PC doesn&amp;#x27;t have any wireless connections and the Geolocation API always fails. I guess I&amp;#x27;d fail this course (which is apparently correct, as I was supposed to be attending in person with a laptop.)&lt;p&gt;Edit: Presumably it would be possible to hack the browser to return a false position.&lt;p&gt;Edit: Make it a convenient browser add-on, perhaps. There must be other applications.&lt;p&gt;Edit: pkulak points out that you just have to set a Firefox option. Why do I even comment on things I know nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ginko:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe it’s because I studied in Austria where universities generally provide very little handholding to students but I don’t understand the point of compulsory attendance in university lectures. If students think they can pass exams without attending the lectures then they should be able to do that. I certainly did that once or twice when I realized I needed some more credits before the end of the term.
It’s a different thing with lab&amp;#x2F;exercise sessions but your lack of participation there would be noticed anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;p1necone:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it common for North American universities to take attendance? Seems like a whole lot of effort to gain little and infantilize your students. They&amp;#x27;re paying tuition, and if they don&amp;#x27;t show up to class they get punished by not learning enough and subsequently failing their exams&amp;#x2F;assessments. And if they don&amp;#x27;t fail their exams&amp;#x2F;assessments then clearly mandating lecture attendance for them wasn&amp;#x27;t necessary anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;denysvitali:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve recently vibe-coded &amp;quot;where-am-i&amp;quot;, a small CLI that returns your approximate location using the technology described here.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;denysvitali&amp;#x2F;where-am-i" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;denysvitali&amp;#x2F;where-am-i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tbh, I think this geolocation method is amazing, and I&amp;#x27;m grateful it exists, because GPS indoor really sucks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pkulak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use a Firefox preference to pin my location to a spot near, but not at, my house:&lt;p&gt;user_pref(&amp;quot;geo.provider.network.url&amp;quot;, &amp;#x27;data:application&amp;#x2F;json,{&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;: {&amp;quot;lat&amp;quot;: 45.0, &amp;quot;lng&amp;quot;: -122.0}, &amp;quot;accuracy&amp;quot;: 128.0}&amp;#x27;);&lt;p&gt;I _believe_ this also stops wifi data from leaking anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ralsei:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good article, but you could also just use a VPN to trick it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.amoses.dev/blog/wifi-location/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985867</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Career Opportunities in 2025: Skills in High Demand</title>
      <link>https://www.linuxcareers.com/resources/blog/2025/11/linux-career-opportunities-in-2025-skills-in-high-demand/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud Engineering and Linux Cloud computing has become inseparable from Linux expertise. DevOps and Linux Integration The DevOps job market is thriving, with Linux skills ranking among the most sought-after technical capabilities. Cybersecurity and Linux Cybersecurity roles heavily leverage Linux systems, with strong demand for professionals who can secure Linux environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987027"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.linuxcareers.com/resources/blog/2025/11/linux-career-opportunities-in-2025-skills-in-high-demand/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mixmastamyk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;None of these are in high-demand right now in my experience.  Despite being an expert in most of these listed, I haven&amp;#x27;t even had an interview in a couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;itomato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;ProTip: Raise your rates. The &amp;quot;typical salary ranges&amp;quot; are laughable, even in 2008 Dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;therealfiona:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What I&amp;#x27;d give to have someone who&amp;#x27;s Linux experience isn&amp;#x27;t using a Mac and using brew to install stuff.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m the only one with formal Linux experience on my team and I&amp;#x27;m the only one who doesn&amp;#x27;t have to look up how to get to the logs...&lt;p&gt;K8s admin != Linux grey beard. SurprisedPikachu.gif&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;debo_:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Linux engineers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cushychicken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And embedded Linux!&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a hell of a time finding good embedded Linux devs.&lt;p&gt;I got &lt;i&gt;insanely&lt;/i&gt; lucky to hire two this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andy99:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So sick of these “Accept all cookies” &amp;#x2F; “reject optional cookies” dark patterns, sites that do this should be banned&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.linuxcareers.com/resources/blog/2025/11/linux-career-opportunities-in-2025-skills-in-high-demand/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45987027</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roblox Requires Age Checks for Communication, Ushering in New Safety Standard</title>
      <link>https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/11/roblox-requires-age-checks-limits-minor-and-adult-chat</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chat outside of experiences remains restricted for users under 13. For example: Elisa (estimated age 12): Elisa has access to chat with users aged 15 or younger in Experience chat. Through Trusted Connections, age-checked users 13 or older can chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985799"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/11/roblox-requires-age-checks-limits-minor-and-adult-chat'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rgregg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;d be nice if they&amp;#x27;d do some simple common sense things - like give you a report of which games were being played and provide parental controls around which games can be played. It shocks me (but not really) that they haven&amp;#x27;t done this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;samename:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is deeply concerning. No parent should be letting their kids faces be scanned with this. They claim to “delete” the image a videos after the scan, but make no mistake, the signature is saved and will be used to track the child online for the rest of their life. We need to have better protections around biometrics. Surveillance is not the solution we want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jswelker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The most impressive thing about Roblox is how many predatory parties they have managed to pack into one children&amp;#x27;s platform. The company itself with its microtransactions, cash hungry creators with lowest common denominator and&amp;#x2F;or sexualized content, creepy adults behaving badly, probably some hostile foreign governments in all likelihood. Maybe add in a 4chan integration next just to cover a wider spectrum of villainy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dbg31415:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Remember, Roblox is toxic and exploits young people.&lt;p&gt;- Roblox Isn&amp;#x27;t a Game | Psychology Today &amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.psychologytoday.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;video-game-health&amp;#x2F;202511&amp;#x2F;roblox-isnt-a-game" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.psychologytoday.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;video-game-health&amp;#x2F;20...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Investigation: How Roblox Is Exploiting Young Game Developers - YouTube &amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=_gXlauRB1EQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=_gXlauRB1EQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Roblox Pressured Us to Delete Our Video. So We Dug Deeper. - YouTube &amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=vTMF6xEiAaY" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=vTMF6xEiAaY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Roblox is Darker Than You Think (ft. Ruben Sim) - YouTube &amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F; &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=Av03P5D11PQ&amp;amp;t=55s" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=Av03P5D11PQ&amp;amp;t=55s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;xeonmc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Roblox calling themselves the industry gold standard in online safety is about as ridiculous as Riot Games calling themselves the beacon of technical excellence in game development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;crtasm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So besides scanning your child&amp;#x27;s face they also want access to their phone contacts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gambiting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does that help with any of this?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hindenburgresearch.com&amp;#x2F;roblox&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hindenburgresearch.com&amp;#x2F;roblox&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Following years of scandals, we performed our own checks to see if the platform had cleaned up its act. As a test, we attempted to set up an account under the name ‘Jeffrey Epstein’…only to see the name was taken, along with 900+ variations.
Many were Jeffrey Epstein fan accounts, including “JeffEpsteinSupporter” which had earned multiple badges for spending time in kid’s games. Other Jeff Epstein accounts had the usernames “@igruum_minors” [I groom minors], and “@RavpeTinyK1dsJE” [rape tiny kids].
We attempted to set up a Roblox account under the name of another notorious pedophile to see if Roblox had any up-front pedophile screening: Earl Brian Bradley was indicted on 471 charges of molesting, raping and exploiting 103 children. The username was taken, along with multiple variants like earlbrianbradley69.
After we found a username, we listed our age as “under 13” to see if children are being exposed to adult content. By merely plugging ‘adult’ into the Roblox search bar, we found a group called “Adult Studios” with 3,334 members openly trading child pornography and soliciting sexual acts from minors.
We tracked some of the members of “Adult Studios” and easily found 38 Roblox groups – one with 103,000 members – openly soliciting sexual favors and trading child pornography.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sanex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been saying we need a separate Internet for kids. Not just because of pedos, but because young adults don&amp;#x27;t have the same level of respect and filters that one should have when dealing with kids and it&amp;#x27;s exposing them to behavior they shouldn&amp;#x27;t. This is a great step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://corp.roblox.com/newsroom/2025/11/roblox-requires-age-checks-limits-minor-and-adult-chat</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985799</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Slide Rules Work</title>
      <link>https://amenzwa.github.io/stem/ComputingHistory/HowSlideRulesWork/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This device was the forerunner of the slide rule. Buildings, bridges, machines, and even computer system components, were designed by slide rule. The largest and most enthusiastic group of slide rule users, naturally, were engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985196"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://amenzwa.github.io/stem/ComputingHistory/HowSlideRulesWork/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;egl2020:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I still have the wooden 10&amp;quot; Keuffel and Esser that I inherited from my father and that I used in college.  These days I use my HP15C unless I want to provoke glee and amusement in my younger colleagues by sporting my Pickett slide rule in my shirt pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;watersb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A sort of non-logarithmic slide rule, the E6B Flight Computer, was still in use when I was a student pilot 20 years ago. I still carry one: they don&amp;#x27;t require electricity (although using one in the dark requires a light source).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;E6B" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;E6B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jamesgill:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Last week I donated several slide rules to Goodwill; a few were very nice. Meanwhile, I still have a pristine HP-41cx and HP-15c, and an HP-25 app on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gerdesj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is worth keeping one around.&lt;p&gt;When the &amp;quot;cloud&amp;quot; is raining and your laptop and phone batteries are drained and you suddenly need to navigate your 4823 times table - its got you covered.&lt;p&gt;You will also need to work out how to write with a pen or pencil on paper or try and fix up your atrophied ability to remember arbitrary &amp;quot;facts&amp;quot; short term.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fjfaase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have one at home, which is the one we had to buy to use in highschool. In the math classrooms we had a 6 feet version that could be mounted on the blackboard such that the teacher could used for instruction. See for a picture on the Dutch page &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rekenlat.barneveld.com&amp;#x2F;rekenliniaal.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rekenlat.barneveld.com&amp;#x2F;rekenliniaal.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clickety_clack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Slide rules are super cool. Such an easy gift to give the engineer in your life.&lt;p&gt;I never spent the time to get quick with it, but I could absolutely see it being quicker than a calculator. You’d just have to be aware of the limits to its precision if you were in a field that required it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetMageSCW:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The HP-35 wasn’t programmable- it was just a scientific calculator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JKCalhoun:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Deep dive, for sure. I suspect Cliff Stoll is enjoying this site.&lt;p&gt;I played with creating a logarithmic slider thing [1] in Javascript that I hoped I could package up as a kind of &amp;quot;widget&amp;quot; people could use on their web pages. But I don&amp;#x27;t really know Javascript that well—or rather how to make an API out of a Javascript thing.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to test it I tried to make an Ohm&amp;#x27;s Law calculator [2].&lt;p&gt;I would love to see a site like the one in this post have some kind of interactive slide rule on the web page itself.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;EngineersNeedArt&amp;#x2F;SlideRule" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;EngineersNeedArt&amp;#x2F;SlideRule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.engineersneedart.com&amp;#x2F;ohmslaw&amp;#x2F;index.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.engineersneedart.com&amp;#x2F;ohmslaw&amp;#x2F;index.html&lt;/a&gt; (the yellow slider is not directly user-moveable in this example)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kingforaday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This would have been helpful for Sam Cooke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://amenzwa.github.io/stem/ComputingHistory/HowSlideRulesWork/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985196</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/tech/823337/switching-linux-gaming-desktop-cachyos</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable. I don’t like where Windows is going. Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985506"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.theverge.com/tech/823337/switching-linux-gaming-desktop-cachyos'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 30 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ndesaulniers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Dunno, just upgraded Fedora to Fedora 43 and all of the games I had set up (wine) stopped working. Will try gaming on Linux again next decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;marcus_holmes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I switched over last year, no problems. Everything runs fine, and often better than on my wife&amp;#x27;s Windows machine. We&amp;#x27;re going to switch her over soon, because Windows 11 is such a shitshow.&lt;p&gt;Really interested to see where Valve goes with the new hardware. I love my Steam Deck, so I have faith they&amp;#x27;ll do a good job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h4kunamata:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Gaming on Linux always sucked because of many factors:&lt;p&gt;1. Linux decades ago was not &amp;quot;new user friendly&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;2. Wine and PLayOnLinux was all we had with endless problem, and heavy dependency on Windows files like DirectX and libraries&lt;p&gt;3. Windows dominated the gaming market&lt;p&gt;4. 3D GPU driver was non-existent&lt;p&gt;The single reason why gaming on Linux now is better than Windows, has one name: Valve&lt;p&gt;SteamDeck&amp;#x2F;SteamOS changed everything, the whole Wine process is managed by the OS and no longer by the user. You may need to change the Proton version, that is all.
That also pushed GPU drivers to be better supported on Linux.&lt;p&gt;Valve single handled what gaming on Linux has become.
I run Mint Cinnamon Linux, and even tho it is not &amp;quot;SteamOS&amp;quot;, I can play Steam games just fine.&lt;p&gt;Microsoft terrible takes and AI, is also pushing gamers over to Linux, better FPS on Linux than Windows. 
The only restriction is kernel anti-cheat software that only runs on Windows, but many games do not use that and the ones that do use it like COD(dead game), BF, etc, isn&amp;#x27;t everybody cup of tea.&lt;p&gt;If it wasn&amp;#x27;t for Valve, Linux gaming would still be as dead as it has always been.&lt;p&gt;To make it more perfect, users that use their computer for browsing, writing docs (LibreOffice), etc, can be done on Linux for free.&lt;p&gt;You as a computer user in 2025, you have little to no excuse to try Linux, but try something good like Mint Cinnamon Linux that is extremely new user friendly, good for browsing, good for development work, solid for gaming, video editing is chef kiss, etc, etc.
Avoid Ubuntu (they are going proprietary).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jachee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There is exactly one game keeping me from running Linux as my main OS… and that’s iRacing.&lt;p&gt;Sadly, they won’t (not &lt;i&gt;can’t&lt;/i&gt;…) ship the flag in EOS (née EAC) that enables anti-cheat support on Linux. It would work, but they just don’t have the resources to support a whole other family of OSes.&lt;p&gt;So, between that and the abject murder of WMR for my Reverb G2, I’m stuck on Win10 for the foreseeable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escapade5160:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you are looking solely for a Linux gaming distro, Bazzite is it. I switched from Windows earlier this year and I haven&amp;#x27;t looked back. Everything works out of the box.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bazzite.gg&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;bazzite.gg&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venn1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This week we closed the doors on our Linux gaming podcast, which has run continuously for the past 13 years. No fuss, no drama. With the announcement of Steam Machine II (we also covered the original launch), it just seemed like the right time. Proton has evolved to the point where most things work out of the box. Few people are bothering with native support, and it’s become difficult to find new things to cover.&lt;p&gt;It really feels like everything is lined up for the year of Linux in the living room, and it’s great to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venn1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This week we shut the doors on our Linux gaming podcast that has been running continuously for the past 13 years. No fuss, no drama, but with the announcement of Steam Machine II (we also covered the origianl launch) it just seemed time. Proton has evolved to the point most things work out of the box. Nobody is bothering with native and it&amp;#x27;s gotten difficuls to find things to cover.&lt;p&gt;It really feels like evertying is ligned up for the year of Linux in the Living room and yeah, it&amp;#x27;s really good to see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dgunay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been gaming on Linux exclusively for the last few years. Problems with games are few and far between these days.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve only had to fully reinstall once every ~2 years or so, and it&amp;#x27;s usually due to some problem with my DE&amp;#x2F;system not booting that I can&amp;#x27;t be fucked to troubleshoot. That&amp;#x27;s mostly my fault for running GNOME on a rolling distro. I just back up my home dir to the storage drive and I&amp;#x27;m back up and running in less than an hour. Other than that, it just continues to work and I can be reasonably assured that if I don&amp;#x27;t touch it, it&amp;#x27;ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LanceH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I just tried installing Heroic Games on Arch, and the install process has left me less than impressed.  It will be one vague error with a bunch of forums saying, &amp;quot;try this&amp;quot; and no &amp;quot;this is what that error means&amp;quot;.  I try to install that one and it has its own error, with the same forum experience.  I&amp;#x27;m not trying to install something which will allow me to install vulkan which will allow me to install heroic games...maybe.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think an Epic games launcher is exactly obscure.  Mind you, I&amp;#x27;m completely commmitted to Linux and having the launcher is just in the &amp;quot;nice to have&amp;quot; category, but it hasn&amp;#x27;t gone well so far.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keithnz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really like windows 11, works great. I have it way more customized to my liking than most &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; users would, but there&amp;#x27;s really no negative impact on me.  I also have a Mac and use Linux  (bounced between arch, ubuntu, and now just use PopOS).  Overall I generally prefer windows, it generally runs everything.  Things like windows powertoys make the user experience pretty nice, doing similar on linux requires a lot more work. Wezterm standardizes the terminal across all platforms.   But the OS really doesn&amp;#x27;t matter too much, it only accounts for maybe &amp;lt;10% of my experience.  But everything just seems a bit easier on windows but I could live just fine in any of the OS&amp;#x27;s if I had to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B-Con:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I just rebuilt my PC and setup Steam on Linux. It was fairly smooth.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve dual-booted Arch and Windows for about 16 years. I always kept Windows around for gaming, and the occasional &amp;quot;doesn&amp;#x27;t support Linux&amp;quot; workflow.&lt;p&gt;For a few years where I didn&amp;#x27;t game I found myself almost exclusively in Linux. But then I spent the last 5-6 years stuck between the two as my PC use for daily tasks dwindled, I stopped working on side projects, and I started gaming a bit more.&lt;p&gt;I hated trying to split my time between them. Most of what I used a PC for was the browser, so I could just stay in Windows most of the time. I wanted to use Linux, but rebooting to use a web browser just didn&amp;#x27;t make sense. As a result I would accidentally go 2-3 months without ever booting Arch. As a result, I had a couple of major updates that didn&amp;#x27;t go smoothly.&lt;p&gt;I wanted to use Linux, though. I like having a customized WM, I like having so many useful tools at my disposal, etc. I just like using Linux, in spite of the occasional technical complexity.&lt;p&gt;In the last couple months I rebuilt my PC and a major requirement was that I get set up to game in Linux as much as possible. I even bought an AMD card to ensure smooth driver support.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m so incredibly thankful that Steam has made gaming not just possible, but relatively simple. Installation was simple. My single-player games seem well supported so far. And most importantly, Steam has made it obvious they&amp;#x27;re committed to this line of support, so this isn&amp;#x27;t some hero effort that will bit rot in a couple years.&lt;p&gt;I still have to reboot to play competitive games, due to their anti-cheat requirements, but that&amp;#x27;s less of a problem, I&amp;#x27;ll take what I can get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vinkelhake:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I recently had my Framework Desktop delivered. I didn&amp;#x27;t plan on using it for gaming, but I figured I should at least try. My experience thus far:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * I installed Fedora 43 and it (totally unsurprisingly) worked great.
    * I installed Steam from Fedora&amp;#x27;s software app, and that worked great as well.
    * I installed Cyberpunk 2077 from Steam, and it just... worked.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Big thanks to Valve for making this as smooth as it was. I was able to go from no operating system to Cyberpunk running with zero terminals open or configs tweaked.&lt;p&gt;I later got a hankering to play Deus Ex: Mankind Divided. This time, the game would not work and Steam wasn&amp;#x27;t really forthcoming with showing logs. I figured out how to see the logs, and then did what you do these days - I showed the logs to an AI. The problem, slightly ironically, with MD is that it has a Linux build and Steam was trying to run that thing by default. The Linux build (totally unsurprisingly) had all kinds of version issues with libraries. The resolution there was just to tell Steam to run the Windows build instead and that worked great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;issafram:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Installing a working Nvidia driver was a nightmare for me.  And this was on a very recent version of Ubuntu.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know if I would use the word approachable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spuz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; So really, why wouldn’t I blow that up and start over?&lt;p&gt;I really wish more people would mention the option of dual booting. Use another separate SSD to install your linux OS and that way you always have the option of going back to your Windows install. You can even reserve some programs for Windows and do everything else with linux.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s really no need to approach it with a &amp;quot;screw it&amp;quot; attitude. You&amp;#x27;ll probably get yourself in too deep with that approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ruined:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;I’m going to install CachyOS, an Arch-based distro optimized for gaming on modern hardware, with support for cutting-edge CPUs and GPUs and an allegedly easy setup.&lt;p&gt;oh no&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vagab0nd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had to briefly go back to Windows and I just couldn&amp;#x27;t understand how anyone serious can run an OS that just decides to reboot itself in the middle of the night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;molave:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Changed from Windows 10 to an Ubuntu with beefy specs. When I saw firsthand the improvement of the user experience, I felt the year of the Linux desktop is nigh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;djhworld:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My gaming PC sits next to the TV in my living room and I use it like a console, I have one of those cheap blutooth wireless keyboards with trackpad for the really basic iteractions and then I just use a game controller for playing games.&lt;p&gt;Windows 11 has been fine for me, I don&amp;#x27;t interact with it much other than seeing it for a bit when launching games.&lt;p&gt;I honestly wouldn&amp;#x27;t mind giving Linux a go, the only downside is I made the mistake of buying an nvidia graphics card, I&amp;#x27;m not sure how much of a pain it is these days but last time I tried it was a bit of a nightmare - the general wisdom at the time was to go with an AMD card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrewmutz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use bazzite linux for gaming full time and can&amp;#x27;t say enough good things about it.  You don&amp;#x27;t need to do anything at all to maintain it.  Every Windows game I&amp;#x27;ve ever tried just works perfectly out of the box.  Sometimes I will see a warning telling me that a certain game is not certified for a good experience by Steam, and it all just works perfect anyway.&lt;p&gt;When I was running Windows on the same machine I was constantly trying to diagnose why things stopped working, and downloading drivers.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my experience with Windows was worse than average, I don&amp;#x27;t know.  But from my perspective there is zero reason not to run Linux full time for gaming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arcfour:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have been waiting for this time to come. Microsoft clearly doesn&amp;#x27;t care about Windows very much, and Linux has never been more ready to break out in market share. Quite exciting to see!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more_corn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My buddy gave me a computer because it wouldn’t run 11. I put Zorin Linux on it. I’m quite pleased.&lt;p&gt;Not once in initial setup or first week of use did it use dark patterns to try to trick or force me into something I don’t want to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pshirshov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It should be NixOS of course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AuthAuth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is bad. New user going onto an arch distro with a ton of tweaks is worst case scenario for a smooth experience.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m sure cachyOS will work a treat out of the box, but i&amp;#x27;m also sure that one day things will stop working and cascade into a distro hop or reinstall leaving a sour taste in the users mouth.&lt;p&gt;You do not need a &amp;quot;gaming&amp;quot; distro, all distros use the same software and you will be fine on ubuntu, fedora etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;I don&amp;#x27;t want to talk to my computer&lt;p&gt;I recently vibe coded a voice typing software (using Parakeet — your best bet is probably Handy though).&lt;p&gt;It works in my terminal. (I just changed my paste shortcut to Ctrl+V&lt;p&gt;I can now literally speak software into existence!&lt;p&gt;I made a thin wrapper around my llm() function I can pipe text into from Bash.&lt;p&gt;This allows me to make many other thin LLM wrappers, such as one that summarizes then contents of entire directories.&lt;p&gt;I have a thing called Jarvis inspired by a Twitter post, where I ask it to do anything in bash, and it just does that.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;#x27;t exactly say it&amp;#x27;s useful (I am unemployed) but I am kind of having my mind blown a little bit.&lt;p&gt;The future is already here, it&amp;#x27;s just not evenly distributed yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jigsy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was still using Windows 8.1 at the start of 2024 and was trying to slowly shift away to Linux at the time, but circumstances beyond my control ended up throwing me into the deep end a lot quicker than I expected.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m really enjoying Linux. It&amp;#x27;s one of those things that makes me somewhat passionate about computing for the first time in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ge96:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I couldn&amp;#x27;t afford new computers in the past, would get some POS but putting Linux on it and a tiling manager gave me more bang for my buck&lt;p&gt;Started with Linux Mint then Debian&amp;#x2F;Ubuntu, tried some others too but ultimately just stuck with Ubuntu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tonymet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Any technical minds care to explain how the &amp;quot;agentic Windows&amp;quot; actually functions?&lt;p&gt;Based on the marketing it seems to run a sandboxed copilot instance that can impersonate the user to take actions, with their permission?&lt;p&gt;Something like &amp;quot;hey copilot install Putty&amp;quot;? and it does it?&lt;p&gt;I can relate to the reluctance to adopt AI features into the OS -- but I would also like to understand how they work and any utility they might provide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seemaze:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt;So if anything goes wrong in my install, it’ll be a lot of forum-hopping and Discord searching to figure it all out&lt;p&gt;This is not &lt;i&gt;inaccurate&lt;/i&gt;, however every time I&amp;#x27;ve had to interface with either Microsoft or Adobe issues, both the professional and community support have been abysmal. Both community forums seem to incentivize engagement to the point where every response is 3+ hyperlinks deep to someone else&amp;#x27;s vaguely related post.&lt;p&gt;Maybe the linux forums self select for independent problem solvers..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;officeplant:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the 2000&amp;#x27;s I used to fear that not having windows at home would lead me to a lack of troubleshooting prowess when it comes to problems with windows at work.&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#x27;m just glad I only have to suffer windows at work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pinewurst:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;DNFkL" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;DNFkL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theverge.com/tech/823337/switching-linux-gaming-desktop-cachyos</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985506</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racing karts on a Rust GPU kernel driver</title>
      <link>https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/news-and-events/racing-karts-on-a-rust-gpu-kernel-driver.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading that memory location and ensuring that its contents match the constant we were expecting shows that the test was executed successfully. Getting kmscube to run would also prove that we were really enforcing the job dependencies that were set by the UMD or we would get visual glitches. Not only would that put the GPU through a demanding workload, but it would also allow us to gauge the KMD's performance more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984623"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/news-and-events/racing-karts-on-a-rust-gpu-kernel-driver.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HeyMeco:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Great accomplishment from the developers. Being announced in July and already running gnome and games. 2026 is going to become very interesting&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.collabora.com/news-and-blog/news-and-events/racing-karts-on-a-rust-gpu-kernel-driver.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984623</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The patent office is about to make bad patents untouchable</title>
      <link>https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/patent-office-about-make-bad-patents-untouchable</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) has proposed new rules that would effectively end the public’s ability to challenge improperly granted patents at their source—the Patent Office itself. IPR hasn’t ended patent trolling. It dismantles abusive patent monopolies that never should have existed, saving entire industries from predatory litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985890"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/patent-office-about-make-bad-patents-untouchable'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;senderista:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Um, the public comment form lists first and last name as required fields (with address and phone number optional), then at the bottom includes this warning:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Do not submit personally identifiable information through this form.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tptacek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Am I crazy or was there a strategy reason that inter partes review at USPTO was disfavored over trial? Like the legal standards are easier for the patentholder at USPTO or something like that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pdonis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I submitted a comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DiabloD3:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I submitted a comment on Regulation.gov, and if any of you actually give a shit about tech, I suggest you do it too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhyUVoteGarbage:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The deadline for comments was November 17.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ortusdux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Who wants this?  Is it just patent troll regulatory capture?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hiccuphippo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And this just after the USPTO gained some good karma for re-examining a bad patent from Nintendo in the Palworld vs Pokemon feud:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.sportskeeda.com&amp;#x2F;mmo&amp;#x2F;news-nintendo-vs-palworld-pokemon-s-patent-viability-reviewed-uspto-director-s-order" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.sportskeeda.com&amp;#x2F;mmo&amp;#x2F;news-nintendo-vs-palworld-po...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rdsubhas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Thank you EFF.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HPsquared:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ah, more IP sclerosis. Great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ttcbj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am surprised this hasn&amp;#x27;t gotten more attention.   I feel like HN used to love nothing more than complaining about patent trolls.   Anyway, this article suggestions an action through regulation.gov which, based on the content of the page, seemed worth doing to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/11/patent-office-about-make-bad-patents-untouchable</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985890</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
