<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 03:50:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Nevada Governor's office covered up Boring Co safety violations</title>
      <link>https://fortune.com/2025/11/12/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnels-injuries-osha-citations-fines-rescinded-nevada-governor-office-documents-altered/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding the meeting, Williams said that the Governor’s office “frequently receives complaints and inquiries” from employers and that “it is standard practice” for the Governor’s office to reach out to leadership to assist with complaints and inquiries. (To read Nevada’s OSHA entire response to this story, click here. “It’s absolutely not appropriate,” said Jess Lankford, who oversaw Nevada OSHA until 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939798"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://fortune.com/2025/11/12/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnels-injuries-osha-citations-fines-rescinded-nevada-governor-office-documents-altered/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;csb6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; When Boring Co.’s Davis called the Governor’s office the day the company received the citations, he spoke to Chris Reilly, the governor’s point person for state infrastructure, who was hired in 2024 after working at Tesla for more than seven years.&lt;p&gt;The revolving door continues to spin. Wouldn’t have guessed that a former Tesla executive now leading state infrastructure policy would give special treatment to another Musk-owned company.&lt;p&gt;Unsurprising but still despicable that the Boring Company disregards worker and emergency responder safety to this level, and that even a slap on the wrist fine was enough for them to go crying to the governor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anigbrowl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Seems like something impeachable, this doesn&amp;#x27;t strike me &amp;#x27;faithful execution of the laws&amp;#x27;. Impeachment requires a 2&amp;#x2F;3 majority in the state senate, which would require only one vote from the Governor&amp;#x27;s party. The corruption will continue until people do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;madhacker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nevada is making a mockery of its own laws by giving Boring Co special exceptions treatment for tunnels that likely get abandoned due to its impracticality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mschuster91:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Proves again that fines aren&amp;#x27;t the answer, jail time is. Fines only matter for the poor, the rich just see fines as a cost of business, and the truly rich and powerful just call their friends and problems just magically go away.&lt;p&gt;Screw this. OSHA and other safety violations should, by default, pierce the corporate veil. Particularly ones where those that help others in need get injured.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alwa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;JUevh" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;JUevh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Long may it live)&lt;p&gt;As to the grout accelerant in question:&lt;p&gt;TDS [PDF]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;assets.ctfassets.net&amp;#x2F;ctspkgm1yw3s&amp;#x2F;DMSY-1685695220-3913&amp;#x2F;f0dbe116ae8932c06c72bb48735b7c35&amp;#x2F;masterroc-aga-41s-tds.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;assets.ctfassets.net&amp;#x2F;ctspkgm1yw3s&amp;#x2F;DMSY-1685695220-39...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;MSDS [PDF]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;assets.ctfassets.net&amp;#x2F;ctspkgm1yw3s&amp;#x2F;3Tp3imoxG5XfZlrlzURb1f&amp;#x2F;f0c8bc4d92df08bd73c2774f6a31b698&amp;#x2F;MasterRoc-AGA-41S-sds_en_us.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;assets.ctfassets.net&amp;#x2F;ctspkgm1yw3s&amp;#x2F;3Tp3imoxG5XfZlrlzU...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am not skilled in the arts of aggregate curing and occupational exposure, but I wonder if it’s the “silicic acid” or a non-table-variety of “sodium salt” (from the MSDS) that’s sloughing the firefighters’ skin off here… or something that happens when the sodium oxide (from the TDS) hits water? Chemistry class was a lifetime ago but does that turn it back into lye? Is the oxide technically a “sodium salt”?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://fortune.com/2025/11/12/elon-musk-boring-company-tunnels-injuries-osha-citations-fines-rescinded-nevada-governor-office-documents-altered/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 19:10:31</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939798</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving Project Euler #45</title>
      <link>https://loriculus.org/blog/euler-45/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://loriculus.org/blog/euler-45/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-16 00:04:29</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941613</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EyesOff: How I built a screen contact detection model</title>
      <link>https://ym2132.github.io/building_EyesOff_part2_model_training</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am building this model for EyesOff. It’s an application which detects people looking at your screen. This was a great starting point, from this I took and labelled 3400 images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935970"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ym2132.github.io/building_EyesOff_part2_model_training'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ym2132.github.io/building_EyesOff_part2_model_training</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 08:42:33</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935970</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Report: Tim Cook could step down as Apple CEO 'as soon as next year'</title>
      <link>https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/14/tim-cook-step-down-as-apple-ceo-as-soon-as-next-year-report/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among his biggest achievements, I would highlight Apple Silicon. You’re reading 9to5Mac — experts who break news about Apple and its surrounding ecosystem, day after day. Check out our exclusive stories, reviews, how-tos, and subscribe to our YouTube channel Check out 9to5Mac on YouTube for more Apple news: Comments Expand Close comments Expand Close comments Guides AAPL Company Breaking news from Cupertino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940681"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/14/tim-cook-step-down-as-apple-ceo-as-soon-as-next-year-report/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 14 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blaufast:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Almost every top comment is negative. This negativity about apple has existed since the 90s.&lt;p&gt;Apple has been the most profitable example of betting against the herd for the last 20 years. And possibly the easiest if you’re willing to look at the world plainly. I’m glad to see the herd hasn’t changed and I have plenty of gains left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tastyface:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tim Cook will be remembered as much for competently maintaining Apple’s course after Jobs’ passing as for flagrantly dismissing democratic regulation while cozying up to (and dining with; and giving golden statues to) authoritarian regimes.&lt;p&gt;Thanks and good riddance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paxys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Appointing John Ternus is going to be a pretty clear indicator to investors that Apple plans on continuing its iterative hardware, supply chain and operations focus and isn&amp;#x27;t looking to shake things up from a product or vision standpoint. Which may be the best move for the company (this strategy has definitely worked wonders for the last decade and a half), but I can&amp;#x27;t help feel that among all the large tech companies Apple is the one most at risk of a major disruption. It might not come tomorrow or even in the next decade, but whenever the next shift in personal computing happens (maybe AI, maybe AR&amp;#x2F;VR, maybe something else entirely) they are going to be caught unprepared and unable to adapt in time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jmcgough:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tim Cook at Apple was like Steve Ballmer at Microsoft. They scaled the company and made stock owners happy, but weren&amp;#x27;t true visionaries. I suppose there&amp;#x27;s a need for both types of leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ProAm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Long over due, he&amp;#x27;s done great but Apple needs fresh eyes.  Apple&amp;#x27;s Ballmer era is over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gyomu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I worked with John in the 2010s, brilliant guy, very human too. Couldn’t think of a single better person at the company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grumblingdev:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes!!! Such great news.&lt;p&gt;Apple has really gone to shit. I am confronted by Apple performance and bug pain every hour of my life. I always think: how can someone think this is acceptable? Steve Jobs wouldn’t.&lt;p&gt;Everything is such trash I could go on for hours.&lt;p&gt;I realized a long time ago that if the person at the top doesn’t care then no one will. It seems hard to believe but it makes sense when you consider individual incentives, politics, and the complexity of software. Everyone wants a safe promotion and doesn’t want to take the risk to push things forwards.&lt;p&gt;Apple Silicon seems great but the Intel MacBook was the worst piece of shit ever so they kind of had to. I have a 2019 that was the top of the line but can’t do anything without overheating. It’s barely usable for any second laptop tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cryptoboy2283:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;He&amp;#x27;s cooked&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ryandrake:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cook&amp;#x27;s been great for massively scaling Apple (and its stock price) up, but the art, vision, and soul of the company is gone. It&amp;#x27;s just a stock price maximizing lawnmower now, just like every other corporate stock price maximizing lawnmower. If that&amp;#x27;s what shareholders want, fine, I guess. But I&amp;#x27;d be bored just manufacturing the same boring rectangles every year. I think Steve would have been, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hackerbeat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Only Craig Federighi can turn the ship around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vlark:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bring back Woz.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PedroBatista:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The type of guy Cook is, was the “best” and safe choice for a company like Apple on the trajectory it was. Now everyone is a multimillionaire on the bank but the culture inside is quite hollowed out. Good luck for the next guy, he’ll need all of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comrade1234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Word is the next CEO is going to be picked ala Charlie and the chocolate factory. I hope that when you bought your Miyake iPhone sock you kept the bone-white ticket naming you the next CEO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bnchrch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you check my comments Im a routine critic of Apple. Specifically its mis-management of Siri.&lt;p&gt;But, in my mind, Tim Cook is also responsible for the only exceptional qualities of Apple. Namely its production of the M series chips and the Vision Pro (yes really).&lt;p&gt;They better have someone outstanding in mind as a replacement.&lt;p&gt;Otherwise I could easily see the successor mildly improve Siri&amp;#x2F;AI functions, while continuing Apples new disastrous design language and drop the ball on the supply chain and vertical integration that makes their hardware products second to none.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://9to5mac.com/2025/11/14/tim-cook-step-down-as-apple-ceo-as-soon-as-next-year-report/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 21:18:55</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940681</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When UPS charged me a $684 tariff on $355 of vintage computer parts</title>
      <link>http://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/when-ups-charged-me-684-tariff-on-355.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are all new old stock items in their Apple Service packaging because obviously Apple hasn't made nor sold any of these parts in decades. This would have been well-under the prior de minimis exemption even with the shipping rolled in. 30, which is what the seller tagged all four items with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941563"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/when-ups-charged-me-684-tariff-on-355.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eqvinox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In Germany, you can pre-register with DHL Express¹ with a bank account and optionally an EORI (Economic operators registration and identification) number, and then they immediately ding your bank account &lt;i&gt;instead of providing their &amp;quot;disbursement service&amp;quot; where they &amp;#x27;benevolently&amp;#x27; loan the customs fee to you for a &amp;#x27;minor&amp;#x27; fee&lt;/i&gt;.  I&amp;#x27;ve not found similar options elsewhere, though I would assume they exist but might be corporate-only.&lt;p&gt;¹ annoyingly enough this doesn&amp;#x27;t even work with DHL, which is a separate thing from DHL Express in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;celeritascelery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had this happen to me on an order from Sweden. The order was about $450 + $50 shipping. I used an online tariff calculator and it said it should be 15%. So I was expecting ~$70. A few days before it is supposed to arrive UPS sends me a $242 bill for “tariffs, customs, and brokerage fees”. That basically made it 50% more expensive, but it was either pay it or loose the item. A month later they sent me an invoice that claimed the item cost $850. No idea how that happened. I am too scared to order anything from the EU anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;delichon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If SCOTUS finds the tariffs unconstitutional in Learning Resources v. Trump, they should order refunds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IncandescentGas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I just got an invoice from ups to pay a $16 brokerage fee to jpmorgan for collecting a $0.60 tariff on a sticker included in a box with a custom keyboard shipped from Taiwan. Seems like wall street is making out better than the US on this arrangement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;al_borland:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had this happen with FedEx. They released the package and delivered it without me paying. I submitted a dispute, which they say could take up to 6 months to process. I hate having this hang over my head, as I don’t want anything going to collections, but figured if I paid it I would have a harder time getting my money back.&lt;p&gt;Mine was for a watch I got serviced. My own watch that I shipped out being returned to me… not a new import. If I end up having to pay what FedEx is saying I owe, it would have been cheaper for me to buy a new watch than to get it serviced, which is very upsetting. The whole process has been a horrible experience from the very start and I regret the entire thing. I should have just risked getting it serviced locally… or not done it at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mrtksn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Ah this is just another step towards Turkification[0] of USA. This situation is just how it is in Erdogan&amp;#x27;s Turkey but you still have way to go if you are able to get your package out of the customs in less than a few weeks and no hustle.&lt;p&gt;When the trade deals and tariff conditions get sufficiently complex(it gets more complex every day as the president accommodates specific companies and personal favors), the bureaucracy also increases so at some point it becomes too much of a nuisance to bother with individual imports.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theglobalist.com&amp;#x2F;the-turkification-of-america-trump-erdogan&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.theglobalist.com&amp;#x2F;the-turkification-of-america-tr...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSR_FDED:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tariffs are great. They protect the struggling domestic IT industry and gives it time to ramp up its production of vintage computer parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dcrazy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I guess we can’t know precisely how this happened without seeing UPS’s original Form 7501.&lt;p&gt;The amended one sounds strange. Why did they claim that the duty for the actual HTS code is $0, and attribute the entirety of the tariff to the special EU-origin code?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gishh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tariffs aren’t a secret. I don’t like them either.&lt;p&gt;This whole blog post could have been the last paragraph. The rest is useless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/when-ups-charged-me-684-tariff-on-355.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 23:55:19</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941563</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blocking LLM crawlers without JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://www.owl.is/blogg/blocking-crawlers-without-javascript/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.owl.is/blogg/blocking-crawlers-without-javascript/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 23:30:04</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941441</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The inconceivable types of Rust: How to make self-borrows safe (2024)</title>
      <link>https://blog.polybdenum.com/2024/06/07/the-inconceivable-types-of-rust-how-to-make-self-borrows-safe.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brief history of Rust Rust 1. However, it didn’t take long before people realized that non-movable types are actually very useful. In particular, async functions nearly always produce non-movable future types, so you can’t have async Rust without support in some fashion for non-movable types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941443"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://blog.polybdenum.com/2024/06/07/the-inconceivable-types-of-rust-how-to-make-self-borrows-safe.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.polybdenum.com/2024/06/07/the-inconceivable-types-of-rust-how-to-make-self-borrows-safe.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 23:31:39</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941443</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AsciiMath</title>
      <link>https://asciimath.org/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get started by loading the default AsciiMath configuration: &lt;script src="https://cdnjs. Syntax Most AsciiMath symbols attempt to mimic in text what they look like rendered, like oo for `oo`. in` sub subset `sub` sup supset `sup` sube subseteq `sube` supe supseteq `supe` -= equiv `-=` ~= cong `~=` ~~ approx `~~` prop propto `prop` Logical symbols Type TeX alt See and `and` or `or` not neg `not` =&gt; implies `=&gt;` if `if` &lt;=&gt; iff `iff` AA forall `AA` EE exists `EE` _|_ bot `_|_` TT top `TT` |-- vdash `|--` |== models `|==` Grouping brackets Type TeX alt See ( `(` ) `)` [ `[` ] `]` { `{` } `}` (: langle `(:` :) rangle `:)` &lt;&lt; `&lt;&lt;` &gt;&gt; `&gt;&gt;` {: x ) `{: x )` ( x :} `( x :}` abs(x) `abs(x)` floor(x) `floor(x)` ceil(x) `ceil(x)` norm(vecx) `norm(vecx)` Arrows Type TeX alt See uarr uparrow `uarr` darr downarrow `darr` rarr rightarrow `rarr` -&gt; to `-&gt;` &gt;-&gt; rightarrowtail `&gt;-&gt;` -&gt;&gt; twoheadrightarrow `-&gt;&gt;` &gt;-&gt;&gt; twoheadrightarrowtail `&gt;-&gt;&gt;` |-&gt; mapsto `|-&gt;` larr leftarrow `larr` harr leftrightarrow `harr` rArr Rightarrow `rArr` lArr Leftarrow `lArr` hArr Leftrightarrow `hArr` Accents Type TeX alt See hat x `hat x` bar x overline x `bar x` ul x underline x `ul x` vec x `vec x` tilde x `tilde x` dot x `dot x` ddot x `ddot x` overset(x)(=) overset(x)(=) `overset(x)(=)` underset(x)(=) `underset(x)(=)` ubrace(1+2) underbrace(1+2) `ubrace(1+2)` obrace(1+2) overbrace(1+2) `obrace(1+2)` overarc(AB) overparen(AB) `overarc(AB)` color(red)(x) `color(red)(x)` cancel(x) `cancel(x)` Greek Letters Type See Type See alpha `alpha` beta `beta` gamma `gamma` Gamma `Gamma` delta `delta` Delta `Delta` epsilon `epsilon` varepsilon `varepsilon` zeta `zeta` eta `eta` theta `theta` Theta `Theta` vartheta `vartheta` iota `iota` kappa `kappa` lambda `lambda` Lambda `Lambda` mu `mu` nu `nu` xi `xi` Xi `Xi` pi `pi` Pi `Pi` rho `rho` sigma `sigma` Sigma `Sigma` tau `tau` upsilon `upsilon` phi `phi` Phi `Phi` varphi `varphi` chi `chi` psi `psi` Psi `Psi` omega `omega` Omega `Omega` Font commands Type TeX alt See bb "AaBbCc" mathbf "AaBbCc" `bb "AaBbCc"` bbb "AaBbCc" mathbb "AaBbCc" `bbb "AaBbCc"` cc "AaBbCc" mathcal "AaBbCc" `cc "AaBbCc"` tt "AaBbCc" mathtt "AaBbCc" `tt "AaBbCc"` fr "AaBbCc" mathfrak "AaBbCc" `fr "AaBbCc"` sf "AaBbCc" mathsf "AaBbCc" `sf "AaBbCc"` Standard Functions sin, cos, tan, sec, csc, cot, arcsin, arccos, arctan, sinh, cosh, tanh, sech, csch, coth, exp,.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940706"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://asciimath.org/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agnishom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One could just use the math fragment of typst, no?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typerino.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typerino.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bottlepalm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s too bad MathML never supported ASCII math. The web might be a different place if it did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MichaelNolan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What exactly is the distinction between this and mathjax? At first glance it looks like this is a wrapper on top of mathjax, or is it something different?&lt;p&gt;I guess it’s just more “natural” and less latex like.&lt;p&gt;$$\sum_{i=0}^n i^2 = \frac{(n)}{2}$$&lt;p&gt;Vs&lt;p&gt;sum_(i=o)^n i^2=((n)&amp;#x2F;2)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;adamnemecek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you like this, check out typst &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typst.app" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;typst.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JoelMcCracken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is cool. I could see myself using this for notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://asciimath.org/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 21:22:57</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940706</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things that aren't doing the thing</title>
      <link>https://strangestloop.io/essays/things-that-arent-doing-the-thing</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Things That Aren't Doing the Thing Preparing to do the thing isn't doing the thing. Reading this essay isn't doing the thing. The only thing that is doing the thing is doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939431"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://strangestloop.io/essays/things-that-arent-doing-the-thing'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 27 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dwaltrip:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It doesn&amp;#x27;t matter how fast you are moving if you are going in the wrong direction.&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, these are good points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1970-01-01:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m trying to do the thing, but the thing is horribly documented and doesn&amp;#x27;t work. And nobody seems to know why. So am I still doing the thing if the thing isn&amp;#x27;t doing its thing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;seizethecheese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Making a to-do list for the thing isn&amp;#x27;t doing the thing.&lt;p&gt;Don’t agree. Planning steps is part of doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RajT88:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I had this Ah-Ha moment a while back when I was presenting on how to shorten cloud outage times, by aggregating impact into a list of details, and hustling around to make connections to support engineers and their customers and the poor backend engineers running around trying to make sense of it all.  Putting a little bit of structure to it, so other people can realize they can make a difference in a large organization.&lt;p&gt;I had a colleague make a passive aggressive comment about it being really cool how I put together &amp;quot;obvious&amp;quot; stuff.  Well, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; obvious.  At the same time, I have never seen him do this &amp;quot;obvious thing&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Doing the thing is being a performer.  Making the thing happen somehow is called leadership.  It&amp;#x27;s all about doing the thing, and not just seeing and understanding the thing - that&amp;#x27;s the easy part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shadowgovt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;All true, but worth noting that sometimes making that to-do list is the first step to doing the thing because picking the first item off the list and taking 10 minutes to do it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; doing the thing. If you aren&amp;#x27;t doing the thing because it&amp;#x27;s a monolith in your brain that is going to consume the next 6 months of your life and you&amp;#x27;re paralyzed by its enormity, salami slicing 10 minute chunks off the front of it can be a good way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;meken:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I see lots of comments focusing on cases where there is necessary research still to do.&lt;p&gt;Which I think misses the point - which is there are times when you’ve already done enough research, but you’re afraid to act so you procrastinate. i.e. not doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tshaddox:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Doing the thing without preparing to do the thing is, depending on your exact definitions, either unwise or impossible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alentred:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s my take, in no particular order:&lt;p&gt;- Ignoring that all people are different does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;- Discovering what procrastination is (and still failing to name it or provide actual coping mechanisms) does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;- Failing to recognize elementary human behavior does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;- Utterly neglecting the act of double creation (first imagine, then create) does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;- Being energetic and with only a few tasks at hand and writing off everyone else as lazy does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;- Writing a post about human psychology does not make you an expert in human psychology&lt;p&gt;I would continue my list, but gotta go. To do... , you know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RossBencina:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;See also: &amp;quot;brain crack&amp;quot; (2006) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.org&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;zefrank-theshow-080" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.org&amp;#x2F;details&amp;#x2F;zefrank-theshow-080&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almondsetat:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am replying to this post without planning whst to actually say&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;croisillon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;i&amp;#x27;m pretty sure there is a &amp;quot;oh no!&amp;quot; comics (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;webcomicname.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;webcomicname.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) saying the same but i couldn&amp;#x27;t find it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andy99:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I see this as a kind of inspiration &amp;#x2F; perspiration thing, and I’m on Tesla’s side that you perspire less if you think more. I like to not do the thing for a really long time, and then do it quickly, having thought it through. I see some people that jump into things without thinking, and take what is imo the more difficult route, with worse results.&lt;p&gt;I know there are some things you need to start to really understand what’s going on, but as much as possible I’d rather mull over things a lot and gather information and clarify my thinking before doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pac0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Writing about what things aren&amp;#x27;t doing the thing is not doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;saulpw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In the Viable System Model[0], &amp;quot;doing the thing&amp;quot; is System 1.  Yes of course you need System 1 or the thing won&amp;#x27;t get done.&lt;p&gt;But in any viable system, you also have the &amp;quot;meta-systems&amp;quot;, Systems 2-5:&lt;p&gt;- System 2: coordination between multiple Systems 1 (which includes prioritization, communication, and exceptional conditions)&lt;p&gt;- System 3: resource allocation and process development&lt;p&gt;- System 4: strategy and risk management&lt;p&gt;- System 5: values and holistic organizational design&lt;p&gt;As a human, you are also striving to be a viable system.  You can&amp;#x27;t only just &amp;quot;do the thing&amp;quot;, you have to:&lt;p&gt;- prioritize which thing to do&lt;p&gt;- take notes and keep records to communicate between past and future versions of yourself&lt;p&gt;- make sure you have the requisite resources for doing the thing&lt;p&gt;- construct your environment and processes for long-term success (habits not motivation)&lt;p&gt;- consider what happens when the thing is done and how it fits into your larger strategy&lt;p&gt;- keep your head and heart connected to make sure you&amp;#x27;re doing the right thing&lt;p&gt;None of these things are doing the thing!  But they&amp;#x27;re also rather essential for getting the right things done well.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Viable_system_model" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Viable_system_model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nrhrjrjrjtntbt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Right but I see this taken too far. Getting side eyed for creating a Jira ticket not doing it now. Dude, I am creating a Jira ticket because I have 100 things to do and need to actual priorise this! If I do stuff in the order of serendipity I will definitely be inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;makeitdouble:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;And now we have a whole post about not doing the thing, which is also not doing the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;afandian:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One day, when I get enough spare time, I will make the thing. I even have some components ready.&lt;p&gt;Until then I daydream of how I will make it and how it will fit together.&lt;p&gt;If I never get round to it then that time will have been wasted. But if I do, all that daydreaming will have been useful mental prototyping.&lt;p&gt;But was it «doing the thing»?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onionisafruit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Having a meeting about doing the thing isn’t doing the thing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cadamsdotcom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wonder what thing the author was avoiding when they published this thing ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nagisa:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you have no idea how to do the thing, isn&amp;#x27;t reading about how others did the thing doing the thing?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gentooflux:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Writing a thing about things that aren&amp;#x27;t doing the thing isn&amp;#x27;t doing the thing unless the thing happens to be writing a thing about things that aren&amp;#x27;t doing the thing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mjd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;LinkedIn is over there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brettgriffin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This gives very strong War of Art (Pressfield) vibes.&lt;p&gt;As simple as it is, just remembering this is enough to make me go do the thing.&lt;p&gt;And on that note, back to the thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mcdonje:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;-Nike&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bix6:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Obligatory &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;mofRHlO1E_A?si=aEimHOsDYa3FkGYv" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;mofRHlO1E_A?si=aEimHOsDYa3FkGYv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thomascountz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m inspired by this and want to extend it, perhaps telescopically, by discussing what the &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; is.&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we see our task as being, &amp;quot;do C,&amp;quot; and we forget the &amp;quot;B&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; that come before.&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can&amp;#x27;t do &amp;quot;C&amp;quot; without discussing it (&amp;quot;B&amp;quot;) or researching how others did it (&amp;quot;A&amp;quot;). In these cases, we shouldn&amp;#x27;t simply think the &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; is &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;—the &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; must first be &amp;quot;A,&amp;quot; then &amp;quot;B,&amp;quot; and then, &amp;quot;C.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;If we forget this, we&amp;#x27;re bound to think &amp;quot;C&amp;quot; is the only &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; of value, that it should take an hour and not a week, or that people doing the &amp;quot;A&amp;#x27;s&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;B&amp;#x27;s&amp;quot; to enable the &amp;quot;Cs&amp;quot; must be doing no&lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; at all!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;johnfn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Marketing is absolutely doing the thing; ignore this to your peril. I don&amp;#x27;t think reality is quite as binary as this post suggests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://strangestloop.io/essays/things-that-arent-doing-the-thing</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:24:58</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939431</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>libwifi: an 802.11 frame parsing and generation library written in C</title>
      <link>https://libwifi.so/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;void parse_packet(unsigned char *args, const struct pcap_pkthdr *header, const unsigned char *packet) { unsigned long data_len = header-&gt;caplen; unsigned char *data = (unsigned char *) packet; struct libwifi_frame frame = {0}; int ret = libwifi_get_wifi_frame(&amp;frame, data, data_len, got_radiotap); if (ret. type == TYPE_MANAGEMENT &amp;&amp; frame. int main(int argc, char **argv) { struct libwifi_beacon beacon = {0}; static unsigned char bcast[] = "\xFF\xFF\xFF\xFF\xFF\xFF"; static unsigned char tx[] = "\x00\x20\x91\xAA\xBB\CC"; int ret = libwifi_create_beacon(&amp;beacon, bcast, tx, tx, "wifi-beacon", 11); if (ret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941025"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://libwifi.so/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RossBencina:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Nice.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; int ret = libwifi_get_wifi_frame(&amp;amp;frame, data, data_len, got_radiotap);&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; ...&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; int ret = libwifi_parse_beacon(&amp;amp;bss, &amp;amp;frame);&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#x27;t looked into the implementation, but if I understand correctly, the above code (extracted from the example on the home page) implies that the unparsed segment of `data` is either (1) copied into `frame` or (2) a pointer-span in `frame` references the unparsed segment of `data`. I wonder why either of these approaches have been taken. I imagine that the pointer-span could be computed (possibly even statically) inside `libwifi_parse_beacon` and `data` could also be passed:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; libwifi_parse_beacon(&amp;amp;bss, &amp;amp;frame, data);&lt;p&gt;This would shrink the size of `frame` and achieve zero-copy. Or perhaps I&amp;#x27;m missing something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;evilmonkey19:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Perhaps a stupid question, but the last release and commit is from 2023. Did something happen to the project?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://libwifi.so/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 22:16:33</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941025</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDEmacs: A Visual Studio Code clone for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://codeberg.org/IDEmacs/IDEmacs</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GZ Download BUNDLE Open with VS Code Open with VSCodium Open with Intellij IDEA Cite this repository BibTeX Cancel contrapunctus e1db4094f4 Mention font in dependencies 2025-11-16 06:43:19 +05:30 img Update screenshot 2024-06-27 00:53:52 +05:30 vscode Replace Bitstream Vera with DejaVu 2025-11-16 06:40:45 +05:30. VSCode configuration (WIP) This is the first and currently the only IDE configuration provided. General Keybinding VSCode description IDEmacs-VSCode c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941835"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://codeberg.org/IDEmacs/IDEmacs'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trenchpilgrim:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This would have been great when I was learning Lisp in school! I tried emacs but due to joint issues the keybinds were painful to use, so I gave up and did the course in vim+SBCL&amp;#x27;s REPL instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiffanyh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was always bummed OniVim v2 didn&amp;#x27;t take off.&lt;p&gt;It was a native IDE but fully supported VS Code plugin system.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20210627210456&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;v2.onivim.io&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;web.archive.org&amp;#x2F;web&amp;#x2F;20210627210456&amp;#x2F;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;v2.onivim...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://codeberg.org/IDEmacs/IDEmacs</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-16 00:56:31</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941835</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://github.com/kavishdevar/librepods</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LibrePods unlocks Apple's exclusive AirPods features on non-Apple devices. Device Compatibility Status Device Features ✅ AirPods Pro (2nd Gen) Fully supported and tested ✅ AirPods Pro (3rd Gen) Fully supported (except heartrate monitoring) ⚠️ Other AirPods models Basic features (battery status, ear detection) should work Most features should work with any AirPods. Android also shows a popup when the other device takes over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941596"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/kavishdevar/librepods'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;losthubble:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;How much effort would it take to get this working on Windows?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;aboardRat4:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Aren&amp;#x27;t airpods just bluetooth headphones?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DerekL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Title has a typo, should be “liberated”.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I noticed that the article&amp;#x27;s page title is also misspelled this way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;t1234s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This excellent.. there needs to be a macos version as well. Using Mavericks I was unable to adjust any settings on my airpods pro 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moonleay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A cool project, when you want to use AirPods outside of Apples ecosystem. Sadly, you have to use a rooted android device with a small patch due to a bug in the Android Bluetooth implementation.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;issuetracker.google.com&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;371713238" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;issuetracker.google.com&amp;#x2F;issues&amp;#x2F;371713238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/kavishdevar/librepods</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-16 00:01:25</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941596</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USA gives South Korea green light to build nuclear submarines</title>
      <link>https://www.navalnews.com/naval-news/2025/10/usa-gives-south-korea-green-light-to-build-nuclear-submarines/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Screenshot of an announcement made by President Trump stating that South Korean Nuclear submarines will be built in the United States. Subsequently, the construction of Nuclear submarines marks a departure from past efforts, as previous South Korean submarine construction has focused primarily on conventionally powered submarines. In tandem with this, South Korean Nuclear Submarine construction projects have remained in limbo for sometime as the U.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939459"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.navalnews.com/naval-news/2025/10/usa-gives-south-korea-green-light-to-build-nuclear-submarines/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;koakuma-chan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is it nuclear in the sense that it has nuclear bombs or it is just nuclear powered?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hearsathought:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Imagine if south korea needed china&amp;#x27;s permission to build nuclear submarines. We&amp;#x27;d called them china&amp;#x27;s vassals and attack china for being bullies who deprived nations of their sovereignty.&lt;p&gt;Imagine if the title was : &amp;quot;China Gives South Korea Green Light to Build Nuclear Submarines&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;What would the comments here be like. No doubt a lot of nonsense about &amp;quot;the ccp&amp;quot; this and &amp;quot;the ccp&amp;quot; that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phendrenad2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Maybe we can buy some of these South Korean nuclear submarines, park them off the coast of the US, and use them for energy. If we do it quick, we might be able to get nuclear power going before the environmentalists notice.&lt;p&gt;Edit: Your downvotes only make me more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wrsh07:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The US has an incredibly strange relationship with shipbuilding.&lt;p&gt;Zvi and the Cato institute both have lengthy pieces about why the Jones act is bad [1] [2], and whether or not you believe that has entrenched our shipbuilders, the US essentially manufactures no ships compared to South Korea and China.&lt;p&gt;This naval news post says there are $5 billion in modernization costs for the shipyard needed for this project so it seems like we&amp;#x27;re still years away from a started (much less completed) project.&lt;p&gt;[1] Nov 2024 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thezvi.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;repeal-the-jones-act-of-1920" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;thezvi.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;repeal-the-jones-act-of-1920&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] June 2018 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cato.org&amp;#x2F;publications&amp;#x2F;policy-analysis&amp;#x2F;jones-act-burden-america-can-no-longer-bear" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cato.org&amp;#x2F;publications&amp;#x2F;policy-analysis&amp;#x2F;jones-act-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;farseer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;South Korea is capable enough to build nuclear submarines even if the US had denied them the said facilities. This saves them money, not having to modify their shipyards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rayiner:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Brilliant move. Giving South Korea the U.S. approval required to provide for its own defense, while using that to incentivize investment into American shipbuilding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.navalnews.com/naval-news/2025/10/usa-gives-south-korea-green-light-to-build-nuclear-submarines/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:29:00</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939459</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMD continues to chip away at Intel's x86 market share</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/amd-continues-to-chip-away-at-intels-x86-market-share-company-now-sells-over-25-percent-of-all-x86-chips-and-powers-33-percent-of-all-desktop-systems</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intel still commands 74. (Image credit: Data by Mercury Research, Compiled by Tom's Hardware)AMD's client unit share rose to 25. 6% share of the desktop PC market, up from 32.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940413"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/amd-continues-to-chip-away-at-intels-x86-market-share-company-now-sells-over-25-percent-of-all-x86-chips-and-powers-33-percent-of-all-desktop-systems'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;snovymgodym:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;(On desktop systems)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/amd-continues-to-chip-away-at-intels-x86-market-share-company-now-sells-over-25-percent-of-all-x86-chips-and-powers-33-percent-of-all-desktop-systems</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 20:35:33</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940413</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS deprecates two dozen services (most of which you've never heard of)</title>
      <link>https://www.lastweekinaws.com/blog/aws-deprecates-two-dozen-services-most-of-which-youve-never-heard-of/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S3 Object Lambdas have always been a bit weird. That leaves Snowball Edge. Read More about Amazon Q: Now with Helpful AI-Powered Self-Destruct Capabilities Get the newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939678"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.lastweekinaws.com/blog/aws-deprecates-two-dozen-services-most-of-which-youve-never-heard-of/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dherls:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I like how the article uses &amp;quot;Googling&amp;quot; as a verb meaning to shut down a service&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rs186:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Anyone can predict what&amp;#x27;s going to happen with Amazon Q?&lt;p&gt;The only people that I know or have seen using Amazon Q are internal employees. Almost nothing on reddit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more_corn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Elastic beanstalk or GTFO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cperciva:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;AWS has done its quarterly housecleaning &amp;#x2F; “Googling” of its services&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: This is actually two quarters of Googling, because they were revising their process during Q3 and put deprecations on hold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gnabgib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Discussion (69 points, 1 month ago, 35 comments) &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45572613"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45572613&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IgorPartola:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AWS has so many services at this point and it feels like so many of them overlap too. Seems like for a while they basically just took any open source project that was somewhat popular and offered a managed version of it. Plus there is a marketplace where others can offer services. The landscape is so vast it feels overwhelming to even try to get a basic layout.&lt;p&gt;For personal projects I end up avoiding AWS and instead prefer things like the Backblaze S3-compatible object storage, Vultr for VMs, and so on just to avoid the power user features that will only get in the way.&lt;p&gt;With that, I am curious how people who do not have an enterprise-size team to manage their AWS infrastructure navigate their offerings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hinkley:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does the service list fit on a 4k monitor with these removed?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;learned:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;CodeCatalyst is pretty surprising on that list. Maybe it tried to do too much?&lt;p&gt;Also, the deprecation alert on the CodeCatalyst site is incorrect at the moment:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Important Notice: Amazon CodeCatalyst is longer open to new customers starting on November 7, 2025&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;codecatalyst.aws&amp;#x2F;explore" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;codecatalyst.aws&amp;#x2F;explore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;topher200:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article is from mid-October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NewJazz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Wasn&amp;#x27;t there a big post about this a few weeks ago?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CobrastanJorji:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Man, deprecating an IoT APIs isn&amp;#x27;t going to affect most folks, but the folks it does affect are gonna be in a fuckload of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jjtheblunt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;language rant: titles with assertions that &amp;quot;you&amp;quot; have or have not $whatever...they seem lazily worded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.lastweekinaws.com/blog/aws-deprecates-two-dozen-services-most-of-which-youve-never-heard-of/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:55:22</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939678</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FBI Director Waived Polygraph Security Screening for Three Senior Staff</title>
      <link>https://www.propublica.org/article/fbi-kash-patel-dan-bongino-waived-polygraph</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ProPublica could not determine whether Bongino sat for a polygraph exam or what its results were. When ProPublica sought comment from the FBI, the agency denied that Bongino or the other senior staff members failed polygraph tests. Dan Bongino, deputy director of the FBI, speaks with Patel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939266"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.propublica.org/article/fbi-kash-patel-dan-bongino-waived-polygraph'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KaiserPro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes polygraphs are bollocks, but, rules are rules.&lt;p&gt;The issue is, if exceptions are made, what&amp;#x27;s stopping other breaking the rules?&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t care if he&amp;#x27;s a dem, rep or maga, rules are rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;expedition32:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Have you ever had paid sex with an underage girl?&lt;p&gt;BLEEP BLEEP BLEEP&lt;p&gt;The cesspool that has been opened in the US the last few years is both mesmerising and appalling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;puppycodes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The only way polygraphs work is by convincing people its an actual lie detection machine. Cops leveredge this belief and tell you that you &amp;quot;failed miserably&amp;quot; so you ultimately confess because &amp;quot;your caught&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;They are about as accurate as flipping a coin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CGMthrowaway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good writeup of what happens in an FBI pre-employment polygraph: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.andrewwatters.com&amp;#x2F;hall-of-shame&amp;#x2F;FBI-SACU&amp;#x2F;FSL&amp;#x2F;poly.phtml" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.andrewwatters.com&amp;#x2F;hall-of-shame&amp;#x2F;FBI-SACU&amp;#x2F;FSL&amp;#x2F;pol...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ms-J:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Polygraphs must not be used as they are completely unreliable and subject to many issues.&lt;p&gt;The government does a lot of security theater and campaigns to make you believe that they are competent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yahoozoo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Bongino use to be Secret Service, tasked with protecting Bush then Obama, for what it’s worth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jghn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;d matter more if polygraphs weren&amp;#x27;t completely bogus pseudoscience in the first place&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bediger4000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;the FBI’s employment eligibility guidelines say all employees must obtain a “Top Secret” clearance in order to work at the agency following a background check.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The furor here is about Dan Bongino, and Nicole Rucker, Kash Patel&amp;#x27;s assitant&lt;p&gt;The article goes on to say that FBI employees at the level Bongino and Rucker are working at have &amp;quot;SCI&amp;quot; clearance on top of Top Secret. Back in the 1990s, it was exceptionally difficult to get TS clearance. SCI on top of that must have been even harder.&lt;p&gt;I guess this is no worse than Jared Kushner getting a waiver to work at the White House during Trump&amp;#x27;s first term, but holy cow, getting this kind of special treatment really does reinforce a big difference between classes, doesn&amp;#x27;t it? Any ordinary, non-rich person getting &amp;quot;alerts&amp;quot; on polygraphs would probably be immediately dropped from getting a Top Secret.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.propublica.org/article/fbi-kash-patel-dan-bongino-waived-polygraph</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:03:37</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939266</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caffeinated coffee consumption or abstinence to reduce atrial fibrillation</title>
      <link>https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2841253</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2841253</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 19:43:39</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940030</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The computer poetry of J. M. Coetzee's early programming career</title>
      <link>https://sites.utexas.edu/ransomcentermagazine/2017/06/28/the-computer-poetry-of-j-m-coetzees-early-programming-career/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coetzee’s early poetry is almost undecipherable. I believe that this experience, while short, was vital for the development of Coetzee’s writerly project. Coetzee’s computer code poetry, dated May 30, 1965.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939569"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://sites.utexas.edu/ransomcentermagazine/2017/06/28/the-computer-poetry-of-j-m-coetzees-early-programming-career/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 3 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gorgoiler:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For me, Brian Westley is the greatest code poet of all.  His poem was a winner in the 1990 round of the International Obfuscated C Code Competition under &amp;quot;Best layout - poetic exchange between lovers&amp;quot;:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;raw.githubusercontent.com&amp;#x2F;ioccc-src&amp;#x2F;winner&amp;#x2F;refs&amp;#x2F;heads&amp;#x2F;master&amp;#x2F;1990&amp;#x2F;westley&amp;#x2F;westley.c" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;raw.githubusercontent.com&amp;#x2F;ioccc-src&amp;#x2F;winner&amp;#x2F;refs&amp;#x2F;head...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Love is a not a toilet&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;From: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ioccc.org&amp;#x2F;1990&amp;#x2F;westley&amp;#x2F;index.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.ioccc.org&amp;#x2F;1990&amp;#x2F;westley&amp;#x2F;index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kragen:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The nature of the output displayed&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    EQUIVOCAL HERESIARCH TAMP THE PRESBYOPIA
    STYPTIC ILLUSION ABSORB THE EIDOLA
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
makes me think that it&amp;#x27;s a sort of mad-libs phrase generator.  The leading adjective &amp;quot;PENSILE&amp;quot; appears twice, as does &amp;quot;CATAMITE&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;PARACLETE&amp;quot; occurs three times, as does the noun &amp;quot;EIDOLA&amp;quot;, once as subject and twice as object.  Hopefully Dr. Roach will be able to present us a full reverse-engineering of the algorithm, but I&amp;#x27;m guessing you could probably infer it just from that page of output: f&amp;#x27;{random.choice(adjectives)} {random.choice(nouns)} {random.choice(verbs)} THE {random.choice(nouns)}&amp;#x27;, which produces lines such as STYPTIC PARACLETE TAMP THE PRESBYOPIA.&lt;p&gt;Before LLMs, I found this a very enjoyable activity; my similar program at &lt;a href="http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canonical.org&amp;#x2F;~kragen&amp;#x2F;sw&amp;#x2F;dev3&amp;#x2F;dramaticphrase.py" rel="nofollow"&gt;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canonical.org&amp;#x2F;~kragen&amp;#x2F;sw&amp;#x2F;dev3&amp;#x2F;dramaticphrase.py&lt;/a&gt; outputs lines such as:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The raw wind of the smooth horse.
    An evil labyrinth of the monstrous, dying waters.
    The mere gate of deserted gardens.
    The smiling stairway of countless sweet fangs.
    The shattered witch of the diseased, ruby monk.
    The asphalt house of the smooth unicorn.
    A haunted fire of the sorrowful theft.
    The stainless raven of countless living gates.
    My haunted cloud beneath her glorious father.
    The brazen father of their raw villages.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
The comments of the program contain a somewhat embarrassing sonnet I wrote with its help.&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a Spanish version at &lt;a href="http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canonical.org&amp;#x2F;~kragen&amp;#x2F;sw&amp;#x2F;dev3&amp;#x2F;frasedramatica.py" rel="nofollow"&gt;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;canonical.org&amp;#x2F;~kragen&amp;#x2F;sw&amp;#x2F;dev3&amp;#x2F;frasedramatica.py&lt;/a&gt;, which says things like:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Cien hijos halagüeños de la emoción infinita y monstruosa.
    Los labios caídos de zorros corruptos y dignos.
    Un exilio inmaculado dentro de las imprecaciones violáceas y ardientes.
    Los dos pies insepultos de mis labios profundos e infinitos.
    El oro bello de una libertad corrompida.
    El angustia monstruosa de zorros desmoronados.
    Aquel campo brillante de su princesa destrozada.
    Una joven emoción de un tronco enmascarado.
    El viento hermoso de su abandono griego.
    Una ley romántica del abandono destrozado.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Now, of course, this sort of thing is much less novel and therefore less entertaining.  GPT-5 will be happy to write as many sonnets for you as you want, as long as it doesn&amp;#x27;t somehow get the idea that they might infringe some kind of copyright or teach you how to do your own electrical work.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve often wondered if J. M. Coetzee was related to Wikipedia editor Derrick Coetzee with whom I used to collaborate on computer science articles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PaulRobinson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a superb piece of research, and odd that nobody has pulled this material before.&lt;p&gt;The Atlas 2 is obviously the successor to the Atlas, which Turing worked on before &amp;quot;The Baby&amp;quot; at Manchester University booted up, at which point he quit and moved to Manchester to work on that.&lt;p&gt;I seem to recall his early programs for The Baby - and his planned use of the Atlas - was to model &amp;quot;morphogens&amp;quot;, his theory of how animals got their strips, spots and other markings. I think it was at the Science Museum in London (worth a trip for computer historians anyway to see Babbage&amp;#x27;s Analytical Engine, built in xxxx, next to a jar containing Babbage&amp;#x27;s actual brain), where there was a collection of printouts showing spots like on a Friesian cow (the most common breed of dairy cows in England).&lt;p&gt;I find this diving back into early uses of computing for creative and scientific purposes fascinating - it&amp;#x27;s like people were just so excited about being able to do interesting things, they just dived in with the tool that they had.&lt;p&gt;The poetry of Coetzee&amp;#x27;s program in this article is interesting - it&amp;#x27;s better, arguably, than you&amp;#x27;d get from an LLM today. It&amp;#x27;s mildly mysterious, grating, intriguing but uncomfortable. A little like the things I remember of Coetzee&amp;#x27;s actual later writing (which I&amp;#x27;ve not read much of, TBH).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sites.utexas.edu/ransomcentermagazine/2017/06/28/the-computer-poetry-of-j-m-coetzees-early-programming-career/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:44:05</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939569</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archimedes – A Python toolkit for hardware engineering</title>
      <link>https://pinetreelabs.github.io/archimedes/blog/2025/introduction.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In short, Archimedes is a Python framework that lets you develop and analyze algorithms in NumPy and automatically generate optimized C code for embedded systems. The Linchpin: Python → C Code Generation¶ Archimedes started with the question, “What would you need to actually do practical control systems development in Python. h&gt; #define N_STATES 4 typedef struct { float H[N_STATES]; // Measurement matrix (1 x n) float R; // Measurement noise covariance (scalar) } kf_params_t; typedef struct { float x[N_STATES]; // State estimate float P[N_STATES][N_STATES]; // Estimate covariance } kf_state_t; typedef struct { float K[N_STATES]; // Kalman gain (n x 1) float M[N_STATES][N_STATES]; // I - K * H temporary float MP[N_STATES][N_STATES]; // M * P temporary float MPMT[N_STATES][N_STATES]; // M * P * M^T temporary float KRKT[N_STATES][N_STATES]; // K * R * K^T temporary } kf_work_t; /** * Kalman filter update step (scalar measurement case) * * Mathematical formulation: * y = z - H·x (innovation) * S = H·P·H^T + R (innovation covariance) * K = P·H^T·S^(-1) (Kalman gain) * x' = x + K·y (state update) * P' = (I-KH)·P·(I-KH)^T + K·R·K^T (Joseph form covariance) * * @param z: Latest measurement * @param kf_state: Pointer to Kalman filter state struct * @param kf_params: Pointer to Kalman filter parameters struct * @param kf_work: Pointer to Kalman filter work struct (for temporaries) * @return: 0 on success, -1 on error */ int kalman_update(float z, kf_state_t *kf_sta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939938"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://pinetreelabs.github.io/archimedes/blog/2025/introduction.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 1 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dcreater:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Its specifically meant for control systems no?&lt;p&gt;hardware engineering is a very broad field and the title is misleading&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pinetreelabs.github.io/archimedes/blog/2025/introduction.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 19:29:32</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939938</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transgenerational Epigenetic Inheritance: the story of learned avoidance</title>
      <link>https://elifesciences.org/articles/109427</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;elegans worms to avoid specific bacteria. However, when worms are exposed to PA14 before the avoidance assay, they avoid PA14 during the assay (second row). Importantly, after the parental generation, worms do not encounter PA14 before testing, but they retain the learned avoidance of the parental generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939550"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://elifesciences.org/articles/109427'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anamexis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Honest question: isn’t all inheritance transgenerational?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mmaunder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This relates to policy because it addresses the question of whether we carry epigenetic baggage from prior generations. For example, trauma that our parents, or grandparents experienced could lead to behavior modifications and poorer outcomes in us. If that is the case, it has profound public policy implications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shevy-java:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So Lamarck wasn&amp;#x27;t entirely incorrect either. Darwin would have been fascinated by these results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurornis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; While the Murphy group consistently observed this attraction in their assays, the Hunter group generally did not (Kaletsky et al., 2025). The Vidal-Gadea group also observed that worms that had not been exposed to PA14 were initially attracted to it, suggesting that this is an important piece of the puzzle (Akinosho et al., 2025). Indeed, when tested directly, the Murphy group did not observe attraction using the temperature-shift method (Kaletsky et al., 2025). However, whether the omission of azide alone explains the discrepancy between the studies is not clear. In a handful of assays, the Hunter group used azide but failed to see the initial attraction to PA14, or to observe learned avoidance in the F2 generation.&lt;p&gt;Every time I look into epigenetic inheritance studies I run into a lot of finicky experiments like this, where the outcomes appear to be highly dependent on several variables that aren’t fully understood.&lt;p&gt;One group of researchers claims to have pinned down the results, but as someone outside of this world trying to interpret the studies it’s hard to know how well they’ve really controlled these finicky experiments to isolate the single effect (epigenetic inheritance) that they claim explains everything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;terminalshort:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If it&amp;#x27;s inheritable wouldn&amp;#x27;t that make it by definition genetic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://elifesciences.org/articles/109427</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 18:40:55</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939550</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mighty Simplex (2023)</title>
      <link>https://galileo-unbound.blog/2023/05/03/the-mighty-simplex/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simplex Geometry In this blog, I will restrict the geometry to the regular simplex. Each node is equivalent and is linked to each other. Each node is a charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938698"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://galileo-unbound.blog/2023/05/03/the-mighty-simplex/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ikjasdlk2234:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The simplex method in linear programming was one of the first times I ever had something relatively complex &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; for me.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s funny, I still think about that feeling weekly. My memory of it happening while working out a homework problem is actually sort of like in the first Harry Potter movie when Harry gets his wand: warm, bright lighting, widening eyes, and a feeling like my head was a helium balloon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ceh123:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the topic of simplices! I did my PhD in dynamical systems and the space of invariant measures [0] is (in the compact setting) always a simplex and the extreme points are the ergodic measures. It&amp;#x27;s because of this that you can kind of assume your system is ergodic do work there and frequently be able to generalize to the non-ergodic case (through ergodic decomposition).&lt;p&gt;But the real thing I wanted to mention here was the Poulsen Simplex [1]. This is the unique Choquet simplex [2] for which the extreme points are dense. This means that it&amp;#x27;s like an uncountably infinite dimensional triangle where no matter where you are inside the triangle, you&amp;#x27;re arbitrarily close to a corner. It&amp;#x27;s my favorite shape and absolutely wild and impossible to conceptualize (even though I worked with it daily for years!)&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Invariant_measure" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Invariant_measure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;eudml.org&amp;#x2F;doc&amp;#x2F;74350" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;eudml.org&amp;#x2F;doc&amp;#x2F;74350&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Choquet_theory" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;Choquet_theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://galileo-unbound.blog/2023/05/03/the-mighty-simplex/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 16:49:49</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938698</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tolerate annoying things</title>
      <link>https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-respond-to-annoying-things-with-greater-ease</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are not the kind of events that disrupt the course of your life. They usually come your way unexpectedly, cause you some stress, and interrupt your flow. That made all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937816"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-respond-to-annoying-things-with-greater-ease'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 10 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;martini333:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The triviality of this articles coping mechanisms annoyed me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPLX:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This article seems fine, but I would say that physical acts are really the core go-to for this. Things like running a marathon or Zen meditation.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s nothing that helps you endure smaller unpleasant things more directly than just a regular practice of enduring them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;steve-atx-7600:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’ve gotten a lot out of the writings of Albert Ellis whose work in the 50s and 60s became cognitive behavioral therapy.  He would have said that it is irrational to demand that everyday inconveniences not exist, and by changing your thinking to accept and expect that unavoidable inconveniences happen, you will be less likely to allow these things to cause emotional distress.&lt;p&gt;He credits the ancient stoics and other philosophers for influencing his methods.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.psychologytoday.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;therapy-types&amp;#x2F;rational-emotive-behavior-therapy" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.psychologytoday.com&amp;#x2F;us&amp;#x2F;therapy-types&amp;#x2F;rational-em...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov&amp;#x2F;articles&amp;#x2F;PMC5836900&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov&amp;#x2F;articles&amp;#x2F;PMC5836900&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aurornis:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have seen some people turn themselves around with ACT-style therapy like this article introduces. Some can build up response patterns that turn minor daily annoyances into bigger problems that disrupt their mood for hours or even the rest of the day.&lt;p&gt;These behaviors of blowing things out of proportion or letting them get under your skin can be both learned and unlearned, in addition to developing organically. Therapy techniques like this are an intentional way to practice unlearning bad habits and replacing with undeniably better habits that you want to practice.&lt;p&gt;Raising and teaching young children is a learning experience for how some of these habits can develop and how to teach better responses to life&amp;#x27;s frustrations. Kids can get frustrated easily and their emotions run strong. Learning how to teach kids to control their emotions and respond appropriately to life is one of the core parenting challenges. I feel like I learned a lot about myself in the process of trying to figure out how to teach it to my kids and set a good example for them.&lt;p&gt;On this topic, I&amp;#x27;ve also observed a few cases in teens and adults who seemingly learn bad habits about becoming overly annoyed by small things, primarily from social media influencers. There is an entire universe of social media influencers dedicated to grievance-based entertainment, where they produce content about things that make you angry or feel like the victim. I think it&amp;#x27;s supposed to be cathartic or helpful, but in the process of producing content they reach further and further for topics to turn into grievances.&lt;p&gt;The early trend of &amp;quot;emotional labor&amp;quot; being an invisible burden was the first time I saw this. The social media influencer version of emotional labor actually diverged from the literature definition and became an umbrella term meaning that your emotions were unpaid labor. If anyone did something that made you feel those emotions or you had to deal with someone else&amp;#x27;s emotions, you were supposed to feel burdened and victimized. There have been other trends like &amp;quot;mental load&amp;quot; that are variations of this idea that you have been made into the victim via other people or the world triggering your own emotional responses, which may have become exaggerated via these social influencers constantly bringing them front and center.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nis0s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don’t think anyone should tolerate what they find annoying, life is too short. If something or someone wants to keep you around, they should be less annoying to you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;retrac:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I am deaf but not completely deaf.  Some sounds I can hear and a lot of the sounds that are loud enough to come to my attention are &lt;i&gt;annoying&lt;/i&gt;.  Often not the same sounds that annoy other people, too.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m reminded of a conversation with my friend who is fully Deaf from birth and a signer.  Hearing people are a foreign culture for him.  It&amp;#x27;s tricky to navigate the hearing world sometimes, when you don&amp;#x27;t know what what noises things make and how they are perceived.  (Stacking metal or ceramic dishes is an almost silent experience for me, for example.)&lt;p&gt;He noted that the sounds hearing people complain about seem related to &lt;i&gt;control&lt;/i&gt;.  Thunder?  Not a problem.  Natural and nothing you can do about it.  The beep of a truck backing up?  That&amp;#x27;s due to a person.  It could be controlled.   Rain?  Not a problem.  Sprinkler system?  That&amp;#x27;s ultimately due to a person.  It could be controlled.  Microwave beep?  Could have been controlled; you&amp;#x27;re supposed to hit the stop button at 0:01.  Dog barking?  Annoying because again, supposed to be controlled.  Wild birds cawing at the crack of dawn?  Filtered out and ignored.  (Mostly, some people do complain about those.)&lt;p&gt;Realizing you don&amp;#x27;t actually have control and that the other person might not actually have control is surprisingly relaxing, I&amp;#x27;ve found.  I suppose that&amp;#x27;s closely related to the &amp;quot;radical acceptance&amp;quot; of the article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hexbin010:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have insane admiration for and quite a serious amount of jealousy of people who are able to sail through life with with every setback sailing right past them, leaving no trace or mark.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve noticed it more in people who had a comfortable upringing and no money worries. Oh dear, dinner is burnt? No worries just order takeout! Lost your passport a few days before a holiday - no sweat, just pay the fast track processing fee. Car broken down? Just jump in a taxi. Coffee ruined your top? Just buy another one. Etc. Money often means far fewer worries in life, and kids must definitely notice and feel that.&lt;p&gt;As you can probably guess, I grew up relatively poor. Every day&amp;#x2F;week something would be causing my parents stress, often related to money. No amount of grounding themselves or belly breathing would have alleviated the stress.&lt;p&gt;I know the article is about smaller things, many of which of money can&amp;#x27;t fix, but I do wonder if growing up in a low-stress environment (largely because of no money issues) instills something that enables you to not sweat the minor things in life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ndr42:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;From the article: Micro-stressors such as running late [...] represent the unavoidable pain that comes with being human.&lt;p&gt;Is running late really unavoidable? I think there are proven strategies to avoid it. (My wife and one of my sons on the other hand would agree that it is in fact unavoidable)&lt;p&gt;Edit: added missing word&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;begueradj:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Can&amp;#x27;t read the article from phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gregschlom:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been reading No Mud, No Lotus recently (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.parallax.org&amp;#x2F;product&amp;#x2F;no-mud-no-lotus&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.parallax.org&amp;#x2F;product&amp;#x2F;no-mud-no-lotus&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) by Zen Master Thich Nhat Hanh and this is very much the same advice.&lt;p&gt;This book has brought me immense joy, I&amp;#x27;d recommend it to anyone.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fascinating how much Buddhism has gotten &amp;quot;right&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://psyche.co/guides/how-to-respond-to-annoying-things-with-greater-ease</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 14:53:09</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937816</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I implemented an ISO 42001-certified AI Governance program in 6 months</title>
      <link>https://beabytes.com/iso42001-certified-ai-governance/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://beabytes.com/iso42001-certified-ai-governance/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 17:04:23</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938815</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wealth</title>
      <link>https://saul.pw/mag/wealth/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally, someone’s wealth level can be inferred from their net worth. If not living out of their car, they are couch-surfing; if they have a permanent address, they are living with someone else and paying a low or flexible amount of rent. People at ↑2 wealth h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938427"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://saul.pw/mag/wealth/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 11 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jeffbee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Hard drugs are plentiful at this level&amp;quot; appears to be something the author invented out of thin air. Cigarettes, alcohol, marijuana, and &amp;quot;hard drugs&amp;quot; all cost money and therefore the rates of abuse of these things are positively correlated with income, which should not surprise you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;trollbridge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting. I guess I would be a 5, but live like a 2, as it’s less stressful that way.&lt;p&gt;I have friends who are 6’s and acquaintances who are 7’s and their manner of thinking and goals in life baffle me. I simply cannot relate to them at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;renewiltord:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;One thing that previous societies definitely got right is to talk about envy negatively. Everything these days is about envy. It’s not enough for one’s life to improve. It has to improve relative to others or people get upset.&lt;p&gt;“Keeping up with the Joneses” is now couched in socialist rhetoric about inequality. We can tell this is the case because when wage compression occurs, people get upset at “inflation” and “it’s so expensive now”.&lt;p&gt;The bottom percentiles saw unprecedented growth in recent years relative to the middle. Rather than celebrate, people got upset because things got expensive. When poor labor gets paid more, they get more expensive. That’s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dougb5:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The &amp;quot;↑11&amp;quot; bucket -- which Saul labeled as &amp;quot;Megacorps ($300b-$3t)&amp;quot; -- now contains at least one individual human.   How far we&amp;#x27;ve come (or fallen?) in just a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pton_xd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Too granular, there are 4 levels of wealth: the destitute, those who have to work, those who have enough assets to not work, and finally the elite who influence the rules of society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nis0s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is also a good article with demarcations you can use to evaluate either family or personal finances and wealth,&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.kiplinger.com&amp;#x2F;personal-finance&amp;#x2F;605075&amp;#x2F;are-you-rich" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.kiplinger.com&amp;#x2F;personal-finance&amp;#x2F;605075&amp;#x2F;are-you-ri...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gooblebrai:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I might be dense today but I thought the upper arrow was like a &amp;quot;Level of wealth&amp;quot; thing. However here:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; About 16 million people (↑7) are designated as HNWI.&lt;p&gt;What does the ↑7 means? Later he starts using it in a context that I don&amp;#x27;t understand (e.g. &amp;gt; About 250,000 people (↑5.5))&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pavlov:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt; ‘“Net worth” is an unfortunate term, because a human’s “worth” is obviously more than just their wealth.’&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a fairly egalitarian 1980s Nordic society and English is my third language.&lt;p&gt;I remember the first time I heard “worth” used in this American idiom:&lt;p&gt;“Person X is worth $Y”&lt;p&gt;It was shocking; almost like the most forbidden thing you could say, a glimpse of eugenics. If a person’s worth is measured in dollars, what does that say about the worth of underpaid women and minorities and children with development challenges…?&lt;p&gt;In the decades since, Silicon Valley has moved so far right that this barely registers anymore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brettgriffin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; Generally, someone’s wealth level can be inferred from their net worth.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; But also, “assets minus liabilities” offers some large shadows to hide behind.&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; So a better quantity to measure would be: the amount of money someone could bring to bear on a problem if they had to. If someone they loved fell deathly ill, but the treatment would cost some large amount of money, how much could they pull together in a month or two? How much could they borrow, and from whom, and on what terms?&lt;p&gt;The following breakdowns are largely just people&amp;#x27;s net worth (assets minus liabilities) with the credit they can tap because of their assets.&lt;p&gt;Not sure I entirely understand the point. Yeah, people with assets are generally more credit-worthy and can tap lines of credit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hshdhdhj4444:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is a nice start to develop a language to discuss wealth.&lt;p&gt;99 vs 1%, normal vs millionaires vs billionaires,  lower vs upper vs middle class, investor vs working class are some of the language I’ve seen used.&lt;p&gt;All of them are extremely inadequate and allow the |^7-11 folks to get away with a lot that they shouldn’t by scaring the folks at |^4-6 that it would apply to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sprotch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I’d argue focusing on wealth inequality is precisely the wrong approach. A better approach would be to look at the quality of life of the poorest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://saul.pw/mag/wealth/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 16:16:42</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938427</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trellis AI (YC W24) Is Hiring: Streamline access to life-saving therapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/trellis-ai/jobs/f4GWvH0-forward-deployed-engineer-full-time</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do this by automating document intake, prior authorizations, and appeals at scale to streamline operations and accelerate care. Trellis helps healthcare providers treat more patients, faster—while eliminating pre-service paperwork. We automate document intake, prior authorizations, and appeals at scale to streamline operations and accelerate care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938785"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/trellis-ai/jobs/f4GWvH0-forward-deployed-engineer-full-time'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/trellis-ai/jobs/f4GWvH0-forward-deployed-engineer-full-time</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 17:00:38</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938785</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weighting an average to minimize variance</title>
      <link>https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/12/minimum-variance/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose A is more volatile than B. We will formalize this problem and determine the optimal allocation, then generalize the problem to more assets. Multiple variables Now suppose we have n independent random variables Xi for i running from 1 to n, and at least one of the variables is not constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938027"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/12/minimum-variance/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thomasahle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What a weird way to write the harmonic average.&lt;p&gt;----&lt;p&gt;Write v_i = Var[X_i].
John writes&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    t_i = \frac{\prod_{j\ne i} v_j}{\sum_{k=1}^n \prod_{j\ne k} v_j}.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
But if you multiply top and bottom by (1 &amp;#x2F; \prod_{m=1}^n v_m), you just get&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   t_i = \frac{1&amp;#x2F;v_i}{\sum_{k=1}^n 1&amp;#x2F;v_k}.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
No need to compute elementary symmetric polynomials.&lt;p&gt;If you plug those optimal (t_i) back into the variance, you get&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    \min Var[\sum t_i X_i] = 1&amp;#x2F;(\sum_{k=1}^n 1&amp;#x2F;v_k) = H&amp;#x2F;n,
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
where `H = n &amp;#x2F; (\sum_{k=1}^n 1&amp;#x2F;v_k)` is the Harmonic Mean of the variances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;paulgerhardt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish there was a Strunk and White for mathematics.&lt;p&gt;While by no means logically incorrect, it feels inelegant to setup a problem using variables A and B in the first paragraph and solve for X and Y in the second (compounded with the implicit X==B, and Y==A).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;esafak:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can also trade bias against variance to minimize the mean squared error, which is the squared bias plus variance. This applies generally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whatever1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is just the observed variance. Which means that you assume that this will be the variance in the future.&lt;p&gt;Don’t make decisions for evolving systems based on statistics.&lt;p&gt;Insider info on the other hand works much better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.johndcook.com/blog/2025/11/12/minimum-variance/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 15:25:08</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938027</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux on the Fujitsu Lifebook U729</title>
      <link>https://borretti.me/article/linux-on-the-fujitsu-lifebook-u729</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This came with the laptop. This is the Fujitsu BIOS update tool. You should have a new BIOS version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937989"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://borretti.me/article/linux-on-the-fujitsu-lifebook-u729'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 12 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;javaunsafe2019:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I also went this route but was disappointed by:
- bad speakers 
- poor battery life 
- inferior screen quality&lt;p&gt;Nowadays where you can get a MacBook Air 16gb m2 for around 600€ this would be my pick if I’d have to find a new machine for travel and casual use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chem83:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;For something portable with a dGPU, I recommend the Asus ProArt px13. Works very well with Linux, including NixOS with the right config, with the community asusctl and supergfxctl. AMD, OLED screen, nVidia 4070 (4060 in the US, maybe we&amp;#x27;ll get 50xx next year). Downsides: the keyboard is not amazing, it comes with MediaTek WiFi, but is replaceable, and the SSD is 2230, which limits capacity. I haven&amp;#x27;t been able to fine-tune touchpad sensitivity in Wayland and I do get some screen flickering despite fiddling with some boot params and being on 6.17.x. Fewer constraints if you&amp;#x27;re willing to go 14-inch with the Zephyrus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sunneyx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s kinda old though&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;internet2000:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; But the thing that got me, in all honesty, was the brand. “Fujitsu laptop” sounds like colour in a William Gibson novel: “crawling into the avionics bay, Case took out a battered Fujitsu refurb, and stuck a JTAG port in the flight computer—”.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s kind of hard to take this opinion seriously after that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UncleSlacky:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;TL;DR: When in doubt, update the BIOS before doing anything else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;varispeed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In my opinion, touching anything made by Fujitsu is not ethical.&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;British_Post_Office_scandal" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&amp;#x2F;wiki&amp;#x2F;British_Post_Office_scandal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;marcodiego:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; install Windows 11. This came with the laptop. And the installation makes installing Linux feel easy: I had to do so many weird tricks to avoid having to create an account with Microsoft during the installation.&lt;p&gt;The way secure boot evolved is disgusting. Specially because, at the time it was becoming popular, people we&amp;#x27;re warned that was more a tool of control than for security. Having to install a proprietary OS to install another should be forbidden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rcarmo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you have an old Intel MacBook Air, they work beautifully with Linux as well: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;taoofmac.com&amp;#x2F;space&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;2200" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;taoofmac.com&amp;#x2F;space&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;05&amp;#x2F;2200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gchamonlive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;If you want portability on something premium, I can&amp;#x27;t recommend enough the Lenovo Yoga Slim 7. Specwise I&amp;#x27;ve got the one with the Core ultra 5 125h. It also has an option with the 155h, but it battery and thermals can take a hit that I don&amp;#x27;t think it&amp;#x27;s worth it. It&amp;#x27;s got 16gb spread across 8x2gb modules and 512gb of ssd, both soldered, both extremely fast.&lt;p&gt;Build quality that rivals MacBooks, but with superior keyboard, very nice battery life and an oled screen on top of it.&lt;p&gt;The problem I had with the oled screen is that I thought it oversaturate reds out of the box on Linux, which I corrected using hyprshade: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;gchamon&amp;#x2F;archie&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;hypr&amp;#x2F;shaders&amp;#x2F;vibrance-oled.glsl" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;gchamon&amp;#x2F;archie&amp;#x2F;blob&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;hypr&amp;#x2F;shaders&amp;#x2F;vib...&lt;/a&gt;. I am looking for a better solution because the filters get picked on screenshots and washes out the colours. I need to find an ICE profile or export one from Windows.&lt;p&gt;The camera also behaves a bit weirdly. It has noticeable quality difference when using chromium and other browsers, the latter with perceptible quality degradation.&lt;p&gt;Other than that, a very good mobile linux driver, snappy, cool, quiet, charges fast and a joy to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jjice:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tossing Linux on used enterprise laptops is maybe the best bang for your buck machine you can get. They&amp;#x27;re often time a great value and within three years old. Used multiple Thinkpads and Dells over the years that were fantastic and gotten sub $400.&lt;p&gt;Things I learned to look out for:&lt;p&gt;- Locked BIOS&lt;p&gt;- Look into the manufacturer&amp;#x27;s repairability reputation. I replaced the entire keyboard on my ThinkPad X1 Carbon and it was perfectly fine. It was a pain to get to, but no problems. On a Dell Latitude, it refused to charge my non-OEM battery replacement. My fault - I should&amp;#x27;ve done some research.&lt;p&gt;In my experience, Dell and Lenovo have excellent Linux hardware support. I don&amp;#x27;t know about other manufacturers, but I hope that that&amp;#x27;s also the case now too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giancarlostoro:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Whenever Microsoft makes me make an account and I cannot bypass it I just make an throwaway with not so pleasant words in the email. Followed by installing EndeavourOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;maelito:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there a good linux ARM laptop, fanless ?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://borretti.me/article/linux-on-the-fujitsu-lifebook-u729</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 15:19:20</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937989</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windhawk Windows classic theme mod for Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://windhawk.net/mods/classic-theme-enable</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://windhawk.net/mods/classic-theme-enable</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 16:53:30</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938723</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kagi Bloopers – Search Results Gone Wrong</title>
      <link>https://help.kagi.com/kagi/bloopers/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hacker Originally on Mastodon. Half pony Originally on Discord. Corporation Originally on X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936964"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://help.kagi.com/kagi/bloopers/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 9 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TriangleEdge:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does Kagi have any value in the era of LLMs? My understanding is that it aggregates result from different providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BinaryPie:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is Kagi worth paying for? It&amp;#x27;s been on my radar for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nkurz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Given the title &amp;quot;Search Results Gone Wrong&amp;quot;, I&amp;#x27;d like to take this opportunity to try to shame Kagi into fixing the search results for the &amp;quot;More results&amp;quot; feature.  This simple feature is broken in that it often gives you repeats of the same initial results it gave.  That is, instead of giving you &amp;quot;More results&amp;quot;, it gives you a lot of &amp;quot;Same results&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I reported this as a bug about 6 months ago, and was quickly told it was planned to be fixed. But it hasn&amp;#x27;t been fixed. I checked in again a few weeks ago to see if there was any progress, and apparently they&amp;#x27;ve given up because it is too hard: &amp;quot;Apologies, seems I forgot to update the thread. Unfortunately it is in fact trickier than it looks to dedupe these results. Mainly this is a result of how we work with results from upstream sources, and deduping is heavily complicated by caching issues.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;Kagi, you&amp;#x27;re generally great.  I&amp;#x27;m usually happy to be a paying customer.  But I refuse to believe that deduping a list of URL&amp;#x27;s is actually too hard for you.  Maybe I&amp;#x27;m one of the few users who actually cares about searching for web pages, but for my use cases my search results would be much better if you actually gave me more results when I click on &amp;quot;More results&amp;quot;. How is this not considered core functionality for a search engine? Please fix this!&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s the bug report: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;kagifeedback.org&amp;#x2F;d&amp;#x2F;7022-clicking-more-results-yields-lots-of-duplicates" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;kagifeedback.org&amp;#x2F;d&amp;#x2F;7022-clicking-more-results-yields...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;phyzome:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Just going to drop a quick complaint here that &lt;i&gt;none of these are search results&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;(though yes, they are funny)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dceddia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Not quite a blooper but I thought it was neat:&lt;p&gt;I searched Kagi for “veterans day 2025” the other day (on Veterans Day, when I was unsure) and it answered&lt;p&gt;“= today”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;card_zero:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I guess for &amp;quot;Pop os&amp;quot; it gave a 2004 estimate for the population of the Cocos Islands. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.axl.cefan.ulaval.ca&amp;#x2F;pacifique&amp;#x2F;cocos-ile.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.axl.cefan.ulaval.ca&amp;#x2F;pacifique&amp;#x2F;cocos-ile.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;maccam912:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Heres one I found: search for &amp;quot;spaceweather&amp;quot; and you get weather for East Derry, New Hampshire. Definitely not space. The results I need are one and two for links below, but a friend pointed out that there is an astronaut (Alan Shepherd maybe?) who lived there which is the only connection to space I can think of for that city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;metayrnc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;“Pure numbers and French are not compatible”&lt;p&gt;Yep that checks out&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;amelius:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The first blooper seems to forget that time == money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://help.kagi.com/kagi/bloopers/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 12:23:08</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936964</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to write type-safe generics in C</title>
      <link>https://raphgl.github.io/blog/generics-in-c.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The header instantiation should look like this: #define VEC_ITEM_TYPE long long #define VEC_SUFFIX num #include "vector. #define G(name) name##_##VEC_ITEM_TYPE Except, this doesn’t work. So we’ll introduce a VEC_SUFFIX: #ifndef VEC_ITEM_TYPE #error VEC_ITEM_TYPE was not defined #endif #ifndef VEC_SUFFIX #define VEC_SUFFIX VEC_ITEM_TYPE #endif #define __G(name, type) name##_##type #define _G(name, type) __G(name, type) #define G(name) _G(name, VEC_SUFFIX) Now we’re free to implement our library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937518"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://raphgl.github.io/blog/generics-in-c.html'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jesse__:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wrote a metaprogramming language that adds another option to the list, for anyone that&amp;#x27;s interested : &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;poof" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;scallyw4g&amp;#x2F;poof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Type safety, generics and C is a bit of oxymoron.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;variadix:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can create macro functions per generic function so something like Vector_New(int)(&amp;amp;v) expands to Vector_New_int(&amp;amp;v). It also looks less foreign (more like templates) than the G macro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;david2ndaccount:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wrote a similar article in the past: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.davidpriver.com&amp;#x2F;ctemplates.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.davidpriver.com&amp;#x2F;ctemplates.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use this technique in my hobby projects as it has worked out the best for me of the options I’ve explored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;synergy20:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;or use nim metaprogramming, which will be transpiled to c&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lelanthran:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Having used this in production around 2004, I never really liked this approach - abusing the preprocessor this much shouldn&amp;#x27;t be necessary and the result is almost unreadable.&lt;p&gt;I think a better way is possible using `_Generic`[1]. Even though it would still use macros, the resulting code is much more readable.&lt;p&gt;---------------------------&lt;p&gt;[1] `_Generic` comes with its own problems too, of course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;schaefer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;A more accurate title would be:&lt;p&gt;“How to write type safe generics using the C preprocessor”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;self_awareness:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Well, another option would be to use a C++ compiler, which supports templates, but limit the use of classes through a coding convention standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://raphgl.github.io/blog/generics-in-c.html</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-11-15 13:58:09</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937518</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
