<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:30:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Implementation of Apple's Private Compute Cloud</title>
      <link>https://github.com/openpcc/openpcc</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read the OpenPCC Whitepaper: https://github. com/openpcc/openpcc" "github. com", } cfg := openpcc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824243"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/openpcc/openpcc'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 6 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;saurik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes: &amp;quot;provably&amp;quot; private... unless you have $1000 for a logic analyzer and a steady hand to solder together a fake DDR module.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45746753"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=45746753&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jabedude:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Where is the compute node source code?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;derpsteb:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I was part of a team that does the same thing. Arguably as a paid service, but source availability and meaningful attestation.&lt;p&gt;Service: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.privatemode.ai&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.privatemode.ai&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;
Code: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;edgelesssys&amp;#x2F;privatemode-public" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;edgelesssys&amp;#x2F;privatemode-public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ryanMVP:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Reading the whitepaper, the inference provider still has the ability to access the prompt and response plaintext. This scheme does seem to guarantee that plaintext cannot be read for all other parties (e.g. the API router), and that the client&amp;#x27;s identity is hidden and cannot be associated with their request. Perhaps the precise privacy guarantees and allowances should be summarized in the readme.&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, does this scheme offer any advantage over the much simpler setup of a user sending an inference request:&lt;p&gt;- directly to an inference provider (no API router middleman)&lt;p&gt;- that accepts anonymous crypto payments (I believe such things exist)&lt;p&gt;- using a VPN to mask their IP?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;pjmlp:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Apple&amp;#x27;s Private Compute Cloud is based on Swift though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kiwicopple:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;impressive work jmo - thanks for open sourcing this (and OSI-compliant)&lt;p&gt;we are working on a challenge which is somewhat like a homomorphic encryption problem - I&amp;#x27;m wondering if OpenPCC could help in some way? :&lt;p&gt;When developing websites&amp;#x2F;apps, developers generally use logs to debug production issues. However with wearables, logs can be privacy issue: imagine some AR glasses logging visual data (like someone&amp;#x27;s face). Would OpenPCC help to extract&amp;#x2F;clean&amp;#x2F;anonymize this sort of data for developers to help with their debugging?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/openpcc/openpcc</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824243</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I analyzed the lineups at the most popular nightclubs</title>
      <link>https://dev.karltryggvason.com/how-i-analyzed-the-lineups-at-the-worlds-most-popular-nightclubs/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data gathering #To visualize data, first you have to get some. After that I analyzed the data. This gives us a rough idea of which clubs are most similar, that is to say, have similar tastes in their bookings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835083"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://dev.karltryggvason.com/how-i-analyzed-the-lineups-at-the-worlds-most-popular-nightclubs/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RobKohr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love finding new music. Looks like now I can go find some far away clubs and listen to their djs while doing some coding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jrrv:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Am I missing something or is the author using dots for both breaking up large numbers and also for decimal points?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bongodongobob:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I actually want to go to Haunted House more than I want to go to Aqua.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;siva7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t confuse this list with actually very popular djs. Many clubs in this list host mostly resident and local djs (like Berghain as the club name&amp;#x2F;culture is the main reason people go there, not the lineup) instead of popular touring djs who have a big fan base of their own (and are more expensive to book).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevetron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Might have been nice to know where the clubs are?  San Francisco?  South Africa?  Belgium?  And what demographic the clubs serve, i.e are any of the clubs LGBTQ+, or are the all hetero?  They don&amp;#x27;t generally play the same material.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;input_sh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I love the idea behind it and the visualisation indeed looks awesome, but the RA data behind it is messy to say the least.&lt;p&gt;For example, 3&amp;#x2F;7 &amp;quot;nightclubs&amp;quot; it lists in Croatia are not nightclubs. I would also group Kalypso and Zrće Beach together as Kalypso is one out of 4 nightclubs located &lt;i&gt;on&lt;/i&gt; Zrće Beach, but the beach &lt;i&gt;itself&lt;/i&gt; is not a venue. Similarly, Barbarella&amp;#x27;s is kind of an afterparty destination for festivals organised at the Garden Resort. They only match 6%, but I wouldn&amp;#x27;t call them completely separate. This is the kind of &amp;quot;lore&amp;quot; that&amp;#x27;s impossible to catch from raw data.&lt;p&gt;I like the Essential Mix visualisation even more! It&amp;#x27;s such a shame most of the other ones appear dead due to API changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alexandregcode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;This is pretty cool, interesting to think about what causes more or  less resident DJs.&lt;p&gt;As a side note, on the RA events sometimes artists are listed in the description but not linked in the description so there could be some artists missing. In my experience it tends to vary on the nightclub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kalli:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The technical details of a visualisation built around the lineups and programming at the world&amp;#x27;s most popular nightclubs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://dev.karltryggvason.com/how-i-analyzed-the-lineups-at-the-worlds-most-popular-nightclubs/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835083</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: See chords as flags – Visual harmony of top composers on musescore</title>
      <link>https://rawl.rocks/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rawl.rocks/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45826472</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare Tells U.S. Govt That Foreign Site Blocking Efforts Are Trade Barriers</title>
      <link>https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-tells-u-s-govt-that-foreign-site-blocking-efforts-are-digital-trade-barriers/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spain Cloudflare writes that Spanish courts allow rightsholders to request “overbroad court orders” that authorize IP address blocking. France In France, Cloudflare highlights Article L. South Korea South Korea has also created trade barriers due to its site-blocking measures, Cloudflare reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835123"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-tells-u-s-govt-that-foreign-site-blocking-efforts-are-digital-trade-barriers/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 8 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACCount37:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m no fan of Cloudflare, but they&amp;#x27;re completely in the right on that. Infrastructure for blocking websites simply shouldn&amp;#x27;t exist.&lt;p&gt;Because if it&amp;#x27;s allowed to exist, it ends up subsumed by political and corporate interests, and becomes a tool of overreach and abuse. We&amp;#x27;ve seen that happen over and over again.&lt;p&gt;If US Trade Office can be leveraged to destroy internet censorship efforts in other countries, then so be it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moralestapia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;That&amp;#x27;s true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tiahura:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Backbone operators in the US should not be allowed to connect to networks that connect to low trust countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ivl:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cloudflare is right. But, it&amp;#x27;s a pretty typical EU play. Protecting more established interests but kneecapping progress.&lt;p&gt;In this case, hitting a massive number of small sites, which aren&amp;#x27;t engaged in piracy, to protect a few large entities from some other small piracy sites. It&amp;#x27;s what&amp;#x27;s happening in both Italy and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stego-tech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the one hand, Cloudflare crying crocodile tears for their policy decisions isn’t remotely moving. If anything, their plea for US intervention feels &lt;i&gt;incredibly&lt;/i&gt; insincere given that their business has been to defend literal Nazis and Pirates alike for decades, and if you’re going to build a business out of defending bad actors, well, you best be prepared for the consequences.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;That being said&lt;/i&gt;, they’re absolutely right that these broad, automated blocks aren’t acceptable for the internet as a whole - especially when a ruling is applicable regionally or globally. Blocking an entire IP range or service provider because of a handful of bad actors on their service is &lt;i&gt;incredibly&lt;/i&gt; excessive, akin to barricading off an entire neighborhood because one apartment is a crack den, i.e. stupidly disproportionate. If countries are having an issue with a company routinely and willfully allowing bad actors to prosper, the solution is simply to bar that company from operating within their jurisdiction commercially.&lt;p&gt;Yet the IT dinosaur in me reads that statement above, and I ultimately find myself back at where I’ve been for years: for a globally distributed network, the only way to effectively punish an operator like Cloudflare is to block its entire IP range, despite the harms innocent customers and users will incur. And I can’t quite figure out a way past that under the current piecemeal system of the internet and the financial incentives for consolidation and centralization.&lt;p&gt;We have to punish bad actors, but when said actor commands a significant swath of the legitimate internet, you either have to harm a disproportionate amount of legitimate traffic in blocking them, or admit they’re too big and important for a government to intervene against. The former is bad, but the latter is infinitely worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;beardyw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;Trade barriers&amp;quot; - mmm, I wonder who&amp;#x27;s attention they are trying to get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;digitalsushi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;i havent been in a tier 1 ISP in 20 years. can anyone who is in that life give a little summary of how much infrastructure we have in the united states to implement the same level of control as what china has available for walling its garden?&lt;p&gt;like, if the direction came down from on high, to copy it ... how few things would have to get flipped on to have roughly the same thing in the united states?&lt;p&gt;i&amp;#x27;d really appreciate an insider&amp;#x27;s summary.  a lot has changed since 2004. probably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;giorgioz:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I hosted a website on Cloudflare and I sent a link to it to a friend on a Sunday.
The friend told me the website was down.
Turns out Spain blocks IP addresses belonging to Cloudflare during big football matches because some pirate streaming websites are hosted on Cloudflare.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;europe&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1nm80wz&amp;#x2F;trying_to_use_cloudflare_websites_in_spain_while&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.reddit.com&amp;#x2F;r&amp;#x2F;europe&amp;#x2F;comments&amp;#x2F;1nm80wz&amp;#x2F;trying_to_u...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to go back to AWS.&lt;p&gt;Frankly Cloudflare is choosing the wrong battle on defending pirate streaming websites.
There are other gray areas that I apprecciate Cloudflare defending freedom of speech online, but pirate streaming websites aren&amp;#x27;t one of those.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://torrentfreak.com/cloudflare-tells-u-s-govt-that-foreign-site-blocking-efforts-are-digital-trade-barriers/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835123</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The trust collapse: Infinite AI content is awful</title>
      <link>https://arnon.dk/the-trust-collapse-infinite-ai-content-is-awful/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In many cases, your prospect already knows they need what you’re selling. Personalized outreach that references your LinkedIn posts (albeit badly). This is the trust collapse for me: it’s not that I don’t believe your product works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833496"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arnon.dk/the-trust-collapse-infinite-ai-content-is-awful/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 24 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lerc:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t think this shows that you can&amp;#x27;t trust things.   I think it means trust should be earned.&lt;p&gt;We might be transitioning to a world where trust has value and is earned and stored in your reputation.  Clickbait is a symptom of people valuing attention over trust.  Clickbait spends a percentage of their reputation by trading it for attention.&lt;p&gt;In a world of many providers, most people have not heard of any particular individual provider. This means they have no reputation to lose, so their choice to act in a reputation losing manner is easy.&lt;p&gt;Beyond a certain scale when everyone can play that game we end up with the problem that this article describes.  The content is easy but vacuous. There are far more people vying for the same number of eyballs now.&lt;p&gt;The solution is, I believe,  earned trust.   Curators select items from sources they trust.   The ones that do a good job become trusted curators.    In a sense HackerNews is a trusted curator.   Reddit is one that is losing, or has lost, trust.&lt;p&gt;AI could probably take on some of the role of that curation.  In the future perhaps more so.  An AI can scan the sources of an article to see if the sources make the claims that the article says it makes.  I doubt it can do so with sufficient accuracy to be useful right now,  but I don&amp;#x27;t think that is too far off.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the various fediverse reddit clones had the wrong idea.  Maybe they should in a distributed fashion where each point is a subreddit analogue operated each with their own ways of curation,  then an upper level curation can make a site of the groups they trust.&lt;p&gt;This makes a multi level trust mechanism.  At each level there are no rules governing behaviour.  If you violate the values of a higher layer, they lose trust in you.   AI could run its own curation nodes.  It might be good at it or it might be terrible, it doesn&amp;#x27;t really matter. If it is consistently good, it earns trust.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t mind there being lots of stuff, if I can still find the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;guzik:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;So I went on X after a long break from social media, and my feed is full of tips like this one:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Growing on X is so simple I’m shocked it works.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;100x comments a day&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;10x posts a day&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;15x DM’s a day&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;1x thread a day&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;1x email a day&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is how you grow your presence on X.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if having a presence matters, how can you actually say something meaningful if you post 10 times a day - there&amp;#x27;s no way (unless you just repeat yourself). Hopefully my algorithm&amp;#x27;s just gone weird but sadly the people I used to follow stopped posting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;returnInfinity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes sick of AI generated &amp;quot;illustrations&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_the_inflator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It didn&amp;#x27;t help documentation at all. I had to work with auth0 for example and their  documentation is such a bloat, that I am already prototyping with better-auth.&lt;p&gt;No structure, outdated stuff marked as &amp;quot;preview&amp;quot; from 2023&amp;#x2F;2024, wikipedia like in depth articles about everything but not for simple questions like: how to implement a backend for frontend.&lt;p&gt;You find fragments and pieces of information here and there - but no guidance at all. Settings hidden behind tabs etc.&lt;p&gt;A nightmare.&lt;p&gt;No sane developer would have done such a mess, because of time constraints and bloat. You see and experience first hand, that the few gems are from the trenches, with spelling mistakes etc.&lt;p&gt;Bloat for SEO, the mess for devs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cantor_S_drug:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We need PageRank like algorithm for &amp;quot;Trust &amp;#x2F; Human Content&amp;quot; to be applied directly to the source of such content. E.g. following all three channels are AI made. But all these content can be liked to an advanced AI version of audio based videos of Wikiarticles. If a video is providing just a summary based on established historical facts, even though it is AI based, how is it different than refering a thesaurus or dictionary? Aren&amp;#x27;t such videos making &amp;quot;knowledge&amp;quot; accessible.&lt;p&gt;FINAL Financial hours of U.S.A. just before the 1929 crash&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=dxiSOlvKUlA&amp;amp;t=1008s" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=dxiSOlvKUlA&amp;amp;t=1008s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Volcker Shock: When the Fed Broke the Economy to Save the Dollar (1980)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=cTvgL2XtHsw" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=cTvgL2XtHsw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;How Inflation Makes the Rich Richer&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=WDnlYQsbQ_c" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=WDnlYQsbQ_c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JCM9:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;We see business go through this cycle a lot. Some new “better cheaper” thing comes along. Everyone implements it to keep up with the Jones’s. Suddenly there’s no differentiation because everyone has it and everyone thinks it sucks. Suddenly going back to some reworked version of the old thing is the new black.&lt;p&gt;One such example was call centers. In the 2000s implementing a call center in India was all the rage on cost cutting. The customer experience was terrible and suddenly having a US-based call center (the thing companies just abandoned) was now a feature.&lt;p&gt;I think we’ll see similar things with AI. Everyone will get flooded with AI slop. Folks will get annoyed and suddenly interacting with a real human or a real human writing original content will be a “feature” that folks flock to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jjoe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Do you think usury is to blame for this aggressive and excessive push to make more money? Synonym for excessive here could be unethical&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharlin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;In other words, many new people now get to know the &amp;quot;using an internet dating service as a woman&amp;quot; experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;heddycrow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I wish we were talking about what&amp;#x27;s next versus what&amp;#x27;s increasingly here.&lt;p&gt;How can infinite AI content be strictly awful if it forces us to fix issues with our trust and reward systems? Short term, sure. But infinite (also) implies long term.&lt;p&gt;I wish I had a really smart game theorist friend who could help me project forward into time if for nothing other than just fun.&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#x27;t get me wrong, I&amp;#x27;m not trying to reduce the value of &amp;quot;ouch, it hurts right now&amp;quot; stories and responses.&lt;p&gt;But damned if we don&amp;#x27;t have an interesting and engaging problem on our hands right now.  There&amp;#x27;s got to be some people out there who love digging in to complicated problems.&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#x27;s next after trust collapses?  All of us just give up?  What if that collapse is sooner than we thought; can we think about the fun problem now?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;slightwinder:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What if this is the plan all along? People losing trust in media, so the rich and powerful can continue doing shit without getting exposed any more, because now they always can say it&amp;#x27;s just AI, and didn&amp;#x27;t really do this or that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stevetron:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;You can&amp;#x27;t build trust in your OS (operating system) when your OS spies on the entire customer base, and you spin it off as telemetry.  Or you remotely target the OS to implement a radical change, and force it to be installed as an &amp;#x27;update&amp;#x27;.&lt;p&gt;I stopped accepting telephone calls before 2010.  They still ring the phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ChrisMarshallNY:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt; Will you still be here in 12 months when I’ve integrated your tool into my workflow?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the biggie; especially with B2B. It&amp;#x27;s really 3 months, these days. Many companies have the lifespan of a mayfly.&lt;p&gt;AI isn&amp;#x27;t the new reason for this. It&amp;#x27;s been getting worse and worse, in the last few years, as people have been selling companies; not products, but AI will accelerate the race to the bottom. One of the things that AI has afforded, is that the lowest-tier, bottom-feeding scammer, can now look every bit as polished and professional as a Fortune 50 company (often, even more).&lt;p&gt;So that means that not only is the SNR dropping, the &amp;quot;noise&amp;quot; is now a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; riskier and uglier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ModernMech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Trust collapse is real, I don&amp;#x27;t trust anything anymore. Take this article for instance, I don&amp;#x27;t trust it because of the random bolding. Does that mean it&amp;#x27;s AI generated? I don&amp;#x27;t know but I&amp;#x27;ve seen lots of AI generated content and it has random bolding, so when I see it, I immediately don&amp;#x27;t trust it. And I don&amp;#x27;t have the time to verify anything, so whether or not this article was written by the author or AI, it&amp;#x27;s gone on the &amp;quot;not credible&amp;quot; heap for me, just because of the bolding. It&amp;#x27;s not a strong signal but it&amp;#x27;s a signal, and due to the volume of slop, I must filter on whatever signals I have to maintain any chance of finding genuine human work product. Maybe I miss something genuine and important by filtering this way, but it&amp;#x27;s the best I can do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applejinx:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m already seeing this. I very much fall into the category of &amp;#x27;delete all email offers&amp;#x27; as I&amp;#x27;m a small youtuber, big enough to be targeted by AI sponsor deals, so I&amp;#x27;m just buried with it.&lt;p&gt;The last five times I&amp;#x27;ve looked at something in case it was a legitimate user email it was AI promotion of someone just like in the article.&lt;p&gt;Their only way to escalate, apart from pure volume, is to take pains to intentionally emulate the signals of someone who&amp;#x27;s a legitimate user needing help or having a complaint. Logically, if you want to pursue the adversarial nature of this farther, the AIs will have to be trained to study up and mimic the dialogue trees of legitimate users needing support, only to introduce their promotion after I&amp;#x27;ve done several exchanges of seemingly legitimate support work, in the guise of a friend and happy customer. All pretend, to get to the pitch. AI&amp;#x27;s already capable of this if directed adeptly enough. You could write a script for it by asking AI for a script to do exactly this social exploit.&lt;p&gt;By then I&amp;#x27;ll be locked in a room that&amp;#x27;s also a Faraday cage, poking products through a slot in the door—and mocking my captors with the em-dashes I used back when I was one of the people THEY learned em-dashes from.&lt;p&gt;One thing about it, it&amp;#x27;s a very modern sort of dystopia!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;renegat0x0:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I use RSS to follow these I want to hear. I do not follow recommendation, since RSS reader is my window to the world.&lt;p&gt;I follow even AI slop via reddit RSS.&lt;p&gt;I control however what comes in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;realitydrift:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What you’re describing is basically the Drift Principle. Once a system optimizes faster than it can preserve context, fidelity is the first thing to go. AI made the cost of content and the cost of looking credible basically zero, so everything converges into the same synthetic pattern.&lt;p&gt;That’s why we’re seeing so much semantic drift too. The forms of credibility survive, but the intent behind them doesn’t. The system works, but the texture that signals real humans evaporates. That’s the trust collapse. Over optimized sameness drowning out the few cues we used to rely on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bee_rider:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What I get from the article is that, proving that a company will stick around for a while after you’ve subscribed is hard now, because anybody can AI generate the general vibe of the marketing department of a big established player. This seems like it’ll be devastating for companies whose business model requires signing new users up for ongoing subscriptions.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it could lead to a resurgence of the business model where you buy a program and don’t have to get married to the company that supports it, though?&lt;p&gt;I’d love it if the business model of “buy our buggy product now, we’ll maybe patch it later” died.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tetris11:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I needed to get some builder quotes for my home. It did not enter my mind to go online to search for any.&lt;p&gt;I just reached out to my family for any trustworthy builders they&amp;#x27;ve had, and struck up conversations with some of my fancier neighbors for any recommendations.&lt;p&gt;(I came to the conclusion that all builders are cowboys, and I might as well just try doing some of this myself via youtube videos)&lt;p&gt;Using the internet to buy products is not a problem for me, I know roughly the quality of what I expect to get and can return anything not up to standard. Using the internet to buy services though? Not a chance. How can you refund a service&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinjut:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;AI-esque blog post about how infinite AI content is awful, from &amp;quot;a co-founder at Paid, which is the first and only monetization and billing system for AI Agents&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alexpotato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yuval Noah Harari, Sapiens fame [0], has a great quote (paraphrasing):&lt;p&gt;Interviewer: How will humans deal with the avalanche of fake information that AI could bring?&lt;p&gt;YNH: The way humans have always dealt with fake information: by building institutions we trust to provide accurate information. This is not a new phenomenon btw.&lt;p&gt;In democracies, this is often either the government (e.g. the Bureau of Labor Statistics) or newspapers (e.g. the New York Times) or even individuals (e.g. Walter Cronkite).&lt;p&gt;In other forms of government, it becomes trust networks built on familial ties e.g. &amp;quot;Uncle&amp;#x2F;Aunt is the source for any good info on what&amp;#x27;s happening in the company&amp;quot; etc&lt;p&gt;0 - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;amzn.to&amp;#x2F;4nFuG7C" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;amzn.to&amp;#x2F;4nFuG7C&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everdrive:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Doesn&amp;#x27;t matter. We must keep building more and more technology no matter the cost. Have an idea for a business? Build it. Does your business make the lives of people worse? Doesn&amp;#x27;t matter, keep pushing. Could some new technology ruin the lives and relationships that people have? Doesn&amp;#x27;t matter, just build it. We always need more, need to do more. Every experiment is valid, every impulse must be followed. More complexity, more control, more distraction, more outrage, more engagement. Just keep building forever no matter the cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bgwalter:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It is becoming unbearable. YouTube now has &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; slop ads for Freenow (Lyft brand in the EU) with fake cars that move without the wheels turning and &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; &amp;quot;actors&amp;quot; that look like plastic.&lt;p&gt;This of course means that Freenow is now on the personal blacklist. People should not engage with companies who advertise with &amp;quot;AI&amp;quot; slop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;piker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The observations in this article about the insane signal-to-noise ratio are valid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;huijzer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Yes nice article. Interesting point.&lt;p&gt;One small one I do not agree with is &amp;quot;Are you burning VC cash on unsustainable unit economics?&amp;quot;. I think it&amp;#x27;s safe to conclude by now that unsustainable businesses can be kept alive for years as long as the investors want it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arnon.dk/the-trust-collapse-infinite-ai-content-is-awful/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833496</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IKEA launches new smart home range with 21 Matter-compatible products</title>
      <link>https://www.ikea.com/global/en/newsroom/retail/the-new-smart-home-from-ikea-matter-compatible-251106/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published 6 November 2025 • Inter IKEA newsroomIKEA launches new smart home range with 21 Matter-compatible products IKEA is launching 21 new smart home products focusing on lighting, sensors, and control — all built to work with Matter, the universal smart home standard. With this launch, IKEA is rebuilding its smart home system and product range from the ground up. Lighting – The new smart bulb range from IKEA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45834980"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.ikea.com/global/en/newsroom/retail/the-new-smart-home-from-ikea-matter-compatible-251106/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nixgeek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is anyone aware of or working on an equivalent to zigbee2mqtt but for both Matter-over-WiFi and Matter-over-Thread devices?&lt;p&gt;It’s so darn convenient to have MQTT in the picture for home automation and my #1 challenge in imagining a future world past my 400+ ZigBee devices is what replaces zigbee2mqtt and has a similar “owner experience”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;thedougd:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I really wish wall switches and dimmers were included in the first drop. I&amp;#x27;ve long been in the market for affordable Matter over Thread switches with a matte white finish from a reliable vendor.&lt;p&gt;They need to cover all the categories too (single, multi-pole, dimmer, and maybe fan speed) so I know I won&amp;#x27;t end up with a hodge podge of brands and looks.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ll keep holding out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exabrial:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;m not investing in any smart home products unless:&lt;p&gt;* I can fully control them without the cloud on a non-internet connected network&lt;p&gt;* I can either pay for updates, or they have free updates for at least 12 years, ideally 15&lt;p&gt;If a hurricane or tornado strikes, or some dictator tries to tell me what I can and can&amp;#x27;t do, my devices need to remain under my command.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;loufe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I just bought an AirGradient sensor and set up home assistant. What an absolute joy, both experiences (though I had issues building AirGradient&amp;#x27;s firmware due to some issues on their end, to their credit their dev team told me they&amp;#x27;re going to adopt my recommendations) are streamlined and professional and super easy to set up for a techie. I&amp;#x27;ve already got in the habit of opening the window to the office as the sensor detects elevated CO2 (happens faster and more often than expected, very glad I invested).&lt;p&gt;However, I also bought a 3 SCD41 sensors and ESP32 C3 Superminis from the most reputable sellers on AliExpress, that&amp;#x27;s been an abject failure. I wanted additional sensors in other rooms less at risk, and wanted to try using ESPHome and putting together my own soldered little devices. Got counterfeit sensors (no laser engraving on the side as Sensiron indicates is without reception the case in genuine parts) and either counterfeit or defective microcontrollers (cannot connect to wifi, even 2.4GHz WPA2, a common enough problem from my research with ). The spread from reputable sellers in NA was absolutely ridiculous and worse then buying premade pieces by a large margin.&lt;p&gt;All to say, as fun as DIY is, I&amp;#x27;m grateful to have trustworthy products available affordably. I&amp;#x27;ll still block internet access and leave them on a dedicated IoT VLAN, but I can at least not worry it&amp;#x27;s going to incorrectly label the air quality for a child&amp;#x27;s bedroom. I&amp;#x27;ll probably pick up 3 of the CO2 sensors from IKEA, if reviews look good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;martin_a:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I find pairing my IKEA bulbs and switches and whatnot to my Conbee 2 stick sometimes hard to do.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m thinking about buying a Dirigera hub instead, using that for the IKEA devices and using the Conbee stick only for non-IKEA products.&lt;p&gt;Does that work flawlessly when being controlled via HA or are there other issues to be expected?&lt;p&gt;edit: Maybe even ditch the Conbee stick after all, build some ESPHome devices as replacements (temperature&amp;#x2F;humidty - or wait for the IKEA version of that).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mongol:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Will zigbee2mqtt be able to talk to these? Or are they in a fully different type of network? If not, any other software that can do MQTT bridging with these?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whitehexagon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Although I have been trying to only buy &amp;#x27;needs&amp;#x27; not &amp;#x27;wants&amp;#x27; recently, I did stockpile a few IKEA ZigBee gadgets before they retired them.  One of the few product lines their MBA&amp;#x27;s hadn&amp;#x27;t destroyed.&lt;p&gt;I was working on some Golang code, talking to them via the very open ConBee II ZigBee gateway.  Great fun, and very fast once I got subscribe vs polling working.  So now I get an SMS for door access, but kinda hopefully never for a water leak.&lt;p&gt;No interest in yet another &amp;#x27;standard&amp;#x27;, especially since Matter seems to mandate PKI device attestation.  ZigBee just feels more open to me, and I have enough eWaste devices with expired certificates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ifh-hn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve never really got the smart home thing, and the shit being pulled with the likes of &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; TVs and cars has really put me off any sort of network connected device I can&amp;#x27;t control.&lt;p&gt;How would you use this and ensure privacy and security? Without investing time in becoming an amateur network engineer?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LeafItAlone:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Their new smart plugs finally seem reasonably sized.
I love IKEA’s smart home products, but their smart plugs (and many of their device power plugs) are comically sized in the US. Their original US version of the TRÅDFRI plugs wouldn’t even allow for two to be plugged into the same (standard size) dual wall outlet. Their more recent TRETAKT is much better, but still larger than competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AndrewDucker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Excellent.&lt;p&gt;I have some Thread&amp;#x2F;Matter smart bulbs, and they work well, but Ikea joining in shows that it&amp;#x27;s finally ready for the mass market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;carderne:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;What “hub” thing do I need to use this? I use an iPhone but really just want to use some physical remote switches.&lt;p&gt;I currently use Home Assistant but want to shift to something more “mass market” as I’m bored of being family tech support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mistletoe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tangential but I was wondering if anyone knows of a thermostat that can work with a security system for the most simple and accurate location sensing possible- when I press away on the alarm it turns the HVAC to eco type settings to save energy.  I used to get this with Google Nest and location sensing from my phone but Google as always is killing my generation of Nest thermostat.  I think I’d like to get away from location sensing entirely.  Every time I leave the house I do the alarm, so that is all I need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nerdjon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there an article that has the US pricing anywhere? It doesn&amp;#x27;t look like any of these are on the US site yet so I am curious what these will actually cost.&lt;p&gt;I keep hoping that Ikea would come up with something that can go over a switch to manually control it. Seems like it would be very much within Ikea&amp;#x27;s target market (renters). There are devices like this on Amazon but having used them in the past they are finicky at best.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;embedding-shape:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Does this mean they&amp;#x27;re abandoning Zigbee compatibility? In my experience, Ikea was making the most reliable Zigbee devices considering the price (as someone who just uses Zigbee and no Ikea hubs, just HA+Zigbee), and would be a shame to lose that, but maybe it&amp;#x27;s a clear sign I should investigate starting to use Matter more instead?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moshib:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;IKEA&amp;#x27;s Zigbee devices have been some of the more stable smart devices I owned. I wasn&amp;#x27;t running their hub, opting to run with deCONZ in the past and moving to Zigbee2MQTT in recent years.&lt;p&gt;I do wish the new range would include blinds; the previous generation (FYRTUR) is out of production, and it doesn&amp;#x27;t seem like there&amp;#x27;s a replacement yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;63stack:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have never heard of Matter before, but I was super satisfied with Ikea&amp;#x27;s zigbee products. Does anyone know why they switched?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.ikea.com/global/en/newsroom/retail/the-new-smart-home-from-ikea-matter-compatible-251106/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45834980</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
