<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss-style.xsl"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker News - English</title>
    <link>https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate</link>
    <description>Hacker News articles summarized and translated to English</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 21:22:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>HN RSS Translator</generator>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://tang1keke.github.io/hn-summary-and-translate/rss-en.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Two billion email addresses were exposed</title>
      <link>https://www.troyhunt.com/2-billion-email-addresses-were-exposed-and-we-indexed-them-all-in-have-i-been-pwned/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In that regard, credential stuffing data becomes "the keys to the castle". However, none of the other passwords associated with my address were familiar. The single password associated with this lady's email address had a massive nine characters, and also hadn't previously appeared in Pwned Passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839901"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.troyhunt.com/2-billion-email-addresses-were-exposed-and-we-indexed-them-all-in-have-i-been-pwned/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 16 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;brikym:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It boggles my mind that most email providers don&amp;#x27;t have a way to generate aliases for sign ups. Looks like proton and fastmail support it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jerf:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;On the plus side, Troy can save a lot of DB space now. Instead of storing which emails have been compromised at this point he can replace that with just&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    def email_compromised(email):
        return True&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jimmar:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I respect Troy Hunt&amp;#x27;s work. I searched for my email address on &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;haveibeenpwned.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;haveibeenpwned.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;, and my email was in the latest breach data set. But the site does not give me any way to take action. haveibeenpwned knows what passwords were breached, the people who breached the data knows what passwords were breached, but there does not seem to be any way for _me_, the person affected, to know what password were breached. The takeaway message is basically, &amp;quot;Yeah, you&amp;#x27;re at risk. Use good password practices.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;There is no perfect solution. Obviously, we don&amp;#x27;t want to give everybody an easy form where you can enter an email address and see all of the password it found. But I&amp;#x27;m not going to reset 500+ password because one of them might have been compromised. It seems like we must rely on our password managers (BitWarden, 1Password, Chrome&amp;#x27;s built-in manager, etc.) to tell us if individual passwords have been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rkagerer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The bit at the end about email deliverability was also interesting:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Notifying our subscribers is another problem... in terms of not ending up on a reputation naughty list or having mail throttled by the receiving server .... Not such a biggy for sending breach notices, but a major problem for people trying to sign into their dashboard who can no longer receive the email with the &amp;quot;magic&amp;quot; link.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this observation he got from someone:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;the strategy I&amp;#x27;ve found to best work with large email delivery is to look at the average number of emails you&amp;#x27;ve sent over the last 30 days each time you want to ramp up, and then increase that volume by around 50% per day until you&amp;#x27;ve worked your way through the queue&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eckesicle:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Is there any real drawback to just never giving your real name or address to service providers to minimise the chance of identity theft? Most likely it’s against terms of service, but other than account suspension are you likely to suffer any legal consequences?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hypeatei:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Cynicism is everywhere these days but these events really don&amp;#x27;t register for me anymore. Companies aren&amp;#x27;t punished by the government for these leaks and they aren&amp;#x27;t punished by consumers either. What incentive is there to reduce this data collection in the first place or to lock down your databases?&lt;p&gt;Even if someone&amp;#x27;s security is awful as the consumer and their account gets hacked because of these leaks, what are the actual consequences of that? Oh bummer, they need to reset their password and make a few phone calls to their bank to reverse the fraudulent charges then life goes on. Techies view that as unacceptable but most don&amp;#x27;t really care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;submeta:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have a throwaway email adresses for every website that requires signup. And a new password for every signup. Using Fastemail and a password manager. When emails adresses&amp;#x2F;passwords leak, I know which one I have to replace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;naet:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;There have been enough data breaches at this point that I&amp;#x27;m sure all my info has been exposed multiple times (addresses, SSN, telephone number, email, etc).  My email is in over a dozen breaches listed on the been pwned site.  I&amp;#x27;ve gotten legal letters about breaches from colleges I applied to, job boards I used, and other places that definitely have a good amount of my past personal information.  And that&amp;#x27;s not even counting the &amp;quot;legal&amp;quot; big data &amp;#x2F;analytics collected from past social media, Internet browsing, and whatever else.&lt;p&gt;I now use strong passwords stored in bitwarden to try to at least keep on top of that one piece. I&amp;#x27;m sure there are unfortunately random old accounts on services I don&amp;#x27;t use anymore with compromised passwords out there.&lt;p&gt;Not really sure what if anything can be done at this point. I wish my info wasn&amp;#x27;t out there but it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jlund-molfese:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Post should&amp;#x27;ve been titled &amp;quot;1.3 billion passwords were exposed&amp;quot;, because, even though the number is slightly smaller, it actually represents something much more important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hirvi74:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I have really started to use the &amp;#x27;Hide my email&amp;#x27; feature from iCloud. It&amp;#x27;s been so nice. If an email gets pwned, which often happens from a service I stopped using many moons ago, then I just deactivate or delete the email address. I imagine many other services provide this feature as well, but it&amp;#x27;s what&amp;#x27;s most convenient for me at this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zkmon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think we should stop seeing email address as a secret or something that can be &amp;quot;stolen&amp;quot;. Password? who is still storing passwords on their servers, instead of a hash?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zwnow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Can anyone enlighten me why an exposed email address is an issue?
I get it if its some kinda admin@foo.com but my private mail, why would I care? Its not like they have my password?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;imgabe:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;My data was exposed in one of the Facebook leaks and it turned out I had an old email on my Facebook account with a domain I had since let lapse and abandoned. Someone else registered the domain and tried to take over my Facebook account by sending a password reset request using it. Luckily I had 2FA and I guess Facebook&amp;#x27;s fraud alerts picked it up so It wasn&amp;#x27;t successful.&lt;p&gt;I guess what I want to say is beware that even something as innocuous as an email being leaked can cause problems, and make sure you delete any unused addresses from your accounts!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joe5150:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s honestly very hard to even care at that scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;worldfoodgood:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The downside to having many vanity urls and giving out a unique email address to each website you visit is that you cannot use haveibeenpwned without paying (despite being a single human). I have no idea how many email addresses I&amp;#x27;ve given out over the years, probably hundreds across at least 6 or 7 domains, and they want to charge me a monthly fee to see which of those have been pwned.&lt;p&gt;I understand they gotta make a buck, but I find it interesting this is the first real negative to running a unique email address per company&amp;#x2F;site I work with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gausswho:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Amidst all of these pwnings, we still don&amp;#x27;t have a standard way to update our passwords from our password managers automatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.troyhunt.com/2-billion-email-addresses-were-exposed-and-we-indexed-them-all-in-have-i-been-pwned/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839901</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLMs Encode How Difficult Problems Are</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18147</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;) Connected Papers Toggle Connected Papers (What is Connected Papers. ) Litmaps Toggle Litmaps (What is Litmaps. ) Links to Code Toggle Papers with Code (What is Papers with Code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838564"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18147'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kazinator:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s all very clear when you mentally replace &amp;quot;LLM&amp;quot; with &amp;quot;text completion driven by compressed training data&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;E.g.&lt;p&gt;[Text copletion driven by compressed training data] exhibit[s] a puzzling inconsistency: [it] solves complex problems yet frequently fail[s] on seemingly simpler ones.&lt;p&gt;Some problems are better represented by a locus of texts in the training data, allowing more plausible talk to be generated.  When the problem is not well represented, it does not help that the problem is simple.&lt;p&gt;If you train it on nothing but Scientology documents, and then ask about the Buddhist perspective on a situation, you will probably get some nonsense about body thetans, even if the situation is simple.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jiito:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I haven&amp;#x27;t read this particular paper in-depth, but it reminds me of another one I saw that used a similar approach to find if the model encodes its own certainty of answering correctly. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2509.10625" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;arxiv.org&amp;#x2F;abs&amp;#x2F;2509.10625&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.18147</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838564</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universe's expansion 'is now slowing, not speeding up'</title>
      <link>https://ras.ac.uk/news-and-press/research-highlights/universes-expansion-now-slowing-not-speeding</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corrections are applied to supernova data from the Dark Energy Survey project. After correction, the dataset no longer supports the ΛCDM model (red line) with a cosmological constant, but instead more closely fits with a time-varying dark energy model favoured by a combined analysis using only baryonic acoustic oscillations and cosmic microwave background data (blue line). 0)The corrected supernova data and the BAO+CMB-only results both indicate that dark energy weakens and evolves significantly with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45840200"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://ras.ac.uk/news-and-press/research-highlights/universes-expansion-now-slowing-not-speeding'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://ras.ac.uk/news-and-press/research-highlights/universes-expansion-now-slowing-not-speeding</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45840200</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: TabPFN-2.5 – SOTA foundation model for tabular data</title>
      <link>https://priorlabs.ai/technical-reports/tabpfn-2-5-model-report</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get In Touch * indicates required Email Address * First Name * Last Name * Company size * 1-49 50-249 250-999 1000+ Industry * Technology / Software Financial Services / Banking / Insurance Retail / E-commerce Manufacturing / Industrial Energy / Utilities Transportation / Logistics Education / Research Consulting / Professional Services Government / Public Sector Media / Communications Agriculture / Food &amp; Beverage Other Company Website * What are you interested in. * Using Prior Labs products for my business Just exploring / curious to learn more Partnership opportunities Press, event, or speaking request Other Interest (Other) Industry (Other) USECASE Have you tried using TabPFN Yes, I am already using it Tried it Exploring No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838540"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://priorlabs.ai/technical-reports/tabpfn-2-5-model-report'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 7 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;scorpion7:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fascinating how this works with such a small model. Especially given that the training is a kind of meta learning of &amp;quot;how to do in-context learning&amp;quot;. I wonder, is there a good intuition of the role of the MLP in this architecture? For LLMs the consensus seems to be that they store knowledge...what would that be for tabular data?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vessenes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I think you need a custom benchmark -- have you considered making one out of the excel world championships?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TheTaytay:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Looks really cool. In reading through the FAQ, it says this:
Q: &amp;quot;How are text features handled?&amp;quot;
A: &amp;quot;In the local package version text features are encoded as categoricals without considering their semantic meaning. Our API automatically detects text features and includes their semantic meaning into our prediction. The local package version encodes text as numerical categories and does not include semantic meaning.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;So that means that automatic embedding&amp;#x2F;semantic meaning is reserved for API use of TabPFN, right? Otherwise, if I use it locally, it&amp;#x27;s going to assign each of my distinct text values an arbitrary int, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abracos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;how does it compare to automl tools?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dill_1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Tabular data is still underrated!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zurfer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The current go to solution for the kinds of problems that TabPFN is solving would be something like XGBoost. In general it&amp;#x27;s a good baseline, but the challenge is always that you need to spend a lot of time feature engineering and tweaking the data representation before something like XGBoost can deliver good performance on your regression or classification problems.&lt;p&gt;For me the promise of foundation models for tabular data is that there are enough generalizable patterns, so that you need less manual feature engineering and data cleaning.&lt;p&gt;And kudos to the team, I think it&amp;#x27;s a really creative application of neural networks. I was always frustrated with neural networks, since they were hard to tune on &amp;quot;structured&amp;quot; data and always under-performed (for me), but we also never had real foundational models for structured data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;klemens_floege:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Good stuff!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://priorlabs.ai/technical-reports/tabpfn-2-5-model-report</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838540</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Show HN: Dynamic code and feedback walkthroughs with your coding Agent in VSCode</title>
      <link>https://www.intraview.ai/hn-demo</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it’s becoming abundantly clear that commoditizing coding is not commoditizing software development. It’s a VS Code extension (Yes, forks like Cursor too) that works with your existing Agent (Claude, GPT5-codex) via a local MCP to build visual tours. Nevertheless, it’s better to show than tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837067"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.intraview.ai/hn-demo'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.intraview.ai/hn-demo</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837067</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK outperforms US in creating unicorns from early stage VC investment</title>
      <link>https://www.cityam.com/uk-outperforms-us-in-creating-unicorns-from-early-stage-vc-investment/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8bn) of early stage investment into 57 successful unicorns, a ratio of 3. 08 start ups per $1bn in seed investment. Seed investment has jumped from $50m in 2014 to $538m in 2024, while early stage investment surged from $576m to $3bn over the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839655"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.cityam.com/uk-outperforms-us-in-creating-unicorns-from-early-stage-vc-investment/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 4 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;anon291:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;The main difference between the US and the UK is that American startups are building platforms for the world, whereas UK ones often consume those platforms. The platform holder holds the strategic keys. The efficiency of the market system is irrelevant to simple dominance. This is the same issue with other startup hubs, like Singapore, Bangalore, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BrenBarn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t really see this as a positive thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0xy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Satire?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fourseventy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;According to the article in the past decade the UK produced 57 unicorns, and the US produced 762. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t really call that outperforming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityam.com/uk-outperforms-us-in-creating-unicorns-from-early-stage-vc-investment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839655</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auraphone: A simple app to collect people's info at events</title>
      <link>https://andrewarrow.dev/2025/11/simple-app-collect-peoples-info-at-events/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With bluetooth your server advertises and when you connect it tells you what characteristics it has. If I have this file already cached, I'm good and I disconnect from this server. Now it's not like this app will keep running when you have your phone in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835931"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://andrewarrow.dev/2025/11/simple-app-collect-peoples-info-at-events/'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tobr:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Interesting from a technical point of view. But the real problem to solve here is buried in this throwaway at the end, and it even suggests that this is entirely the wrong tech for the job:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; So the way I see auraphone working at an event, you walk around and mingle as normal but yeah every one has their phone out and running the app but ONLY this app. You are still present and in the conversation not just looking at other distractions from your phone.&lt;p&gt;What is so magic about this app that it will make your phone not be a distraction? And how do you get everyone to download a new app? And if you can get them to do that, why not just exchange the info through a normal server? Then you could literally just tell the app which event you’re at (and sure, use Bluetooth for that, but a QR code or even just a link would probably work better) and then they don’t need to walk around with the app open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wigglefruit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;Streetpass for phones&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://andrewarrow.dev/2025/11/simple-app-collect-peoples-info-at-events/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835931</comments>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Hole Flare Is Biggest and Most Distant Seen</title>
      <link>https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/black-hole-flare-is-biggest-and-most-distant-seen</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The supermassive black hole behind the flare is a type of accreting, or feeding, black hole called an active galactic nucleus (AGN). This phenomenon occurs when a supermassive black hole's gravity shears a star that comes too close, slowly consuming the star over time as it spirals into the black hole. If the flare is from a TDE, the scientists estimate that the supermassive black hole gobbled a star with a mass at least 30 times greater than that of our Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838864"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HN Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/black-hole-flare-is-biggest-and-most-distant-seen'&gt;Read Original Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 2 Comments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SoftTalker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;quot;the star wandered too close to a gargantuan black hole&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;As if the star had any agency in that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="margin: 10px 0; padding: 10px; background: #f6f6f6; border-left: 3px solid #ff6600;"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0 0 5px 0;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vkou:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0;"&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot;If you convert our entire Sun to energy, using Albert Einstein&amp;#x27;s famous formula E = mc2, that&amp;#x27;s how much energy has been pouring out from this flare since we began observing it,&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a great journalistic quote, but the implication here is that the star&amp;#x27;s entire mass is being converted to energy as part of this process, which it very obviously isn&amp;#x27;t. (The black hole is net-gaining mass as a result of all this.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.caltech.edu/about/news/black-hole-flare-is-biggest-and-most-distant-seen</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838864</comments>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
